<text>
<front>
  <pb n="1" xml:id="P001" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/9/" />
  <titlePage>
  <docTitle>
    <titlePart type="main">LAWS, ORDERS
<lb />AND
<lb />CONTRACT ON COLONIZATION
<lb />1821 TO 1829</titlePart>
<titlePart type="sub">
UNDER WHICH COLONEL STEPHEN F. AUSTIN INTRODUCED
<lb />AND SETTLED EMIGRANTS IN TEXAS.</titlePart>
<titlePart type="desc">Translated from The Spanish.</titlePart></docTitle>
<publisher>SALTILLO.</publisher>
<docDate>1829</docDate>
</titlePage>
</front>


<pb n="2" xml:id="P002" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/10/" />

<body><div type="document">
<pb n="3" xml:id="P003" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/11/" />

<head>LAWS, ORDERS
AND
CONTRACTS FOR AUSTIN’S COLONY.</head>

<epitaph>
Translation of the Laws, Orders and Contracts on Colonisation from
January, 1821, uf to 1829; in virtue of which, Colonel Stef hen F.
Austin introduced and settled foreign emigrants in Texas: with an
Exflanatory introduction.</epitaph>

<head>INTRODUCTION.</head>
<p>
To the Settlers in what is called Austin's Colony," in Texas.
In order that the settlers, who have been established in Texas, under
the authority granted by the government, to Mr. Stephen Fuller Austin,
may fully understand the means by which they obtained admission, and
procured titles for land in this country, and the nature of those titles,
the following succinct narrative is presented to them, as an introduction
to the translations of the several laws, decrees and contracts on colonisa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
which follow, in the regular order of their dates. Manuscript trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations
of these documents, have heretofore been made and published, so
far as it was practicable to give publicity to them in that shape, and the
originals have always been open to the inspection of any one who called
at the office for that purpose. The earliest, and only opportunity which
has ever occurred, of publishing them in print, is now embraced.
</p>
<p>
The idea of forming a settlement of North Americans in the wilder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness
of Texas, originated with Mr. Moses Austin, of Missouri, and after
the conclusion of De Onis’s treaty in 1819, efforts were made by him to
put matters in train for an application to the Spanish government in
Spain. If the application succeeded, it was contemplated to remove a
number of families in a body, through Arkansas territory; and as a pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paratory
step, his son, Stephen Fuller Austin, was sent to Long Prairie,
on Red river, with some hands, &amp;c., for the purpose of opening a farm
near the boundary line, which it was thought would be useful, to fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nish
provisions, and afford facilities to emigrants; and a resting place,
until some preparation could be made in the wilderness of Texas. It
was thought that the farm could be advantageously sold afterwards, or
continued as a cotton plantation, should the enterprise totally fail. At
that time, there were but three families at Long Prairie, and Hempstead
county had just begun to settle. In answer to the inquiries of the elder
Austin, as to the best mode of laying the subject before the Spanish gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment,
he was advised to apply to the Spanish authorities of New

<pb n="4" xml:id="P004" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/12/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

Spain. He accordingly undertook the journey, from Missouri to the capi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tal
of the province of Texas. The information collected by the younger
Austin, on Red river, had convinced him that the route by way of Natch<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />itoches,-or
by water from New Orleans, was much preferable to the one
originally contemplated through Arkansas territory; which, added to the
unhealthiness of the situation at Long Prairie, and other circumstances,
caused an abandonment of the farming project at that place; and he met
his father at Little Rock in the summer of 1820. It was there arranged,
that the father should proceed to the capital of Texas, and the son to
New Orleans; the former to see what could be done by an application
to the Spanish authorities of New Spain; and the latter to make some
preparatory arrangements in New Orleans, for facilitating the transpor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tation
of families, furnishing supplies, &amp;c., and also, to be ready to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed
to the Havana, in the event of its being necessary to have recourse
to the government in Spain.
</p>
<p>The elder Austin arrived at Bexar, the capital of Texas, early in De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cember,
1820, and, on presenting himself to the governor, he received
a peremptory order to leave that capital instantly, and the province, as
soon as he could get out of it. This order was issued in consequence
of the general regulations then existing, prohibiting any foreigner from
entering the Spanish territory, without a specific description of pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port.
There was no remedy; and he left the governor’s house to prepare
for his departure. In crossing the public square, he accidentally met
the Baron De Bastrop, with whom he had a slight acquaintance, in the
United States many years previous. Mr. Austin became a Spanish sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject
in Upper Louisiana, in 1799, and De Bastrop went to the governor
with the documents which he had brought with him to prove the fact;
a second interview was thus obtained with the governor, and after several
days deliberation, and consultation with the cdbildo, a memorial was
presented by Mr. Austin, asking for permission to settle three hundred
families in Texas; which was sent on to the superior government of the
eastern internal provinces, strongly recommended by the local authori<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties
of this province.
</p>
<p>He left Bexar in January and arrived in Missouri in the spring, and
immediately set about making the necessary preparations for a removal
to Texas, as soon as he should hear of the success of his application. His
preparations, however, were greatly retarded by ill health, and on his
return in the winter through Texas, he suffered greatly from exposure
to bad weather, swimming and rafting rivers and creeks, and for want
of provisions; for at that time, Texas was an entire wilderness, from
Bexar to the Sabine. Nacogdoches and the settlements in its vicinity
had been totally broken up, and the inhabitants driven off by the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pedition
that was sent the year before by the Spanish government against
the revolutionists in that quarter. He reached Natchitoches, on his re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turn,
much afflicted by a severe cold that had settled in his breast, and
which terminated in an inflammation that finally ended his existence in
Missouri, a few days after he had received information of the success
of his application. He left a request that his son Stephen should prose<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cute
the enterprise, which he had thus commenced, of forming a settle<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
in Texas.
</p>
<p>Mr. Moses Austin was a native of Durham, in the state of Connecticut,
and much distinguished for enterprise and perseverance. At the age of


<pb n="5" xml:id="P005" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/13/" />

<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

twenty he married Miss Maria Brown, in Philadelphia, and soon after
established a commercial house in Richmond, Virginia, in partnership
with his brother Stephen, who was at the head of an extensive import<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
house in Philadelphia. They afterwards purchased the lead mines,
called Chissel’s mines, on New river, Wythe county, Virginia, to which
he removed and established a regular system of mining and smelting
shot, sheet lead, and other factories of lead, for which purpose, miners
and mechanics, in those branches, were introduced from England; for,
at that time, manufactories of this description, were in their infancy in
the United States. Revolutions, incident to extended commercial busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness,
and to adventurous enterprise, brought on a reverse in both the
Philadelphia and Virginia houses, and Mr. Moses Austin having received
flattering accounts of the lead mines of Upper Louisiana, (now Missouri,)
he determined to visit that distant and then unknown country. Accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ingly,
having procured the necessary passports from the Spanish minis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter,
he visited upper Louisiana in 1797, and procured a grant from the
governor general, Baron de Carondelet, for one league of land, including
the Mine-a-Burton, forty miles west of St. Genivieve; and after closing
all his affairs in the United States, he removed his family and a number
of others from Wythe county, by a new and almost untried route, down
the Kanhaway river, to his new grant, in 1799, and laid a foundaton for
the settlment of what is now called Washington county in Missouri.
The family of his nephew, Elias Bates, was the first, and his own, the
second, that ever spent a winter at Mine-a-Burton, now Potosi. The
early settlers of that place and county, will bear ample testimony, as to
his enterprise, public spirit, and honorable character; which qualities,
in fact, brought on another reverse of fortune, and caused him to turn,
with unabated ardor, in the decline of life, to a new and hazardous enter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prise,
in the wilderness of Texas.—It is hoped the reader will pardon
this digression; it was thought due to the real author of that enterprise,
which has led to our location in this country.</p>

<p>The memorial of Moses Austin was granted on the 17th of January,
1821, by the supreme government of the eastern internal provinces of
New Spain at Monterey. It gave permission to said Austin to introduce
three hundred families in Texas. A special commissioner was despatched
by the governor of Texas, in conformity with the orders of the command<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ant
general, Don Joaquin de Aredondo, to the United States, for the
purpose of communicating to Mr. Austin the result of his application,
and of conducting the said families, in a legal manner, into the country.
This commissioner was Don Erasmo Seguin, a very respectable citizen
of Bexar.</p>

<p>S. F. Austin, who was in New Orleans, as before stated, having re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived
information of the arrival of the commissioner, Don Erasmo Se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />guin,
at Natchitoches, proceeded to that place, and there heard the death
of his father. He then determined to accompany the said commissioner
to Bexar, explore the country, and make such further arrangements as
might be necessary to prosecute the enterprise. He accordingly started
from Natchitoches the 5th July, 1821, with seventeen companions, in
company with said commissioner, and some other gentlemen from Bexar,
among whom was Don Juan Martin Berrimendi, also a respectable citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zen
of that place. The whole company arrived in the capital of Texas,
on the 10th of August, by the upper or San Antonio road. He was

<pb n="6" xml:id="P006" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/14/" />

<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

kindly received by governor Martinez, who granted him a general per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission
to explore the country on the Colorado river, sound its en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trance,
harbor, &amp;c., and select such a situation as he might consider the
most advantageous for the new settlement.</p>

<p>The governor requested Austin verbally, to furnish a plan for the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tribution
of land to the new settlers; he accordingly-proposed one, which,
in his opinion, was sufficiently advantageous to the settlers, and at the
same time, adapted to the wilderness state of the country, which required
a compact location, to ensure safety from the Indians. The basis estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished
in the plan proposed, was, to give each head of a family and each
single man over age, six hundred and forty acres, three hundred and
twenty acres in addition for the wife, should there be one, one hundred
and sixty acres in addition for each child, and eighty acres in addition
for each slave. This plan was presented in writing, and Austin received
authority from the governor to promise that quantity to the settlers.
He was also commissioned by the governor to take charge of the local
government of the new settlement, until it could be otherwise organised.</p>

<p>He departed from Bexar the last of August, and from La Bahia, (now
Goliad,) the 10th of September. At the latter place he procured a guide
from the alcalde, in virtue of an order to that effect from the governor.
His company was now reduced to nine men, the others having returned
from La Bahia to the United states. He explored the river Guadalupe,
down to the bay, and attempted to follow round the bay shore to.the
mouth of the Colorado; but finding that the guide knew nothing of the
route, after leaving the Guadalupe, and frequently involved the company
in difficulties among the numerous tide inlets; he dismissed him, and bore
up north until he struck the road of the crossing of La Baca, and ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plored
the Colorado and Brazos, as far as was practicable, and sufficient
to convince him of the fertility of tkre country on those two rivers; and its
elegibility for the new settlement. LOn his return to Louisiana, he pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished’
in the newspapers a notice of the contemplated new settlement,
stating the quantity of land which he was authorised by the governor’s
letter of the 19th of August, to promise; and also stating that each
settler must pay twelve and a half cents per acre—he, Austin, taking
upon himself all the cost of surveying, and all other costs and fees or
charges of whatever kind, as well as the translating, trouble and labor
of attending to the business, and procuring the titles, &amp;c. Said sum
was to be paid after receipt of title, in instalments. This twelve and a
half cents per acre was also designed to provide for the defence of the
new settlement against the hostile Indians, to furnish supplies to aid
poor emigrants, and to defray the necessary expenses of the local gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment.
He also considered that he was justly entitled to a remunera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
for his labor and expenses, and he run the risk of saving something
for himself out of said funds: his father had also expended much time
and money in the enterprise; besides the fatigue, privations and suffer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings
of such a journey, as that from Potosi, in Missouri, to Bexar and
back again; the most of it through a wilderness. It was evident that
a fund was necessary, or the settlement must fail. A moment’s reflection
showed the utter impracticability of attempting to raise it by voluntary
contribution or subscription amongst the settlers, and the plan of a tax
on each settler would have been kindling a volcano under the cradle of
the enterprise. There was, in fact, no other safe mode but to make it

<pb n="7" xml:id="P007" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/15/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

a matter of voluntary contract, formed and entered into, by and between
Austin on the one part, and the settlers on the other; and in order to
give due notice of said contract, to all concerned, it was published in
the newspapers, so that each might know, before he started from his
former residence, to emigrate, on what terms he would be received; and
the act of applying for admission, as one of the 300 settlers, was an ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceptance
by the applicant, of the terms offered, and a ratification on his
part, of said contract, whether he specially signed a bond to that effect
or not. Austin consulted the governor of Texas on this subject; and
after explaining its nature and objects, he asked the opinion of the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor,
as to whether the government would be likely to interfere with
such an arrangement, between him and the settlers. The governor ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />served,
that the government would expect a strict • compliance, as
to the number and description of settlers, but he could see no
reason why it should interfere with any private arrangement, legally
and fairly made with them, of the kind indicated. The case was sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed
that should 900 families apply for admission, only 300 of them
could be received, and he should therefore say to them, those who pay
me a certain sum will be admitted. The opinion was expressed that if
no fraud, or deceptive allurements were held out, to mislead, even such
an arrangement as that, freely and voluntarily made, and understood
by all parties, would not be interfered with by the government; he ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />served,
however, that it was merely a matter of opinion with him, as he
could not say what the superior government might do in such cases.
Under this view of the matter, and for the objects of general utility,
before explained, Austin adopted the plan he did, in regard to the twelve
and a half cents per acre. This explanation is given, because this sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject
belongs properly to the history of the land titles; and it is one about
which there has been some erroneous impressions. It is very evident
that mere speculation was not the object, as some have stated, for but
little would have been left, at best, after paying the expense of surveying,
the office fees, the commissioner’s fees, the stamp paper, and defraying
the other necessary expenses; the object, therefore, must have been the
general good of all, and not the private speculation of one individual.
</p>
<p>
In December, 1821, Austin arrived on the river Brazos, at the La
Bahia road with the first emigrants, and the new settlement.was com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />menced
in the midst of an entire wilderness. Without entering into a
detailed history of the settlement, and noticing all the difficulties, priva<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
and dangers that were surmounted by the first emigrants, it is
sufficient to say, that such a detail would present examples of inflexible
perseverance and fortitude, on the part of those settlers, which have
been seldom equalled, in any country or in any enterprise.
</p>
<p>In March, Austin proceeded to Bexar, to make his report to the gover<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nor,
where he was informed for the first time, that it would be necessary
for him to proceed immediately to the city of Mexico, in order to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cure
from the Mexican congress, then in session, a confirmation of the
permission to Moses Austin, and receive special instructions, as to the
distribution of land, the issuing of titles, &amp;c.
</p>
<p>
It should have been stated before, that Austin received the first posi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive
information of the revolution, and plan of Iguala, of the 24th Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary,
1821; and of the complete independence of Mexico, on his arrival
at Bexar, in August of that year; so that the official acts of governor

<pb n="8" xml:id="P008" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/16/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

Martinez, relative to the new settlement, dated in August, 1821, were
from a governor of the independent Mexican nation, and not from a
Spanish governor. For this reason, the intimation as to the trip to
Mexico, was totally unexpected, and very embarrassing; for not calcu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lating
on any thing of the kind, he had not made the necessary prepara<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
for such a journey. There was no time for hesitation; arrange<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments
were made for Mr. Josiah H. Bell to take charge of the new set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tlement,
and Austin departed for Mexico, a journey of 1200 miles by
land.</p>
<p>
The Mexican nation had just sprung into existence. The galling
chains of Spanish despotism had been gloriously thrown off, but the
necessary restraint of law, system, and local police, had not yet been
sufficiently established; much disorder prevailed in consequence, in many
parts of the country; and the roads were infested in many places, with
deserters, and the lawless bands of robbers. Austin, however, arrived
in the great capital of this nation, on the 29th of April, 1822, without
any other accident than being overhauled, and partially robbed by a war
party of 54 Comanches, on the river Nueces, about one hnndred miles
beyond Bexar. From Monterrey he had one companion, Lorenzo Christie,
who had been a captain, in general Mina’s expedition. They both dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />guised
themselves, in ragged clothes, with blankets, &amp;c.,. in the same
style, as to pass for very poor men, who were going to Mexico, to petition
for compensation for services, in the revolution. Their passports ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plained
to the several authorities, as they passed, who they were, and
many friendly cautions were given as to the robbers.</p>

<p>The national congress had been in session since the 24th of February
of that year. The form of government, as then established, was a limited
monarchy, in conformity with the plan of Iguala, and treaty of Cordova,
and the Spanish constitution was provisionally adopted. The executive de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partment
was admisinstered by a regency, of which, the generalissimo,
Don Agustin Iturbide, was president. The state of political affairs in
the capital, at this time, was very unsettled. Generals Victoria and
Bravo, and several other republican leaders of rank, who had been im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prisoned
by Iturbide in November, for opposing his ambitious designs,
had escaped from confinement, not long before; serious dissentions had
already arisen between the generalissimo and congress; the regency were
divided, and in discord among themselves: Yanez, one of its principal
and most liberal members, having had a personal dispute of great
warmth with Iturbide, during one of the sittings, in which the terms
“traitor,” “usurper,” &amp;c., were mutually passed; the friends of liberty
were .greatly alarmed at the ascendency which the generalissimo had
acquired over the military, and lower class of the populace; and every
thing indicated an approaching crisis. Accordingly on the night of
the 18th of May, the soldiery and populace, headed by sergeants and
corporals, proclaimed Iturbide emperor. It was a night of violence,
confusion and uproar. The 700 bells of the city, pealing from the
steeples of monasteries, convents and churches; the firing of cannon and
musketry from the different barracks; and the shouts of the poulace
in the strees, proclaimed to the true friends of freedom, that a few com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mon
soldiers, in union with a city mob, had taken it upon themselves
to decide the destiny of Mexico, and to utter the voice of the nation.
The session of congress on the 19 th was held, surrounded with bayonets,

<pb n="9" xml:id="P009" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/17/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

and the man who was thus proclaimed by a rabble, amidst darkness and
tumult, was declared by a decree of the majority of that body, to be
emperor of Mexico.</p>
<p>
In such a state of political affairs, all that a person could do, who
had business to transact with government, was to form acquaintances,
try to secure friends, and wait for a favorable opportunity. Austin
adopted this course, and devoted the principal part of his time to study<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
the Spanish language; for when he arrived. at Mexico, he labored
under the disadvantages of being a foreigner, a total stranger, and igno<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant
of the language of the country, except what little he had acquired
in his first trip to Bexar, and on his journey to the capital. 1
</p>
<p>
On the examination into the state of this colonisation business, he
found that the regency had decided, that the governor of Texas, Mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinez,
was not sufficiently authorised to stipulate what quantity of land
the new settlers were to get, as he did, by his letter to Austin, of 19th
August, 1821, and that this point must be settled by a law of congress:
for which purpose all the documents relative to said new settlement, were
transmitted by the regency to congress. This at once explained the
reason, why governor Martinez urged Austin to go to Mexico, for he
was doubtless well aware, that in the then existing state of political
affairs, nothing would be done in the business unless some one was pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent
to attend to it.</p>

<p>Austin endeavored to procure the despatch of his business by means
of a special law, but found it to be impracticable, owing to several pe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titions
having been presented for colonies, which gave rise to an idea
among the members, that a general colonisation law ought to be passed,
and that all should be placed on the same footing; nothing, therefore,
could be done, until such a general law was enacted. A standing com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee
on colonisation had been appointed, previous to his arrival in the
city, to which his business was referred. This committee made some
progress towards settling- the basis of a law; but the coronation on the
21st July, the dissensions between the emperor and congress, the general
alarm amongst the liberal members, at the strides of the former towards
absolute power; the events which grew out of the violent proceedings of
the 26th August, when fourteen of the principal members of congress
were seized in their beds and imprisoned; added to the necessary atten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
to the revenue, and financial departments, and to national affairs
generally, precluded any advancement in a matter which was considered
to be so comparatively unimportant, as a new settlement amongst bar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />barous
savages, 1200 miles distant, in the wilderness of Texas. Not<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />withstanding
the many embarrassments, however, which retarded the
business, the committee on colonisation reported a general colonisation
law; the discussion of which had proceeded, in detail, to within three
articles of the end, when, on the 31st of October, the congress was turned
out of doors by an armed force, acting under a decree of the emperor,
which declared that congress was dissolved, and vesting the legislative
power of the nation in a Junta Instituyente, whose members were all
nominated by himself. This event, of course, threw back the colonisa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
law to its first stage; all had to be begun de novo; a new colonisation
committee was appointed, a new law was reported, though not differing
much from the former, which finally passed, and was approved by the
emperor, and promulgated on the 4th of January, 1823.
</p>

<pb n="10" xml:id="P0010" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/18/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

<p>Thus, eight months after his arrival in the capital, Austin had the
satisfaction of finding himself advanced one step; a colonisation law was
enacted and promulgated. The next step was to procure the despatch
of his business from the executive, a task which at first promised to be
almost as' difficult to accomplish as the other had been, owing to the
excitement which was daily becoming more open and manifest, against
the arbitrary proceedings of the emperor, which portended another revo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lution,
and of course, a further suspension of all business of an individual
nature. Fortunately, however, the minister of exterior and interior re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations,
Don Jose Manuel Herrera, and the sub-minister of the same
department, Don Andres Quintana, were both men of liberal and en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lightened
principles, and, so far as the then existing state of politics
would permit, they were favorable to the emigration of foreigners. The
despatch of individual affairs appertaining to the interior, or home de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partment,
was principally confided to the sub-minister, Quintana. The
captain general of the internal provinces, Don Anastacio Bustamente,
(now vice president of the nation,) within whose command Texas was
included, also took a very liberal and enlightened view of the advantages
which would result to the nation, from settling the wilderness of Texas,
to which he was very favorably inclined: also, a number of the members
of the Junta Instituyente, and of the council of state, were favorably
disposed towards the enterprise: added to all of which, the claims of
Austin, on the attention and justice of government, were strong and in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />controvertible. He came into Texas with the emigrant settlers, in vir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tue
of a permission, legally granted to his father, by the competent
Spanish authorities, previous to the change of government; he was also
officially conducted into the country, by a ‘commissioner, expressly ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed
by the governor of Texas, for that purpose; and on his arrival
at the capital of that province, he was officially received, and recognised
by governor Antonia Martinez, after the change of government; and of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficially
authorized by that functionary of the independent Mexican nation,
to proceed with the settlement; the amount of land to be distributed to
each settler was stipulated; and he, (Austin,) was appointed to admin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ister,
provisionally, the local government of the new settlement. Fie
had also been detained nearly a year in Mexico, on this business. These
circumstances enabled him to bring the matter before the council of
state, in a shape which procured its speedy and favorable despatch, by.
that body, who reported their opinion relative to it, on the 14th of Jan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uary;
and on the 18th of February, 1823, the minister Andres Quintana,
issued the emperor’s final decree on the subject. This decree was con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formable,
in general, to the advice given to the emperor, by the council,
in their report, though not exactly, in every particular.</p>

<p>The great object which took Austin to Mexico being accomplished,
he made preparation to depart immediately for Texas, and intended
to have started on the 23d of February, but, previous to that day in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formation
reached the city, relative to the progress of the revolution
against the emperor which convinced all reflecting men, that a great
political change of some kind was near at hand.</p>

<p>On the 2d December, Gen. Santa Ana, who commanded at Vera Cruz,
raised the standard of opposition to the arbitrary proceedings of Itur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bide,
and on the 6th, in union with the civil authorities of that city,
he published a “plan;” the basis of which was the re-union of the same

<pb n="11" xml:id="P0011" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/19/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

congress, whose members had been dispersed by the arbitrary order of
the emperor, on the 31st October; and that its deliberations should be
free from military restraint. General Victoria suddenly appeared from
the retreat where he had remained concealed, since his flight from Mex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ico,
in February, 1822, and joined the congress party. A severe, though
not decisive battle, was founght at Xalapa, on the 21st of December,
between Santa Anna and the imperial troops, in which the former failed
to get possession of that town. General Guerrero and Bravo also retired
suddenly from the capital, and took the field in favor of congress, at
the head of the guerillas, in Oaxaca, and towards Acapulco; and on the
2d of February, the army that was beseiging Santa Anna in Vera Cruz,
under the command of Gen. Echavarri, revolted in a body from the
emperor, and forming a junction with the beseiged, declared in favor
of congress, and published another plan, similar to that of Santa Anna’s,
called the Plan of Casa Mata. These events gave great impulse to the
revolution, which spread through the provinces of Vera Cruz, Puebla,
Oaxaca, and parts of Mexico. Vivanco, the captain general of Puebla,
declared in favor of congress; and owing to his popularity with the
soldiers, was appointed commander-in-chief of the ‘‘liberating army.”
All the other parts of the nation, however, had thus far appeared to
remain quiet, and in favor of the emperor: though a general anxiety,
suspense and excitement, had prevailed since Santa Anna’s defection;
which was daily becoming more intense, and tending towards a decisive
crisis. On the 19th February, the minister Jose Manuel Herrera, secretly
fled from the capital, and concealed himself so effectually, that he was
supposed to be dead for two years afterwards. And on the 20th and
21st, information was circulated in the city, of the general defection
from the emperor, of those parts of the nation, which had heretofore
remained passive; and Iturbide began to be publicly spoken of as a
usurper; and some were of opinion that all his acts would be annulled
by congress. This would have thrown Austin back to where he started
the year before: and it was therefore too important a matter to be left
unattended to. Fie consulted several lawyers and other persons of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formation
on the subject: some gave the opinion that all acts of the
government de facto, of such an individual nature as this, where the
rights and interests of individuals alone were concerned, without being in
any way connected with the general politics of the government or nation,
would be good; and others thought that it would be safer to obtain the
sanction of congress. It was sufficient for Austin, that any doubt ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peared
to exist; and he determined to suspend his journey to Texas, and
wait the meeting of congress, which it was now evident, must soon take
place.</p>

<p>Early in February, the emperor marched out of the city in person, at
the head of all the troops he could collect, and occupied a station at the
village of Istapaluca, five leagues on the road to Puebla. Finding, how<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever,
that he could not rely upon his troops, and that the opposing force,
which was approaching on the Puebla road, under Vivanco, greatly ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeded
his, and was daily augmenting by desertions from his own army;
he consented to a cessation of hostilities, and commissioners were ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed
on both sides, to treat. ' The said commissioners met in the
village of Mexicansingo, a few leagues out of the capital, and agreed in
substance: that the emperor should retire to Tacubaya, three leagues

<pb n="12" xml:id="P0012" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/20/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

from the city; that congress should convene, as soon as its dispersed
members could be collected; and that all parties should unconditionally
submit to whatever congress might dictate; neither to have any troops
in the city, and the necessary guards to keep order, were to be placed
under the direction of the local civil authority, until congress met. Both
parties complied with this treaty. Congress convened, and on the 29th
of March decided: 1st. That the sovereign constituent congress of the
Mexican nation was in legal session, there being one hundred and three
members present, which was a majority of the whole number, and that
its deliberations were entirely free from all military, or other forcible
restraint. 2d. That the executive power of Mexico, which had existed
since the 19th of May, 1822, up to that time, had ceased. 3d. That this
decree should be communicated to the supreme executive power, which
would be established by congress, for its publication, &amp;c. On the 31st,
congress decreed that the executive authority of the Mexican nation
should be provisionally deposited in a body, who should be styled, the
Supreme Executive Power, and be composed of three individuals, &amp;c.
On the same day, three persons who were to compose the executive, were
elected by congress, viz.: Nicholas Bravo, Guadalupe Victoria, and Pedro
Celestino Negrettee; and Jose Mariano Michelena, and Miguel Domin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />guez
were elected supernumeraries, to fill the places of any of the others
who might be absent until their arrival. An entirely new organisation
of the different branches of the government now took place. On the
8th of April, congress decreed that the coronation of Don Augustin de
Iturbide, was an act of violence and force, and was null; and conse<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quently,
that the resignation of the crown tendered by him, on the 19th
of March, could not be considered by congress, and that the hereditary
succession, and all titles emanating from said coronation, were null; and
all the acts of the last government, from the 19th May, 1822, to the 29th
May, 1823, were illegal, and subject to be revised, confirmed, or revoked
by the government now established; and finally, said decree banished
Iturbide from the Mexican territory forever; but assigned him $25,000
annually, (provided he resided in some part of Italy,) and fixed a pension
of $8,000 annually on his family after his death.
</p>
<p>
In consequence of the decree, of Sth April, Austin presented a mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />orial
to congress, together with the concession which he had obtained
from the last government on the 18th February; and petitioned congress
to confirm said concession, or dispose of it as that body might deem
proper. On the 11th April, congress passed a decree, referring said
memorial and concession to the supreme executive power, to be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />firmed
by that power, should it have no objection to said confirmation;
said decree also suspended, for the future, the law of colonisation, passed
by the Junta Instituyente, the 4th of January, 1823, until a new resolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of congress on the subject. On the 14th of April, the supreme ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ecutive
power issued a decree, in virtue of the act of congress above<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mentioned,
by which that power confirmed in full, the accession granted
to Austin by the imperial government, on the 18th of February, 1823;
and said decree was circulated by the minister of interior and exterior
relations, Don Garcia Ilueca, to the captain-general of the internal pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vinces;
and a certified copy of it was' delivered to Austin.
</p>
<p>
Thus, after one year’s detention and exertion in Mexico, Austin, at
last, had the satisfaction of leaving there, with his business despatched

<pb n="13" xml:id="P0013" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/21/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

and confirmed by all the governments which had ruled the Mexican
nation, during the said year; and as the last confirmation was by the
sovereign constitutent congress, whose members were the acknowledged
and legal representatives of the people of the nation, there could no
shadow of doubt remain, as to the legality and validity of his conces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion;
and on the 28th day of April, he departed from the capital.
</p>
<p>
On his arrival at Monterrey, the capital of the eastern internal pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vinces,
he presented a consultation to the commandant-general, Don
Felipe de la Garza, requesting special instructions, and copies of the
laws, for the administration of the local government of the new colony,
which was committed to his charge, in general terms, by the decree of
the supreme government of 18th February, 1823. This consultation was
transmitted by the commandant-general, to the provincial deputation of
Nueva Leon, Coahuila and Texas, then in session, in that city; who de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />creed
in substance, that Austin’s authority, under the said decree of
18th of February, was full and ample, as to the administration of justice,
and of the civil local government of the colony; and the command of
the militia; and that his grade or rank as a military officer should be lieu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenant
colonel; that he could make war on the Indian tribes, who were
hostile and molested the settlement; that he could introduce, by the
harbor of Galveston, such supplies of provisions, &amp;c. as might be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary
for the settlement in its infancy; in short, that he should preserve
good order, and govern the colony in all civil, judicial, and military
matters, according to the best of his abilities, and as justice might re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire,
until the government was otherwise organised, and copies of laws
were furnished, rendering to the governor of Texas an account of his
acts, or of any important event that might occur, and being himself sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject
to him and the commander-general. The local government was thus
committed to him with the most extensive powers, but without any copies
of laws, or specific instructions whatever, for his guide; the act of the
deputation, therefore, left the matter in substance, precisely where the
decree of 18th of February had placed it.
</p>
<p>
On the 17th of July, the governor of Texas, Don Luciano Garcia, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed
the Baron de Bastrop, commissioner on the part of the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
to survey the lands for the settlers of the new colony, and in
union with Austin, to issue titles to each one, in the name of the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
conformably to the decree of 18th February, 1823. The said
governor, by an official act dated the 26th July, also gave the name of
“San Felipe de Austin,” to the town, which was to be laid off for the
capital of the new colony.
</p>
<p>
In August Austin arrived in the colony in company with the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner
Baron de Bastrop. The settlement was nearly broken up in
consequence of his long detention in Mexico, and emigration had totally
ceased. Many of the first emigrants had returned, and a number of
those who started from the United States for this settlement, had stop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ped
on the Ayesh Bayou, and round Nacodoches, or on the Trinity; and
by this means the settlement of those sections of country was com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />menced.
Such arrangements were made by the commissioner, Bastrop,
as were necessary, and he then returned to Bexar to fill his station as
a member of the deputation of Texas.
</p>
<p>
In 1824 the commissioner, Bastrop, again returned to the colony, and,
in union with Austin, issued the titles to the settlers, for the lands which

<pb n="14" xml:id="P0014" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/22/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

had been surveyed up to that time; but, as the said Bastrop had been
elected a member of the legislature of the state of Coahuila and Texas,
just established, he could not remain long enough to complete the sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veys
and titles for the whole of said 300 families, all of whom had by
this time emigrated, and were in the country. He therefore departed
for Saltillo, in September, and left a part of the titles unfinished, which,
together with the other unfinished business of the colony, was completed
by the commissioner Gasper Floris, who was specially comissioned -for
that purpose by the lieutenant governor of the state of Coahuila and
Texas, Don Victor Blanco, then exercising the duties of governor.
</p>

<p>By referring to the 23d article of the law of 4th January, 1823, it
will be seen that the lands granted under that law, in virtue of the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cession
of the 18th February of the same year, are subject to the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dition
of being cultivated by the grantee, within two years from the
date of the title, and the same condition is also inserted in each of the
titles; which condition being complied with, the title is unconditional,
clear, absolute and inviolable, as will be seen by examining said law, and
particularly the 22d article.</p>

<p>As regards the limits of the old colony, it will be seen by reference
to the concession of the emperor, of 18th February, 1823, that specific
limits were not considered necessary, because the colony would be com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed
of the lands occupied by .said 300 families. The rambling dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />position
of the emigrants dispersed them from the east bank of Labaca
to the east side of San Jacinto, and from the sea shore to the upper, or
San Antonio road, and land was granted to them in those limits. All
the vacant lands that remained -after supplying the settlers and the
empresario with their portions, was, of course, the public land of the
nation. This dispersed settlement of the emigrants, rendered the task
of locating, protecting and governing them, much more difficult and
expensive than it otherwise would have been; and it was only tolerated
on the ground, that if the settlers could sustain themselves from Indian
attacks, (and they thought they could,) a scattered settlement, within
reasonable bounds, would ultimately be of more advantage to the nation
than if the emigrants had all been huddled together; for it disseminated
facilities for an establishment of new emigrants, hereafter, over an ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tensive
tract of country. The good policy of this scattering system is 1
now daily proved: corn, pork, &amp;c., can now be had in every direction,
without the trouble of distant transportation. It is, however, also at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tended
with inconveniences which hardy enterprise alone would sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit
to.</p>

<p>The foregoing narrative, with an examination of the documents re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred
to, will, it is believed, be sufficient to explain to the settlers of the
first colony how, and under what authority, they originally came into
this country; the delays growing out of the revolutionary state of politi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cal
affairs, and other circumstances, that were beyond the control of
Austin, which embarrassed the progress of ■ the settlement in its first
stages; the exertions made by him to remove these embarrassments, and
procure titles for the settlers; and finally, the nature and validity of these
titles.</p>

<p>As regards the local government of the colony, it will be sufficient
to state, that Austin finding on his return from Mexico, that it would
be impossible for him to attend to the land business of the settlers,

<pb n="15" xml:id="P0015" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/23/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

and the civil affairs of the local government, and also to attend in per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son,
to the administration of justice, through all its perplexing details,
in every small case that might occur; continued the two alcalde’s dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricts,
into which the settlement had been previously divided, by order
of the governor of Texas, Jose Feliu Trespalacios, and likewise formed
some additional ones, directing that an alcalde or justice should be
elected by the people in each; he gave these alcades jurisdiction to 200
dollars, with an appeal to him, as the judge of the colony, on all sums
over 25 dollars. He also formed a code of provisional regulations, in
civil and criminal matters, which was approved by the governor of
Texas.</p>

<p>In the month of September, 1824, Mr. Samuel M. Williams was ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ponted
by Austin, secretary of the local government of the colony, which
appointment was approved by the governor of Texas, and since that
time, he has discharged the duties of that office with a degree of fidelity
and industry, which justly entitles him to the approbation and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fidence
of the inhabitants of this settlement. Austin not having the
means of paying him a compensation equal to his services, he has labored
without an adequate salary; and the perquisites which he has received
in five years would not have supported him one. The land and other
records of this colony, present abundant evidence of his neatness and
accuracy; and the register, or record book, in which the land documents,
and title deeds, are recorded, will forever afford proof of the labor, care
and precaution, that have been devoted for the perpetuation of those
important documents. It will be remembered that this labor, the forma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of the register, was gratuitous on the part of Austin, and the secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary
Williams. Neither of them have ever received one cent of compen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation
for it. The former considered it necessary for the future security
of the settlers, that the records should be placed in such a shape, as
would render them less liable to be lost or defaced, than they would be,
in their original state; for, agreeably to the mode of issuing the titles,
each one was on a separate and loose sheet of stamp paper, the original
being retained in the office as the record, and a certified copy issued to
the interested person. It is evident, that records kept in that way would
be liable in time, to wear out, and be totally - destroyed, even if they
were not misplaced, and lest any difficulties should arise from this, Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin
petitioned the government of the state, that an order might be issued
from the competent authority, for the transfer of all the records of the
colony, that were on loose sheets of paper, into a large bound register
or record book. The said order was accordingly issued, prescribing, par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticularly,
the mode of making such transfer, and declaring that docu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments
thus transferred, should have the same validity in law, as the
originals. The mode of transfer was, that each document should be
copied into said register, and then compared, word for word, with the
original, by the commissioner Gasper Floris, the empresario Austin, and
the alcade of the jurisdiction; all of whom should certify that each docu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
was truly copied from the original, and then sign their names,
with two witnesses. This was an immense labor; for, independent of the
documents and title deeds, it also included the plot of each tract, at
the end of the title. Austin paid the surveyor, Seth Ingram at the rate
of five dollars per day, for this part of the work.</p>

<p>It will be seen by an examination of the authority that was vested

<pb n="16" xml:id="P0016" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/24/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

in Austin relative to the local government of the colony, that it was
extensive, and without clearly defined limits, except submission to the
governor of Texas, and the commandant general; and that consequently
the degree of moral, as well as personal responsibility, which rested upon
him indivdually, was co-extensively great. Had he been furnished with
laws and fixed rules for a guide, his responsibility would have depended
on his observance of, or departure from those laws or fixed rules; but
placed as he was, a peculiar or prejudiced view of his acts, by his su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />periors,
might have involved him in total ruin or unmerited disgrace. It
will also be seen that no salary or alowance whatever was assigned him,
to defray the expenses of the local government, all of which consequently
had to be borne by himself, and which in this jurisdiction were many,
owing to its peculiar situation with respect to the Indians, and also for
the want of regular soldiers, for expresses, guards, &amp;c., as well as many
other expenses, besides those of the office, and the secretary’s salary. It
will also be remembered that Austin contracted with the government
to introduce a certain number of families, for which he was to receive
as a premium, a certain quantity of land; but he was not bound in any
manner by that contract, to take upon himself the labor, responsibility
and expense of the local government; and had he refused to have done
it, and some other person had been appointed for that purpose, it would
not in any way have interfered with his right to premium land. So that
it was, in fact, altogether gratuitous on his part, so far as depended
on his contract with the government, to undertake that labor, or not,
as he pleased. Why then did he accept of so heavy and expensive
a charge? — He accepted it because it was necessary for the advance<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
of the colony that some one should do so; and no
one would have accepted it without a compensation; he considered that he was
bound by the original contracts, which he thought were fairly and publicly
made, between him and the settlers, previous to the commencement
of the colony, as heretofore stated, to be at all the labor and expense of
procuring the titles, and advancing the .settlement, so far as it lay in his
power, by his individual exertions; calculating that the settlers would
never wish to evade the payment stipulated on their parts, when they
saw that he had complied, and more than complied on his; for he prom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ised
them lands by hundreds of acres, and they have received it by thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sands,'
league tracts were granted to them by the government, in place
of the sections promised by Austin. His expectations, however, were
all disappointed; the original contracts passed away, and the colony was
dragged forward, amidst pecuniary embarrassments and poverty, with
the fatal weight of internal opposition superadded to its other diffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />culties.
</p>
<p>
Some misunderstanding has heretofore existed in regard to the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments
on land in this colony. For instance, it has been stated by those
who knew nothing of the law, or of the subject, that Austin sold the
land to the settlers; that he exacted from them what he had no right
by law to exact; that he was speculating on the settlers, &amp;c., &amp;c. Never
has he asked one settler to pay him one cent in virtue of the colonisation,
or any other law, except the law of mutual good faith, between man
and man, in their private and individual dealings. He entered into a
fair and equitable contract with them, in a public and open manner,
in 1821, binding himself to do certain things for their benefit; to wit—

<pb n="17" xml:id="P0017" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/25/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

to receive them in the number of the three hundred families, which he
was authorised to introduce, and settle in Texas; a privilege which, at
that time, was not, and never before had been granted, to any foreign<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers,
except individual cases, under peculiar circumstances, and obtained
by the most powerful patronage; and one which was not, and could not
be legally granted to any others, except to said three hundred families,
until after the passing of the national colonisation law of 18th August,
1824, and the state law of 25th March, 1825; up to that time, there was
no colonisation law, and no authority whatever in any other person to
admit emigrants; for the same act of congress of the 11th April, 1823,
which confirmed this privilege to Austin, closed the door as to all others,
by suspending the law of 4th January, 1823. True it is, that emigrants
did come in previous to the passing of the law of 18th August, 1824,
or that of the state law of 1825, who stopped on the Ayesh Bayou, round
Nacogdoches, and on Trinity; but they have not yet obtained titles, and
were liable to be driven off by the government. Those who will take the
trouble to enquire, may see that Austin, at an early day, informed the
government, that many of those settlers came into the country in con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sequence
of his publications in the United States, relative to the three
hundred families, and had stopped where they were, owing to his long
detention in Mexico, and the consequent discouraging reports about his
settlement; and that, therefore, they were innocent of any intention to
intrude, illegally into the country. He agreed to procure for said three
hundred families, titles for a certain quantity of land, and deliver them
to settlers at his own cost, he being at all the expense and labor of pe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titioning,
translating, surveying, managing their affairs with govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
and all other expenses of a necessary and public nature, for the ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vancement
of the colony; for all which, they, on their parts, stipulated in
the manner before stated, to pay him twelve and a half cents per acre,
to be paid in instalments, in produce of the country, after receipt of
title. His great object and ambition were, and always have been, to suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed
with the enterprise, which he believed he could not do, without the
aid of funds. He also believed that the above contracts opened the only
safe means of raising them; and they also presented to him a distant
prospect of refunding to him the money he had spent in the outset, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore
he could call on the settlers for any payments; for he had no right
to make such call until after the titles were delivered; and consequently,
all the risk of money, labor, and character, was run by him alone, until
he completed the business. Because, had he failed in the enterprise, he
would have lost all—the character of a visionary or wild speculator
would have been given to him by many, and some would have considered
that a failure was a crime, or evidence of a want of industry or capacity;
which to a certain degree, must have injured his prospects in any other
business; and to this heavy account, was to be superadded, the time,
expenses, and sufferings of his father. Under the faith of those con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tracts,
therefore, he abandoned all prospects in the United States, some
of which were flattering; undertook the enterprise, and devoted himself
to a life of toil and privations in a wilderness. He also made engage<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments
in 1821, which, added to other pecuniary embarrasments, growing
out of this colonisation business, has kept him too poor even to afford
the means of living with that decency which would be expected from
the head of such an enterprise as this; and which, in fact, the respect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ability

<pb n="18" xml:id="P0018" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/26/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

of the settlement itself, would seem to require; and if what land
he has acquired, (and he has but little else,) was valued at its present
rates, he is now nearly insolvent. Other men, who have never had any
other trouble than to attend to their private affairs, and to receive their
titles, have derived more benefit from his labors than he has. As re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gards
his selling land to settlers: the idea of an empresario, under the
colonisation law, selling the land of this nation, is so absurd, that it
would be an insult to the understanding of those who can read that
law, even to refute it. There never have been any payments made to
him under the original contracts, although many offered it; but those
contracts were interfered with in a manner which rendered it doubtful
whether they could have been generally enforced, without jeopardising
the principal motive which had stimulated him to persevere in the enter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prise,
which was to settle the country, and not merely to make a specu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lation.
Had the latter been his object, he certainly would have made a
totally different use of the extensive powers that were placed in his
hands, than spending his life in a wilderness, harassed by constant cares
and perplexities. He, therefore, would not accept of a compliance of the
original contracts, from any one, unless it was also exacted from all; thus,
those contracts passed away forever; and the payments on the land titles
were regulated by the political chief or governor of Texas, by a fee bill
which he published the 20th of May, 1824: those payments were for the
commissioner’s fees, office fees, stamp paper, surveying fees, &amp;c. A con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />siderable number of the settlers have never to this day paid those fees,
that part of them who are too poor have never been called on. The por<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of their fees that had to be promptly paid before they could have
gotten a title, has been raised for them by Austin, out of other means.
He has himself been their translator, their agent, and done all their
business for them, even in some cases, to the selecting and locating their
lands, and has delivered their deeds to them; for all which, he has re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived
from some of them, murmurings and abuse. It can, however, be
truly said, to the honor of the North American character, that the mur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />muring
part of the settlers is limited to a very small number, and it is
to be hoped that what has appeared to be ingratitude, even in them, has
arisen solely, from not understanding the subject, rather than from dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />position.
</p>
<p>
It is just to correct another erroneous idea, that at one time prevailed,
which was, that the fees were paid in money. Money was required from
those who it was known had it to spare, which was used to make up
the cash payments to the government for the stamp paper, commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner’s
fees, &amp;c.; and thus money was raised for the cash payments which
had to be made on the deeds of all those who could not raise it them<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />selves;
and by that means, and that alone, the poor were provided for
as well as the rich; no one was turned away, or even waited for his title,
because he was poor; and many have received leagues of land in this
colony, who were not worth twenty dollars when they reached here.
This system, however, caused murmurs against Austin, on the ground
that a distinction was made, and partiality shown. They did not reflect
that is was the interest of all to get the settlement under way, and that
if poor men had been turned off, because they could not pay the fees,
the settlement would have been thinned so much, that it would have
been totally broken up. A clamor was raised, and, strange as it may

<pb n="19" xml:id="P0019" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/27/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

now appear, some of the poorer class, who were most benefitted by that
system, joined in it. The mass of the settlers who have paid any thing,
paid it in cows, at twenty to twenty-five dollars a head, corn at two or
three dollars a bushel,	which property, thus received, has been sold
for two-thirds less than it was received at to raise cash, it being necessary
to resort to all manner of shifts, to raise the means of keeping up the
local government, and managing along the settlers, so as to prevent them
from running headlong into anarchy and confusion. It will be remem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bered
that Austin was not supported by the strong arm of government;
there never was one soldier stationed in the colony; and for the first
four years there were not fifty in all Texas, nor within five hundred miles
of it; that he had not the aid of general laws, printed and published in
the language of the settlers, by which to restrain them, or guide him<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />self;
and that he was not even left to the uncontrolled dictates of his
own judgment; for, in that particular, he was absolutely subject to the
commandant general, and governor of Texas, or to the land commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner,
who was united with him, all of whom, except the last, had seen
but little of North Americans, except under unfavorable circumstances,
and knew but little of their real character or habits: he had, therefore,
to resort to such resources as circumstances would permit. In the ab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sence
of specific laws, there are two modes of governing—one by force,
the other by reason and mild measures. The latter course, perhaps, was
most congenial with his disposition, even if the other had been in his
power; he adopted it, and has been censured by some for following it
to the extent he did. His task was rather difficult; he was isolated, desti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tute
of funds, and inexperienced; no disinterested advisers could ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proach
him, for it was the interest of each one to get all he could for
himself; and he may have committed many errors; he has, however, the
consolation of having succeeded in the enterprise, a thing which no
other, who has attempted it, has done; he has uniformly received the
approbation of government; and within the last two years has also re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived
manifestations of confidence from the settlers, themselves, in
general; which to him is the most gratifying testimonial that could pos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sibly
be offered; for they ought to be the best judges of his acts, having
witnessed them all, and been immediately interested.
</p>
<p>
The foregoing remarks relative to the payments on land, and to the
local government of the colony, are made, in order to correct some er<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />roneous
impressions that at one time prevailed on the subject. It is no
more than justice that the matter should be placed in its true light; and
it is equally just, that the conduct and motives of the settlers should be
noticed, lest, from what has been said, some should be inclined to cen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sure
them; for any such censure would be unmerited. It will be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />membered
that these settlers had always been accustomed, from their
infancy, to see all the laws and orders of government printed and pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished:
that none of them understood the Spanish language; and that
there were no translators but Austin and the secretary; and conse<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quently
that every thing had to pass through, and from them; that there
was no way of publishing any thing except by manuscript copies. Also,
it was natural, as regards the twelve and a half cents per acre, for the
settlers to make a gross calculation of the amount, that all the land dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tributed
in the colony would come to, and suppose that all that sum
was to .go into the pockets of Austin, for they made no allowance for

<pb n="20" xml:id="P0020" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/28/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

many of the settlers who would be unable to pay any thing at least for
many years; neither did they make allowance for the incalculable loss
on payments in produce, and property, at double, and treble, its cash
value; neither were they competent to make any calculation at all, as
to the amount which he had spent, and was still compelled to spend,
to complete the titles, and keep the local government in progress and
safety; for on these subjects they had no data, nor any opportunity of
procuring them. It will also be remembered that an opinion prevailed,
that Austin’s authority was almost absolute; and that most of the set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tlers
were strangers to him, and to each other, and uninformed as to
the nature of the government as it then existed. They understood, in
general terms, that is was a republic, but they did not reflect that is was
an infant republic, just springing into existence, and that there had not
been time to form the constitution, and complete the organisation and
details of all the various departments. Added to all this, innumerable
embarrassments arose in the selecting, surveying, and distributing lands,
owing to the rambling and unsettled disposition of some of the emi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grants,
and to the want of more specific and fixed rules on the subject,
in the colonisation law, and also to the envy and jealousies which grew
out of the extensive powers that were granted to Austin and the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner,
by the 9th article of the colonisation law, and by that part
of the decree of 18th February, 1823, which speaks of an increase of
quantity. When all these things are duly considered, and also that duty
to themselves and families, required the settlers to be cautious about in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curring
pecuniary responsibilities; abundant reasons may be discovered
why they should think that causes for jealousy and complaints against
Austin existed; they doubtless thought they were right, and acted ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cordingly.
</p>
<p>
A candid and impartial review of the whole matter, therefore, leads
to the conclusion, that the settlers have done their duty, and have been
much clearer from internal dissensions, than could be expected, under
all the circumstances. They have uniformly' been unshaken in their
fidelity, and ready and willing to discharge their obligations as Mexican
citizens; they have borne, with the most inflexible fortitude, all the pri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vations
to which their situation exposed them, and have contributed
largely in laying a foundation for the future prosperity of Texas, by
commencing the settlement of its wilderness. The idea, which appears
to be entertained, by some persons in the United States, that the early
population of Texas is composed of fugitives from other countries, is
totally incorrect and unjust. It was natural to suppose that some fugi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
might enter the country, and measures were taken at an early day,
both by the government and by Austin, so far as his authority extended,
to shield Texas from that evil. He expelled several from this colony in
1823-24, under the severest threats of corporal punishment if they re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turned,
and in one instance, he inflicted it. This is mentioned for the
sole purpose of proving, that there could not have been many of that
class here, for Austin had no force but the militia, which was composed
of the settlers themselves. As regards the general morality and hospi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tality
of the inhabitants, and the commission of crime, this settlement
will bear a favorable comparison with any county in the United States,
however celebrated for its exemption from such crimes.</p>

<p>If, having escaped many perils, is to be considered as a presage, that

<pb n="21" xml:id="P0021" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/29/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

fortune has taken this new settlement under her protection, there is
abundant reason for hoping that it will prosper in future. It was under<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taken,
and has been established by individual enterprise alone, without
the aid of strong capitalists, and totally unsupported by troops, or suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cors
of any kind, from government. In this respect, it presents an
anomaly, in the history of similar establishments. Independent of the
perils from hostile Indians, scarcity of provisions, internal dissensions,
and many others, incident to an infant and wilderness settlement; it has
seen four great political changes in the government of this nation, and
it has worked its way in peace and safety through them all. Those
changes were from the despotic government of Spain to the- independent
government under the regency,in 1821-22,from that to the imperial gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment
in 1822-23, from that to the republic under the supreme execu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive
power, in 1823-24, and from that to the federal system, which now
exists.</p>

<p>The foregoing observations have been exclusively confined to the first,
or “old colony," as it is frequently called. The colonisation laws which
are generally in force at this time, will now be noticed, and also the
contracts entered into, with the government, by Austin, under those
laws, in order that the emigrants who have been settled, or who may
wish to settle under said contracts, may fully understand the subject,
and the nature of their titles.</p>

<p>In order to give a clear idea of the authority which enacted those
laws, the decrees of congress establishing the federal system, will be
first referred to.</p>

<p>On the 17th June, 1823, congress decreed that a new constituent
congress should be elected by the people, for the express purpose of
adopting the form of government, forming the constitution, and or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganising
the nation, agreeably to the will of the people; which would
be fairly expressed by said new congress, thus elected for that purpose.
The members of the first congress were ineligible to be elected for the
second.</p>

<p>On the 19th of the same month, congress passed a resolution directing
the supreme executive power, to inform the people that the then existing
congress were in favor of the federal republican system of government,
but had not formally adopted that system, and proceeded to form the
constitution, because it had decreed on the 17th, that a new congress
should be elected for that purpose.</p>

<p>The first congress finally closed its sessions on the 30th of October;
and the second constituent congress, whose members had been elected
in virtue of the decree of 17th June, convened and opened its sessions
on the 5th of November. On the 31st of January, 1824, congress de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />creed
the “Acta Constituvia de la Federacion Mexicana” or act of con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federation,
by which the federal system was formally adopted, and the
basis and outlines of the government established. The federal con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution,
however, was not finally sanctioned and promulgated until the
4th of October.</p>

<p>On the 7th of May, congress decreed that the former provinces of
Coahuila and Texas should form a state and proceed immediately to
elect its legislature; but that so soon as the latter should be in a situation
to form a separate state of itself, the national congress should be- in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formed
thereof for its resolution.</p>

<pb n="22" xml:id="P0022" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/30/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

<p>It will be remembered that the colonisation law, passed by the im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perial
government on the 4th of January, 1823, was suspended on the
11th of April of that year, except in Austin’s case. On the 18th of
August, 1824, congress passed the general colonisation law, which is
now in force, giving to the states full authority to form colonisation
laws, and to dispose of the vacant lands within their respective limits
agreeably to the basis and conditions therein established. In virtue of
this law, the legislature of the state of Coahuila and Texas passed the
state colonisation law, which was approved by the governor, and promul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gated
the 24th of March, 1825, and is now in force.</p>

<p>In 1824, there was no mail established from Bexar to Nacogdoches,
passing through this place, as at this time, and the law of the 18th of
August was not received here until December: previous to that time,
and on the 6th of November, Austin forwarded a petition addressed
to the supreme executive power of the nation, asking for authority to
colonise two or three hundred families more, in addition to his first
colony, and praying that Galveston might be made a port of entry.
This representation was transmitted to the governor of the state. After<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wards
having seen the law of the 18th of August, and understanding that
a state law was discussing in the legislature of the state, he forwarded
a petition addressed to the governor of the state, on the 4th of February,
1825, repeating in substance what he had said in that of the 6th of
November, relative to Galeveston, and asking for permission to colonise
three hundred families. Having afterwards received information that
the state colonisation law was about to be sanctioned, and having heard
nothing of his two former petitions, on the '4th of April, 1825, he for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />warded
a third petition to the governor of the state asking for authority
to colonise five hundred families. Before the last petition reached him
the governor had granted his former one for the additional three hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
families, and had transmitted to Austin the contract which he was
required to sign, and which was to take effect from the day he (Austin)
approved and signed it, which he did on the 4th of June, 1825. After
despatching from Saltillo said contract for three hundred families, the
governor received Austin’s petition of 4th April, asking for authority
to colonise five hundred families, which was granted by him on the 20th
May, 1825, and made a part of the before-mentioned contract, which
was thus extended to five hundred, instead of three hundred families.
The said five hundred families were to be settled on the vacant land
remaining within the limits of his first colony, which had not been as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signed
to any other empresario, and which was not within the ten league
reserve on the coast. As the limits of the first colony were not fixed by
specific boundaries, as before stated, Austin petitioned the. governor
on the subject, who, on the 7th of March, 1827, added another article
to the contract, for said five hundred families, by which the limits,
within which they were to be settled, were fixed. The term of six years
from the 4th June, 1825, the day on which Austin signed it, is fixed
for the completion of this contract for five hundred families. On the
1st of April, 1826, the government commissioned Gasper Flores, commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner
for issuing titles in said colony, for five hundred families.</p>

<p>On the 20th November, 1827, Austin entered into another contract
with the government of the state, for one hundred families to be settled

<pb n="23" xml:id="P0023" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/31/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

on the east side of the Colorado, above the San Antonio road. The
contract expires six years from its date.</p>

<p>On the 5th June, 1826, Austin petitioned the president for permission
to colonise the vacant land lying within the ten league reserve, on the
coast from Labaca to San Jacinto, and on the 22d of April, 1828, the
president granted said petition, in virtue of which, a contract was en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tered
into by Austin with the state government to settle three hundred
families within said ten league reserve, which contract expires six years
from the 29th July, 1828, that being the day on which he'signed said
contract. Austin is also appointed the government commissioner, for
surveying the land, and issuing titles to said three hundred families,
within said ten league reserve colony.</p>

<p>It is not considered necessary to make any remarks on the national
law of 18th August, 1824, on the state law of 25th March, 1825, nor
on the contracts or the instructions to Austin, as commissioner of the
reserve lands on the coast, for translations of them all are herein pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished;—here this introduction will therefore close.</p>

<head>ADVERTISEMENT.</head>

<p>In the foregoing introduction, I have endeavored to present to my
companions and fellow laborers in the first settlement of this wilder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness,
a faithful history of their land titles, which was considered neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary
for the better understanding of the laws, decrees, &amp;c., herein pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished.
This matter was so closely connected with the agency which
my deceased father and myself have had in procuring the titles, that
one could not be fully explained without giving a detailed account of
the other: which, it is hoped, will be a sufficient apology for having
noticed so minutely all his and my own acts in the business. I also con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sidered
that it was no more that justice to the settlers and to myself to
place the whole matter in its true light, in order to remove any erron<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eous
impressions which may have existed.</p>

<p>This colony has received the most cordial and uninterrupted mani<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />festations
of liberality, confidence, and kindness from every superior
officer, who has governed the province of Texas, or the state of Coahuila
and Texas, from its first commencement to the present time; and for
its services on one occasion, it received in flattering terms the appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bation
of the president. These testimonials are too high and unim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peachable,
. to leave any doubt as to the morality, honor and integrity
of the great mass of the settlers. But to say that there are no bad men
here would be a violation of candor and truth. There are some individ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uals
who are exceptions to the highly honorable general character which
these inhabitants justly deserve, and who are meeting their reward in
the frowns of public opinion.</p>

<p>As stated in the introduction, the object was not to give a minute
history of the colony, except so far as was necessary to a clear eluci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dation
of the authority under which it was undertaken, and has pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gressed.
To have entered into the particulars of all the privations, In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dian
expeditions, &amp;c., would have swelled the introduction to a size, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />yond
what the present means of printing it would permit; and besides,

<pb n="24" xml:id="P0024" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/32/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

such a detail would have added nothing material to an understanding
of the nature and validity of the titles, except so far as it tended to
prove that the settlers have fully earned, and justly deserved all the
land, and privileges they have obtained. This, however, is a fact too
evident to require any other proofs for its establishment, than those
which are self-evident, and publicly known.</p>

<p>The translations have been carefully made by Mr. S. M. Williams,
and myself. It is believed, that should there be any inaccuracies in
them, they will be found on examination, to be more of a verbal and
unimportant, than of a substantial nature: the originals, however, will
always be open in the office, to the inspection of those who wish to
examine them.</p>

<p>I should consider that I had not fully complied with my duty,
were I to refrain from calling the attention of the settlers to a subject,
perhaps of as much importance to them, as the acquisition of their titles
has been; which is, the preservation and safe keeping of the records.
Since February, 1828, all the records of the colony, except those apper<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining
to land titles, have been under the charge of the ayuntamiento
and alcalde. The land records have remained in my charge, and will
probably so continue a short time longer, when they will pass to the
ayuntamiento and alcalde. It should be remembered, that those records
are all in Spanish, and that all official communications with the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
must be in that language, and that neither the alcalde, nor one
of the members of the ayuntamiento, understands Spanish, neither is
it probable that any one will be elected for many years, who does under<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stand
it. The records of that body are now kept in a very loose and
careless manner in a log cabin, exposed to all manner of casualties. The
law requires the ayuntamiento, to provide a safe building to keep the
records in, and a suitable secretary, thoroughly acquainted with the
Spanish and English languages, to take charge of them on his own
responsibility, as well as on that of the alcalde and ayuntamiento. The
law also fully authorises that body to raise funds by a municipal tax
for the above purposes, and to defray the necessary expenses of the local
government, and it is their duty so to do; a duty which the people owe
to themselves, to their own security, and to the protection of their best
interests, which are involved in the safe keeping of the records, and sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porting
the local government of the municipality; to pay said tax, so
far as is necessary and reasonable, with promptness and cheerfulness.</p>

<p>It is well known that up to February, 1828, the labor and expense
of the local government fell principally on me, individually, and that
since that period all the Spanish part of the labor has fallen on Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liams
and myself, without any compensation. It is also well known,
that the translating and other duties connected with the local govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
are sufficient to occupy all the time and attention of a secretary.
Since February, 1828, I have held no office which imposes any other
duty on me to aid or interfere in the local civil government, than what
belongs to any other citizen. As a citizen, I advised the ayuntamiento
of 1828, to resort to a municipal tax; that body thought it would be
unpopular, and feared to move. I repeated the advice to the ayun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tamiento
of 1829, and strongly urged the vast importance of giving
respectability, system, and permanency to the local government, by the
creation of municipal funds, and the erection of public buildings: as

<pb n="25" xml:id="P0025" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/33/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

the friend of the settlers, I again repeat the same advice. The muni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cipality
is without a jail, a house for public use, or a place to keep the
records in; and it is also without a secretary, when it is well known
that all its official business must be transacted in Spanish, and that not
one of the municipal officers understood one word of that language.
For two years past, the business of the ayuntamiento has been done
for it, and not by it, and an excessive burden has thus been thrown upon
the liberality of others. I have before stated, that all the land records
would shortly pass from my hands to the alcalde and ayuntamiento;
perhaps I ought to be more explicit, and to state distinctly that it is,
and for some time past has been, my wish and intention to withdraw,
as soon as the welfare of the colony will permit, from every kind of pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic
charge, either direct or indirect. This course is rendered necessary
by the state of my health, which is perceptibly declining; and also, by
the embarrassed situation of my private affairs, which will require more
of my time and attention, than I have heretofore been able to devote to
them. These considerations may perhaps have caused too much anxiety
to see our local government placed on a more respectable and systematic
basis than it is at present; I may have wished to accelerate matters more
than the resources of the country will admit, and been too far influenced
by an excess of zeal, for what I considered to be the general welfare. My
motives, however, were good, and had no other object in view than
general utility; and I must be permitted to say that this colony is abun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dantly
able to support its local government with decency and energy;
I must also observe that the proposed tax is fully as heavy on me, in
proportion to my disposable means, as on any other person. For eight
years I have endeavored to be a faithful servant to this colony; it ought
not to be supposed that I am to be its slave for life. Owing to my exer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
when at the seat of government in 1827, the local government of
this municipality was placed exclusively in the hands of the people,
sooner than it otherwise would have been; and all that I now ask, is that
they will provide the necessary means of administering it, for their own
welfare.</p>

<p>With the most sincere wishes for the continued health and prosperity
of these settlers,</p>

<p>I remain their most obedient and faithful servant,
S. F. AUSTIN.
San Felipe de Austin, Nov. 1, 1829.</p>

<head>TRANSLATIONS.</head>

<p>[No. 1.] — <emph rend="italic">Official Communications from Don Antonio Martinez,
Governor of Texas, to Moses Austin.</emph></p>

<p>Under date of 17th January, last past, the commandant general,
and superior political chief of the eastern internal provinces writes to
me as follows:</p>

<p>"Having thought proper to hear the most excellent provincial de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />putations,
on the representation which your lordship, (usia) directed
to me with your official letter, No. 1116, of the 26th December last,

<pb n="26" xml:id="P0026" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/34/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

I have just received its resolution, to which I have conformed; it is
of the following tenor:”</p>

<p>“It will be very expedient to grant the permission solicited by Moses
Austin, that the three hundred families, which he says are desirous to
do so, should remove and settle in the province of Texas, but under the
conditions indicated in his petition on the subject, presented to the
governor of that province, and which your lordship (usia) transmitted
to this department, with your official letter of the 16th instant. There<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore,
if to the first or principal requisite of being catholics, or agreeing
to become so, before entering the Spanish territory, they also add that
of accrediting their good character and habits, as is offered in said peti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
and taking the necessary oath to be obedient in all things to the
government; to take up arms in its defence against all lands of enemies;
and to be faithful to the Idng; and to observe the political constitution of
the Spanish monarchy; the most flattering hopes may be formed, that
the said province will receive an important augmentation, in agriculture,
industry, and arts, by the new emigrants, who will introduce them;
which is all that this deputation have to say, in reply to your lordship's
aforementioned official letter.”</p>

<p>“And I transcribe it to your lordship, for your information and cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />responding
effects, that you may cause the interested person to be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formed
thereof, by means of a person of your confidence, who you will
despatch with an express; and you will at the same time, send in by
said express, some copies of the decree, which I transmitted under date
of yesterday, granting a pardon and amnesty to the Spanish refugees,
who are on the frontier, in order that they may be restored to the bosom
of their country. God preserve your lordship many years. Monterey,
17th January, 1821. Joaquin de Arredondo. To the governor of the
province of Texas.”</p>

<p>
All of which I transcribe to you, for your information and satisfac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
in answer to your petition, for which purpose, and in order to
inform you of the deliberations of the most excellent deputation of
these provinces, I have despatched with this, a person of my confi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence,
who is citizen Don Erasmo Seguin; and after having arranged
for the removal of said families, which you have contracted with me,
it will be important for you to direct, that when said families come on,
information shall be immediately given of the time of their arrival,
and the place where they have stopped in this territory; and that you
then come on in company with my said commissioner, in order that we
may agree as to the place or places, where they may wish to establish
themselves; so that I may go on there, and delineate the town, and appor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
out the lands, agreeably to the families, and species of agriculture
they intend to establish; and also to receive from them the beforemen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned
oath, in order that they may be from that time considered, as
members united to the Spanish nation, and enter upon the enjoyment
of the benefits which it extends, and concedes to its citizens and to
Spaniards.</p>

<p>I also expect from the prudence which your deportment demonstrates,
and for your own prosperity and tranquility, that all the families you
introduce, shall be honest and industrious, in order that idleness and vice
may not pervert the good and meritorious, who are worthy of Spanish
esteem, and of the protection of this government, which will be extended


<pb n="27" xml:id="P0027" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/35/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

to them, in proportion to the moral virtues displayed by each individual.
I also inform you, in order that you may communicate it to those who
intend to emigrate, that the supreme Spanish government has just
opened the port of the bay of San Bernard, for navigation, and for intro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ductions
into this province, which measure, will doubtless be very ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vantageous
to all, and particularly to the new settlers.</p>

<p>God preserve you many years,
<lb />ANTONIO MARTINEZ, Gov.
<lb />Bexar, 8th February, 1821.
<lb />To Mr. Moses AUSTIN, of the new settlement.
</p>

<p>[No. 2.] <emph rend="italic">{Same to the same.)</emph></p>

<p>Having seen your representation to this government, and finding it
to be conformable with its ideas, I have to inform you that, although I
shall render an account of it to the supreme government, for its delib<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eration,
still not doubting it will be approved of, you can immediately
offer to the new settlers the same terms as contained in your proposals,
assuring you that should the superior government make any small varia<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
I will in due time communicate it to you; with which I answer
your aforementioned representation.
God preserve you many years,
ANTONIO MARTINEZ.
</p>

<p>[No. 3.] <emph rend="italic">{Same to the same.)</emph></p>

<p>For the better regulations of the Louisiana families, who are to emi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grate,
and whilst the new settlement is forming, you will cause them all
to understand, that until the government organises, the authority which
has to govern them and administer justice, they must be governed by,
and be subordinate to you; for which purpose, I authorise you as their
representative, and relying on your faithful discharge of the duty. You
will inform me of whatever may occur, in order that such measures may
be adopted as may be necessary.
God preserve you many years,
ANTONIO MARTINEZ.
Bexar, 24th, August, 1821.
</p>

<p>[No. 5.] <emph rend="italic">Colonisation Law of 1823.</emph></p>

<p>
AUGUSTIN, by divine providence, and by the congress of the nation,
first constitutional emperor of Mexico, and grand master of the im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perial
order of Guadalupe; To all who shall see these presents: Know
ye, That the junta nacional instituyente of the Mexican empire, has
decreed, and we sanction the following:</p>

<p>
The Junta Nacional Instituyente of the Mexican empire, being con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vinced
by the urgent recommendations of the government, of the neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity

<pb n="28" xml:id="P0028" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/36/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

and importance of giving to the empire a general law of colonisation,
have thought proper to decree as follows:</p>

<p>ART. 1. The government of the Mexican nation will protect the
liberty, property and civil rights, of all foreigners, who profess the Ro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man
Catholic apostolic religion, the established religion of the empire.</p>

<p>Art. 2. To facilitate their establishment, the executive will distribute
lands to them, under the conditions and terms herein expressed.</p>

<p>Art. 3. The empresarios, by whom is understood those who intro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duced
at least two hundred families, shall previously contract with the
executive, and inform it what branch of industry they propose to follow,
the property or resources they intend to introduce for that purpose, and
any other particulars they may deem necessary, in order that with this
necessary information, the executive may designate the province to
which they must direct themselves, the lands which they can occupy
with right of property, and the other circumstances which may be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sidered
necessary.</p>

<p>Art. 4. Families who emigrate, not included in a contract, shall im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mediately
present themselves to the ayuntamiento of the place where
they wish to settle, in order that this body, in conformity with the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structions
of the executive, may designate the lands corresponding to
them, agreeably to the industry which they may establish.</p>

<p>Art. 5. The measurement of land shall be the following; establishing
the vara, at three geometrical feet: a straight line of five thousand varas
shall be a league; a square, each of whose sides shall be one league, shall
be called a sitio; and this shall be the unity of counting one, two, or
more sitios; five sitios shall compose one hacienda.</p>

<p>Art. 6. In the distribution made by government, of lands to the
colonists, for the formation of villages, towns, cities, and provinces, a
distinction shall be made between grazing lands, destined for the rais<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
of stock, and lands suitable for farming or planting, on account of
the facility of irrigation.</p>

<p>Art. 7. One labor shall be composed of one million square varas,
that is to say, one thousand varas on each side, which measurement
shall be the unity for counting one, two, or more labors. These labors
can be divided into halves and quarters, but not less.</p>

<p>Art. 8. To the colonists, whose occupation is farming, there can<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />not
be given less than one labor, and those whose occupation is stock
raising there can not be given less than one sitio.</p>

<p>Art. 9. The government of itself, or by means of the authorities
authorised for that purpose, can augment said portions of land as may
be deemed proper, agreeably to the conditions and circumstances of the
colonists.</p>

<p>Art. 10. Establishments made under the former government which
are now pending, shall be regulated by this law in all matters that may
occur, but those that are finished shall remain in that state.</p>

<p>Art. 11. As one of the principal objects of laws in free governments,
ought to be to approximate, so far as possible, to an equal distribution
of property, the government, taking into consideration the provisions of
this law, will adopt measures for dividing out the lands, which may have
accumulated in large portions, in the hands of individuals or corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions,
and which are not cultivated, indemnifying the proprietors for
the just price of such lands, to be fixed by appraisers.</p>

<pb n="29" xml:id="P0029" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/37/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

<p>Art. 12. The union of many families at one place, shall be called
a village, town or city, agreeably to the number of its inhabitants, its ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tension, locality, and other circumstances which may characterise it,
in conformity with the law on that subject. The same regulations for
its internal government and police, shall be observed as in the others
of the same class in the empire.</p>

<p>Art. 13. Care shall be taken in the formation of said new town, that,
so far as the situation of the ground will permit, the streets shall be
laid off straight, running north and south, east and west.</p>

<p>Art. 14. Provinces shall be formed, whose superfice shall be six
thousand square leagues.</p>

<p>Art. 15. As soon as a sufficient number of families may be united
to form one or more towns, their local government shall be regulated,
and the constitutional ayuntamientos and other local establishments
formed in conformity with the laws.</p>

<p>Art. 16. The government shall take care, in accord with the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective
ecclesiastical authority, that these new towns are provided with
a sufficient number of spiritual pastors, and in like manner, it will pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose
to congress a plan for their decent support.</p>

<p>Art. 17. In the distribution of lands for settlement among the dif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferent
provinces, the government shall take care that the colonists shall
be located in those which it may consider the most important to settle.
As a general rule, the colonists who arrive first, shall have the pref<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erence
in the selection of land.</p>

<p>Art. 18. Natives of the country shall have a preference in the distri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bution
of land; and particularly the military of the army, of the three
guarantees, in conformity with the decree of the 27th of March, 1821;
and also those who served in the first epoch of the insurrection.</p>

<p>Art. 19. To each empresario who introduces and establishes fami<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lies
in any of the provinces designated for colonisation, there shall be
granted at the rate of three haciendas and two labors, for each two
hundred families so introduced by him, but he will lose the right of
property over said lands, should he not have populated and cultivated
them in twelve years from the date of the concession. The premium
cannot exceed nine haciendas, and six labors, whatever may be the
number of familes he introduces.</p>

<p>Art. 20. At-the end of twenty years the proprietors of the lands,
acquired in virtue of the foregoing article, must alienate two thirds
part of said lands, either by sale, donation, or in any other manner he
pleases. The law authorises him to hold in full property and dominion
one third-part.</p>

<p>Art. 21. The two foregining articles are to be understood as gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erning
the contracts made within six months, as after that time, count<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
from the day of the promulgation of this law, the executive can
diminish the premium as it may deem proper, giving an account thereof
to congress, with such information as may be deemed necessary.</p>

<p>Art. 22. The date of the concession for lands constitutes an invio<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lable
law, for the right of property and legal ownership; should any
one through error, or by subsequent concession, occupy land belonging
to another, he shall have no right to it, further than a preference in case
of sale, at the current price.</p>

<pb n="30" xml:id="P0030" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/38/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

<p>Art. 23. If after two years from the date of the concession, the colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nist
should not have cultivated- his land, the right of property shall be
considered as renounced; in which case, the respective ayuntamiento
can grant it to another.</p>

<p>Art. 24. During the first six years from the date of the concession,
the colonists shall not pay titles, duties on their produce, nor any con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tribution
under whatever name it may be called.</p>

<p>Art. 25. The next six years from the same date, they shall pay half
tithes, and the half of the contributions, whether direct or indirect, that
are paid by the other citizens of the empire. After this time, they shall
in all things relating to taxes and contributions, be placed on the same
footing with the other citizens.</p>

<p>Art. 26. All the instruments of husbandry, machinery, and other
utensils, that are introduced by the colonists for their use, at the time
of their coming to the empire, shall be free, as also the merchandise
introduced by each family, to the amount of two thousand dollars.</p>

<p>Art. 27. All foreigners who come to establish themselves in the em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pire,
shall be considered as naturalised, should they exercise any useful
profession or industry, by which, at the end of three years, they, have a
capital to support themselves with decency, and are married. Those
who with the foregoing qualifications, marry Mexicans, will acquire par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticular
merit, for the obtaining letters of citizenship.</p>

<p>Art. 28. Congress will grant letters of citizenship to those who
solicit them, in conformity with the constitution of the empire.</p>

<p>Art, 29. Every individual shall be free to leave the empire, and can
alienate the lands over which he may have acquired the right of prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty,
agreeably to the tenor of this law, and he can likewise take away
from the country, all his property, by paying the duties established by
law.</p>

<p>Art. 30. After the publication of this law, there can be no sale or
purchase of slaves which may be introduced into the empire. The chil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dren
of slaves born in the empire, shall be free at fourteen years of age.</p>

<p>Art. 31. All foreigners who may have established themselves in any
of the provinces of the empire, under a permission of the former govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
will remain on the lands which they may have occupied, being
governed by the tenor of this law, in the distribution of said lands.</p>

<p>Art. 32. The executive, as it may conceive necessary, will sell er
lease the lands, which, on account of their local situation, may be the
most important, being governed with respect to all others, by the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions
of this law.</p>

<p>This law shall be presented to his Imperial Majesty for his sanction,
publication and fulfilment.—Mexico, 3d January, 1823—3d of the inde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pendence
of the empire.—Juan Francisco, Bishop of Durango, Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent.—Antonio
de Mier, Member and Secretary.—Juan Batista de
Arispe, Member and Secretary.</p>

<p>Therefore, we order all tribunals, judges, chiefs, governors, and all
other authorities, as well civil as military and ecclesiastical, whatever
class or dignity they may be, to comply with this decree, and cause it
to be complied with in all its parts; and you will cause it to be printed,
published and circulated.—Given in Mexico, 4th January. 1823.—
Signed by the Emperor.—To Don Jose Manuel de Herrera, Minister of
Interior and Exterior Relations.</p>

<pb n="31" xml:id="P0031" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/39/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

<p>[No. 8.] <emph rend="italic">(Decree of the Emperor.)</emph></p>

<p>Mexico, February 18, 1823.</p>

<p>Having rendered an account to his majesty of the subject, on which
the council has given the foregoing opinion, he has thought proper to
resolve, in conformity therewith; and consequently declares, in the first
place, that Austin was not officially authorised to stipulate with the emi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grants
what quantity of land they should receive in the new settlement,
and therefore they are subject to the regulations of the government,
.agreeably to the law on that point; and consequently in virtue of said
law, there shall be granted to each head of a family, one labor or one
league, agreeably to the occupation which he may profess; offering to
augment the quantity of land, for all those who may have a numerous
family, or who may merit such augmentation, by the establishment of
a new species of industry, or by the perfection of those already known,
or by other circumstances, which may be useful to the province, or to
the empire, it being understood, that to the colonist, who besides farm<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
also dedicates himself to the raising of stock, there may be granted
a league and a labor, in conformity with the 8th article of said law. As
respects the designation of boundaries for the new establishment, with
the limits described by Austin in his memorial, it is declared to be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />admissible,
for the reasons given by the council.</p>

<p>In the second place, Austin is authorised, in union with the governor
of Texas, or a commissioner appointed by the latter, to proceed to divide
and designate land, and put each of the new colonists in possession of the
quantity above indicated, and issue to them the titles in the name of the
government. A certified copy of which shall be transmitted to the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor,
for the purpose connected with the subject.</p>

<p>In the third place, all the families over and above the said three hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred,
who come to settle in Texas, must establish themselves in the inte<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rior
of the province, adjacent to the ancient settlements, in the manner
prescribed by the colonisation law.</p>

<p>In the fourth place, and conformity with the said colonisation law,
there is granted to Austin, for the expenses which he has been at, a
quantity of land in proportion to his families, agreeably to the provisions
of the 19th article of said law, and under the conditions contained in
said article.</p>

<p>In the fifth place, Austin is authorised to proceed in conformity with
said law, to form a town, with the families who have emigrated, or may
emigrate, to the number of the three hundred of the permission, at the
most suitable place in the section of country which they at present occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />py,
taking care that it shall be as central as possible, to the lands distrib<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uted
to the colonists, who must accredit that they are Roman apostolic
catholics, and of steady habits. It being understood that the governor of
Texas, or his commissioner, in union with Austin, can designate the place,
and measure out the land for the establishment of said town; selling the
building lots, at the price to be regulated by appraisers, the other par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticulars
embraced under this head, which were petitioned for by Austin,
are granted; the governor of Texas is required to give information, of
whatever may be necessary for the regulation of the government of said

<pb n="32" xml:id="P0032" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/40/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

town, and that both it, and any others that are founded, may be furnished
with spiritual pastors.</p>

<p>As regards the citizenship which Austin solicits, he is notified to
apply to the J unta Nacional Instituyente, whose province it is to grant it.</p>

<p>And finally, he is authorised to organise the colonists into a body
of national militia, to preserve tranquillity, rendering an account of all
to the governor of Texas, and acting under his orders, and those of the
captain general of the province; also, until the government of the set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tlement
is organised, he is charged with the administration of justice,
settling all differences which may arise among the inhabitants, and pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />serving
good order and tranquillity; rendering an account to the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment
of any remarkable event that may occur.</p>

<p>ANDRES QUINTANA.</p>

<p>Copy of the fifth article of the memorial of Stephen F. Austin, relative
to colonisation in the province of Texas, which was granted in the
manner stated in the foregoing decree:
That authority be granted to him, to found one or moro towns, at
such points as he may deem most proper, within the limits designated,
and to take for himself, and for his family, sufficient lots for their uses,
and with power to grant lots to useful mechanics, gratis; but that all
others should pay for them, at the price the government may think
proper to establish; the proceeds of which shall be applied to the build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
of a church, and other establishments of public utility.
I certify the above to be a copy from the original.
MIGUEL RIESGO, Official Primero.
Mexico, 18th Feb., 1823.</p>

<p>[No. 11.] <emph rend="italic">Decree of the Sovereign Congress,</emph></p>

<p>
Most excellent Sir:—Having seen the reasons which the empresario,
S. F. Austin, has given in his last representation, praying that the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cession
made to him, by the late government, for the establishment of
three hundred families in Texas, should be confirmed: The sovereign
constituent congress have thought proper to resolve, that the said peti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
should be transmitted to the executive, in order that should it have
no objections, it may grant this petition, and any others of the same
kind;—also, the sovereign congress have determined, that hereafter, the
colonisation law, passed by the Junta Instituyente, shall be suspended
until a new resolution on the subject. And by order of the sovereign
congress, we communicate this to your excellency, accompanied by the
said petition.—God preserve your excellency many years.—Mexico, 11th
April, 1823.	FLORENTINO MARTINEZ,
Member and Secretary.
JOSE MARIA SANCHEZ,
Member and Secretary.
To his excellency, the Minister of Interior and Exterior Relations.</p>

<pb n="33" xml:id="P0033" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/41/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

<p>[No. 12.] <emph rend="italic">Decree of the Supreme Executive Power.</emph></p>

<p>
Mexico, 14th, April, 1823.<lb />

Having seen the new representation of Stephen F. Austin, praying
for a confirmation of the concession granted to him by the late govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
by its decree of 18th February last, relative to colonisation in the
province of Texas; and finding it to be in conformity with the law passed
on the subject, by the Junta national instituyente; the supreme execu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive
power have thought proper to confirm the said concession, and order
that the corresponding title should be given to the interested person, and
that the resolution should be communicated to the commandant general
of the internal provinces, and to the governor of the province of Texas,
for their information and the corresponding effects. ■
JOSE IGNACIO GAECIA ILLUECA,
Minister of Relations.</p>

<p>No. 14. <emph rend="italic">Commission of the Baron de Bashop.</emph></p>

<p>San Fernando de Bexar, 16th July, 1823.<lb />

Inasmuch as the more important attentions of government prevent
my executing, in person, the various duties connected with the colonial
establishment forming by Stephen F. Austin, and using the power grant<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed
to me by the laws, and in obedience to the decree of the commandant
general of these provinces, brigadier Don Felipe de la Garza, dated 16th
June last past, I have thought proper to appoint, and by these presents,
do appoint the second alcalde of this city, the Baron de Bastrop, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner,
giving to him all legal powers, to proceed to the district of the
Colorado and the Brazos, to ■ organise that establishment, in conformity
with the decrees on the subject, and such instructions as I may communi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate:—a
certified copy of which is herewith delivered to him, in order
that in continuation he may proceed to discharge the duties which may
be necessary, transmitting a statement of his proceedings when they are
finished, to this government, for the purposes which may be necessary.
Thus, I, Luciano Garcia, lieutenant colonel of cavalry of New San<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tender,
and governor pro tem., of this province, order and command,
signing the present with assisting witnesses, for the want of a notary
public, as the law requires; to which I give faith.
LUCIANO GARCIA.


Assisting witnesses.—Jose Antonio Saucedo, and Ilario de la Garza.,
</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Official letter from Governor Garcia, to S. F. Austin, on the same
subject.</emph></p>

<p>As the more important attentions of the government, prevent my
going on personally to organise the colonial establishment, forming by
you in this province, I have thought proper to commission, with all
necessary powers, the second alcalde of this city, Baron de Bastrop, who
has been selected on account of his well known and superior qualifica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions,
in order that in conformity with the decrees on the subject, and

<pb n="34" xml:id="P0034" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/42/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

the colonisation law, copies of all of which I have delivered to him, and
also in conformity with such instructions as may in future he communi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated
to him, he shall proceed to organise said establishment:—which I
communicate to you for your information, in order that in accord with
said commissioner, you may appoint a day for your departure from this
place, and inform me thereof, that I may have the escort ready to ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />company
you.—God and liberty.—Bexar, 38th July, 1823.
LUCIANO GARCIA.</p>

<p>[No. 15.] <emph rend="italic">Official Letter from Governor Garcia, to the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner Bastrop, naming the town of San Felipe de Austin.</emph></p>

<p>
Under date of the 22nd inst., I reported to the commandant general
of these provinces as follows:—</p>

<p>“In virtue of your official communication of the 16th ultimo, trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitting
to me the documents relative to the colonial establishment,
forming in this province, by Don Stephen F. Austin, of three hundred
families, the receipt of which I acknowledged, by my letter of the 9th
inst.—I have commissioned the second alcalde of this city, Baron de Bas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trop,
on account of his geographical knowledge, and his understanding
the English language, to proceed to the organisation of said establish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
in conformity with the aforementioned documents on the subject,
and with such instructions as it may hereafter be necessary to give him;
.and also to lay out the town, and survey the lands for lots, farms, and
stock farms. The name which I have given to the town, but subject to
your determination, is San Felipe de Austin, and for its greater for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mality,
should you dem it necessary, I wish the corresponding approval
transmitted to me, in order that the commissioner may proceed to exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cute
what may be necessary.”</p>

<p>Which I transcribe to you for your information, accompanied with a
copy of the colonisation law, in order that, in the discharge of your com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missison,
you will be governed by it, and by the decrees which I have
already communicated to you, as also by such instructions as may be
necessary to give. You will therefore inform me of the day fixed for
your departure, in order that the escort of soldiers, who are to accom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany
you, may be ready.—God and Liberty.
LUCIANO GARCIA.
Bexar, 26th July, 1833.</p>

<p>[No. 16.] <emph rend="italic">Official Letter of the Commissioner Bastrop, to fames
Cummings, -provisional alcalde, on the Colorado.</emph></p>

<p>The governor pro tem. of this province, Lieutenant Colonel Don
Luciano Garcia, under date of the 16th of last month, says to me as
follows:—</p>

<p>“The commandant general of these provinces, Brigadier Don Felipe
de la Garza, under date of the 16th of June, last past, says to me as
follows:</p>

<pb n="35" xml:id="P0035" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/43/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

<p>“I transmit to you the documents relative to the colonial establish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
which Don Stephen F. Austin is permitted to form in that prov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ince,
in order that, on your part, you give due compliance to the decree
of the last government, dated 18th February last past, resanctioned by
the present government on the 14th April, and by me under this date.
You will use all possible efforts to complete the organisation of said
establishment; charging the commissioner who may be appointed by you
to be expeditious in concluding his duties, and that he make frequent
reports of his progress, in order that you may do the same to me, and on
its conclusion you will inform me thereof.”</p>

<p>“And I transcribe it to you for your information, and that in virtue
of the commission which I have conferred upon you, by- my decree of
this date, you will proceed in company with said Austin to organise the
colonial establishment which the government has granted to him in this
province, for three hundred Louisiana families. You will be governed
in all things by the decrees and orders contained in the certified copy of
them, which I have delivered to you, and by such other instructions as
it may be necessary to communicate to you until said establishment is
organised, and ayuntamientos are established at the places where they
may be necessary. The said Don Stephen F. Austin is authorised by the
government to administer justice in that district, and to form a regiment
of national militia, over which, for the present, he must be the chief,
with the rank of lieutenant colonel; all of which you will make known
to the inhabitants of said district, in order that they may recognise the
said Austin, invested with said powers, and obey whatever he may order
relative to the public service of the country, the preservation of good
order, and the defence of the nation to which they belong.”</p>

<p>And I transcribe it to you for your information, and strict compliance
on your part; notifying you, that on Saturday, the 9th instant, you will
collect as many of the inhabitants of the district under your charge as
you can, at the house of Sylvenus Castleman, that I may communicate
to them the superior orders with which I am charged, and that said Don
Stephen F. Austin may be recognised by the civil and military authori<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties
dependent on him, and by the new colonists who are under his
charge.—God- preserve vou manv vears.—At Castleman’s, August 5th,
1823.	EL BARON DE BASTROP.</p>

<p>[No. 17.] <emph rend="italic">Official Letter from Jose Antonio Saucedo, political chief
of Texas, to Austin.</emph></p>

<p>
Under this date I have transmitted to the alcaldes of the Colorado
and Brazos, the following order:—</p>

<p>“The Baron de Bastrop, the commissioner of this government, pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds
to that district, to put the inhabitants established in it in posses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion
of their lands agreeably to law, and to issue to them the correspond<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
titles for their security, so soon as they pay the fees established by
the fee bill, which I circulated when I was at that point; which I com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />municate
to you for your information, and in order that there may be
no delay in the organisation of that establishment, you will notify all
the inhabitants who wish to settle in it that they must positively as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />semble

<pb n="36" xml:id="P0036" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/44/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

on the day, and at the place fixed by said commissioner, to put
them in possession of their lands, and issue the titles therefor. And you
will make the corresponding report of the receipt and execution of this
order.”</p>

<p>Which I communicate to you for your information and necessary pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses.—God
and Liberty.—San Fernando de Bexar, 23d June, 1824.
JOSE ANTONIO SAUCEDO.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Same to the Same.</emph></p>

<p>The great scarcity of public funds under which this province is suffer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing,
and the urgent necessities at this time felt by its representative
bodies, has compelled the Baron de Bastrop, sixth member of the most
excellent deputation, to undertake the fatiguing journey to that place,
to collect as much as possible of fees belonging to the nation, agreeably
to the fee bill, which I left with you, on the lands granted to those in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitants,
and also for the purpose of issuing titles to them, as the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner
of this government, in union with yourself. You will in both
cases use every possible exertion to carry these measures into due effect,
for thus the good of the country requires.—God and Liberty.—San Fer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nando
de Bexar, 22d June, 1824. JOSE ANTONIO SAUCEDO.</p>


<p><emph rend="italic">Same to the Same, relative to Stamp Paper.</emph></p>

<p>I send you a copy of the law relative to stamp paper, in order that in
conformity therewith, those inhabitants may make out their petitions
for lands, on the corresponding stamp, and that the titles may be issued
to them on the stamp prescribed by law. And as there is not a sufficiency
of stamps in the depot of this city, I authorise you to stamp as much
common paper as may be necessary for those inhabitants, doing it by
means of a line at the top of each sheet, with these expressions: “Sello
30. 4rrs. Habilitado par la Nacion Mexicana para el ano de 1824, Austin.
Signing it with your surname only. After which the'interested person
shall take the same paper to the alcalde of the district, who, as the provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sional
collector of the revenue, shall collect its value, and put on the mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gin
of each sheet the following expressions: “Pago el interesado en este
jusgado de mi cargo les cuatro riales importe del Sello anterior.” Date and
signature of the alcalde. The same will be observed with regard to
stamps of other classes. To avoid mistakes, you must keep a circum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stantial
account of the paper stamped by you, and the alcalde will in
like manner, keep an account of the amount collected by him, and each
one will make a return thereof, to the government, at the end of the
year, without, however, delaying to remit the proceeds, as soon as pos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sible,
by any safe opportunity that may present.—God and Liberty.—San
Fernando de Bexar, 22d June, 1824.
JOSE ANTONIO SAUCEDO.</p>

<pb n="37" xml:id="P0037" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/45/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

<p>[No. 18.] <emph rend="italic">Appointment of Gasper Flores, as Commissioner, in the
place of Baron de Bastrop.</emph></p>

<p>His excellency, the lieutenant governor of the state, under date of 7th
February last past, says to me as follows:—</p>

<p>“It being impossible for Don Felipe Henrique Neri Baron de Bas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trop
the former commissioner of .the first colony of the empresario, citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zen
Stephen F. Austin, to leave this capital to conclude the unfinished
business of said colony; as well on account of his station as a member
of the legislature, as also because he is dangerously ill; I have thought
proper to determine in consequence of your official representation, No.
11, of the 16th January last past, and with the consent of said Bastrop,
to authorise citizen Gasper Flores, who has been commissioned by the
government, for the second colony of said empresario, to complete the
business which may be unfinished, in the said first colony, which you
will communicate to said citizen, Gasper Flores, for his information and
corresponding effects.”
And I transcribe it to you for the purpose indicated.—God and Lib<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ertv.—Nacogdoches,
19th March, 1827.
JOSE ANTONIO SAUCEDO,
Chief of Department.
To citizen Gasper Flores.</p>

<p>[No. 19.] <emph rend="italic">Order relative to the Register.<lb />Executive Department, of the State of Coahuila and Texas.</emph></p>

<p>Under this date I have issued the following order, to citizen Gasper
Flores, commissioner of that colony.</p>

<p>"Having considered the official representation, dated th ultimo, di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rected
to me by citizen Stephen F. Austin, empresario of Austin’s colony,
in that department, relative to the mode of preventing the original docu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments
of that colony from being lost or destroyed by the lapse of time, I
have thought it proper to approve of it, and in consequence, order that
the following articles shall be observed on the subject, which are in ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dition
to the instructions heretofore given to you.</p>

<p>Art. 1. In order to preserve and perpetuate the documents apper<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining
to the first enterprise of colonisation of the empresario, citizen
Stephen F. Austin, in Texas, established in virtue of the supreme decree
of the Mexican government, dated 18th February, 1823; of which you
are appointed commissioner, in the place of the former commissioner,
Baron de Bastrop, all the said documents shall be transcribed, together
with, the decrees of the government on the subject, and the titles issued
in virtue of them, to individuals, and to said empresario, accompanied
with a plot of each tract of land, and of the town of San Felipe de
Austin, in a large book, well bound, and destined for that object.</p>

<p>Art. 2. At the top of the first page of said book, the following words
shall be written, “Register of the documents and titles, issued in the
first enterprise of colonisation of the empresario, citizen Stephen F. Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin,

<pb n="38" xml:id="P0038" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/46/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

in Texas,” which shall be signed by the commissioner, empresario
and alcalde, of the town, with assistant witnesses.</p>

<p>
Art. 3. At the end of each document, and title, the following words
shall be put: "The foregoing instrument of writing, is literally copied
from its original, which is on file in the archives of this colony;” date
and signature of the commissioner, empresario, and alcalde, with as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sistant
witnesses.</p>

<p>Art. 4. At the end of the register of the whole, the following words
shall be put: “The foregoing register, composed of------pages, contains
literal and exact copies of all the documents and titles filed in the ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chives
of the first colony of the empresario, citizen- Stephen F. Austin,
established in Texas, in virtue of the colonisation law, of the 4th Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary,
1823, and of the decree of the supreme government of the Mexican
nation, of the 18th of February, confirmed by those of the sovereign
constituent congress, and supreme executive power, dated the 11th and
14th April of the said year 1823, which are copied into this book,
and compared with their originals, by the commissioner, citizen Gasper
Flores, empresario citizen Stephen F. Austin, and the alcalde of this
town, in compliance with the instructions of his excellency, the governor
of the state of Coahuila and Texas, dated 31st of May, 1827, for the
purpose of preserving and perpetuating said documents in the archives
of said colony in a secure form, in order that they may at all times have
the same value and legality in law, as their originals: in attestation of all
which, we, the said commissioner, empresario, and alcalde, sign, &amp;c. &amp;c.”</p>

<p>“Inasmuch as I am informed that the book destined for this object,
is already acquired by the empresario, and that the stamp paper on
which the original titles are extended, has been paid for;—the said book
shall be stamped by the collector of the stamp duties of the town of San
Felipe de Austin, with the stamp of the fourth seal; and he will col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lect
the value of one stamp for each leaf, for which purpose he will put
the corresponding certificate, on the first and last leaf, expressing in the
latter the whole amount of stamps collected, which shall be entered in
the accounts of his office.”</p>

<p>Which I transcribe to you for your intelligence and observance, so
far as appertains to you in answer to your official representation of the
5th of last month, relative to the matter.—God and Liberty.—Saltillo,
31st Mav, 1827.	AEISPE, Governor of the State.
JUAN ANTONIO PADILLA, Secretary of State.
To Citizen Stephen F. Austin.</p>

<p>[No. 20.] (Decree No. 72) <emph rend="italic">National Colonisation Law.</emph></p>

<p>The Supreme Executive Power, provisionally appointed by the general
sovereign Constituent Congress—To all who shall see and understand
these presents: Know ye—that the said Congress has decreed as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows
:—</p>

<p>Art. 1. The Mexican nation offers to foreigners, who come to estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish
themselves within its territory, security for their persons and prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty,
provided, they subject themselves to the laws of the country.</p>

<p>Art. 2. This law comprehends those lands of the nation, not the

<pb n="39" xml:id="P0039" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/47/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

property of individuals, corporations, or towns which can be colonised.</p>

<p>Art. 3. For this purpose the legislatures of all the states will, as soon
as possible, form colonisation laws, or regulations for their respective
states, conforming themselves in all things, to the constitutional act,
general constitution, and the regulations established in this law.</p>

<p>Art. 4. There cannot be colonised any lands, comprehended within
twenty leagues of the limits of any foreign nation, nor within ten leagues
of the coasts, without the previous approbation of the general supreme
executive power.</p>

<p>Art. 5. If for the defence and security of the nation, the federal gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment
should deem it necessary to use any portion of these lands, for
the construction of warehouses, arsenals, or other public edifices, they
can do so, with the approbation of the general congress, or in its recess,
of the council of government.</p>

<p>Art. 6. Until after four years from the publication of this law, there
shall not be imposed any tax whatever, on the entrance of foreigners,
who come to establish themselves for the first time in the nation.</p>

<p>Art. 7. Until after the year 1840, the general congress shall not
prohibit the entrance of any foreigner, as a colonist, unless imperious
circumstances should require it, with respect to the individuals of a
particular nation.</p>

<p>Art. 8. The government, without prejudicing the objects of this
law, shall take such precautionary measures as it may deem expedient,
for the' security of the confederation, as respects the foreigners who come
to colonise.</p>

<p>Art. 9. A preference shall be given in the distribution of lands, to
Mexican citizens, and no other distinction shall be made in regard to
them except that which is founded on individual merit, or services ren<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dered
the country, or under equal circumstances, a residence in the
place where the lands to be distributed are situated.</p>

<p>Art. 10. The military who in virtue of the offer made on the 27th
March, 1821, have a right to lands, shall be attended to by the states,
in conformity with the diplomas which are issued to that effect, by the
supreme executive power.</p>

<p>Art. 11. If in virtue of the decree alluded to, in the last article, and
taking into view the probabilities of life, the supreme executive power
should deem it expedient to alienate any portion of land in favor of any
officer, whether civil or military of the federation, it can do so from the
vacant lands of the territories.</p>

<p>Art. 12. It shall not be permitted to unite in the same hands with
the right of property, more than one league square of land, suitable for
irrigation, four square leagues in superficies, of arable land without the
facilities of irrigation, and six square leagues in superficies of grazing
land.</p>

<p>Art. 13. The new colonists shall not transfer their property in mort<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />main
<emph rend="italic">(manus muertosi)</emph></p>

<p>ART. 14. This law guarantees the contracts which the empresarios
make with the families which they bring at their own expense, provided
they are not contrary to the laws.</p>

<p>Art. 15. No person who by virtue of this law, acquires a title to
lands, shall hold them if he is domiciliated out of the limits of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public.</p>

<pb n="40" xml:id="P0040" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/48/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

<p>Art. 16. The government in conformity with the provisions estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished
in this law, will proceed to colonise the territories of the republic.</p>

<p>
Mexico, 18th August, 1824.
CAYETANO IBARRA, President.
PEDRO DE AHUMADA, Member and Secretary.
MANUEL DE VILLAY COCIO, Member and Secretary.
Therefore, we command it to be printed, circulated, and obeyed.
NICHOLAS BRAVO, ) Members of the
VICENTE GUERRERO, &gt; Supreme Execu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive Power.
MIGUEL DOMINGUEZ.</p>

<p>[No. 21.] <emph rend="italic">Colonisation law of the state of Coahuila and Texas.</emph></p>

<p>The Governor provisionally appointed by the Sovereign Congress of
this state; to all who shall see these presents: Know, that the said
congress, have decreed as follows:</p>

<p>Decree No. 16. The constituent congress of the free, independent and
sovereign state of Coahuila and Texas, desiring by every possible
means, to augment the population of its territory; promote the culti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vation
of its fertile lands; the raising and multiplication of stock, and
the progress of the arts, and commerce; and being governed by the
constitutional act, the federal constitution, and the basis established
by the national decree of the general congress. No. 72, have thought
proper to decree the following LAW on colonisation:</p>

<p>Art. 1. All foreigners, who in virtue of the general laws of the 18th
August, 1824, which guarantees the security of their persons and prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty,
in the territory of the Mexican nation, wish to remove to any of
the settements of the state of Coahuila and Texas, are at liberty to do
so; and the said state invites and calls them.</p>

<p>Art. 2. Those who do so instead of being incommoded, shall be ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted
by the local authorities of said settlements, who shall freely per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit
them to pursue any branch of industry, that they may think proper,
provided they respect the general laws of the nation, and those of the
state.</p>

<p>ART. 3. Any foreigner, already in the limits of the state of Coahuila
and Texas, who wishes to settle himself in it, shall make a declara<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
to that effect, before the ayuntamiento of the place, which he
selects as his residence, the ayuntamiento in such case, shall admin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ister
to him the oath, which he must take to obey the federal and state
constitutions, and observe the religion which the former prescribes; the
name of the person, and his family if he has any, shall then be registered
in a book kept for that purpose, with a statement of where he was born,
and whence from, his age, whether married, occupation, and that he has
taken the oath prescribed, and considering him from that time, and not
before, as domiciliated.</p>

<p>Art. 4. From the day in which any foreigner has been enrolled,
as an inhabitant, in conformity with the foregoing article, he is at lib<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty
to designate any vacant land, and the respective political authority
will grant it to him in the same manner as to a native of the country, in
conformity with the existing laws of the nation, under the condition

<pb n="41" xml:id="P0041" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/49/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>


that the proceedings shall be passed to the government for its approba<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>

<p>Art. 5. Foreigners of any nation, or a native of any of the Mexican
states, can project the formation of new towns on any lands entirely
vacant, or even on those of an individual, in the case mentioned in
the 35th article: but the new settlers who present themselves for ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission,
must prove their Christianity, morality, and good habits, by a
certificate from the authorities where they formerly resided.</p>

<p>Art. 6. Foreigners who emigrate at the time in which the general
sovereign congress may have prohibited their entrance, for the- purpose
of colonising, as they have the power to do, after the year 1840, or pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vious
to that time, as respects those of any particular nation, shall not
then be admitted; and those who apply in proper time, shall always sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject
themselves to such precautionary measures of national security,
which the supreme government, without prejudicing the object of this
law, may think proper to adopt relative to them.</p>

<p>Art, 7. The government shall take care, that within the twenty
leagues bordering on the limits of the United States of the North, and
ten leagues in a straight line from the coast of the Gulf of Mexico,
within the limits of this state, there shall be no other settlements, except
such as merit the approbation of the supreme government of the Union,
for which object, all petitions on the subject, whether made by Mexicans
or foreigners, shall be passed to the superior government, accompanied
by a corresponding report.</p>

<p>Art. 8. The projects for new settlements in which one or more
persons offer to bring at their own expense, one hundred or more fam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ilies,
shall be presented to the government, and if found conformable
with this law, they will be admitted: and the government will immedi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ately
designate to the contractors, the land where they are to establish
themselves, and the term of six years, within which they must present
the number of families they contracted for, under the penalty of losing
the rights and privileges offered in their favor, in proportion to the
number of families which they fail to introduce, and the contract totally
annulled if they do not bring at least one hundred families.</p>

<p>Art. 9. Contracts made by the contractors or undertakers, im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />presarios,
with the families brought at their expense, are guaranteed by
this law, so far as they are conformable with its provisions.</p>

<p>Art. 10. In the distributions of land, a preference shall be given to
the military entitled to them, by the diplomas issued by the supreme
executive power, and the Mexican citizens who are not military, among
whom there shall be no other distinction, than that founded on them
individual merit, or services performed for the country, or in equal
circumstances, a residence in the place where the land may be situated;
the quantity of land which may be granted, is designated in the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
articles:</p>

<p>Art. 11. A square of land, which on each side has one league or
five thousand varas, or what is the same thing, a superficies of twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five
million varas, shall be called a sitio, and this shall be the unity for
counting one, two, or more sitios; and also the unity for counting one,
two, or more labors, shall be one million square varas, or one thousand
varas on each side, which shall compose a labor. The vara for this
measurement shall be three geometrical feet.</p>

<pb n="42" xml:id="P0042" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/50/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

<p>ART. 12. Taking the above unity as a basis, and ‘observing the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinction
which must be made between grazing land, or that which is
proper for raising of stock, and farming land, with or without the facility
of irrigation; this law grants to the contractor or contractors, for the
establishment of a new settlement, for each hundred families which he
may introduce and establish in the state, five sitios of grazing land, and
five labors at least, the one half of which, .shall be without the facility
of irrigation, but they can only receive this premium for eight hundred
families, although a greater number should be introduced, and no frac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
whatever, less than one hundred, shall entitle them to any premium,
not even proportionally.</p>

<p>ART. 13. Should any contractor or contractors in virtue of the num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber
of families which he may. have introduced, acquire in conformity
with the last article, more than eleven square leagues of land, it shall
nevertheless be granted, but subject to the condition of alienating the
excess, within twelve years, and if it is not done, the respective political
authority shall do it, by selling it at public sale, delivering the proceeds
to the owners, after deducting the costs of sale.</p>

<p>Art. 14. To each family comprehended in a contract, whose sole
occupation is cultivation of land, one labor shall be given;. should he
also be a stock raiser, grazing land shall be added to complete a sitio;
and should his only occupation be raising of stock, he shall only receive
a superfice of grazing land, equal to twenty-four million square bars.</p>

<p>Art. 15. Unmarried men shall receive the same quantity when they
enter the matrimonial state, and foreigners who marry native Mexicans,
shall receive one-fourth more; those who are entirely single, or who do
not form a part of some family whether foreigners or natives, shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tent
themselves with the fourth part of the above mentioned quantity,
which is all that can be given them until they marry.</p>

<p>Art. 16. Families or unmarried men who, entirely of their own
accord, have emigrated and may wish to unite themselves to any new
towns, can at all times do so, and the same quantity of land shall be
assigned them, which is mentioned in the last two articles, but if they
do so in the first' six years from the ’ establishment of the settlement, one
labor more shall be given to families, and single men in place of the
quarter designated in the 15th article, shall have the third part.</p>

<p>Art. 17. It appertains to the government to augment the quantity
indicated in the 14, 15, and 16th articles, in proportion to the family,
industry and activity of the colonists, agreeably to the information given
on these subjects by the ayuntamientos and commissioners; the said gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment
always observing the provision of the 12th article, of the decree
of the general congress on the subject.</p>

<p>Art. 18. The families who emigrate in conformity with the 16th
article shall immediately present themselves to the political authority
of the place which they may have chosen for their residence, who finding
in them the requsites, prescribed by this law for new settlers, shall admit
them, and put them in possession of the corresponding lands, and shall
immediately give an account thereof to the government; who of them<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />selves,
or by means of a person commissioned to that effect, will issue
them a title.</p>

<p>Art. 19. The Indians of all nations, bordering on the state, as well
as wandering tribes that may be within its limits, shall be received in

<pb n="43" xml:id="P0043" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/51/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

the markets, without paying any duties whatever for commerce, in the
products of the country; and if attracted by the moderation and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fidence,
with which they shall be treated, any of them, after having first
declared themselves in favor of our religion and institutions wish to
establish themselves in any settlements that are forming, they shall be
admitted, and the same quantity of land given them, as to the settlers,
spoken of in the 14th and 15th articles, always pref erring. native Indians
to strangers.</p>

<p>Art. 20. In order that there may be no vacancies between tracts, of
which, great care shall be taken in the distribution of lands; it shall be
laid off in squares, or other forms although irregular, if the local situa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
requires it; and in said distribution, as well as the assignation of
lands for new towns, previous notice shall be given to the adjoining pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prietors,
if any, in order to prevent dissentions and law suits.</p>

<p>Art. 21. If by error in the accession, any land shall be granted, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />longing
to another, on proof being made of that fact, an equal quantity
shall be granted elsewhere, to the' person who may have thus obtained
it through error, and he shall be indemnified by the owner of such land,
for any improvements he may have made; the just value of which im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provements
shall be ascertained by the appraisers.</p>

<p>Art. 22. The new settlers as an acknowledgement, shall pay to the
state, for each sitio of pasture land, thirty dollars; two dollars and a half
for each labor without the facility of irrigation, and three dollars and
a half for each one that can be irrigated, and so on proportionally ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording
to the quantity and quality of the land distributed; but the said
payments need not be made, until six years after the settlement, and by
thirds; the first within four years, the second within five years, and the
last within six years, under the penalty of losing the land, for a failure,
in any of said payments; there are excepted from this payment, the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tractors,
and military, spoken of in the 10th article; the former, with
respect to lands given them, as a premium, and the latter, for those
which they obtained, in conformity with their diplomas.</p>

<p>Art. 23. The ayuntamientos of each municipality (Comarca,) shall
collect the abovementioned funds, gratis, by means of a committee, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed
either within or without their body; and shall remit them as
they are collected, to the treasurer of their funds; who will give the
corresponding receipt, and without any other compensation than two
and a half per cent., all that shall be allowed him, he shall hold them
at the disposition of the government, rendering an account every month
of the ingress and egress, and of any remissness or fraud, which he may
observe in their collection, for the correct management of all which, the
persons employed, and the committee, and the individuals of the ayun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tamientos
who appoint them, shall be individually responsible, and that
this responsibility may be at all times effectual, the said appointments
shall be made viva voce, and information shall be given thereof, immedi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ately
to the government.</p>

<p>Art. 24. The government will sell to Mexicans, and to them only,
such lands as they’may wish to purchase, taking care that there shall
not be accumulated in the same hands more than eleven sitios; and
under the condition, that the purchaser must cultivate what he acquires
by this title within six years from its acquisition, under the penalty of
losing them, the price of each sitio, subject to the foregoing condition,

<pb n="44" xml:id="P0044" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/52/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

shall be one hundred dollars, if it be pasture land; one hundred and
fifty dollars, if it be farming land without the facility of irrigation; and
two hundred dollars if it can be irrigated.</p>

<p>Art. 25. Until six years after the publication of this law, the legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature
of this state, can not alter it as regards the acknowledgment, and
price to be paid for land, or as regards the quantity and quality, to be
distributed to the new settlers, or sold to Mexicans.</p>

<p>Art. 26. The new settlers, who within six years from the date of the
possession, have not cultivated or occupied the lands granted them, ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording
to its quality, shall be considered to have renounced them, and
the respective political authority shall immediately proceed to take pos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />session
of them, and recall the titles.</p>

<p>Art. 27. The contractors and military, heretofore spoken of, and
those who by purchase have acquired lands, can alienate them at any
time, but the successor is obliged to cultivate them in the same time,
that the original proprietor was bound to do; the other settlers can
alienate theirs when they have totally cultivated them, and not before.</p>

<p>Art. 28. By testamentary will, made in conformity with the existing
laws, or those which may govern in future, any new colonist, from the
day of his settlement, may dispose of his land, although he may not have
cultivated it, and if he dies intestate, his property shall be inherited by
the person or persons entitled by the laws to it; the heirs being subject
to the same obligation and condition imposed on the original grantee.</p>

<p>Art. 29. Lands acquired by virtue of this law, shall not by any title
whatever, pass into mortmain.</p>

<p>Art. 30. The new settler who wishing to establish himself in a for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eign
country, resolves to leave the territory of the state, can do so freely
with all his property; but after leaving the state, he shall not any longer
hold his land, and if he had not previously sold it, or the sale should not
be in conformity with the 27th article, it shall become entirely vacant.</p>

<p>Art. 31. Foreigners who in conformity with this law, have obtained
land, and established themselves in any new settlement, shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sidered
from that moment, naturalised in the country; and by marrying
a Mexican, they acquire a particular merit to obtain letters of citizenship
of the state, subject however to the provisions which may be made rela<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive
to both particulars, in the constitution of the state.</p>

<p>Art. 32. During the first ten years, counting from the day on which
the new settlements may have been established, they shall be free from
all contributions, of whatever denomination, with the exception of those
which, in case of invasion by any enemy, or to prevent it, are generally
imposed, and all the produce of agriculture or industry of the new set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tlers,
shall be free from excise duty Alcabala, or other duties, throughout
every part of the state, with the exception of the duties referred to in the
next article; after the termination of that time, the new settlements shall
be on the same footing as to taxes, with the old ones, and the colonists
shall also in this particular, be on the same footing with the other in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitants
of the state.</p>

<p>Art. 33. From the day of their settlement, the new colonists shall
be at liberty to follow any branch of industry, and can also work
mines of every description, communicating with the supreme govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
of the confederation, relative to the general revenue appertaining

<pb n="45" xml:id="P0045" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/53/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

to it, and subjecting themselves in all other particulars, to the ordinances
or taxes, established or which may be established on this branch.</p>

<p>Art. 34. Towns shall be founded on the sites deemed most suitable,
by the government, or the person commissioned for this effect, and for
each one, there shall be designed four square leagues, whose area may be
in a regular or irregular form, agreeably to the situation.</p>

<p>Art. 35. If any of the said sites should be the property of an indi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vidual,
and the establishment of new towns on them, should notoriously
be of general utility, they can, notwithstanding, be appropriated to this
object, previously indemnifying the owner for its just value, to be deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mined
by appraisers.</p>

<p>Art. 36. Building lots in the new towns shall be given gratis, to the
contractors of them, and also to artists of every class, as many as are
necessary for the establishment of their trade; and to the other settlers
they shall be sold at public auction, after having been previously valued
—under the obligation to pay the purchase money by instalments of one
third each; the first in six months, the second in twelve months, and the
third in eighteen months; but all owners of lots, including contractors
and artists, shall annually pay one dollar for each lot, which, together
with the produce of the sales, shall be collected by the ayuntamientos,
and applied to the building of churches in said towns.</p>

<p>Art. 37. So far as practicable, the towns shall be composed of natives
and foreigners, and in their delineations great care should be taken to
lay off the streets straight, giving them a direction from north to south,
and from east to west, when the site will permit it.</p>

<p>Art. 38. For the better location of the said new towns, their regular
formation and exact partition of their lands and lots, the government
on account of having admitted any project, and agreed with the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tractor
or contractors, who may have presented it, shall commission a
person of intelligence and confidence, giving him such particular in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structions
as may be deemed necessary and expedient; aud authorising
him under his own responsibility, to appoint one or more surveyors to
lay off the town scientifically, and do whatever else may be required.</p>

<p>Art. 39. The governor in conformity with the last fee bill Arancel,
of notary publics of the ancient audience of Mexico, shall designate the
fees of the commissioner, who, in conjunction with the colonists, shall
fix the surveyor’s fees; but both shall be paid by the colonists, and in
the manner which all parties among themselves may agree upon.</p>

<p>Art. 40. As soon as at least forty families are united in one place,
they .shall proceed to the formal establishment of the new towns, and
all of them shall take an oath to support the general and state constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions;
which oath -will be administered by the commissioner, they shall
then, in his presence, proceed for the first time to the election of their
municipal authority.</p>

<p>Art. 41. A new town, whose inhabitants shall not be less than two
hundred, shall elect an ayuntamiento, provided there is not another
one established within eight leagues, in which case, it shall be added
to it. The number of individuals which are to compose the ayunta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />miento,
shall be regulated by the existing laws.</p>

<p>Art. 42. Foreigners are eligible, subject to the provisions which the
constitution of the state may prescribe, to elect the members of their
municipal authorities, and to be elected to the same.</p>

<pb n="46" xml:id="P0046" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/54/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

<p>Art. 43. The municipal expenses, and all other others which may be
considered necessary, or of common utility to the new towns, shall be
proposed to the governor, by the ayuntamientos through the political
chief, accompanied with a plan of the taxes arbitrios, which in their
opinion may be just and best calculated to raise them, and should the
proposed plan be approved by the governor, he shall order it to be exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cuted,
subject however to the resolution of the legislature, to whom it
shall be immediately passed with his report and that of the political
chief, who will say whatever occurs to him on the subject.</p>

<p>Art. 44. Tor the opening and improving of roads and other public
works in Texas, the government will transmit to the chief of that de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partment
the individuals who, in other parts of the state, may have
been sentenced to public works as vagrants, or for other crimes, these
same persons may be employed by individuals for competent wages, and
as soon as the time of their condemnation is expired, they can unite
themselves as colonists to any new settlement, and obtain the corres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ponding
lands, if their reformation shall have made them worthy of
such favor in the opinion of the chief of the department, without whose
certificate they shall not be admitted.</p>

<p>Art. 45. The government in accord with the respective ordinary
ecclesiastics, will take care to provide the new settlements with the
competent number of pastors, and, in accord with the same authority,
shall propose to the legislature for its approbation, the salary which the
said pastors are to receive, which shall be paid by the new settlers.</p>

<p>Art. 46.' The new settlers as regards the introduction of slaves, shall
subject themselves to the existing laws, and those which may hereafter
be established on the subject.</p>

<p>Art. 47. The petitions now pending relative to the subject of this
law, shall be despatched in conformity with it, and for this purpose,
they shall be passed to the governor, and the families who may be es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablished
within the limits of the state, without having any land assigned
them, shall subject themselves to this law, and to the orders of the
supreme government of the Union, with respect to those who are within
twenty leagues of the limits of the United States of America, and ten
leagues in a straight line of the coast of the Gulf of Mexico.</p>

<p>Art. 48. This law shall be published in all the villages of the state,
and that it may arrive at the notice of all others throughout the Mexi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />can
confederation, it shall be communicated to their respective legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tures,
by the secretary of this state: and the governor will take particu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lar
care to send a certified copy of it, in compliance with the 161st article
of the federal constitution, to the two houses of congress, and the su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme
executive power of the nation, with a request to the latter to
give it general circulation through foreign states, by means of your
ambassadors.</p>

<p>The governor pro tem, of the state will cause it to be published and
circulated.—Saltillo, 24th March, 1825.—Signed.
RAFAEL RAMOS Y VALDEZ, President.
JUAN VICENTE GAMPOS, Member and Sedy.
JOSE JOAQUIN ARCE ROSALES, Member and Sedy.
Therefore, I command all authorities, as well civil as military and
ecclesiastical, to obey, and cause to be obeyed, the present decree in all
its parts.	RAFAEL GONZALES, Governor.</p>

<pb n="47" xml:id="P0047" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/55/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

<p>[No. 22.] <emph rend="italic">Contract with the Government of the State for the Coloni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation of five hundred Families.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Executive Department of the State of Coahuila and Texas.</emph></p>

<p>I have before me the representation, directed by you to the supreme
government of the nation, dated 6th November, 1824, soliciting that
Galveston might be made a port of entry, and asking authority to
settle two or three hundred families, more or less, on the lands con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tiguous
to those already distributed in that colony, and particularly on
the bay of Galveston, and the rivers that discharge into it; you also ask
authority to found a town, on the island of Galveston, or at some suitable
point; which representation was transmitted to me by the honorable
legislature of the state, when it communicated to me the law of coloni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation,
passed by that body the 24th of March last, for the purposes
which might be necessary, relative to said new colony proposed by you.
Subsequently, I received your representation of the 4th of February
last, on the same subject, and. proposing to colonize three hundred honest
and industrious families, a part of whom were in the country on the
Trinity, and Neches rivers, beyond your limits; which families you offer
to settle on the waters of the Brazos and Colorado, as high as to the
San Antonio road.</p>

<p>In consequence of your representations, and keeping in view the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tracts,
made by this government a few days since, with four other em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />presarios,
to colonize all the lands adjacent to your colony on the east,
north and west, with two thousand four hundred families; in conformity
with the law of colonisation, and the conditions imposed by the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
excepting only, the ten border leagues on the coast, and twenty
border leagues on the boundary line, reserved by the national colonisa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
law, of the 18th August, 1824, subject to the disposition of the
national government; and being informed that there remains much va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cant
land within the limits of your first colony, not granted to any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son;
I hereby grant the permission which you petition for, to settle the
three hundred families you mention, on the vacant lands, remaining in
the colony now under your charge, and not comprehended in any of
those already granted to other empresarios, so as to avoid granting an
establishment on lands already assigned to others for that purpose.</p>

<p>In case you still wish to effect the colonisation of the said three
hundred families, which you propose, within the limits of your first col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ony,
the said additional families must subject themselves to the federal
constitution, and that of the state, and to the general and local laws of
their adopted country; the said new colony shall also be regulated by the
colonisation law of the state of the 24th March last, and you as em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />presario,
must be subject to the following stipulations:</p>

<p>Art. 1. The government admits the proposition presented by citizen
Stephen F. Austin, in his representation of the 4th February, of the last
year, relative to the colonisation of three hundred families, so far as may
be conformable with the colonisation law, passed by the honorable legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature
of this state, 24th March last; and I hereby designate, in com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pliance
with the 8th article of said law, and in consequence of your repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentation,

<pb n="48" xml:id="P0048" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/56/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

the vacant land within the limits of the colony which you have
already established, excepting only the ten border leagues on the coast,
which can only be colonised with the previous approbation of the su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme
executive power of the nation, in conformity with the law of the
18th August, 1824.</p>

<p>
Art. 2. You shall respect the possessions given to individuals, who
occupy the lands within your limits, under legal titles.</p>

<p>Art. 3. In conformity with the said colonisation law of the 24th
March, the empresario, citizen Stephen F. Austin, shall introduce the
three hundred families which he proposes, within the term of six years,
counting from the day on which the said empresario signs this contract,
under the penalty of losing the rights and privileges granted to him by
the eighth article of said law.</p>

<p>Art. 4. The families that are to compose this colony, besides being
industrious as offered in the representation, must also be catholics, and
of good moral habits, which qualifications must be proved by the docu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments,
required in the 5th article of the colonisation law, of the 24th
March.</p>

<p>Art. 5. It shall be an obligation upon him, not to admit criminals,
vagabonds, or men of bad conduct, and he shall cause all those of this
description, who are found within his limits to leave it, and should it be
necessary, he shall put them out by force of arms.</p>

<p>Art. 6. Tor this purpose the colonists shall be formed into a body
of national militia, of which he shall be the chief, until otherwise di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rected.</p>

<p>Art. 7. So soon as he shall have introduced at least one hundred
families, he shall notify the government thereof, in order that a com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner
may be sent with competent instructions to put new colonists
in possession of their lands, and to establish the new towns agreeably
to law.</p>

<p>
Art. 8. The official communications with the-government, and with
the authorities of the state, instruments, and other public acts, must be
written in the Spanish language, and when new towns are formed he
/shall promote the establishment of schools in the Spanish language, in
such towns.</p>

<p>
Art. 9. It shall also be his duty to promote the building of churches
in said towns, and the providing of them with ornaments, sacred vases
and other furniture, destined for divine- worship, and to solicit in due<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />time
the necessary number of priests for the administration of spiritual
affairs.</p>

<p>Art. 10. In all other particulars not expressed in the above stipula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions,
he shall subject himself to the colonisation law, and other general
laws.</p>

<p>Art. 11. The foregoing are the conditions or stipulations on which
this government admits the new project of colonisation, proposed by
you in your aforementioned official representation, and should they be
accepted by you, you will so declare under your signature at the end of
this instrument, which you will then return to me, to be filed in the
archives of this government, and a certified copy thereof, and of your
official representation attested by the secretary of state, shall be im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mediately
transmitted to you for your security in order that you may

<pb n="49" xml:id="P0049" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/57/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

immediately proceed with said project. God and Liberty. Saltillo, 27th
of April, 1825.
RAFAEL GONZALES, Governor of the State.
To Citizen Stephen F. Austin.</p>

<p>Having seen the stipulations and conditions, stated in the foregoing
official instrument of his excellency, Rafael Gonzales, governor of the
state of Coahuila and Texas, relative to the colonisation of three hundred
foreign families on the vacant lands remaining within the colony which I
have already established in Texas; I hereby declare my acceptance of the
same, and agree to comply with them in every particular under the pen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alty
of losing the rights and privileges mentioned in the third article
of said stipulations. San Felipe de Austin, 4th of June, 1825.
STEPHEN F. AUSTIN.</p>

<p>[No. 23.] <emph rend="italic">Official letter of the Governor extending the foregoing
Contract to five hundred families.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Executive Department of the state of Coahuila and Texas.</emph></p>

<p>On the 27th of April last, I transmitted to you the conditions on which
the government admitted the peroject of colonising three hundred fami<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lies,
proposed by you to the government of the Union in your represen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tation
of the 6th of November, 1824, and in that to the government of
this state, of the 4th of February last, specifying more particularly the'
section you wish to colonise.</p>

<p>I have just received the new representatiou which you have trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted,
under the date of the 4th of April last, proposing to establish
five hundred families in said new colony; and understanding that the
district designated for you in my communication of the 27th of April
last, is sufficiently extensive to settle the five hundred families which
you now propose, I hereby grant you permission to do so on the same
conditions which I have before indicated to you, it being understood
that your former petitions on this subject are all consolidated in the
last ones of the 4th of April.</p>

<p>As regards establishing the port of Galveston I will communicate
the result to you separately as soon as the sovereign congress of the
nation determines that question. God and Liberty. Saltillo, 20th of.
May, 1825.
RAFAEL GONZALES, Governor of the State.
To Citizen Spephen F. Austin.
</p>

<pb n="50" xml:id="P0050" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/58/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

<p>[No. 24.]<emph rend="italics">Limits of the above mentioned Colony.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italics">Executive Department of the State of Coahuila and Texas.</emph></p>

<p>Taking into consideration the representation of citizen Stephen F.
Austin, an empresario of the department of Texas, for the colonisation
of five hundred families on unappropriated lands of the state, asking a
specific demarcation of limits within which the said families are to be
settled; in order to avoid at all times any kind of doubts, or disputes
between adjoining empresarios, or the respective colonists, situated
near the same limits, and keeping in view the concessions granted by
this government to the empresarios Green De Wit, Robert Leftwitch,
and John Lucius Woodbury, which are situated on the west, north and
east of the colony, of said citizen, Stephen F. Austin; I have thought
proper to add as an additional article to the contract on colonisation,
concluded the 4th of June, 1835, the following permanent demarcation
of limits for the before mentioned colony.</p>

<p>Commencing on the west bank of the river San Jacinto, at the termi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation
of the ten league reserve, from the gulf of Mexico and thence
following up the right bank of said river to its head, thence due north,
to the road leading from Bexar to Nacogdoches; thence follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing
said road westwardly, to a point from whence a line due south
will strike the La Baca to within ten leagues of the Gulf of Mexico,
and thence eastwardly along the said ten league line parallel with the
coast, to the place of beginning.</p>

<p>This order and the petition of said Austin on the subject, shall he
added to the documents relative to said colony of five hundred fami<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lies,
and it shall also be communicated to said empresario, and all others
who may be interested, for their information.</p>

<p>And I communicate it to you, and under this date have also com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />municated
it to the commissioners of that colony, for the corresponding
effects. God and Liberty. Saltillo, 7th March, 1827.
ARISPE, Governor of the State.
To Citizen STEPHEN F. Austin. '
JUAN ANTONIO PADILLA,
Secretary of State.</p>

<p>[No. 25.] <emph rend="italic">(Commission of Gaspar Flores, for the second colony.)</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Executive Department, of the State of Coahuila and Texas.</emph></p>

<p>Convinced of your honor, integrity, and other necessary qualifications,
I have thought it proper to appoint you commissioner for the partition
of lands, to the new colonists, in the contract of colonisation, of citizen
Stephen F. Austin, with the government of this state; which I com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />municate
to you, for your information, with the understanding that I
will transmit to you the instructions, and other documents, by which

<pb n="51" xml:id="P0051" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/59/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

you are to be governed in the discharge of this most important com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission.—God
and Liberty.—Saltillo, 21st April, 1826.
ARISPE.
To citizen Gasper Flores.
JUAN ANTONIO PADILLA,
Secretary of State.</p>

<p>[No. 27.] <emph rend="italic">Contract with the Government for settling the reserve land
on the coast, between La Baca and San Jacinto.</emph></p>

<p>Petition of S. F. Austin, to the President.—The land situated within
the ten border leagues from the Gulf of Mexico on the Brazos and Colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rado
rivers is in part colonised by me, under the concession granted by
the supreme government of the Mexican nation, thus leaving a portion
of vacant land within said ten leagues; and as it is of great importance
to the prosperity of this new colonial establishment, that said ten leagues
should be added to the colony, which the government of the state of
Coahuila and Texas has assigned to me, for the settlement of the five
hundred families which I have contracted to introduce; I therefore
petition the national government to grant me permission to colonise
the ten border leagues on the coast, within the following limits—to wit,
beginning on the east side of the La Baca, ten leagues from the coast,
thence eastwardly following the northern boundary of the ten border
leagues, to the river San Jacinto; thence down the same to the coast,
thence following the latter westwardly to the mouth of said La Baca,
and up said river to the place of beginning; comprehending all the
vacant lands between the said rivers La Baca and San Jacinto, and
within the ten border leagues from the coast; and that section of coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />try
should be added to the beforementioned colony, to be colonised
under the same conditions stipulated with the government of the state
of Coahuila and Texas, for said colony of five hundred families.
STEPHEN F. AUSTIN.
San Felipe de Austin, 5th June, 1826.</p>

<p>Opinion of the Governor of the State on the foregoing petition.
Most Excellent Sir:—I have the honor to transmit to your excellency
the original petition of citizen Stephen F. Austin, empresario of the
colony of this name, on the Brazos and Colorado rivers in Texas; solicit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
permission to colonise the ten border leagues on the Gulf of Mexico,
between La Baca and San Jacinto.</p>

<p>Having completed the colony of three hundred families, which the
said Austin contracted with the supreme government of the nation in
April 1823, he solicited, in 1825, authority from the State government
to introduce five hundred families more, and settle them in the section
of country designated for his first colony, and a contract was entered into
with him, for that purpose, on the terms and conditions expressed in the

<pb n="52" xml:id="P0052" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/60/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

copy of said contract; which I herewith have the honor of transmitting
to your excellency for the better elucidation of this subject.</p>

<p>This government in forwarding the above mentioned petition to
your excellency, in compliance with the 7th article of the colonisation
law of this state of the 24th of March, 1825, has the satisfaction of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />forming
your excellency, that it can discover no objections whatever to
the approval of said petition by the supreme government of the nation,
but on the contrary it is of opinion that great benefits will result from
said establishment; and that commerce, in the products of the new col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />onists,
will flourish in consequence of the settlement of those lands, and
the opening of the ports of Brazos, Colorado and La Baca.</p>

<p>As regards the merits of the said empresario, I can assure your ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cellency,
that besides being the first who introduced the first families in
Texas, when the country was an entire wilderness, and being a citizen of
this nation, by a special letter of citizenship, he has proved by his con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duct
and adhesion to the established government, that he merits the
highest confidence. God and liberty. Saltillo, 17th July, 1826.
VICTOR BLANCO,
To his Excellency, the Minister of
Interior and Exterior Relations.
JUAN ANTONIO PADILLA,
Secretary of State.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Approbation of the President.</emph></p>

<p>Most Excellent Sir:—Having rendered an account to his excellency,
the president, of the petition of citizen Stephen E. Austin, empresario
of the colony of this name, on the Brazos and Colorado Rivers of Texas,
asking permission to colonise ten border leagues on the Gulf of Mexico,
between the La Baca and San Jacinto; the president has thought proper,
in conformity with your opinion of the 17th July, 1826, which accom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panied
said petition, to approve of the concession of the lands which the
interested person has petitioned for, under the condition of subjecting
himself, in all things relative to said new colony, to the law on the sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject
of the 18th August, 1824.</p>

<p>Which I communicate to your excellency by order of the president,
for the corresponding effects. God and liberty. Mexico, 22d April, 1828.
CANEDO.</p>

<p>To his Excellency the Governor of the State of Coahuila and Texas.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Representation of S. F. Austin to the Governor of the State.</emph></p>

<p>Citizen Stephen E. Austin, with due respect, represents that his excel<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lency
the president of the United Mexican States, having granted me per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission
to colonise the ten border leagues on the coast, between La Baca
and San Jacinto, as appears by the official letter of the minister of rela<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
dated 22d April last; and as I am ready to commence the enterprise
so soon as I receive the competent authority from the government of the
state of Coahuila and Texas; I therefore solicit your excellency to au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorise

<pb n="53" xml:id="P0053" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/61/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

me, in conformity with the law on the subject, to colonise the
land comprehended within the before mentioned limits, and to survey
and divide out said lands, to the colonists, in the portions prescribed by
law, and to issue to them their titles of possession and property, in the
name of the government of this state, giving to me the term of six years
to complete said enterprise, the colonists paying the expenses of the sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veying,
titles, and possessions, according to the provisions of the law; I
also ask authority to select and take for my own proper use, benefit and
property, the quantity of five leagues and five labors, which I am entitled
to as empresario agreeably to law, for each one hundred colonists, which
I establish within said limits, governing myself in all things by the gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral
law of colonisation of 18th August, 1824, and the state law of the
24th March, 1825: and for my security I petition that your excellency
will be pleased to transmit to me an attested copy in due form, of the
said official letter of his excellency, the minister of relations, of 22d April
last, and of this petition, and of the authority which your excellency may
think proper to give me on this subject. Town of Austin, 2d June, 1828.
STEPHEN F. AUSTIN.
</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Contract between the Government of the state and Austin; and ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointment</emph>of the latter as commissioner.</p>

<p>In the city of Leona Vicario (Saltillo) this ninth day of July 1828,
His Excellency the governor of the State of Coahuila and Texas, having
examined the foregoing petition of citizen Stephen F. Austin, and the
accompanying documents relative to the colonisation of the border lands,
situated on the coast of the Gulf of Mexico, from the La Baca to the San
Jacinto, and taking into consideration the merits and qualifications of
said citizen Stephen F. Austin, has thought proper to declare on said
petition and documents, the resolution contained in the following arti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cles
and conditions.</p>

<p>Art. 1. In virtue of the approbation of the supreme government
of the nation, dated 22d April, of the present year, which forms a part
of the documents in this matter; the government of this state admits the
project of colonisation, presented by said empresario, so far as it is
conformable to the general law of the 18th August, 1824, and the law of
the state, pf the 24th March, 1825, both of them on the subject of colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nisation,
and I hereby designate in compliance with the 8th article of
the said state law, the territory which he solicits, under the following
boundaries: beginning at the mouth of the La Baca on its left bank,
thence following along the coast of the Gulf of Mexico to the point where
the San Jacinto river discharges into Galveston Bay; thence following
up the left hank of the San Jacinto river ten leagues in a straight line,
thence westwardly parallel with the coast to a point on the La Baca,
ten leagues in a straight line above its mouth, thence following down
the left bank of said La Baca to its mouth, at the place, of beginning.</p>

<p>Art. 2. All possesions under legal titles which may be found within
the territory, designated in the preceding article, shall be respected by
the new colonists, and the said empresario is hereby charged with the
fulfilment of this duty.</p>

<pb n="54" xml:id="P0054" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/62/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

<p>Art. 3. At any time, in case the government should need any tracts
of land which, from their local situation, may be useful, beneficial, and
proper, for the construction of any forts, wharves, or public warehouses,
for the defence of any ports, or establishment of the public administra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
the empresario shall not have any right to impede the occupation
of any such lands or useful points which may be selected by officers
appointed by the government, and which may be necessary for any ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jects
of public security or integrity of the territory, although they
may not be comprehended in those specified in this article.</p>

<p>Art. 4. Citizen Stephen F. Austin, having the confidence of the
government, is hereby authorised in due form to discharge, at the same
time, both the obligations of empresario, and the duties and functions
of commissioner of the government, in the establishment of new towns
and settlements in the before-mentioned border lands, which are the
subject of this contract, and to cause said lands to be surveyed and
divided out to the colonists, with entire conformity to the law, on the
subject and to the instructions of the government, which will be sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />arately
directed to him.</p>

<p>Art. 5. Inasmuch as the said empresario has not clearly expressed
the number of families which he offers to introduce on said border ter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ritory,
which he is now permitted to colonise; it is necessary that he
should make a specific declaration to the government as to this particu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lar,
or whether he has another contract of five hundred families pending,
to be established in the interior of the country, it is his wish to locate
a part of them in said border territory, as appears to be indicated by his
representation of 5th June, 1826, whatever said Stephen F. Austin may
determine on this point shall be considered as inserted in this article.</p>

<p>Art. 6. The said empresario shall have the right to receive the lands
designated in the 12th article of the colonisation law of this state in
proportion to the number of families he is to introduce, and to select
said land at the sites or situation which he may choose, the titles of pos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />session
for said lands in favor of the said empresario shall be delivered
by the first alcalde of the town of San Felipe de Austin, who is hereby
commissioned in due form for the sole purpose.</p>

<p>Art. 7. The other duties and obligations of citizen Stephen F. Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin,
as empresario, are those of a general nature, which, although not
expressed in this contract, are inserted in his contract for five hundred
families, extended by this government the 27th of April, 1825, all of
which shall be considered as herein inserted.</p>

<p>Art. 8. His duties and obligations as commissioner of the govern- ■
ment for this enterprise, are those prescribed by the law of colonisa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of this state, of the 24th March, 1825, and by the instructions to
the commissioner approved by the legislature the 4th of September,
1827, and by which all his operations shall be governed under the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sponsibilities
therein specified.</p>

<p>Art. 9. The certified copy in due form, solicited by said citizen Ste<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />phen
F. Austin, of the documents on this subject, and of this con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tract,
shall be delivered to him attested by the secretary of state, in order
that, should this contract be accepted of by him, said Austin, it shall
be considered as concluded and perfected from the date of his accepta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
thereof, from which date the term of six years shall be computed,

<pb n="55" xml:id="P0055" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/63/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

prescribed by law for the introduction of the families under this coloni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation
enterprise.</p>

<p>Art. 10. The salary or fees corresponding to the commissioner, shall
be regulated by the provisions of the law of the legislature of the state,
No. 62, dated 15th of May of the present year.—Date as above.</p>

<p>
J. MAEIA VIESCA.
JUAN ANTONIO PADILLA, Sec’y of State.
Citizen Juan Antonio Padilla, secretary of the state of Coahuila and
Texas. I certify that the foregoing is literally and legally copied from
the originals, which are on file in this office under my charge.
JUAN ANTONIO PADILLA,
Secretary of State.
Leona Vicario, 12th July, 1828.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Acceptance of the foregoing Contract by S. F. Austin.</emph></p>

<p>Having examined the contract which his excellency the governor of
the state of Coahuila and Texas has thought proper to comprise in ten
articles, dated in the city of Leona Vicario, 9th July, 1828, for the colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nisation
of the ten border leagues on the coast of the Gulf of Mexico,
between the La Baca and San Jacinto, in Texas; I, citizen Stephen F.
Austin, declare that I accept of the said contract, under its stipulations;
and as respects the fifth article of the same, which requires a declara<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
on my part of the number of families which I engage to introduce,
in virtue of said contract, I hereby declare and offer to introduce the
number of three hundred; it being understood that I am to receive the
premium land, in proportion to the families which I introduce, desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated
for empresarios, in the 12th article of the colonisation law of the
state, although they should not amount to three hundred, if they exceed
one hundred as provided in said 12th article; and being regulated by
the maximum, established in the same article of said law, and by the
contracts entered into with the govetment, by me on the 27th April,
1825, and the 20th November, 1827.-—God and Liberty.— Town of Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin,
20th July, 1828.</p>

<p>
STEPHEN F. AUSTIN.
To his excellency the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Executive Decree on the above Acceptation.</emph></p>

<p>
Leona Vicario, 21st August, 1828.

The above acceptation is added to the documents, and a copy of it,
and of this decree, shall be transmitted to the empresario for his se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curity.

VIESCA.
JUAN ANTONIO PADILLA, Sec’y of State.
A copy from the original, filed with the respective documents in this
office under mv charge.—Leona Vicario, 22d August, 1828.
JUAN ANTONIO PADILLA, Sec’y of State.</p>

<pb n="56" xml:id="P0056" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/64/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

<p><emph rend="italic">Instructions to the Commissioner appointed by the Legislature of
the State.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Executive Department of the State of Coahuila and Texas.</emph></p>

<p>
Instructions by which the commissioner shall be governed in the par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tition
of lands to the new colonists, who may establish themselves
in the state, in conformity with the colonisation law of the 24th
March, 1825.</p>

<p>Art. 1. It shall be the duty of the commissioner, keeping in view
the contract which an empresario may have entered into with the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment,
and also the colonisation law of the 24th March, scrupulously
to examine the certificates or recommendations which foreign emigrants
must produce from the local authorities of the place where they re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moved
from, accrediting their Christianity, morality, and steady habits,
in conformity with the 5th article of said law, without which requisite
they shall not be admitted in the colony.</p>

<p>Art. 2. In order to prevent being imposed on by false recommenda<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions,
the commissioner shall not consider any as sufficient without a
previous opinion in writing as to their legitimacy, from the empresario,
for which purpose they shall be passed to him by the commissioner.</p>

<p>Art. 3. The commissioner shall administer to each of the new colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nists
the oath in form, to observe the federal constitution of the United
Mexican states, the constitution of the state, the general laws of the
nation, and those of the state which they have adopted for their country.</p>

<p>Art. 4. He shall issue in the name of the state the titles for land,
in conformity with the law, and put the new colonists in possession of
their lands, with all legal formalities, and the previous citation of ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />joining
proprietors, should there be any.</p>

<p>Art. 5. He shall not give possession to any colonists who may have
established, or who may wish to establish themselves within twenty
leagues of the limits of the United States of the north, or within ten
leagues of the coast, unless it should appear that the supreme govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
of the nation had approved thereof.</p>

<p>Art. 6. He shall take care that no vacant lands be left between pos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessions,
and in order that the lines may be clearly designated, he shall
compel the colonists, within the term of one year, to mark their lines,
and to establish fixed and permanent corners.</p>

<p>Art. 7. He shall appoint, under his own responsibility, the surveyor,
who must survey the land scientifically, requiring him previously to take
an oath truly and faithfully to discharge the duties of his office.</p>

<p>Art. 8. He shall form a manuscript book of paper of the 3d stamp,
in which shall be written the titles of the lands distributed to the colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nists,
specifying the names, the boundaries, and other requisites, and
legal circumstances; and a certified copy of each title shall be taken from
said book on paper of the 2nd stamp, which shall be delivered to the
interested person on his title.</p>

<p>Art. 9. Each settler shall pay the value of the stamp paper used in
issuing his title both for the original and copy.</p>

<p>Art. 10. This book shall be preserved in the archives of the new
colony, and an exact form of it shall be transmitted to government,

<pb n="57" xml:id="P0057" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/65/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">for Austin’s Colony.</fw>

specifying the number of colonists, with their names, and the quantity
of land granted to each one, distinguishing that which is farming land
with or without the facilities of irrigation, and that which is granted
as grazing land.</p>

<p>Art. 11. He shall select the site which may be the most suitable for
the establishment of the town or towns, which are to be founded agree<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ably
to the number of families composing the colony, and keeping in
view the provisions of the law of colonisation on this subject.</p>

<p>Art. 12. After selecting the site destined for the new town, he shall
take care that the base lines run north and south, east and west; and
he will designate a public square one hundred and twenty varas on each
side, exclusive of the streets, which shall be called the principal, or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitutional square, and this shall be the central point from which the
streets shall run, for the formation of squares and blocks in conformity
with the model hereto annexed.</p>

<p>Art. 13. The block situated on the east side- of the principal square
shall be destined for the church, curate’s house, and other ecclesiastical
buildings. The block on the west side of said square shall be desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated
for public buildings of the municipality. In some other suitable
situation a block shall be designated for a market square, another for
a jail and house of correction, another for a school and other edifices
for public instruction, and another beyond the limits of the town for
a burial ground.'</p>

<p>Art. 14. He shall, on his responsibility, cause the streets to be laid
off straight, and that they are twenty varas wide, to promote the health
of the town.</p>

<p>Art. 15. Mechanics, who at the time of founding a new town, pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent
themselves to settle in it, shall have the right of receiving one lot
a piece without any other cost than the necessary stamp paper for issu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
the title, and the light tax of one dollar annually for the construction
of the church.</p>

<p>Art. 16. The lots spoken of in the preceding article shall be dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tributed
by lot, with the exception of the empr-esario, who shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled
to any two lots he may select.</p>

<p>Art. 17. The other lots shall be valued by appraisers according to
their situation, and sold to the other colonists at their appraised value.
In case there should be a number of applicants for the same lot, owing
to its situation or other circumstances, which may excite competition,
it shall be decided by lot as prescribed in the preceding article; the
product of said lots shall be appropriated to the building of a church
in said town.</p>

<p>Art. 18. He shall, in union with the empersario, promote the set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tlement
of each town by the inhabitants belonging to its jurisdiction,
who take lots in it, and cause them to construct houses on said lots
within a limited time under the penalty of forfeiting them.</p>

<p>Art. 19. He shall form a manuscript book of each new town, in
which shall be written the titles of the lots which are given as a dona<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
or sold, specifying their boundaries and other necessary circum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stances,
a certified copy of each one of which on the corresponding
stamp shall be delivered to the interested person as his title.</p>

<p>Art. 20. He shall form a topographical plan of each town that may

<pb n="58" xml:id="P0058" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/66/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws, Orders and Contracts</fw>

be founded, and transmit it to the government, keeping a copy of it in
the said register book of the colony.</p>

<p>Art. 21. He shall see that at the crossing of each of the rivers on
the public roads, where a town is founded, a ferry is established at the
cost of the inhabitants of said town, a moderate rate of ferriage is es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablished
to pay the salary of the ferryman and the cost of the neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary
boats, and the balance shall be applied to the public funds of the
town.</p>

<p>Art. 22. In places where there is no towns, and where ferries are
necessary, the colonists who may be settled there shall be charged with
the establishment of the ferry, collecting a moderate ferriage until such
ferries are rented out for the use of the state. Any colonist who wishes
to establish a ferry on the terms above indicated, shall form an exact
and certified account of the costs which he may be at for the building
of boats, and also an account of the produce of the ferry, in order that
when said ferry is rented out for the use of the state, he shall have a
right to receive the amount of .said expenses which had not already been
covered by the produce of the ferry, which for the present he will col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lect.
</p>

<p>Art. 23. He shall preside at the popular elections mentioned in the
40th article of the colonisation law for the appointment of the ayunta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />miento,
and shall put the elected in possession of their offices.</p>

<p>Art. 24. He shall take special care that the portions of land granted
to the colonists by articles 14, 15, and 16, shall be measured by the
surveyors with accuracy, and not permit any one to include more land
than is designated by law, under penalty of being personally responsible.</p>

<p>Art. 25. Should any colonist solicit, in conformity with the 17th
article of the law, an augmentation of land beyond that designated in
the preceding articles, on account of the size of the family, industry, or
capital, he shall present his petition in writing to the commissioner,
stating all the reasons on which he founds his petition, who shall trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit
it to the governor of the state, together with his opinion, for which
opinion he shall be responsible in the most rigid manner, in order that
the governor may decide on the subject.</p>

<p>Art. 26. All the public instruments, titles, or other documents is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sued
by the commissioner, shall be written in Spanish, the memorials,
decrees, and reports of the colonists or empresarios, on any subject what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever,
shall be written in the same language, whether they are to be
transmitted to the government, or preserved in the archives of the
colony.</p>

<p>Art. 27. All public instruments or titles of possession, and the copies
signed by the commissioner, shall be attested by two assistant witnesses.</p>

<p>Art. 28. The commissioner shall be personally responisble for all acts
or measures performed by him contrary to the colonisation law, or these
instructions.</p>

<p>
A copy.—
Saltillo, September 4th, 1827.
TIJERINA, ) Secretaries of the
ARCINIEGA, 5 Legislature.
A copy, JUAN ANTONIO PADILLA.
Secretary of State.</p>

</div>
</body>
</text>
