<text><front>

<pb n="59" xml:id="P0059" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/67/" /><p>CONSTITUTIVE ACTS
OF THE
MEXICAN FEDERATION
21 OF JANUARY, 1824
ALSO
FEDERAL CONSTITUTION
OF THE
UNITED MEXICAN STATES
OCTOBER 4, 1824
MEXICO.
1824</p>

<pb n="60" xml:id="P0060" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/68/" />
</front>
<body>
    <div type="document">

<pb n="61" xml:id="P0061" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/69/" />

<head>CONSTITUTIVE ACTS
<lb />OF THE
<lb />MEXICAN FEDERATION
<lb />21 OF JANUARY, 1824</head>

<p><emph rend="italic">The Supreme Executive Power</emph>, provisionally appointed by the sover<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eign
Mexican Congress, to all to whom these presents shall come, greet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing:
Know ye, that the sovereign Constituent Congress has decreed as
follows:</p>

<p>The sovereign Constituent Mexican Congress has thought proper to
enact the following <emph rend="italic">Constitutive Act of the Federation.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Form of government and Religion.</emph></p>

<p>Art. 1. The Mexican nation is composed of the provinces formerly
known as the vice-royalty of New Spain, the captain-generalship of
Yucatan, and the internal provinces of the east and west.</p>

<p>Abt. 2. The Mexican nation is for ever free and independent of Spain,
and of every other power, and it is not, nor can it ever become the patri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mony
of any family or person.</p>

<p>Art. 3. The sovereign power resides wholly and exclusively in the
nation, which has consequently the exclusive power to adopt and to es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablish
by means of its representatives, the form of government and other
fundamental laws, which may appear to it best suited to its preservation
and prosperity, and to change and to modify such laws, whenever it may
think proper.</p>

<p>Art. 4. The religion of the Mexican nation is and shall perpetually
remain the Roman Catholic and Apostolic. The nation protects it by
just and wise laws, and prohibits the exercise of every other.</p>

<p>Art. 5. The nation adopts for the form of its government, a popular
representative and federal republic.</p>

<p>Art. 6. Its integral parts are free, sovereign and independent states,
in as far as regards exclusively its internal administration, according to
the rules laid down in this act, and in the general constitution.</p>

<p>Art. 7. The states, at present comprising the federation, are the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing;
viz: Guanjuato; the internal state of the west composed of the
provinces of Sonora and Sinaloa; the internal state of the east comprising
the provinces of New Leon, Coahuila and Texas; the internal state of the
north containing the provinces of Chihuahua, Durango and New Mexico;
Mexico; Michoacan; ajaca; Puebla de los Angeles; Queretaro; San Luis

<pb n="62" xml:id="P0062" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/70/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

Potosi; New Santander, called also Tamaulipas; Tabasco; Tlascala; Vera
Cruz; Jalisco; Yucatan and Zacatecas. The Californias and the district
of Colima, (except the town of Tonila, which remains annexed to Jalisco)
will for the present be territories of the Federation and directly subject
to its supreme power. The districts and towns composing the province
of the Isthmus of Guasacualco will return to those to whom they for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />merly
belonged. The Lagune of Terminos appertains to the state of
Yucatan.</p>

<p>Abt. 8. The constitution may increase the number of states mentioned
in the preceding article, and modify them as it may deem most conducive
to the happiness of the people.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Division of Powers.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 9. The supreme power of the Federation is divided into the legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lative,
executive, and judicial, and two or more of these powers can never
be united in one person or corporation, nor can the legislative power be
entrusted to a single individual.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">The Legislative Power.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 10. The legislative power of the Federation resides in a Cham<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber
of Deputies and a senate, to be formed by the general congress.</p>

<p>Abt. 11. The members of the Chamber of Deputies, and of the Senate
shall be named by the states in the manner prescribed by the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>

<p>Abt. 12. The population shall be the basis of appointment of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
to the Chamber of Deputies. Each state shall name two sena<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors
in the manner prescribed by the constitution.</p>

<p>Abt. 13. The general congress shall have the exclusive right to enact
laws and decrees;</p>

<p>1.	To sustain the national independence, and to provide for the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />servation
and security of the nation in its external relations.</p>

<p>2.	To preserve public peace and order in the interior of the Federation
and to promote its improvement and general prosperity.</p>

<p>3.	To maintain the independence of the states among themselves.</p>

<p>4.	To protect and to regulate the liberty of the press throughout the
Federation.</p>

<p>5.	To preserve the federal union of the states, definitely to adjust their
limits, and terminate their differences.</p>

<p>6.	To sustain the relative equality of obligations and rights which the
states are entitled to according to law.</p>

<p>7.	To admit new states and territories into the federal union, by in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporating them with the nation.</p>

<p>8.	To fix annually the expenses of the nation, after examining the
statements, which for that purpose will be presented to it by the execu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive
power.</p>

<p>9.	To establish the contributions necessary to defray the general ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses
of the republic, to determine their investment, and to require an
account of their disbursement from the executive power.</p>

<p>10.	To regulate commerce with foreign nations, and among the dif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferent
states of the Federation and the Indian tribes.</p>

<pb n="63" xml:id="P0063" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/71/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

<p>11.	To incur debts on behalf of the republic, and to give securities for
their payment.</p>

<p>12.	To acknowledge the public debt of the nation, and to indicate the
means of consolidating the same.</p>

<p>13.	To declare war after considering the facts which may be presented
to its consideration by the executive power.</p>

<p>14.	To grant letters of marque, and to declare lawful or otherwise the
captures by land and sea.</p>

<p>15.	To designate and to organise the sea and land forces, fixing the
quota of each state.</p>

<p>16. To organise, arm and discipline the militia of the states, reserving
to each the appointment of its respective officers, and the faculty of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structing
them in conformity with the discipline prescribed by the gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral
congress.</p>

<p>17.	To approve all treaties of peace, alliance, amity, federation, armed
neutrality, and every other which may have been entered into by the
executive power.</p>

<p>18.	To regulate and make uniform the weight, value, form, fineness
and denomination of the money in all the states of the Federation, and
to adopt a general system of weights and measures.</p>

<p>19.	To grant, or to refuse the entry of foreign troops into the terri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tory
of the Federation.</p>

<p>20.	To authorise the formation of ports and harbors.</p>

<p>Art. 14. The constitution shall fix the other general, special and econ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />omical
attributes of the congress of the Federation, the mode of exer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cising
them, as well as the prerogatives of this body and its members.
Executive Power.</p>

<p>Art. 15. The supreme executive power will be confided to such indi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vidual,
or individuals as the constitution may designate, who must be
residents and native born citizens of some one of the states or territories
of the Federation.</p>

<p>Art. 16. The attributes of the executive power, in addition to others
which may be fixed by the constitution, shall be the following:</p>

<p>1.	To carry into execution the laws intended to consolidate the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tegrity
of the Federation, and to sustain its exterior independence, and
its internal union and liberty.</p>

<p>2.	To appoint and to remove at pleasure the Secretaries of State, &amp;c.</p>

<p>3.	To watch over the collection and to decree the distribution of the
general contributions, according to existing laws.</p>

<p>4.	To appoint the officers of the general treasury according to the
constitution and existing laws.</p>

<p>5.	To declare war, having first obtained a decree sanctioning the same
from the general congress if in session, and if that be not the case, ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording
to the mode pointed out in the constitution.</p>

<p>6.	To dispose of the permanent army and navy and of the active mili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tia
for the external defence, and the internal security of the Federation.</p>

<p>7.	To dispose of the local militia for the same objects, even though it
should be necessary to employ the same beyond the limits of its respect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ive
states, after previously obtaining the consent of the general congress,
which shall designate the force necessary.</p>


<pb n="64" xml:id="P0064" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/72/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

<p>8.	To appoint the officers of the army, of the active and the armed
militia with reference to existing laws and ordinances, and the disposi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
of the constitution.</p>

<p>9.	To grant discharges and licenses, and to regulate the pay of the
military officers mentioned in the preceding articles in conformity to law.</p>

<p>10.	To appoint the diplomatic agents and consuls, with the approba<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of the senate, and until that body shall have been organised, with
the approbation of the actual congress.</p>

<p>11.	To direct diplomatic negotiations, make treaties of peace, friend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ship,
alliance, federation, truce, armed neutrality, commerce and others;
but in order to grant or refuse the ratification of any such treaty, it must
obtain the previous approbation of the general congress.</p>

<p>12.	To watch over the prompt and complete administration of justice
by the general tribunals, and that their sentences be executed according
to law.</p>

<p>13.	To cause to be published, circulated and observed, the laws and
the general constitution; possessing the right of opposing once the pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age
of a law, provided it be done within ten days, and to suspend its exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cution
until the resolves of congress be known.</p>

<p>14.	To issue decrees and orders for the better carrying into effect the
constitution and the general laws.</p>

<p>15.	To suspend from their employments for the space of three months
or less, and to deprive of a portion of their salaries not to exceed one
half, for the same period of time, all the officers of the Federation, in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fringing
such orders or decrees, and in cases where it shall be deemed
necessary, have them tried, in which event all the proceedings must be
transferred to the competent tribunal.</p>

<p>Abt. 17. All the decrees and orders of the supreme executive power
ought to be signed by the secretary of that department to which they be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />long,
and without this formality they are not to be obeyed.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Judicial Power.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 18. Every person inhabiting the territory of the Federation, has
the right to require the prompt, complete, .and impartial administration
of justice: and with this object the Federation confides the administra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of justice to a supreme court of justice, and to such tribunals as
may be established in the separate states, reserving to itself the right to
determine in the constitution the powers of the supreme court.</p>

<p>Abt. 19. No person can be judged in the states and territories of the
Union, except by laws in force, and by tribunals established prior to the
act for which he is tried. Consequently all judgments by special com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missions
and all retroactive laws are forever prohibited.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Individual Government of the States.</emph></p>

<p>ART. 20. The government of each state shall he divided as to the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ercise
of its powers into a legislative, executive and judicial department;
and two or more of these powers can never he entrusted to the same per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son
or corporation, nor can the legislative power he confided to a single
individual.</p>

<p>Abt. 21. The legislative power of each state shall he entrusted to a

<pb n="65" xml:id="P0065" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/73/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

congress composed of such a number of individuals as may be determined
by the constitution of each particular state, elected by the people, and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />movable
at such time and in such manner as they may determine.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Executive Power.</emph></p>

<p>Art. 22. The exercise of the executive power of each state shall only
be exercised for a determinate period to be fixed by the respective consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tutions
of each state.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Judicial Power.</emph></p>

<p>Art. 23. The judicial power of each state shall be exercised by such
tribunes as may be established by its constitution.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">General Provisions.</emph></p>

<p>Art. 24. The constitutions of the different states cannot be in oppo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sition
to the act, nor to the provisions of the general constitution, and
on this account they cannot be sanctioned until'the publication of the
latter.</p>

<p>Art. 25. Nevertheless the legislature of the different states may pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visionally
organise an internal government, and in the mean time they
must see that the laws actually in force be observed.</p>

<p>Art. 26. The criminal of one state shall not receive asylum in an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />other;
but on the contrary must be immediately delivered over to the
authorities requiring his delivery.</p>

<p>Art. 27. No state shall impose, without the consent of the general
congress, any tonnage duty, nor maintain troops or vessels of war in
time of peace.</p>

<p>Art. 28. No state shall, without the consent of the general congress,
impose any tax or duty upon importations and exportations, during the
period that this subject is not properly regulated by law.</p>

<p>Art. 29. No state shall enter into any transactions or contracts with
another state, nor with any foreign power, nor engage in war, except in
the event of actual invasion, or of such imminent danger that it does not
admit of delay.</p>

<p>Art. 30. It is the duty of the nation to protect by wise and just laws
the rights of man and of the citizens.</p>

<p>Art. 31. Every inhabitant of the Union has the liberty of writing,
printing, and publishing his political ideas, without any necessity for
previous license, revision or approbation, under the restrictions and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sponsibilities imposed by law. </p>

<p>Art. 32. The congress of each state must transmit annually to the
general congress of the Union a circumstantial and correct account of
the receipts and expenses of all the treasuries, which may exist in their
respective districts, with an account of the causes of both, and of the dif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferent
branches of industry, agriculture, commerce, and manufactures,
indicating their progress, or decline together with the causes to which it
can be attributed; the new modes of industry, which may be introduced
and the means of fostering them; also their respective population.
Art. 33. All the debts, contracted before the adoption of this act,

<pb n="66" xml:id="P0066" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/74/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

shall be acknowledged by the Federation; reserving to the general con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress
the right of establishing the rules, which must govern its liquida<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
and classification.</p>

<p>Art. 34. The general constitution and this act guarantee to the states
of the Union the form of government adopted by this law, and each state
assumes likewise the obligation of sustaining the Federal Union at every
sacrifice.</p>

<p>Art. 35. This act can only be changed within the time and in the
manner expressed in the general constitution.</p>

<p>Art. 36. The execution of this act is confided to the executive power,
which is strictly responsible to carry the same into effect, and from the
time of its publication it shall be observed in every respect.</p>

<p>Mexico the 31st of January, 1824.</p>

<p>Here follow the signatures of the deputies.</p>

<p>In consequence we command that all tribunals, justices, chiefs, and
other authorities, civil, military, and ecclesiastical, of whatever class or
dignity, observe, and cause to be observed, accomplish and execute the
present decree in all its parts, and cause it to be understood, that it may
be carried into effect, and see that it be printed, published, and circulated.</p>

<p>Given in Mexico the 31st of January, 1824.</p>

<p>Jose Mariano Michilena, President; Miguel Domingo, Vincente Guer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rero.</p>

<p>To the minister of foreign and internal affairs.</p>
<p>By order of their highness this is made known to you that you may
understand it, and see that it he executed.</p>
<p>God and Liberty, Mexico, the 31st of January, 1824.
<lb />JUAN GUZMAN.</p>

<p>THE FEDERAL CONSTITUTION OF THE UNITED MEXICAN
STATES, SANCTIONED BY THE GENERAL CONSTITUENT
CONGRESS ON THE 4TH OF OCTOBER, 1824.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">The General Constituent Congress to the Inhabitants of the
Federation.</emph></p>

<p>Mexicans:—The General Constituent Congress in putting into your
hands the most arduous work which you could have entrusted to its care,
the fundamental Code, which fixes the fate of the nation, and serves as
an indestructible basis of the great edifice of your society, has thought
it their duty to address you, in order to explain briefly the objects they
had in view from the first moments of their union; the labors it has un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dertaken,
and what it expects from your docility and submission when
you begin to enjoy the gifts consequent on the federal system decreed
and sanctioned by the majority of your deputies.</p>

<p>Congress will not employ itself in describing the series of events which
have occurred in a revolution, which has lasted fourteen years, nor the
great sacrifices which became necessary before the nation were able to
secure the inestimable blessing of national independence. This is a task
which the history of the present times will one day accomplish. At

<pb n="67" xml:id="P0067" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/75/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

present it is only necessary to remark, that the constant assaults of pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />triotism
having broken the chain which united us to Spain, there could
remain no other centre of union, no other connecting link between the
different provinces of this great nation, but the leader who had induced
all the towns to pronounce their independence. An impartial world will
judge of the events which induced him to place himself at the head of a
second revolution, and of his tragical end; but the fact is certain, that the
State was dissolved by the fall of this unfortunate man, and that noth<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
could restrain the revolution of the provinces; none possessed supe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />riority
over the other; and the ship of state would have been wrecked
by the pitiless storm, if the wisdom and prudence, with which the people
hastened to convoke the former Congress, had not given the nation a
new existence. Congress could not fail to attend to the wishes of a na<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
which had just given so striking a proof of its intelligence, and the
deputies could not vote against the wishes of their constituents. Never
have the legislators of any nation had a clearer manifestation of public
opinion to direct their deliberations, and never will the representatives of
any people find themselves in a more favorable situation of knowing the
desires of those from whom they received their mandate; and your depu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties
will retire to the bosom of their families, with the pleasing satisfac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of having labored in the spirit, and agreeably to the necessities of
their constituents.</p>

<p>To create a firm and free government, without its being dangerous to
the people; to place the Mexican nation in the rank which it ought to
hold among civilised nations, and enable it to exercise the influence to
which it is entitled by its situation, its population, and its wealth; to
make all equal before the law; to create peace without disorder; peace
without oppression; justice without rigor; clemency without weakness;
to mark the limits of the supreme auhorities of the nation; to combine
them in such a manner that their union shall always be productive of
good, and render evil impossible; to regulate the march of the legislature,
sheltering it at the same time from precipitation and error; to arm the
executive power with sufficient power and dignity to make it respected in
the interior, and deserving every consideration from foreigners; to secure
to the judiciary such an independence, that it will never create fears in
the breast of the innocent, and still less afford the hope of impunity to
the guilty; all this is in effect difficult, and here you perceive, Mexicans,
the sublime objects to which your General Congress has aspired in the
Constitution, which it presents to you. It has, however, not the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sumption
to think, that it has completely satisfied all your expectations;
but it flatters itself, that you will view with indulgence the numerous
errors which the weakness of its abilities may have stamped upon it, in
consideration of the zeal of the virtuous, of wise patriots engaged in
framing it, in the very short space of eleven months allowed them.</p>

<p>Your representatives, in meeting in the hall of their sessions, take with
them the wishes of the people, expressed with unanimity and energy.
The voice of the Federal Republic has made itself heard from every cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner
of the republic; and the public desire for this form of government
has explained itself so generally, and with as much force as it explained
itself in favor of independence. Your deputies therefore entertained no
doubt on this subject, as to the desires of the nation. Nevertheless cir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cumspection, which ought to guide all legislators, required that they
<pb n="68" xml:id="P0068" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/76/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

should enter upon the examination, not only of the form of government,
but likewise of the general existence of a desire to create one. You
know, Mexicans, the discussions which have taken place
on this subject, as well as their results. Your representatives cannot accuse themselves
of having hurried on the march of events, nor of having given an im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pulse
to the revolution. On the contrary, the nation being dissolved and
disorganised, as well as exposed to be the sport of passions and parties,
the General Congress, smoothing the difficulties, and sacrificing even
their own reputation, lends its aid to arrest the genius of discord' and
disorder, restores peace and tranquillity, and pursues calmly its delibera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions.</p>

<p>The division of the States, the installation of its respective legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tures,
and the construction of a multitude of establishments, which have
arisen in the short period of eleven months, furnish evidence that Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress
has fulfilled in a great degree the hopes of the people, without pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tending
on this account to attribute to itself all the glory of such pros<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perous
principles, and still less the original invention of the institutions
which it has dictated. It had, fortunately, to do with a people obedient
to the voice of duty, and a model to imitate in the flourishing republic
of our neighbors to the North. It knew, fortunately, that the Mexican
nation only intended to shake off passive obedience, and to enter on the
discussion of their duties, interests, and obligations. It was fortunately
penetrated with the desires and necessities of its constituents, and en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />deavored
to fix their destinies, by giving to the public spirit a direction,
conformable to an opinion formed by circumstances truly extraordinary,
which had involved in a most disastrous revolution another people be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />yond
the limits of Mexico.</p>

<p>The Federal Republic has been, and was the necessary fruit of these
discussions. The systematic tyranny of the Spanish mandarins could
alone induce them to govern so immense a territory by the same laws,
considering the enormous differences of its climates, dispositions of its
inhabitants, and their consequent influence. What relations of con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />venience
or uniformity could possibly exist between the burning soil of
Vera Cruz and the frozen mountains of New Mexico? How could the
same institutions govern the inhabitants of California and Sonora and
those of Yucatan and Tamaulipas? The innocence and candor of the
interior populations, have no occasion for laws relative to crimes and in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trigues
which are entirely unknown to them. The inhabitants of Ta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />maulipas
and Coahuilas will reduce their code to a hundred articles,
while the inhabitants of Mexico and Jalisco will be on a level with the
great nations which have advanced in the career of social order. These
are the advantages of the federal system: It gives each people the
right of selecting for itself laws, analogous to its customs, locality, and
other circumstances; to dedicate itself without impediment to the crea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
and improvement of those branches of industry which it may deem
best calculated to promote its prosperity; to give to its labors all the im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pulse
of which they are susceptible, without the difficulties created by
the colonial system, or any other which, being at enormous distances,
would lose sight of the interests of those it governed; to provide for its
necessities in proportion to its progress; to place at the head of its ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ministration,
individuals attached to the country, and possessing at the
same time sufficient knowledge to discharge their duties efficiently; to

<pb n="69" xml:id="P0069" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/77/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

create the tribunals necessary for the prompt punishment of offences,
the protection of property, and the security of its inhabitants; to ter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />minate
its domestic affairs without going beyond the limits of the state;
in one word, to enjoy the rights of freemen.</p>

<p>The general congress was penetrated with the difficulties which the
nation must conquer, in order to plant a system which, to say the truth,
is complicated. It knows that it is an arduous undertaking, to obtain
from intelligence and patriotism that, which can only be the effect of
time and experience. But besides the consideration, that the soil of
America is not contaminated with the vices of old Europe, we have be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore
us the examples of modern nations, which have formed themselves,
and enriched us with their knowledge. We have profited by the lessons
which the world has received, since the happy invention of social science
has loosened the cements of tyranny; and we ourselves have passed over,
in the space of fourteen years the long period of three centuries. With
such joyful presages, what ought not the Mexican nation to expect from
its general congress?</p>

<p>Ancient legislators, in promulgating their laws, accompanied them
with august preparations and ceremonies, calculated to produce that
respect and veneration, which ought always to be their safeguard. An
age of light and philosophy has dispersed these auxiliary prestiges of
truth and justice; and these laws are now presented to the people, in
order to undergo examination and discussion. A our representatives,
employing this plain and natural language, place this day in your hands
the code of your fundamental laws, the result of their deliberations, ce<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mented
in the soundest principles which hitherto have been acknowl<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />edged
as the basis of social happiness in civilised countries. It was, for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tunately,
not required to compromise with those colosses, who in their
fall disfigured the revolutions of other countries. If in our annals, we
meet with an ambitious son of the country, his history will teach, by its
example to our descendants, the danger which attends the attempt of
appropriating exclusively to yourself advantages reserved to the entire
body of society.</p>

<p>Your representatives therefore hope, from the heroic patriotism and
pure virtues of the Mexicans, that, next to their national independence,
they will sustain, at every sacrifice, the republican government to the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clusion
of royalty in every shape. An implied and eternally obligatory
contract unites all the nations of independent America, not to admit into
its bosom any other form of government, the tendency of which to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pagate
itself is irresistible and dangerous. The institutions of the new
world present a new and unknown order; like itself in the history of the
great events 'which change the ordinary march of things; and as the fall
of the Caesars confirmed in Europe the monarchical government, after
the bloody and dangerous political revolutions which had preceded it,
so, on the continent of Columbus, the democratical must necessarily
finally prevail, after being revived with improvements on the ancient
republics, owing to the vivifying inspirations of modern genius.</p>

<p>The time elapsed since the beginning of our revolution, has been use<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fully
employed in collecting suitable arms, to drive back to the shades,
whence they proceeded, all gothic governments, and to look for the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitutive
bases of human associations in the immortal works of those
sublime genii, who knew how to discover the lost rights of mankind.

<pb n="70" xml:id="P0070" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/78/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

The moment has arrived to apply these principles, and to open the eyes
of the Mexicans to the torrent of light which they send forth. They have
declared, that neither force, prejudices, nor superstition shall be the reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ulators
of their government. They have declared, with a philosophical
writer, that, after having verified with Newton the secrets of nature, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fined
with Rousseau and Montesquieu the principles of society, and fixed
their basis, extended with Columbus the superficies of the known globe,
arrested with Franklin the lightning of the clouds, and given it direction,
and given, with other creating geniuses, an indestructible life and un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />limited
extension to the productions of man. Finally, that after having
united by a thousand ties, of commerce and social relations, they can no
longer tolerate any other government than that which is analogous to
such an order, created by so great and so precious acquisitions. The
elevation of character which the American people has acquired, does not
permit them again to bend their knees before despotism and prejudice,
always fatal to the welfare of nations.</p>

<p>But in the midst of this progress of civilisation, our country requires
of us great sacrifices and a religious respect for morality. Your repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
inform you, that if you wish to place yourself on a level with
the'happy republic of our neighbors to the North, it is necessary, that
you should elevate yourself to the lofty height of civic and moral vir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tues,
which characterise that singular people. This is the sole basis of
true liberty, and the best guarantee of your rights, and the permanency
of your Constitution. The faithful observance of promises, the love of
labor, the education of youth, respect for .your fellow men, these, Mexi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cans,
are the sources whence. your own happiness and that of your de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scendants
must emanate. Without these virtues, without due obedience
to law and authority, without a profound respect for our admirable re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ligion,
we will in vain possess a code of liberal maxims; in vain boast
of good laws, and in vain proclaim a sacred liberty.</p>

<p>The General Congress also expects from the patriotism and activity
of the authorities and corporations of the Federation, as well as from
the individuals of the States, that they will use their best endeavors to
establish and to consolidate our new-born institutions. But if instead
of confining themselves to the sphere of their attributes, they endeavour
to go beyond it; if instead of setting an example, by a just observance
of the constitution and general laws, they endeavor to elude their ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />complishment
by interpretations and subterfuges, the offspring of our
scolastic education; in such an event we already renounce the right of
being free, and succumb easily to the caprice of a tyrant national or
foreign, who will introduce among us the peace of the sepulchre and ths
calm of a prison.</p>

<p>To you, therefore, legislators of the states, it belongs to develop the
system of our fundamental law, the corner stone of which is the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ercise
of public and private virtue. The wisdom of your laws will shine
forth in their justice and utility; and their accomplishment will be the
result of a severe vigilance on the manners. Inculcate, therefore, on
your constituents the eternal rules of morality and public order; teach
them religion without fanaticism, the love of liberty without exalta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion;
the most inviolable respect for the rights of others, which is the
foundation of human associations. Marats and Robespierres have ele<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vated
themselves among their fellow citizens by proclaiming these prin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciples,

<pb n="71" xml:id="P0071" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/79/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

and these monsters have stained with tears and blood, the most
illustrious nation on the earth, while they, imbued with crimes, rose by
degrees to dignities whence they insulted the credulity of their fellow
citizens. Washington proclaimed the same maxims, and this immortal
man made the happiness of the States of the North. How are we to
distinguish the first from the second; but by examining their manners,
observing their progress, and remembering that without justice there
can be no liberty, and that the bases of justice are founded on a just
equilibrium between the rights of others and our own. This is the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sult
of the problem of moral science.</p>

<p>Sheltered by this aegis, Mexicans, you have nothing to fear from
your enemies. It is of no importance that our obstinate oppressors,
dare even yet in speaking of us to employ the degrading word of colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nists,
while the Mexican name is already inscribed among cultivated
nations, among those of other sovereign powers. It is of no importance
that proud Spain, at present impotent, and an object of compassion to
the rest of Europe, makes her feeble voice heard in the cabinets of for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eign
monarchs; all her pretensions will vanish before the consolidation
of our institutions, and the strength the of arms of the sons of the
country consecrated to the defence of their native land.</p>

<p>Let us, therefore, show the world, that only tyranny and the influence
of despotic governments could retain us in the sad degradation in which
we were confined for so many years, and that at the moment of shaking
off this dominion, nothing can prevent us from returning to the great
family of mankind, from which we appeared to be severed. Europe and
the rest of America have their eyes fixed upon us, and our national
honor is strongly engaged in our future conduct.</p>

<p>If we deviate from the path of the Constitution, if we do not re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gard
it as one of our most sacred duties, to maintain order, and scru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pulously
to observe the laws contained in our new code; if we do not
unite to save this deposit, and to shelter ourselves from the attacks of
the malevolent; Mexicans, we will be disgraced for the future, without
having been formerly happy, and we shall bequeath to our children,
misery, war and slavery, while to ourselves there will remain no other
resource than to choose between the sword of Cato, and the unfortunate
fates of a Hidalgo, a Mina or a Morelos.</p>

<p>Mexico, the 4th of October, 1824.</p>

<p>Lorenzo de Zavala, President; Manuel de Viya y Cosio Deputy Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary;
Epigmenio de la Piedra, Deputy Secretary.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Department of the first Secretary of State.</emph>—Section of the Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment—The
Supreme Executive Power has thought proper to direct to
me the following decree:</p>

<p>The supreme executive power, appointed provisionally by the sov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ereign,
general and constitutive congress of the United Mexican States,
to all to whom these -presents may come, greeting; be it known, that
the same sovereign congress has been pleased to decree as follows:</p>

<p>The sovereign, general and constitutive congress of the United Mexi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />can
States has thought proper to decree:</p>

<p>That the government shall proceed solemnly to publish without loss
of time, the constitution in this capital, and shall immediately com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />municate
the same to the governors of the states and political author!<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties

<pb n="72" xml:id="P0072" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/80/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

in order to enable them to do the same in all the towns within their
limits.</p>

<p>The supreme executive power shall regard it as understood, and take
the necessary measures to carry it into effect, causing it to be printed
published and circulated.</p>

<p>Lorenza de Zavala, President; Manuel de Viya y Cosio, Deputy Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary;
Epigmenio de la Piedra, Deputy Secretary.</p>

<p>In consequence we enjoin on all tribunals, justices, commanders, gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernors
and other authorities as well civil as military and ecclesiasti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cal,
of whatever class and dignity, that they observe and cause to be
observed, accomplished and executed the present decree in all its parts.
You will therefore hold it understood for its execution and take suit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able
dispositions to have it printed, published and circulated.</p>

<p>In the National Palace of Mexico, 4th October, 1824.</p>

<p>Guadalupe Victoria, President; Nicholas Bravo Miguel Dominguez,
A. D. Juan Guzman.</p>

<p>Which is made known to you for your information and its accom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plisment.—May
God preserve you many years.</p>

<p>Mexico, 4th October, 1824.
<lb />JUAN GUZMAN.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">The Supreme Executive Power</emph> appointed provisionally by the sover<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eign
congress of the nation, to all to whom these presents shall come,
greeting; Know ye that the said sovereign congress has decreed and
sanctioned the following</p>

<head>FEDERAL CONSTITUTION OF THE UNITED MEXICAN
STATES.</head>

<p>In the name of Almighty God, supreme author and legislator of so<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciety.
The general constituent congress of the Mexican nation in dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />charge
of the duties imposed upon it by its constituents in order to fix
their political independence, to establish and consolidate their liberty
and to promote their prosperity and glory decree as follows:</p>


<head>CONSTITUTION OF THE UNITED MEXICAN STATES.</head>

<head>TITLE 1.</head>

<p><emph rend="italic">Only Section.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Mexican Nation, its Territory and Religion.</emph></p>

<p>Art. 1. The Mexican nation is for ever free and independent of the
Spanish government and of every other power.</p>

<p>Art. 2. Its territory comprehends the former vice-royalty of New
Spain, the captain-generalship of Yucatan, the former commandancies
of the internal provinces of the east and west and Upper and Lower

<pb n="73" xml:id="P0073" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/81/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

California with the lands annexed and the adjacent islands in both
oceans. A'constitutional law will be made for designating the bound<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />aries
of the Federation as soon as circumstances will permit.</p>

<p>Abt. 3. The religion of the Mexican nation shall perpetually remain
the Roman Catholic and Apostolic. The nation protects it by wise and
just laws and prohibits the exercise of every other.</p>

<head>TITLE II.</head>

<p><emph rend="italic">Only Section.</emph></p>
<p><emph rend="italic">Of the form of Government of the Nation, of its integral parts, and
of the division of the Supreme Power.</emph></p>

<p>ART. 4. The Mexican nation adopts for the form of its government
a popular representative and federal republic.</p>

<p>Abt. 5. The constituent parts of the Federation are the following
States and Territories, viz: the States of Chiapas, Chihuahua, Coahuila
and Texas, Durango, Guanajuato, Mexico, Michoacan, Nuevo Leon,
Oajaca, Pueblo de los Angeles, Queretaro, San Luis Potosi, Sonora and
Sinaloa, Tabasco, Tamaulipas, Vera Cruz, Jalisco, Yucatan, and Zaca<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tecas;
the Territories of Upper California, Lower California, Colima,
and Santa Fe de Nuevo Mexico. A constitutional law will fix the char<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />acter
of Tlascala.</p>

<p>Abt. 6. The Supreme power of the Federation as to its exercise, is
divided into the legislative, executive and judicial powers.</p>

<head>TITLE III.</head>

<p>OF THE LEGISLATIVE POWER.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section First.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Of its Nature, the Mode of exercising it.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 7. The legislative power of the nation is confided to a General
Congress, which is divided into two chambers, one for the Deputies,
and the other for the Senators.</p>

<p><emph rend="itlaic">Section Second.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Chamber of Deputies.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 8. The Chamber of Deputies shall be composed of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives,
the whole of which shall be elected every two years by the citizens
of the States.</p>

<p>Abt. 9. The qualifications of the electors shall be constitutionally
prescribed by the legislatures of the states, to which it also belongs to
regulate the elections conformably to the principles established by this
constitution.</p>

<pb n="74" xml:id="P0074" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/82/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

<p>Art. 10. The general basis for the appointment of deputies shall
be the population.</p>

<p>Art. 11. A deputy shall be elected for every eighty-thousand inhabi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tants
and for every fraction exceeding forty thousand. Any state, which
may not have so large.a population is nevertheless entitled to one dep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uty.</p>

<p>Art. 12. A census of the whole confederation shall be taken with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in
five years, and shall be renewed afterwards every ten years, which
shall serve to designate the number of deputies to which each state
is entitled. In the meantime the elections are to be regulated on the
basis established in the preceding article, and the census which served
to regulate the election of deputies in the congress now in session.</p>

<p>Art. 13. There shall also be elected in every state deputies subsi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tutes
in proportion of one for every three deputies or one for every frac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of two. States having less than three deputies will elect one sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute.</p>

<p>Art. 14. Every territory containing more than fifty thousand inhab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />itants,
shall name one deputy and one substitute, who shall have voice
and vote in the formation of all laws and decrees.</p>

<p>Art. 15. A territory not possessing the aforesaid population, shall
name a deputy and a substitute, who shall have the right to speak on'
all subjects. The elections of the deputies from the different territories
shall be regulated by a special law.</p>

<p>Abt. 16. In all the states and territories of the Federation, the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointment
of the deputies shall take place the first Sunday in the month
of October next preceding the renovation, which is an indirect election.</p>

<p>Art. 17. As soon as the election of deputies is concluded, the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />toral
boards shall, through their president, forward to the council of
the government evidence, in due form, of the act of election, and duly
certified, and they shall notify to the persons appointed their election,
which shall serve as their credentials.</p>

<p>Art. 18. The president of the council of the government shall give
to this evidence, spoken of in the preceding article, that direction which
is prescribed by the regulations of said council.</p>

<p>Art. 19. In order to be appointed deputy it is necessary:
1st. To have, at the time of election, full twenty-five years.
2d. To have resided in the state from which elected full two years,
or to be born in it, though residing in a different state.</p>

<p>Art. 20. Those not born in the territory of the Mexican nation, must,
in order to be elected deputies, have resided at least eight years within
the same, and possess real estate in some part of the republic worth eight
thousand dollars, or some species of industry making them an income
of one thousand dollars annually.</p>

<p>Art. 21. Are excepted from the operation of the preceding article:</p>

<p>1st. All those born in any part of America, which, in 1810, depended
on Spain, and which has not united with any other nation, and which no
longer remains dependent on Spain, for whom , three years residence
will suffice, provided they have the other requisites prescribed by the
19th article.</p>

<p>2d. All military men not born in the territory of the Republic, but
who have supported with arms the independence of the country, for

<pb n="75" xml:id="P0075" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/83/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

whom it shall be sufficient to have resided eight years in the country,
and to possess the qualifications required by article 19.</p>

<p>Art. 22. The election of deputies on account of residence shall be
preferred to that made on account of birth.</p>

<p>Art. 23. The following cannot be deputies, viz:</p>

<p>1st. Those deprived of, or suspended from, the rights of citizens.</p>

<p>2d. The president and vice president of the Union.</p>

<p>3d. The members of the supreme court of justice.</p>

<p>4th. The secretaries of the different departments, their officers and
secretaries.</p>

<p>5th. The officers of the treasury, whose employments extend through<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out
the Union.</p>

<p>6th. The governors of the states and territories, the commandant
generals, the right reverend archbishops and bishops, the governors of
the archbishops and bishops, the provisor and vicar generals, the circuit
judges, and the commissary generals of war and finance for the states
and territories in which they exercise their functions.</p>

<p>Art. 24. In order that the persons comprehended in the preceding ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticle
may be elected deputies, it is necessary that their functions should
have entirely ceased six months previous to the elections.</p>

<p><emph rend="itlaic">Section Third.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Chamber of the Senators.</emph></p>

<p>ART. 25. The senate shall he composed of two senators from each
state, elected by an absolute majority of the legislature of each state,
one half of their number to be renewed every two years.</p>

<p>Art. 26. The senators elected in the second place shall cease to hold
their places at the end of the two first years, and afterwards the most
ancient.</p>

<p>Atr. 27. When there occurs a vacancy in the senate on account of
death, resignation, or other cause, such vacancy shall he filled by the
legislature of the respective state, if such legislature be in session, and
if not, as soon as it may be in session.</p>

<p>Art. 28. In order to be senator the same qualities are required, which
are prescribed in the preceding section for deputy, and moreover to be
thirty years at the time of the election.</p>

<p>Art. 29. Those who cannot be deputies cannot be senators.</p>

<p>Art. 30. Article 22 shall likewise govern the election of senators.</p>

<p>Art. 31. When the same individual is elected senator and deputy,
he shall prefer the election prior in point of time.</p>

<p>Art. 32. The periodical election of senators shall take place in all
the states on the same day, which shall be the 1st of September next, to
the renewal of one-half of the senate.</p>

<p>Art. 33. When the election of the senators, the different legislatures
shall forward a certificate of the same, through their presidents to the
council of the government, in the usual form of acts of election, and
make known to the persons elected their appointment by another in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strument
which shall serve as a credential of their election. The presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent
of the council of the government shall dispose of these certificates
of election in the manner prescribed in the 18th article.</p>

<pb n="76" xml:id="P0076" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/84/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

<p><emph rend="itlaic">Section Fourth.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="itlaic">Of the Economical Functions of the two Chambers and of the Pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rogatives
of their Members.</emph></p>

<p>Art. 34. Each chamber in its preparatory boards, and in all which
has reference to its interior government, will observe the regulations
which shall be formed by the present congress, without prejudice to
such reforms, which may in future be introduced, if both chambers shall
deem it proper.</p>

<p>Art. 35. Each chamber is judge of the elections of its respective
members, and shall resolve all doubts which may arise relative to the
same.</p>

<p>Art. 36. The chambers cannot open their sessions without the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />currence
of more than the half of all the members- elected; but the
members present of both chambers ought to unite on the day indicated
by the regulation for the interior government of both, and compel re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spectively
their absent members to attend under the penalties prescribed
by law.</p>

<p>Art. 37. The chambers shall communicate with each other and with
the executive power by means of their secretaries, or by means of depu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tations.</p>

<p>Art. 38. Each of the chambers in their capacity of grand jurors can
take cognisance of the following offences, viz:</p>

<p>1.	Of the President of the Union, for the crimes of treason against the
national independence, or the established form of government, and for
bribery and corruption committed during the period of his employment.</p>

<p>2.	Of the same president; for acts manifestly intended to hinder the
elections of presidents, senators and deputies, or to prevent them from
serving in their respective employments during the periods pointed out
by the constitution, or for preventing the chambers from exercising any
of the powers conferred on them by the constitution.</p>

<p>3.	Of the members of the supreme court of justice, and the secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taries
of the departments; for any offences committed during the time
of their holding their employments.</p>

<p>4.	Of the governors of the states; for infractions of the constitution,
the laws of the Union, or the orders of the President of the Federation,
which are not obviously contrary to the constitution and the general
laws of the Union, and also for the publication of the laws or decrees
of the legislatures of their respective states contrary to the same con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution
and laws.
</p>

<p>Art. 39. The Chamber of Representatives shall be exclusive grand
jurors, when the President and his ministers shall be accused of acts
in which the senate and the council of the government have inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vened
by virtue of their attributes. The same chamber shall also serve
as grand jurors in all cases where the vice president shall be accused
of any offence committed during the time of holding his office.</p>

<p>Art. 40. The Chamber before which may have been made the accu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sations
spoken of inthe preceding articles, shall form itself into a grand
jury, and shall declare by the vote. of two-thirds of its members present,
if there be sufficient cause for having the accused tried, in which event

<pb n="77" xml:id="P0077" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/85/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

he shall be suspended from office, and the cause sent to the competent
tribunal.</p>

<p>Art. 41. Every deputy and senator has the right of presenting in
writing propositions and projects of laws or decrees in his respective
Chamber.</p>

<p>Art. 42. The deputies and senators are not responsible for any
opinions which they may express in the discharge of their employ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments,
and they can never be called to account for the same</p>

<p>Art. 43. In criminal prosecutions brought against the senators or
deputies from the day of their election, until two months after they
shall have discharged their functions, the former cannot be accused
except before the Chamber of Deputies, and the latter, except before
the Senate, and in the event of similar accusations the Chamber shall
form itself into a- grand jury, for the purpose of determining if there
be any foundation for such accusation.</p>

<p>Art. 44. If the? Chamber, constituting the grand jury in the cases
mentioned in the preceding article, should declare by the vote of two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds
of the members present, that the accusation is well founded;
the accused remains suspended from his employment, and placed at
the disposal of the competent tribunal.</p>

<p>Art. 45. The compensation of the deputies and senators’shall be
determined by law, and be paid by the General Treasury of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federation.</p>

<p>Art. 46. Each Chamber as well as the boards spoken of in the 36
art., may issue such orders as it deems convenient, in order to carry into
effect any resolutions adopted by virtue of the function, delegated to
each by virtue of the 35, 36, 39, 40, 44 and 45th art., of the Constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
and the President of the United States ought to cause them to be
executed, without possessing the right of making any observations on
their tenor.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Fifth.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Powers of the General Congress.</emph></p>

<p>Art. 47. No resolution of the General Congress shall assume any
other form than that of a law or a decree.</p>

<p>Art. 48. The resolutions of the General Congress, in order to have
the force of a law or decree ought to be signed by the President, except
in those cases excepted by the Constitution.</p>

<p>Art. 49. The laws or decrees, which emanate from the General
Congress, shall have for their object:</p>

<p>1.	To sustain the national independence, and to provide for the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />servation
and security of the nation in its exterior relations.</p>

<p>2.	To preserve the Federal Union of the States, and peace and public
order in the interior of the Confederation.</p>

<p>3.	To maintain the independence of the States among themselves,
so far as respects their government according to the Constitutive act and
this Constitution.</p>

<p>4.	To sustain the proportional equality of obligations and rights
which the states possess in point of law.</p>

<pb n="78" xml:id="P0078" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/86/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

<p>Abt. 50. The exclusive powers possessed by the General Congress are
the following, viz:</p>

<p>1.	To promote instruction by securing for a limited time to authors
the exclusive privilege to their works; by establishing colleges for the
Marine, Artillery and Engineer Departments; by erecting one or more
establishments, for the teaching of the natural and exect sciences, the
political and moral sciences, the useful arts and languages; without pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />judice
to the rights which the states possess, to regulate the public edu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation
in their respective states.</p>

<p>2.	To promote the general prosperity, by decreeing the opening of
roads, canals, and their improvement without hindering the states from
opening and improving their own; establishing post offices and post
roads, and securing for a limited time to inventors, or those who have
perfected, or introduced any new invention, the exclusive privilege for
their respective invention, improvements or new introductions.</p>

<p>3.	To protect and regulate the political liberty of the press in such a
manner that its exercise can never be suspended, and much less be abol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ished
in any of the states or territories of the confederation.</p>

<p>4.	To admit new states and territories into the federal union, and to
incorporate the same with the nation.</p>

<p>5.	To’regulate definitively the boundaries of the states, and terminate
the differences, when they cannot agree among themselves about the
lines of demarcation of their respective, districts.</p>

<p>6.	To erect territories into states and regulate them in conformity
with those already existing.</p>

<p>7.	To unite two or more states, upon their petition to that effect, into
one, or to erect new7 states within the limits of those already in existence,
with the approbation of three fourths of the members present in both
chambers, and the ratification of an equal number of the legislatures of
the other states of the Union.</p>

<p>8.	To fix the general expenses, establish the contributions necessary
in order to defray them, to regulate their collection, determine their ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penditure,
and to require annually account of the same from the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment.</p>

<p>9.	To contract debts on the credit of the confederation, and to fix the
guarantees of their repayment.</p>

<p>10.	To acknowledge the national debt, and indicate the means to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />solidate
and extinguish the same.</p>

<p>11.	To regulate the commerce with foreign nations, between the dif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferent
states of the Union and with the Indian tribes.</p>

<p>12.	To give instructions for the forming of Concordates with the Holy
See, to approve and ratify the same, and to regulate the right of patron<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age
(patronato) in the -whole Union.</p>

<p>13.	To approve treaties of peace, alliance, friendship, confederation,
armed neutrality, and all others which the President of the United
States may enter into with foreign powers.</p>

<p>14.	To establish ports of all kinds, erect custom-houses, and designate
their location.</p>

<p>15.	To determine and render uniform the -weight, fineness, value,
stamp and denomination of the coins throughout the Union, and to
adopt a general system of weights and measures.</p>

<pb n="79" xml:id="P0079" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/87/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

<p>16.	To declare war, upon examining the facts presented to its consid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eration
by the President of the United States.</p>

<p>17.	To establish rules for the granting of letters of marque, and for
declaring valid or invalid prizes on land and water.</p>

<p>18.	To designate the force of the army and navy, to fix the contingent
of men to be furnished by each state, to establish ordinances and rules
for- their organisation and service.</p>

<p>19.	To form regulations for the organisation, arming and disciplining
of the local militia of the states; reserving to each state the appointment
of its own officers and the faculty of instructing them according to the
discipline laid down in the aforesaid regulations.</p>

<p>20.	To grant or to refuse the entrance of foreign troops into the ter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ritory
of the confederation.</p>

<p>21.	To permit or to refuse squadrons belonging to foreign powers to
remain for more than one month in Mexican harbors.</p>

<p>22.	To permit the departure of the national troops beyond the limits
of the republic.</p>

<p>23,	To create or suppress all public employments of the Federation,
to fix, increase or diminish the appointed salaries, rewards, in case of
retirement, and pensions of the same.</p>

<p>24,	To grant rewards and compensations to persons who have ren<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dered
great services to the republic, and to decree public honors in mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ory
of great men.</p>

<p>25.	To grant amnesties and indulgences for offenses the cognisance of
which appertains to the tribunals of the confederation, in such cases,
and upon observing the prerequisites prescribed by law.</p>

<p>26.	To establish a uniform rule of naturalisation.</p>

<p>27.	To establish general rules as to bankruptcy throughout the Union.</p>

<p>28.	To select a place of residence for the supreme powers of the
Federation and to exercise in its district the attributes of the legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive
power of a state.</p>

<p>29.	To change such residence whenever it may deem it necessary.</p>

<p>30.	To grant laws and decrees for the interior administration of the
Territories.</p>

<p>31.	To dictate all laws and decrees, which may conduce to accom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plish
the objects spoken of in the forty-ninth article without intermed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dling
with the interior administration of the states.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Sixth.</emph></p>
<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Formation of the Laws.</emph></p>

<p>ART. 51. The formation of all laws and decrees may begin indis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinctly
in either of the chambers, except those having for their object
the levying of contributions or of raising taxes, which must originate
in the Chamber of Deputies.</p>

<p>Art. 52. The following shall be considered as initiatives of laws;</p>

<p>1.	Propositions which the President of the United Mexican States
shall deem advantageous to the Union and which as such he shall
specially recommend to the Chamber of Deputies.</p>
<p>2.	Propositions, projects of laws or decrees, which the legislatures
of the states may address to either chamber.</p>

<pb n="80" xml:id="P0080" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/88/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

<p>Art. 53. All projects of laws or decrees without any exception what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever
shall be successively discussesd in the two chambers, observing in
both with exactness what it prescribed in the regulations as to the form
of debate, as well as to the delays and modes of proceeding in voting.</p>

<p>Art. 54. Propositions of laws or decrees, which have been rejected
in the chamber, where they originated, before the final reading cannot
again be proposed by any member during the sessions of that year, nor
until the ordinary sessions of the year following.</p>

<p>Art. 55. If the propositions of laws or decrees after having been
discussed be approved by an absolute majority of the members present
in both chambers, they shall be sent to the president, who if he also
approves shall sign and publish the same; and if not, shall return them
with his observations within ten working days to the chamber whence
they originated.</p>

<p>Art. 56. The propositions of laws or decrees returned by the presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent,
according to the preceding article, shall be a second time discussed
in the two chambers. If in each of them, they be approved by two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds
of the members present, they shall again be sent to the president,
who without further excuse must sign and publish them; but if not
approved by the votes of two-thirds of the members, they cannot again
be proposed until the year following.</p>

<p>Art. 57. If the president should not return a proposed law or decree
within the period prescribed in the 55th art. it shall be considered as
approved by that very fact, and be promulgated as law; unless while
the delay is not yet expired, congress should have closed or suspended
its sessions, in which event the return must be made on the first day
thereafter when congress shall again unite.</p>

<p>Art. 58. The projects of laws or decrees once wholly rejected by
the chamber of revision, shall be returned by said chamber to that in
which it originated. If upon re-examination in the latter, it be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved
by two-thirds of the members present, it shall be sent back again
to the chamber by which it was rejected, who shall not again reject it,
unless by the vote of two-thirds of the members present.</p>

<p>Art. 59. All proposed laws or decrees, which, on a second examina<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
have been approved by two-thirds of the members of the chamber
where they originated, and not disapproved by two-thirds of the cham<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber
of revision, shall be sent to the president who must sign and circu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />late
them, or send them back within ten working days to the chamber
where they originated.</p>

<p>Art. 60. All propositions of laws or decrees which, according to the
preceding article, the president may send back to -the chamber where
they originated, shall be again considered, and if they are approved by
two-thirds of the members present, and the chamber of .revision be
not equally divided, they shall be returned to the president, who shall
cause them to be published. But if in their origin they were approved
by two-thirds of the chamber, or disapproved by an equal number of
the chamber of revision, they cannot again be taken up except at a
subsequent regular session.</p>

<p>Art. 61. In case they should be reproved a second time by the cham<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber
of revision, according to article 58, the proposition shall be consid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered
as thrown out, and it cannot again be taken up until the following
year.</p>
<pb n="81" xml:id="P0081" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/89/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

<p>Abt. 62. In the amendments, which the chamber of revision may
make to proposed laws or decrees, the same formalities must be observed
as on other subjects requiring the approbation of the president.</p>

<p>Abt. 63. The portions of a proposed law or decree, which may be
once disapproved by the chamber of revision, are subject to the same
formalities as those propositions which have been wholly disapproved.</p>

<p>Abt. 64. In the interpretation, modification, and repeal of laws and
decrees the same formalities must be observed which are required for
their formation.</p>

<p>Abt. 65. Whenever any resolution of the general congress is com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />municated
to the President of the Republic, it must be signed by the
presidents of both chambers, and by a secretary belonging to each.</p>

<p>Abt. 66. No law or decree can be formed in either chamber with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out
the presence of an absolute majority of the members composing it.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Seventh.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Time, Duration and Place of holding the General Congress.</emph></p>

<p>Abt, 67. The general congress shall meet every .year on the 1st
of January, in the place designated by law. The regulations for the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terior
government of the same, shall prescribe the formalities previous
to the opening of the same, as well as those to be observed at its installa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>

<p>Abt. 68. The President of the Confederation shall assist at this open<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing,
and shall pronounce a discourse suitable to this important act: to
which, the presiding officer of congress shall reply in general terms.</p>

<p>Abt. 69. The ordinary sessions of congress shall be held daily, with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out
any other interruption than solemn days of festivals; and in order to
suspend its meetings for more than two days, the consent of both cham<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers
is necessary.</p>

<p>Abt. 70. The chambers shall reside in the same place; and they can<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />not
remove to another, without previously agreeing on such removal,
as well as the time and manner of effecting it, and designating the same
point for their re-union. But if both agree on the removal, but differ
as to time, mode, and place, the President of the Union shall decide the
question, by choosing one of the places in dispute.</p>

<p>Abt. 71. The general congress shall close its sessions annually on the
15th of April, with the same formalities prescribed for its opening, with
the faculty of prolonging it for thirty working days whenever they deem
it necessary, or the President of the Union may request it.</p>

<p>Abt. 72. Whenever the general congress may unite in extra session,
it shall be composed of the same deputies and senators which formed the
ordinary session, and who will confine their attention exclusively to the
objects for which they were convoked; but if these be not disposed of
at the day appointed for the regular session, the extra session must be
closed, and the points pending left to the decision of the ordinary con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress.</p>

<p>Abt. 73. The resolutions taken by congress relative to the change,
prorogation, or suspension of its sessions, according to the three preced<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
articles, must be communicated to the president, who will cause them
to be executed without making any observations thereon.</p>

<pb n="82" xml:id="P0082" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/90/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

<head>TITLE IV.</head>

<p>OF THE SUPREME EXECUTIVE POWER OF THE CONFEDERATION.</p>

<p><emph rend="itlaic">Section First.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="itlaic">Of the Persons to whom this Power is confided, and their Election.</emph></p>

<p>Art. 74. The supreme executive power is entrusted to a single indi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vidual,
who shall be styled President of the United Mexican States.</p>

<p>Art. 75. There shall also be a vice president, who shall discharge
all the duties of the president, in case of physical or moral inability of
the latter.</p>

<p>Art. 76. In order to be president or vice president it is necessary
to be born a Mexican citizen, to be thirty-five years of age at the time of
election, and residing in the country.</p>

<p>Art. 77. The president cannot be re-elected until the fourth year
after his functions have ceased.</p>

<p>Art. 78. He .who has been elected president or vice president of the
republic, will discharge these functions in preference to all others.</p>

<p>Art. 79. The 1st of September, of the year immediately preceding
that on which the president ought to enter on his office, the legislature of
each state must elect, by an absolute majority of votes, two individuals,
of which one at least shall not be a resident of such state.</p>

<p>Art. 80. When the vote has been taken, the legislatures shall for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ward
to the president of the council of government, evidence of the act
of election in due form, in order that he may dispose of the same in the
manner prescribed by the regulations of the council.</p>

<p>Art. 81. On the 6th of January following, the evidence, spoken of
in the preceding section, shall be opened and read in joint session of the
chambers, if two-thirds of the votes of the states have been received.</p>

<p>Art. 82. When this evidence has been read, the senators shall retire,
and a committee, appointed by the chamber of deputies, and composed
of one member from each state represented, shall give an account of the
result.</p>

<p>Art. 83. The chamber shall forthwith proceed to examine the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
.and enumerate the votes.</p>

<p>Art. 84. He who unites the absolute majority of the votes of the
legislatures shall be president.</p>

<p>Art. 85. If .two were to possess a majority, he shall be president who
has the greatest number of votes, and the other vice president. In case
of equality, the chamber of deputies shall elect one as president, and the
other shall be vice president.</p>

<p>Art. 86. If neither have the absolute majority of votes of the legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />latures,
the chamber of deputies shall elect the president and vice presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent,
choosing for each one having the greatest number of votes.</p>

<p>Art. 87. When more than two individuals possess a majority, or
equal number of votes, the chamber shall choose among them the presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent
or vice president, as the case may be.</p>

<p>Art. 88. If one have the absolute majority, and two or more an

<pb n="83" xml:id="P0083" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/91/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>


equality of votes, but greater than the rest, the chamber shall choose
from those having the greatest votes.</p>

<p>Art. 89. If all have an equal number of votes, the chamber shall
choose a president and vice president from among the whole; as also,
when one has a greater number, and the rest an equal number of votes.</p>

<p>Art. 90. Should there be a tie, when voting upon the elections of
the legislatures, the vote shall be repeated once, and if it still continues
to be a tie, chance shall decide.</p>

<p>Art. 91. In competitions between two or more, having an equal
number of votes, the voting must be directed to reduce the competitors
to two or one, in order that the remaining party be placed in competi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
with him who has a majority of votes.</p>

<p>Art. 92. ' As a general rule, in voting for president and vice presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent,
chance shall not be resorted to till after two votings.</p>

<p>Art. 93. In voting on the elections of the legislatures, as well as
on the nomination of president and vice president, the representation
of each state shall have but one vote; and in order to have a decision
of the chamber, there must be an absolute majority of votes.</p>

<p>Art. 94. In order to deliberate on the objects mentioned in the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceding
article, there must concur more than one-half of the whole
number of members, and three-fourths of the deputies of the states.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Second.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Duration of the Presidency and Vice Presidency, and the
mode of filling Vacancies in each, and of their Oath.</emph></p>

<p>Art. 95. The President and Vice President of the Union shall enter
on their functions on the 1st of April; and shall vacate their offices, on
the same day four years afterwards, by a new and constitutional election.</p>

<p>Art. 96. If from any cause whatever, the elections of president and
vice president should not be completed and published by the first of
April on which the installation is to take place, or the persons elected
should not be ready to enter on the office, the functions of the former
shall, nevertheless, cease, and the chamber of deputies, voting by states,
shall elect a president ad interim.</p>

<p>Art. 97. In case the president or vice president be temporarily pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vented,
what has been prescribed in the preceding article shall take
place, and if the impediment were to occur while the congress is not in
session, the supreme executive power is confided to the president of
the supreme court of justice and two individuals chosen by the absolute
plurality of votes of the council of the government. These cannot be
members of the general congress, and they ought to possess the quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fications
required of the president of the Union.</p>

<p>Art. 98. While the elections above spoken of are making, the presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent
of the supreme court of justice discharges the executive power.</p>

<p>Art. 99. In the event of perpetual impossibility of the president or
vice president, congress, and in their recess the council of government,
shall provide for the case according to the 96th and 97th articles, and
take steps that the legislatures proceed to elect a president and vice
president according to the constitutional forms.</p>

<pb n="84" xml:id="P0084" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/92/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

<p>Abt. 100. The election of president and vice president made by the
legislatures, in consequence of the perpetual impossibility of those hold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
these offices, shall not prevent the ordinary elections which take
place the first of September every four years.</p>

<p>Abt. 101. The president and vice president elected every four years,
ought to be on the first of April in the place where the supreme powers
of the Union reside, and take an oath before the united chambers to
fulfil their duties in the following form: I, -------, appointed president
(or vice president) of the United Mexican States, swear before God and
his holy evangelists, that I will faithfully discharge the office which
the United States have entrusted me with, and that I will observe, and
cause to be observed, exactly the constitution and the general laws of
the confederation.</p>

<p>Abt. 102. If neither the president nor the vice president present
themselves to take the preceding oath, and the session of congress is
open, they shall take such oath before the council of government as soon
as each presents himself.</p>

<p>Abt. 103. . If the vice president present himself, and take the oath
before the president, he shall be at the head of government until the
president has taken the oath of office.</p>

<p>Abt. 104. The president and vice president, constitutionally ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed
according to the 99th article, and the individuals provisionally
appointed to exercise the functions of president according to the 96th
and 91th articles, shall take the oath mentioned in the 101st article,
before the chambers if in session, and if not, before the council of the
government.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Third.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Prerogatives of the President and Vice President.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 105. The president may propose to congress such new laws or
reform in old laws as he may think conducive to the general good, by
proposing them to the chamber of deputies.</p>

<p>Abt. 106. The president may once, within ten working days, make
observations on laws and decrees passed by the general congress, and
suspend their publication until the resolution of congress, except in
cases provided for by the constitution.</p>

<p>Abt. 107. The president, while he remains in office, can only be
accused before one of the chambers, and only for the offences men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned
in the 38th article, and committed at the time therein specified.</p>

<p>Abt. 108. Within one year, counting from the time at which the
office of the president ceases, he cannot be accused except before the
chambers, for offences mentioned in the 38th article, as well as for all
others committed during the time he was in office. When the year is
passed, he cannot be accused for such offences.</p>

<p>Abt. 109. The vice president, during the four years of his employ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
can only be accused before the chamber of deputies for an offence
committed during the time of such employment.</p>

<pb n="85" xml:id="P0085" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/93/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Fourth</emph></p>

<p><emph rends="italic">Of the Attributes of the President, and the Restrictions of his Powers.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 110. The attributes of the president are the following:</p>

<p>1.	To publish, circulate, and cause to be observed, the laws and
decrees of the general congress.</p>

<p>2.	To make regulations, decrees, and orders for the'better observ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance
of the constitution, constitutive act, and general laws.</p>

<p>3.	To execute the laws and decrees having for their object the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ervation
of the integrity of the Union, and to sustain its exterior inde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pendence,
and its interior union and liberty.</p>

<p>4.	To appoint and remove at pleasure the secretaries of state.</p>

<p>5.	To watch over the collection, and decree the appropriation of the
general contributions agreeably to law.</p>

<p>6.	To name the heads of the treasury, the general commissaries,
diplomatic agents, consuls, colonels and other superior officers of the
permanent army, and of the armed and active militia, with the approba<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of the senate, and in the recess, by the council of the government.</p>

<p>7.	To appoint the other officers of the permanent army and of the
armed and active militia, and the officers of the confederation observing
therein the dispositions of the law.</p>

<p>8.	To appoint, out of three candidates proposed by the supreme
court, the judges and fiscals of the circuit and district courts.</p>

<p>9.	To grant discharges and furloughs, and regulate the pensions of
the military, agreeahly to law.</p>

<p>10.	To dispose of the permanent army and navy and the active
militia for the interior security and external defence of the nation.</p>

<p>11.	To dispose of the local militia for the same objects, and even
employ the same beyond the limits of their respective states and terri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tories,
after previous consent of the general congress, which shall specify
the force necessary, and, if congress be not in session, the council of the
government shall give its consent, and make the aforesaid specification.</p>

<p>12.	To declare war in the name of the United Mexican States, upon
a previous decree of the general congress; grant letters of marque ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording
to the provisions of law.</p>

<p>13.	To make concordats with the Apostolic See, according to the
terms of the 12th power of the 50th article.</p>

<p>14.	To direct diplomatic negotiations, and make treaties of peace,
friendship, alliance, truce, confederation, armed neutrality, commerce,
and all other kinds; but in order to give or withhold ratification of the
same, the approbation of the general congress is necessary.</p>

<p>15.	To receive ministers and other agents of foreign powers.</p>

<p>16.	To ask of the general congress the prorogation of their sessions
for thirty working days or less.</p>

<p>17.	Convoke extra sessions of congress when he thinks it necessary,
and two-thirds of the members present of the council of government
shall agree to it.</p>

<p>18.	Also to convoke extra sessions of congress, when two-thirds of
the members present of the council of government think it necessary.</p>


<pb n="86" xml:id="P0086" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/94/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

<p>
19.	To see that prompt and perfect justice is administered by the
supreme court and other tribunals of the Union, and that their decrees
be carried into effect, according to law.</p>

<p>20.	To suspend from their employments, for a space not exceeding
three months, and deprive of not more than half their salaries for the
same period, all persons employed by the Union, who violate his orders
or decrees, and, if he thinks such persons should be tried, to send them
before the competent tribunals.</p>

<p>21.	To approve or retain decrees of councils, pontificial bulls, letters,
and rescripts, with consent of the general congress, consulting the sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate,
and, in the recess, the council of government, when they treat on
subjects peculiar to the administration, and the supreme court, when
on subjects of litigation.</p>

<p>Abt. 111. The president, in publishing the laws and decrees, shall
use the following formula: “The President of the United Mexican
States makes known to the inhabitants of the Republic, that the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral
Congress has decreed as follows: [here insert the text]-.” Where<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore,
I order that the same be printed, published, and circulated and
carried into effect.</p>

<p>
Abt. 112. The restrictions of the president’s powers, are the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing:
</p>

<p>1.	The president cannot command in person the army or navy with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out
the previous consent of the general congress, or, in its recess, the
council of government, by a vote of two-thirds of the members present,
and when he commands them with such permission, the vice president
shall act as president.</p>

<p>
2.	The president cannot deprive any one of his liberty, nor impose
any punishment; when the welfare and security of the Union requires,
he may, however, arrest persons, placing them, within forty-eight hours,
at the disposition of the competent tribunals.</p>

<p>3.	The president cannot occupy the property of any individual
or corporation, nor disturb them in their possession or use of the same;
and if in any case it should be necessary for some object of acknowl<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />edged
utility to take the property of an individual or a corporation, it
cannot be done without previous approbation of the senate, and in the
recess, the council of government, always indemnifying the party the
value fixed by appraisers chosen by himself and the government.</p>

<p>4.	The President cannot impede elections nor the other acts spoken of
in the 38th article.</p>

<p>5.	Neither the President nor the Vice President can leave the repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic
during the time of their office, nor for a year afterwards.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Fifth.</emph></p>
<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Council of the Government.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 113. During the recess of Congress there shall be a Council of
Government composed of half the senate, one from each state.</p>

<p>Abt. 114. For the first two years the council shall be composed of
those first elected by their respective legislatures, and in the sequel by
the oldest.</p>

<p>Abt. 115. The Vice President shall be president of the council, and

<pb n="87" xml:id="P0087" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/95/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

he shall appoint according to his own regulation a president pro tempore
to discharge his functions in his absence.</p>

<p>Abt. 116. The attributes of this council shall be as follows:</p>

<p>1.	To watch over the observance of the constitution and the consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tutive
act and general laws, keeping a record of all incidents relating
to this subject.</p>

<p>2.	To make such observations to the President as they deem useful
to the accomplishment of the constitution and laws of the Union.</p>

<p>3.	To require, of their own accord, or at the request of the President,
extra sessions of Congress, but in such cases two thirds of the members
present must concur, according to §§ 17. and 18. of art. 110.</p>

<p>4.	Give their consent for using the local militia, according to § 9. of
art. 110.</p>

<p>5.	Approve of the appointments mentioned § 6. of art. 110.</p>

<p>6.	Give its consent in the case of art. 112. § 1.</p>

<p>7.	Appoint two individuals, who jointly with the president of the su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme
court, shall exercise provisionally the supreme executive power,
according to art. 97.</p>

<p>8.	To receive the oath of art. 101, from the individuals of the supreme
executive power, in the cases mentioned in the constitution.</p>

<p>9.	To give their opinion in consultation with the President, accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
to § 21, art. 110. and on other subjects on which he may consult
them.</p>

<p><emph rend="itlaic">Section Sixth.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="itlaic">Of the Business of Government.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 117. For the despatch of the business of government of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public,
there shall be appointed such a number of secretaries as Congress
may establish by general law.</p>

<p>Abt. 118. All the regulations, decrees and orders of the President
ought to be signed by the secretary of state of the department to which
it belongs, and without this formality they are not to be obeyed.</p>

<p>Abt. 119. The secretaries of state shall be responsible for all acts of
the President, signed by them contrary to the constitution, the consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tutive
act, general laws, and the constitutions of particular states.</p>

<p>Abt. 120. The secretaries of state shall give to each chamber, as soon
as it opens, an account of the situation of their respective departments.</p>
<p>
Abt. 121. In order to be secretary of state, one must be born a Mex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ican
citizen.</p>
<p>
Abt. 122. The secretaries of state shall form regulations for the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tribution
and despatch of business under their care, which shall be sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted
by government to Congress for their approbation.</p>

<pb n="88" xml:id="P0088" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/96/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

<head>TITLE V.</head>

<p>OF THE JUDICIAL POWER OF THE UNION.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section First.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Nature and Distribution of this Power</emph></p>

<p>Art. 123. The judicial power of the Union shall reside in a supreme
court of justice, and in circuit and district courts.</p>


<p><emph rend="italic">Section Second.</emph></p>
<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Sufreme Court of fustice, the Election, Duration and Oaths
of its Members.</emph></p>

<p>Art. 124. The supreme court of Justice shall be composed of eleven
ministers, divided into three chambers, and of one fiscal, the general
Congress having power to increase this number if they think proper.</p>

<p>Art. 125. In order to be elected member of the supreme court, it is
necessary to be instructed in the science of law, in the opinion of
the legislatures of the states, to have thirty-five years of age, be a natural
born citizen of the republic, or born in some part of America, which
prior.to 1810 belonged to Spain, and which has separated from it, pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided
he have five years residence within the republic.</p>

<p>Art. 126. The individuals composing the supreme court of justice
shall hold the office for life, unless removed according to law.</p>

<p>Art. 127. The election of the members of the supreme court shall
take place on the same day, by the legislatures of the state by an abso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lute
majority.</p>

<p>Art. 128. The elections concluded, each legislature shall send to the
president of the council of the government a certified list of the twelve
individuals elected, noticing him who has been appointed Fiscal.</p>

<p>Art. 129. The president of the council as soon as he shall have
received the lists of at least three-fourths of the legislatures, shall dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose
of them in the manner prescribed by the regulations of the council.</p>

<p>Art. 130. On the day appointed for the meeting of Congress, the said
list shall be opened and read, in the presence of both chambers, after
which the senators shall retire.</p>

<p>Art. 131. Immediately the chamber of deputies shall appoint by, an
absolute majority a committee, which must be composed of one deputy
from each state, whose representatives are present, to which the lists
must be sent, in order to verify the result, after which the chamber
will verify the election and count the votes.</p>

<p>Art. 132. The individual or individuals uniting more than one half
of the votes given by all the legislatures, and not by those of their
respective members, shall be regarded as elected, and the chamber will
so declare them.</p>

<p>Art. 133. If those uniting a majority of the suffrages spoken of in
the preceding article do not amount to twelve, the same chamber shall
<pb n="89" xml:id="P0089" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/97/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

elect successively among the individuals who have obtained the greatest
number of votes of the legislatures, observing in relation to such election,
what has been prescribed in the first section of tit. 4th, which treats of
the election of President and Vice-President.</p>

<p>ART. 134. If a senator or deputy be elected minister or fiscal of the
supreme court, he will prefer such election.</p>

<p>Abt. 135. When a vacancy occurs in the supreme court, it shall be
filled agreeably to the provisions of this section, information having
been previously given to the governors and legislatures of the states.</p>

<p>Aet. 136. The members of the supreme court, before entering into
office, shall take the following oath before the president of the republic;
"Ye swear by God our Lord to conduct yourselves faithfully and legally
in the discharge of the duties confided to you by the nation, and if ye
act thus God will reward you, if not, punish you.”</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Third.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Attributes of the Supreme Court.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 137. The following are the attributes of the supreme court:</p>

<p>1.	To take cognisance of disputes, which may arise between the
different states of the Union, whenever there arises litigation in relation
to the same, requiring a formal decree, and that arising between a state
and one ot more of its inhabitants, or between individuals in relation
to lands, under concessions from different states, without prejudice to
the right of the parties to claim the concession from the party which
granted it.</p>

<p>2.	To decide disputes which grow out of contracts and transactions
between the supreme government and its agents.</p>

<p>3.	To consult upon the acceptance or refusal of papal bulls, letters
and rescripts, granted on litigated points.</p>

<p>4.	Decide on the competency of the tribunals of the Union, and on
conflicting jurisdictions between them and the state tribunals.</p>

<p>5.	To take cognisance,</p>

<p>First. Of accusations against the president and vice-president ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording
to arts. 38 and 39, after the previous declaration of art. 49.</p>

<p>Secondly. Of criminal prosecutions of the deputies and senators in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicated
in art. 43, after the declaration spoken of in art. 44.</p>

<p>Thirdly. Of those against the governors of the states in the cases
mentioned in art. 38. part 3d, after the declaration spoken of in art. 40.</p>

<p>Fourthly. Of those against the secretaries of state agreeably to art.
38 and 40.</p>

<p>Fifthly. Of the civil and criminal affairs of the diplomatic agents
and consuls of the republic.</p>

<p>Sixthly. Of causes in admiralty, prizes by land and water, and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />traband;
of crimes committed on the high seas; of offences against the
united Mexican nation; of the officers of the treasury and justice of
the Union; of infractions against the constitution and general laws,
according to the dispositions of law.</p>

<p>Aet. 138. It shall be determined by law, in what manner the su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme
court shall take cognisance of the cause mentioned in this section.</p>

<pb n="90" xml:id="P0090" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/98/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Fourth.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Mode of judging the Members of the Supreme Court.</emph></p>

<p>ART. 139. To judge the members of the supreme court, the chamber
of deputies shall elect every two years, in the first month of their ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nary
session, and voting by states, twenty-four individuals, not mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers
of congress, and possessing the qualifications of the members of
the supreme court. From these shall be chosen by lot a fiscal, and a
number of judges equal to the first chamber of the court, and when it
is necessary, the chamber of deputies, and, in the recess, the council of
government, shall elect in the same manner the other chambers (salas).</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Fifth.</emph></p>
<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Circuit Courts.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 140. The circuit court of a judge skilled, in law and a fiscal,
both named by the supreme executive power from three candidates,
designated by the supreme court, and of two associates, according to
law.</p>

<p>
Abt. 141. To be circuit judge, it requires to be a citizen, and thirty
years of age.</p>


<p>Abt. 143. To these courts belong, to judge causes in admiralty; cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tures
by land and sea, contraband; crimes committed on the high seas;
offences against the United States of Mexico; suits against consuls, and
civil causes in which the Union is interested exceeding five hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars
in value. A special law shall designate the number'of these courts,
the manner and form in which they ought to exercise their powers:
they are under the inspection of the supreme court.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Sixth.</emph></p>
<p><emph rend="italic">Of the District Judges.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 143. The United Mexican States shall be divided into a certain
number of districts, in each of which there shall be a judge skilled in
law (<foreign>letrado</foreign>), and who shall take cognisance, without appeal, of all causes
in which the Union is interested, and whose value does not exceed five
hundred dollars, and in the first instance of all causes which belong to
the jurisdiction of the circuit courts.</p>

<p>
Abt. 144. To be judge of the district court, it is necessary to-be a
citizen of the Union, and twenty-five years of age. The president ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />points
these judges from three candidates named by the supreme court.</p>>

<pb n="91" xml:id="P0091" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/99/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Seventh.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">General Rules for Administration of Justice in the States and Terri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tories
of the Union.</emph></p>
<p>Art. 145. Each state shall give faith and credit to the acts, registers,
and procedings of the judges and other authorities of the other states,
and congress shall establish a uniform law for proving such acts, regis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ters,
&amp;c.</p>

<p>Art. 146. The penalty of infamy does not extend beyond the person
punished.</p>

<p>Art. 147. The confiscation of goods is forever abolished.</p>

<p>Art. 148. All judgments by commissions and retroactive laws, are
forever prohibited.</p>

<p>Art. 149. No authority shall ever inflict the torture under any pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tence.</p>

<p>Art. 150. No one can be confined unless there be half proof or indi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cations
of his guilt.</p>

<p>ART. 151. No one shall be detained on indications alone, for more
than sixty hours.</p>

<p>Art. 152. No authority can direct the seizure and registry of papers
and effects in houses, except in cases and in the form expressly prescribed
by law.</p>

<p>Art. 153. No one is bound to accuse himself in criminal matters.</p>

<p>Art. 154. The military and ecclesiastic remain subject to the same
laws and tribunals as heretofore.</p>

<p>Art. 155. No suit can be instituted, either for civil or criminal in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jury,
without previous demand in conciliation.</p>

<p>Art. 156. No one can be deprived of the right of terminating his dif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferences
before arbitrators chosen by each party, in every stage of the
cause. </p>

<head>TITLE VI.</head>

<p>OF THE STATES OF THE FEDERATION.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section First.</emph></p>
<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Particular Government of the States.</emph></p>

<p>Art. 157. The government of each state shall be divided into three
powers, viz: the legislative, executive, and judicial, and two or more
of these can never be united in the same person or corporation, nor can
the legislative power be vested in a single individual.</p>

<p>Art. 158. The legislative power of each state resides in a legislature,
composed of the number of individuals determined by their particular
constitutions, elected by the people, and removable at the time and in
the manner they may prescribe.</p>

<p>Art. 159. The person or persons to whom the states confide the exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cutive
power can exercise it only for a limited time, fixed by their con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitutions.</p>

<pb n="92" xml:id="P0092" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/100/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitutive Acts</fw>

<p>Abt. 160. The judicial power in each state shall be exercised by the
tribunals established by their constitutions, and all causes as well civil
as criminal which originate in such courts must be therein finally dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed
of.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Second.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Of the Obligations of the States.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 161. Each state is bound;</p>

<p>1.	To organize its government agreeably to the constitution and the
constitutive act.</p>

<p>2.	To punish through their governors, their constitutions and laws.</p>

<p>3.	To cause the constitution and general laws of the Union to be ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />served,
as well as all treaties made or to be made with foreign powers.</p>

<p>4.	To protect its inhabitants in the enjoyment of the liberty of wri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ting,
printing and publishing their political ideas, without license, or
previous revision or approbation, causing however the laws relative to
this matter to be duly observed.</p>

<p>5.	To surrender criminals to the governments of other states, claiming
them.</p>

<p>6.	To surrender fugitives from other states to the persons justly claim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
them or compel them in some other mode to satisfy the party inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ested.</p>

<p>7.	To contribute to the extinguishment of the debts acknowledged by
congress.</p>

<p>8.	To send annually to each of the chambers of congress a circum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stantial
account of the receipts and expenditures of the treasuries in
their respective districts, with the origin of each, the state of agricul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture,
commerce and manufactures, of the new modes of industry which
might be usefully introduced and protected, as well as the population
and the means of protecting and augmenting the same.</p>

<p>9.	To forward to the chambers, and in the recess to the council of
government, and the executive power, a copy of their constitutions and
laws.</p>

<p><emph rend="italic">Section Third.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="italic">The Restrictions of the Powers of the States.</emph></p>

<p>Abt. 162. No state can,</p>

<p>1.	Establish tonnage duties nor ports of entry without consent of
congress.</p>

<p>2.	Impose duties on imports and exports without consent of congress.</p>

<p>3.	Have a standing army or navy without the consent of congress.</p>

<p>4.	Engage in transactions or declare war with foreign powers, resist<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
them however in case of actual invasion, of which immediate notice
is given to congress.</p>

<p>5.	Enter upon any transaction with other states of the Union, with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out
consent of congress, or its subsequent approval if. it has reference
to boundaries.</p>

<pb n="93" xml:id="P0093" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/101/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">of the Mexican Federation.</fw>

<head>TITLE VII.</head>

<p><emph rend="itlaic">Only Section.</emph></p>

<p><emph rend="itlaic">Of the Observance, Interpretation, and Reform of the Constitution
and Constitutive Act.</emph></p>

<p>Aet. 163. All public functionaries without exception, before enter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
on their offices must take an oath to observe the constitution and
the constitutive act.</p>

<p>Aet. 164. Congress will enact laws to punish those violating the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution.</p>

<p>Aet. 165. Congress alone has the right to interpret the constitution
in doubtful cases.</p>

<p>Aet. 166. The legislatures of the states may make observations on
the different provisions of the constitution and constitutive act, but
congress shall take them into consideration till the year 1830.</p>

<p>
Aet. 167. The congress of the present year will select such observa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
as deserve to be referred to the next congress, which must be com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />municated
to the president who will cause them to be published without
any observations.</p>

<p>Aet. 168. Next congress in the first year of its ordinary session, shall
take into consideration these observations, and make such reforms as
it thinks necessary. But the same congress can not propose amendments
and act on them.</p>

<p>Aet. 169. The reforms and additions which may; be proposed after
1830, shall be considered by congress in the 2d year of their session, and
if regarded as necessary according to the preceding articles, this resolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
shall be published for the consideration of the next congress.</p>

<p>Aet. 170. To reform or add to this constitution or the constitutive
act, all the rules shall also be observed, which are required for the for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mation
of laws except that the president shall not have the right to make
the observations of art. 106.</p>

<p>Aet. 171. Those articles of this constitution and of the constitutive
act which establish the liberty and independence of the Mexican nation,
its religion, form of government, liberty of the press and the division
of the supreme powers of the Union and of the states can never be
changed.</p>

<p>
Given in Mexico on the 4th of October in the year of our Lord 1824,
in the 4th year of the Independence, 3rd of Liberty and 2d of the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federation.</p>

<p>(Signed)
LORENZO DE ZAVALA, President, &amp;c.
</p>

<pb n="94" xml:id="P0094" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/102/" />

</div></body></text>
