<text>
<front>
<pb n="95" xml:id="P0095" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/103/" /><p>LAWS OF COLONIZATION
PASSED BY
THE SUPREME GOVERNMENT
OF
MEXICO,
AND
BY THE PROVINCIAL GOVERNMENT
OF
COAHUILA AND TEXAS
1824-25
LONDON:
1828
</p>



<pb n="96" xml:id="P0096" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/104/" />
</front>
<body>
    <div type="document">
<pb n="97" xml:id="P0097" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/105/" />

<head>TRANSLATION
OF THE
GENERAL LAW OF COLONIZATION</head>

<p>No. 72. DATED 18th AUGUST, 1824.</p>

<p>The Sovereign General Congress, assembled for .the purpose of fram<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
the Constitution of the United Mexican States, has decreed as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows:—</p>

<p>Akt. 1.—The Mexican Nation offers to those foreigners who may be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />desirous
of settling in her territory security for their persons and prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty,
provided they obey the laws of the country.</p>

<p>Abt. 2.—This law relates to those lands, national property, which, as.
belonging to no individual, corporation or town, may be occupied by
settlers.</p>

<p>Abt. 3.—For this purpose the Congresses of the States shall as.
speedily as possible frame laws or regulations for the colonization of
those lands which appertain to them, conforming in every respect with
the fundamental Constitutional Act, the General Constitution, and the
regulations established by this law,</p>

<p>Abt. 4.—No lands lying within 30 leagues of the boundaries with any
foreign nation, nor within 10 leagues of the coast, can be occupied by
settlers, without the previous approbation of the Supreme Executive
Power.</p>

<p>Abt. 5.—If, with a view to the defence or security of the nation, the
government of the federation should think fit to occupy any of the
lands, in order to construct magazines,' arsenals, or other public build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings,
it is empowered so to do, with the approbation of the general
Congress, and during its recess with that of the Council of Government.</p>

<p>Abt. 6.—Until 4 years from the publication of this law, no impost
shall be levied for the admission of those foreigners who may come for
the first time, in order to settle in the nation.</p>

<p>Abt. 7.—Until the year 1840 the general Congress shall not prohibit
the admission of foreigners to colonize, excepting, indeed, circumstances
should imperiously oblige it so to do, with regard to the individuals of
any nation.</p>

<p>Abt. 8.—The Government, without defeating the purposes of this
law, shall take those measures of precaution which it may deem expe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dient
for the security of the federation, with regard to those foreigners
who may come to colonise.</p>

<p>Abt. 9.—In the distribution of lands a preference is to be given to
Mexican citizens, and be'tween them no other distinction shall be made

<pb n="98" xml:id="P0098" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/106/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws of Colonization.</fw>

than that to which individual merit, or services rendered to the country,
may justify, or, where in other cases a parity exists, residence in the
part to which the lands appertain.</p>

<p>Art. 10.—Those military men who, agreeably to he offer of the 21th
March, 1821, have a right to lands, shall be recompensed on presenting
the documents with which the Supreme Executive Power shall for that
purpose provide them.</p>

<p>Art. 11.—If, according to decrees for paying off the principal accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
to a calculation of the probability. of the length of life of the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cumbent,
the Supreme Executive Power should think proper to alienate
any portions of land in favour of any public servants of the federation,
military or civil, it is impowered so to do, with the government lands
of the territories of the Republic.</p>

<p>ART. 12.—In the possession of no individual shall be allowed to be
united, as his own property, more than one square league of 5000 yards
of’lands fit for irrigation, 4 of arable land not irrigated, and 6 of pasture
land.</p>

<p>Art. 13.—The new settlers are not permitted to transfer their prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty
to religious communities.</p>

<p>Art. 14.—This law guarantees the contracts which speculators may
make with those families which they may convey at their own expense,
provided they are not contrary to the laws.</p>

<p>Art. 15.—No one who in virtue of this law obtains possession of
lands, can hold them if settled out of the territory of the Republic.</p>

<p>Art. 16.—The government agreeably to the principles established in
this law shall proceed to colonise the territories of the Republic.
The Supreme Executive Power is hereby made acquainted with this
law, and will take the requisite measures for its fulfilment, directing that
it be printed, published, and circulated.—Mexico, 18th Aug. 1824.</p>

<p>
(Signed)
To Dox Lucas ALAMAN,
C. IBARRA,
President, Etc., Etc., Etc.
PEDRO DE AHUMADA,'
MANUEL DE VILLA Y CRIO,
Deputies Secretaries.
(Signed)
(Signed)
Directed to be published by the Executive
PoWER, in Mexico, 18th Aug. 1824.
N. BRAVO,
President, Etc., Etc., Etc.
VICTE. GUERRERO.
MIG—. DOMINGUEZ.
And published on the same day.
ALAMAN.</p>

</div></body></text>
