<text>
    <body>

<div type="document">
    <pb n="99" xml:id="P0099" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/107/" />

<head>LAW
<lb />FOR
<lb />PROMOTING COLONIZATION
<lb />IN
<lb />THE STATE OF COAHUILA AND TEXAS
</head>

<p>
Decree, No. 16.—The Congress, assembled for the purpose of form<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
the Constitution of the Sovereign and Independent State of
Coahuila and Texas, desirous of augmenting by all possible means the
population of its territory: of encouraging the cultivation of its fertile
lands, the raising of stock, and the progress of arts and commerce, in
exact conformity with the Act on which the Constitution is founded;
with the federal Constitution; and the basis establishded by the Sover<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eign
Decree of the general Congress, No. 72; decreeas follows:—</p>

<p>LAW OF COLONIZATION
<lb />OF
<lb />THE STATE OF COAHUILA AND TEXAS.
</p>
<p>
Art. 1.—All those foreigners who in virtue of the general law of the
18th August, 1824, by which security for their property and persons
is offered in all the territory of the Mexican Nation, may be desirous
of establishing themselves in any of the towns of Coahuila and Texas,
are hereby permitted; that State invites and proposes to them so to do.</p>

<p>Art. 2.—Those who shall do so, far from being in any way molested,
shall be secured by the local authorities- of the above mentioned towns;
which shall allow them full liberty to engage in whatever honest calling
may suit them, as long as they duly obey the general laws of the nation,
and the ordinances of the State.</p>

<p>Art. 3.—Whatever foreigner at present resident in in Coahuila and.
'Texas, may determine on settling there, shall make a declaration to that
effect, addressed to the municipal authorities of the town in which he
is desirous of fixing his residence. The municipal authorities then shall
bind him by oath, which he shall make, to abide by and obey the gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral
Constitution, and that of the'State; to observe the Religion as stipu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lated
by the former; and in a book (the register of foreigners) which
shall be kept for that purpose, his name and those of the members of
his family, if he has any, shall be set down; noting the country from
whence he comes, whether married or single, his employment; and he

<pb n="100" xml:id="P0100" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/108/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws of Colonization.</fw>

having taken the requisite oath, shall be considered thenceforward, and
not before that time, a fellow-citizen.</p>

<p>Art. 4.—From the very day in which any foreigner becomes a citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zen,
agreeably to the preceding article, he may denounce any land be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />longing
to the State, and the proper civil authority being under the
obligation of passing to the government, for its approbation, the peti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
thus made on this subject, shall award it to him; as also to every
native of the country, acting in conformity with the laws on that sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject.</p>

<p>Art. 5.—The foreigners of any nation and the native Mexicans may
undertake to form new settlements on lands belonging to the nation,
and even if belonging to individuals under the circumstances stated in
Art. 35; but the new settlers, who may demand admission into the
nation, must prove, by certificate from the authorities of the place from
whence they came, that they are Christians, and also the morality and
propriety of their conduct.</p>

<p>Art. 6.—Whatever foreigners shall arrive at a period at which the
sovereign general Congress shall have prohibited, as it may do after the
year 1840, or previously as regards the natives of any one nation, shall
not then be admitted; and all those who shall arrive within the time
allowed them, agreeably to this article, shall, nevertheless, be subjected
to such measures for the security of the federation as the supreme gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment
may adopt, regarding them without prejudice to the object
of this law.</p>

<p>Art. 7.—The government shall take care that no settlement be made
within 20 leagues of the boundaries of the United States of North
America, and 10 leagues along the coast of the Gulf of Mexico, except
such as shall obtain the sanction of the Supreme Government of the
Union: for which purpose it shall forward to it every petition on- that
head, made by Mexicans or foreigners, adding to it whatever remarks
it may deem expedient.</p>

<p>Art. 8.—All projects for establishing colonies, on which one or more
persons may offer to bring, at their own expense, 100 or more families,
shall be presented to the government, which, if it finds them agreeable
to the law, shall approve of them, and immediately mark out to the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jectors
the lands which they are to occupy, and the number of years
allowed them for presenting the number of families for which they have
stipulated, under penalty of forfeiting the rights and benefits offered
them in proportion to the number of families they shall omit to provide,
and the grant shall be wholly annulled should they not present, at the
least, 100 families.</p>

<p>Art. 9.—This law guarantees all contracts made between the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jectors
and the families brought at their expense, inasmuch as they are
in conformity with its provisions.</p>

<p>Art. 10.—In the distribution of lands a preference shall be given to
military men, who, agreeably to the documents granted by the Supreme
Executive Power, may have a right to them; and Mexican citizens not
military men, amongst whom no other distinction shall be made than
that which may be founded on the individual merits, and services ren<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dered
the country; or if no other difference exists, residence in the parts
where the lands lie: the dimensions of the divisions of those lands will
be designated in the following articles.</p>

<pb n="101" xml:id="P0101" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/109/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws of Colonization.</fw>

<p>Art. 11.—A square of land, of which each side is one league of 5,000
yards, or, what is precisely the same, 25,000,000 yards of surface, shall
be named a lot, and this shall be considered as the unity in counting
one, two, or more lots: thus, also, the unity in counting one, two, or
more subdivisions shall be 1,000,000 yards of surface, or a square of
1,000 yards each side, which is the measure of one subdivision: the yard
used in these measurements shall be three geometrical feet.</p>

<p>Art. 12.—Supposing the quantity of land above stated to be the unity,
and a division of the land being made, when distributed into grazing
lands and those, adapted for tillage by means of irrigation, or not re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quiring
irrigation;—this law grants to such projector or the projectors
of plans for colonization, for each 100 families which they convey, and
establish in the State, 5 lots of grazing land, and 5 subdivisions, of which
at least one-half shall be arable land, not requiring irrigation; but they
shall only receive this premium for as many as 800 families, even if they
should introduce a greater number; nor shall any fractional number, be
it what it may, which does not amount to 100, give them a right to any
recompense, even in proportion to its amount.</p>

<p>Art. 13.—If any one or more projectors shall, on account of the fami<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lies
they have conveyed, obtain, agreeably to the preceding article, more
than 11 square leagues, the whole of the land shall be granted to them,
but they shall be under the obligation of selling the surplus within 12
years; and should they neglect to do so, the proper civil authorities shall
do it, selling it at public auction, and delivering to them the net proceeds,
after deducting all the expenses attending the sale.</p>

<p>Art. 14.—To each of the families included in a project of coloniza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
whose sole occupation is the cultivation of the land, one division
of land shall be given; should it also breed cattle, it shall receive also
of grazing land a sufficient quantity to complete one lot; and if it only
breeds cattle, it shall have of grazing land an extent of 24,000,000 super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficial
yards.</p>

<p>Art. 15.—Bachelors shall on marrying obtain a similar quantity, and
those foreigners who marry Mexican women shall have one-fourth more;
.but all those who are alone, or forming a part of no family, whether
they are Mexicans or foreigners, must content themselves with one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fourth
part of the above-mentioned portions, nor will any greater quan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tity
be allowed to them, and the allotments will be assigned to them in
this proportion.</p>

<p>Art. 16.—The families, and single men, who having performed the
journey at their own expense may wish to join any of the new settle<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments,
shall be permitted to do so at any time; and their assignments
of lands shall be to each individual the same as those mentioned in the
preceding articles; but if they do so within the first 6 years of the estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lishment
of the colony, one more subdivision shall be given to each
family, and each bachelor, in lieu of the one-fourth which the 15th
Article designates, shall receive one-third part.</p>

<p>Art. 17.—The government is empowered to augment the assignment
mentioned in the 14th, 15th, and 16th Articles, in proportion to the
number of persons in each family, and to the industry and activity of
the colonists, in conformity with the information relative to those points
conveyed by the municipal authorities and the commissioners; but the

<pb n="102" xml:id="P0102" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/110/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws of Colonization.</fw>

government must always bear in mind the purport of the 12th Article
of the decree of the General Congress on this point.</p>

<p>ART. 18.—Whatever families shall settle in conformity with the 16th
Article shall immediately present themselves to the civil authorities of
the settlement which they have selected, which on finding in them the
requisites which this law demands in the new settlers, shall admit
and put them in possession of the lands to which they are entitled, and.
immediately inform the government, in order that it, or the person
whom it designates for this purpose, may give them the title deeds.</p>

<p>Art. 19.—The Indians of all the tribes on the confines of the States,,
as also those of the wandering tribes in it, shall be received in the
markets without demanding of them any duties on account of the traffic
which they carry on in the natural productions of the country; and, if
thus induced by kindness and confidence any of them should be desirous
(previously making a declaration in favor of the religion and institu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />•
tions) to establish themselves in any of the settlements which may be
formed, they shall be admitted, and obtain the same quantity of land as.
the settlers mentioned in Articles 14 and 15; the natives being always
preferred to the Indians coming from a foreign country.</p>

<p>Art. 20.-—In order that no lands may be left without possessors,,
which will be most sedulously avoided when they are distributed, the'
. divisions will be made in squares or some other figures, although it be
irregular, if the situation requires it; and in the above-mentioned dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tribution,
as also in the selection of those in which the new towns are to
be placed., the owners of the adjacent lands shall be cited, in order to
avoid disputes and contentions.</p>

<p>Art. 21.—If, owing to any mistake in the grant, any land previously
belonging to an individual should be occupied, his claim being proved,
any portion of land wholly unclaimed shall be given to the person who
had obtained it; and, moreover, he shall be indemnified by the occupant,,
agreeably to a just computation made by proper persons and agreeably
to the laws, for all his expenses and the costs of the improvements which
may be on it.</p>

<p>Art. 22.—The new colonist shall, as a species of acknowledgment,,
pay to the State for each lot of pasture land, 30 dollars; 22 for each
subdivision of arable land not irrigated, and 34 dollars for each one of
irrigated land, each in proportion to the kind and quantity of land which
has been allotted to him; but the payment of those sums shall not be
made in less than 6 years after their settlement, and in 3 equal instal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments,
the first at the expiration of the fourth, the others at.the expira<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of the fifth and sixth years, under penalty of forfeiting their lands
should they neglect the payment of any one of these instalments: but
the projectors and military men, mentioned in the 10th Article, are ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cepted,
with regard to those lands which the former have obtained as a
recompense, and the latter agreeably to the documents given them by the
government.</p>

<p>Art. 23.—The municipal authorities, each in its respective district,
shall collect the abovementioned sums gratis, by means of a committee
of its own members or other persons, and shall deliver them as soon as
collected to the person who is the depositary or treasurer of its funds
and receipts, and he shall give the requisite receipt, and, with no other
charge than that of 24 per cent, which, and no more, will be allowed

<pb n="103" xml:id="P0103" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/111/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws of Colonization.</fw>

him, will hold them at the disposal of the government, informing it
monthly of the receipts and disbursements, and of any inattention and
partiality in the collection; the public functionaries and the individuals
of the municipal authorities which have named them, shall be respon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sible
with their property for the conduct of the person, and, of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee,
and in order that their responsibility may be at all times posi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive,
the nominations shall be made by vote, naming each individual,
and the government shall be immediately acquainted with their names.</p>

<p>Art. 24.—The government shall sell to the Mexicans, and only to
them, the lands which they may be desirous of purchasing, but shall
not allow more than eleven lots to fall into the hands of one individual,
and under the express condition, that the purchaser must cultivate the
lands which he obtains by these means within 6 years, under the penalty
of losing them: the price of each lot, in conformity with the preceding
Article, shall be 100 dollars for grazing, 150 for arable not watered, and
250 for irrigated lands.</p>

<p>Art. 25.—Until 6 years after the publication of this law, the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature
of the State shall have no power to alter it, inasmuch as regards
the measurement of lands, the price to be paid for them, the quantity
and description of those which are to be granted to new settlers, and
sold to Mexicans.</p>

<p>Art. 26.—It shall be considered, that the many settlers who within
6 years from the date of their grant have hot cultivated or occupied
according to its quality the land which has been granted to them, have
renounced their rights, and the proper civil authority shall resume the
grant and the title deeds.</p>

<p>Art. 27.—The projectors, and military men, of whom previous men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
has been made, and those who have purchased lands, can sell their
lands at any time, on condition that the purchaser oblige himself to
cultivate them within the period in which the original possessor ought
to do so, including also the time which they have been in his hands;
the other settlers may sell theirs when they have cultivated them wholly,
and not before that time.</p>

<p>Art. 28.—Every new settler from the very day of his settlement can
dispose of his lands by will, made agreeably to the present or then exist-'
ing law, even although he has not cultivated them; and if he should die
intestate, the person or persons who inherit his property agreeably to
the laws, shall succeed to them under the same obligations and condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
that he held them.</p>

<p>ART. 29.—The lands granted in virtue of this law can on no account
be allowed to pass into the hands of religious communities.</p>

<p>Art. 30.—The new settler who shall determine on quitting the State,
in order to establish himself in a foreign country, shall be allowed so to
do, together with all his property, but in this case shall not retain his
land, and if he has not previously sold it, or the sale been effected
agreeably to the 27th Article, it shall be again considered as wholly
belonging to the State.</p>

<p>Art. 31.—Those foreigners who agreeably to this law have obtained
lands, and established themselves in these settlements, are consid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered
from that moment as naturalized in the country, and should they
marry Mexican women will be considered to have established a meri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />torious
claim to obtain the rights of citizenship of the State, except,

<pb n="104" xml:id="P0104" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/112/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws of Colonization.</fw>

however, in both instances the cases provided for by the enactments of
the Constitution of the State.</p>

<p>Art. 32.—During the first 10 years, counting from the day in which
settlements are established, they shall be free from every contribution
under whatever denomination, excepting such as in the event of the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vasion
of an enemy or in order to prevent it every citizen is subjected to,
and the produce and effects of the agriculture, and industry of the new
settlers shall neither pay a duty on transit, or sale in the markets, nor
any other kind of impost in any part of the State, excepting, indeed,
the dues referred to in the following Article. At the expiration of the
abovementioned period the new settlements shall bear the same imposts
as the old settlements, and the colonists those paid by the other inhabi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tants
of the State.</p>

<p>Art. 33.—From the very day of their establishment the new settlers
shall be at liberty to pursue every branch of industry, as well as to work
mines of every description, previously coming to an agreement with the
Supreme Government of Federation relative to those which belong to
the general revenues of the nation, subjecting themselves in the working
of the others to the ordinances and laws already established, or which
may hereafter be established on this subject.</p>

<p>Art. 34.—The towns shall be founded on the spots deemed by the
government, or the person it names for that purpose, most fitting, and
for each of them four leagues square shall be designated, which space
shall be either of a regular or irregular shape, according to the locality.
Abt. 35.—If any one or more of the abovementioned sites should be
the property of an individual, and the establishment of new towns in
them should be of evident public utility, they shall nevertheless be des<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tined
to this purpose; an indemnification agreeably to the decision of
arbitrators being previously given.</p>

<p>Art. 36.—The sites for houses in the new towns shall be given gratis
to the projectors of them, as also to artizans of every description those
which they may require for their workshops, and they shall be sold to
the others at public auction, an estimate of the value being previously
made, on condition of the price being paid in three equal instalments,
the first in six months, the second in twelve, and the third in eighteen;
but every possessor of sites, including projectors and artizans, shall pay
yearly one dollar for each one that he holds, and this sum, as also the
product of those sales, shall be collected by the municipalities, and ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plied
to the purpose of erecting a church in the town.</p>

<p>Art. 37.—At least, inasmuch as is possible, the towns shall be com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed
of natives, and foreigners, and in tracing them care shall be taken
to give them the most appropriate plan to preserve the straightness of
the streets, running in a parallel direction to each other from South to
North, and East to West, in as much as the ground may permit.
Abt. 38.—In order to place the new towns more conveniently, to
regulate their plan, and the exact division of the lands and sites, the
government, in consequence of having admitted the projects, and agreed
with any projector or projectors who have presented it, shall commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion
a skilful confidential agent, giving him those instructions on the
subject which it may deem requisite and proper powers, in order that on
his own responsibility he may name one or more land surveyors, who

<pb n="105" xml:id="P0105" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/113/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws of Colonization.</fw>

may measure the land scientifically, and perform whatever other duties
may be required.</p>

<p>Art. 39.—The government, agreeably to the latest tarif of notaries
public of the old ordinance of Mexico, shall designate to the commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner
his salary, and he, with the consent of the colonists, shall decide
on the dues payable to the land surveyor or surveyors; but the expenses
of both shall be paid by the colonists themselves, and the mode, and the
terms on which each payment shall be made, shall be arranged by an
agreement between all parties.</p>

<p>Art. 40.—As soon as at least 40 families are united, they shall pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed
to the formal establishment of a new town, all binding themselves
by oath, taken before the commissioner, to observe the general Consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution,
and that of the State, and subsequently the commissioner pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />siding
for this the first time, shall proceed to the election of the munici<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pality.</p>

<p>Art. 41.—The new town whose population amounts to 200 inhabi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tants
shall elect a corporate body, if there be no other established within
the distance of 8 leagues, but if there be one it shall be added to its
jurisdiction; the number of members of which the corporation is to be
composed shall be regulated agreeably to the existing laws.</p>

<p>Art. 42.—A reservation being made in favour of all the enactments
of the Constitution of the State, the foreign settlers are permitted to
elect and be elected members of the municipal body.</p>

<p>Art. 43.—Each corporate body shall propose. to the government,
through the medium of the chief of the civil authorities, a tarif of the
municipal and other charges, accompanying a note of the revenues which
it considers calculated to cover them, and if the plan proposed should be
approved of by the government, it shall order that it shall be carried
into effect, without however in any way interfering with whatever the
Congress may determine, and it shall immediately be made acquainted
with it, together with the opinion of the government, and of the above<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mentioned
chief of the civil authority, who shall always forward his
opinion on the subject.</p>

<p>Art. 44.—The government shall send to the head of that department
those individuals who in other parts of the State may be sentenced to
hard labour as vagrants or for other crimes, in order that they may be em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployed
in making and repairing the roads in Texas. These persons may
also be employed in the services of individuals, who shall in that case
pay them the requisite daily allowance, and at the expiration of the
period for which they were condemned, they shall be allowed as settlers
to join any of the nev towns, and to obtain the due quantity of land,
if by the improvement of their conduct they shall, in the opinion of the
aforesaid chief of the civil department, have rendered themselves fit,
but they shall not be admitted without his certificate.</p>

<p>Art. 45.—The government, agreeably to an arrangement with the
proper ecclesiastical authorities, shall see that the new. towns are pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided
with a proper number of clergy, and agreeably to an arrangement
with the aforesaid authorities, shall propose to the Congress the salary
which the new settlers are to pay them.</p>

<p>Art. 46.—As regards the introduction of slaves, the new settlers shall
obey the laws already established, and which hereafter may be estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished
on the subject.</p>

<pb n="106" xml:id="P0106" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/114/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Laws of Colonization.</fw>

<p>Art. 47.—All petitions pending relative to matters which are the sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject
of-this law, shall be decided in conformity with it, and for this
purpose they shall be passed to the government; and those families which
are established within the limits of the State, without having any land
legally designated to them, shall be subjected to it; and those within 30
leagues of the boundaries of the United States of North America, and
10 of the coast of the Gulf of Mexico, shall obey the the dispositions
made by the Supreme government.</p>

<p>Art. 48.—This law shall be published in all the towns of the State;
land in order that it may come to the knowledge of those who compose
the federation, it shall be communicated to (by the secretary of this) their
respective Congresses, the government being specially charged to pass
a certified copy, agreeably to the 161st Article of the Constitution, to
the 3 Chambers, and to the Supreme Executive Power of the nation,
together with a request to the latter, by means of its envoys to foreign
nations, it may be generally known.</p>

<p>
The officiating governor of the State will make himself acquainted
with this law, in order that it may he obeyed, causing it to he published
and circulated.</p>

<p>
Given in town of Saltillo, 24th March, 1825.
(Signed)
RAFAEL RAMOS Y VALDEZ,
President.
JUAN VICENTE CAPOS,
JOSE JOAQUIN DE ARCE ROSALES,
Deputies Secretaries.</p>

</div></body></text>
