<text><front /><body><div type="document"><pb n="423" xml:id="P0423" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/431/" /><p>CONSTITUTION
OF THE
STATE OF COAHUILA AND TEXAS
The Governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas, to all the inhabit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ants
thereof: Be it known, that the organizing congress of said state has
decreed and sanctioned the following political constitution of the State
of Coahuila and Texas.
In the name of the Creator and Supreme Lawgiver of the Universe, the
Congress of the State of Coahuila and Texas, desiring to comply with
the will of the people, their constituents, and for the purpose of duly
fulfilling the grand and magnificent object of promoting the glory and
prosperity of said state, decrees for its administration and government
the following
CONSTITUTION.
Preliminary Provisions.
Art. 1. The State of Coahuila and Texas is the union of all the
Coahuiltexanos.
Art. 8. It is free, and independent of the other Mexican United States,
and of every other power and dominion whatsoever.
Art. 3. The sovereignty of the state resides originally and essentially
in the general mass of the individuals who compose it, but they shall not,
of themselves, exercise any other acts of sovereignty than those pointed
out in this constitution, and in the form which it provides.
Art. 4. In all subjects relating to the Mexican confederacy the state
delegates its powers and rights to the general congress of the same, but
in all that belongs to the internal government and administration of said
state, it retains its liberty, independence and sovereignty.
Art. 5. Wherefore, the right of establishing its fundamental laws
through the medium of its representatives, in conformity to the basis
established in the constitutive act and general constitution, belongs ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clusively
to the said state.
(423 )</p><pb n="424" xml:id="P0424" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/432/" /><p>314
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
Art. 6. The territory of the state is the same as that embraced in the
provinces formerly known by the names of Coahuila and Texas. A con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitutional
law shall mark out its limits, in respect to the adjoining states,
of the Mexican Confederacy.
Art. 7. For the better administration thereof, the territory of the state
shall for the present be divided into three departments as follows,—
viz:
Bexar,—Embracing all the territory corresponding to what was called
province of Texas, which shall form one sole district.
Monelova,—Consisting of the district of the same name, and that of
Rio Grande.
Saltillo,—Comprehending the district of the same name, and that of
Parras.
Art. 8. Hereafter congress may alter, vary, and modify this division
of the territory of the state as it shall judge most conducive to the felicity
of the people.
Art. 9. The Roman Catholic Apostolic Religion shall be the religion
of the state. The state protects it by wise and just laws, and prohibits the
exercise of any other.
Abt. 10. The state shall regulate and pay all expense that should be
necessary for the preservation of religious worship, agreeably to the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cordates
the nation should ratify with the Apostolic See, and to the laws
that shall be prescribed on the exercise of the patronato throughout the
republic.
Art. 11. Every man who resides within the limits of the state, al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />though
but transiently, shall enjoy the imprescriptible rights of liberty,
security, property and equality; and it is the duty of said state to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />serve
and protect by wise and equitable laws, these universal rights of
men.
Art. 12. The state is also obligated to protect all its inhabitants in the
exercise of the right which they possess of writing, printing and freely
publishing their sentiments and political opinions, without the necessity
of any examination, or critical review previous to their publication, under
the responsibility and restrictions that are now, or shall be hereafter es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablished
by the general laws on the subject,
Art. 13. From and after the promulgation of the constitution in the
capital of each district, no one shall be born a slave in the state, and after
six months the introduction of slaves under any pretext shall not be
permitted.
Art. 14. In return, all men who inhabit the state shall obey its laws,
respect its constituted authorities, and constribute to its support in the
manner it requires.
Art. 15. All kinds of vacant property within its limits, and all intestate
property without a legal successor, shall belong to the state.
Art. 16. The state shall be composed solely of two classes of persons,—
viz: Coahuiltexanos, and the citizens of Coahuila and Texas.
Art. 17. The following persons shall be Coahuiltexians.
( 424)</p><pb n="425" xml:id="P0425" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/433/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
315
First,—All men born and domiciliated in the territory of the state,
and the children of the same.
Second,—All those born in any other part of the territory of the repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic,
who shall fix their residence in the state.
Third,—Foreigners, of whatever nation, now legally established in the
state.
Fourth,—Foreigners, who obtain from congress letters of citizenship,
or become domiciliated in the state according to the law that shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />acted
as soon as the general congress issues the general Nuturalization
Law, which, agreeably to the 27th prerogative conferred by the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of the republic, ought to be established.
Abt. 18. The following shall be freemen of Coahuila and Texas.
First,—All men born in the state and domiciliated in any part of the
territory thereof.
Second,—All citizens of the other states and territory of the republic,
as soon as they are domiciliated in the state.
Third,—All sons of Mexican citizens, born without the territory of
the republic, who establish their domicil in the state.
Fourth,—Foreigners, from whatever country, now legally domiciliated
in the state.
Fifth,—Foreigners, now enjoying the rights of Coahuiltexanos, who
shall obtain special certificates of citizenship from congress. The laws
shall prescribe the qualifications and conditions for granting them the
same.
Abt. 19. Those born within the territory of the republic, and foreign<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers
domiciliated therein (except minors, when the political liberties of the
country were proclaimed, who did not remain true to the cause of its
independence, but emigrated to a foreign country, or dependency of
Spain, shall neither be Coahuiltexians, nor citizens of Coahuila and
Texas.
Abt. 20. The rights of citizenship shall be forfeited.
First,—By becoming naturalized in a foreign country.
Second.—By admitting office, pension, or title form a foreign govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
without permission from congress.
Third,—By receiving executory sentence, wherein corporal or dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />graceful
punishment is imposed.
Fourth,—By a person selling his vote, or buying that of another for
himself, or a third person, whether in popular assemblies, or in any other;
and by violation of public trust in the said assemblies, whether by presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dents,
secretaries, tellers, or those discharging any other public func<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.

Fifth,—By having resided five years in succession without the territory
of the republic, without a commission from the general government or
that of the state, or without licence from the latter.
Abt. 21; A person who forfeits the rights of a citizen cannot recover
the same, unless reinstated therein by congress.
( 425 )</p><pb n="426" xml:id="P0426" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/434/" /><p>316
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
Art. 22. The exercise of the said rights shall be suspended.
First,—For moral or physical disability, after judicial investigation.
Second,—For not having attained the age of twenty-one years, except
married persons, who shall enjoy the said rights from the time they marry,
whatever be their age.
Third,—For being debtor to the public funds, the time of payment hav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
expired, and payment having been demanded.
Fourth,—For being under criminal prosecution, until acquitted or sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenced
to a punishment not corporal or disgraceful.
Fifth,—For having no employment, trade, or known way of sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port.

Sixth,—For not being able to read and write, but this provision shall
not take effect until after the year 1850, and with respect to those who
shall enter on the exercise of the rights of citizens after that time.
Art. 23. Only for the causes specified in articles 20 and 22 shall the
rights of citizenship be forfeited or suspended.
Art. 24. None but citizens in the exercise of their rights shall vote for
officers of the state in cases designated by law, and such only shall be
elected to the said officers, and all othes of the state.
Art. 25. Offices requiring persons belonging to any professional facul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty
shall be excepted from the latter part of the preceding article, and may
be conferred upon persons not residing in the state.
FORM OF GOVERNMENT OF THE STATE.
Art. 26. The object of the government shall be the happiness of the
individuals who compose it, since the end of every political society is no
other than the wellbeing of its members.
Art. 27. The officers' of the gevernment cloathed with any kind of
authority are mere agents or delegates of the state, responsible to the
same for their political conduct.
Art. 28. The federal republican shall be the form of government of the
state. In pursuance thereof there shall be no hereditary office or privi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege
in the state.
Art. 29. The supreme powers of the state shall be divided for its ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ercise
into legislative, executive and judicial, and neither these three pow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers,
or any two of the same, shall ever be united in one corporation or
person, nor shall the legislative be deposited in one individual alone.
Art. 30. The exercise of the legislative power shall reside in a congress
composed of deputies, chosen by the people.
Art. 31. The executive power shall reside in a citizen, to be styled the
governor of the state, and to be chosen by the people.	’
Art. 32. The exercise of the judicial power shall reside in the tribunals
and courts of justice established by this constitution.
(426 )</p><pb n="427" xml:id="P0427" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/435/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
317
TITLE 1.
LEGISLATIVE POWER OF THE STATE.
SECTION I.
Deputies of Congress.
Art. 33. Congress shall be the union of the deputies, representing
the state, and elected in conformity to this constitution. Until the year
1832, it shall consist of the number of twelve deputies proper, and six
substitute deputies.
Art. 34. During the present year, and last of every ten years follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing,
Congress, may augment the number of its deputies, on the basis of
one for every thousand souls:
Art. 35. The election of deputies proper and substitutes, shall be
holden at the same time in each and every district of the state.
Art. 36. To be eligible to the office of deputy, proper or substitute
the following qualifications at the time of the election shall be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired.

First,—To be a citizen in the enjoyment of his right.
Second,—To have attained the age of Twenty-five years.
Third,—To be domiciliated in the state, and te have resided therein
the two years immediately preceding the election.
Art. 37. Those not born within the territory of the republic, to be
■eligible as deputies, proper or substitutes, shall have been eight years
domiciliated therein, and possess real estate to the amount of eight thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand
dollars, or an industrious employment that that shall yield them one
thousand dollars per annum, and the qualifications provided in the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceding
article.
Art. 38. Natives of any other part of America, subject to Spain in
1810, and not now annexed to any other nation, nor in subjection to
the former, shall be excepted from the foregoing article, and' for such
three years domicil in this republic, and the requisites prescribed in
article 36, shall be sufficient.
Art. 39. The following persons cannot be deputies, proper or sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitutes.

First,—The governor and vice governor of the state, and members
of the executive council.
Second,—Officers of the republic.
Third,—Civil officers appointed by the executive of the state.
Fourth,-—Ecclesiastics, exercising any jurisdiction or authority in the
district where the election is holden.
Fifth,—Foreigners in time . of war between their own country and
this republic.
(427)</p><pb n="428" xml:id="P0428" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/436/" /><p>318
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
Abt. 40. The officers of the republic, or of the state, comprised in
the foregoing article, to be eligible as deputies, shall have entirely ceased,
in office four months previous to the election.
Abt. 41. Should the same person be chosen deputy proper for two
or more districts, he shall prefer the choice for that wherein he is
domiciliated for the time being. Should he not be domiciliated in either,
that of his native district shall prevail. Should he neither be domicili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated
in, or a native of any of said districts, that of the one which the
deputy chosen shall himself designate, shall be effective. In either of
these cases, or in that of death, should it be impossible, in the opinion,
of congress, for the deputies proper to perform their functions; the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective
substitute deputies shall fill their places.
Abt. 42. Should the same person also prove to be elected substitute
deputy for two or more districts, the same order of preference shall be
observed as provided in the three first parts of the preceding article,
and in the other districts that remain without a. substitute deputy, the
vacancy shall be filled by the one who received in the respective electoral
assembly, the next highest number of votes to that of the one whose’
place is to be filled. In case of a tie, it shall be decided by lot.
Abt. 43. The deputies during the time of discharging their duties,
shall receive from the state treasury such pay as the preceding con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress
shall assign them, and they shall furthermore be paid the amount
that said congress thinks proper for the expense they have to incur in
repairing to the place of session, and in returning home after the close of
the same.
Abt. 44. At no time, in no case, and to no authority shall the deputy
be responsible for the opinions they manifest in the discharge of their
duties. In criminal actions that should be commenced against them
they shall be tried by the tribunals hereinafter mentioned, and from
the day of their election until the expiration of the two years term of
service, they can be accused only before congress, which shall form itself
into a grand jury, for declaring whether there be a just ground of ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.

Abt. 45. During the time of their service, reckoned for this object
from the day of their election, they can obtain no office of provision of
the executive, either for themselves, or request it for another, not even
promotion, except by the scale in their respective career.
SECTION II.
ELECTION OF DEPUTIES.
Abt. 46. For the election of deputies, municipal and district electoral
assemblies shall be holden.
(428 )</p><pb n="429" xml:id="P0429" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/437/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
319
PARAGRAPH FIRST.
Municipal Electoral Assemblies.
Art. 47. Municipal electoral assemblies shall be composed of citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zens
in the enjoyment of their rights, domicilated and resident within the
limits of the respective Ayuntamiento. No person of this class shall
-decline attending the same.
Art. 48. Said assemblies shall be holden on the first Sunday, and day
following, in the month of August of the year preceding that of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />newal
of congress, for choosing district electors, who are to elect the
deputies, and eight days previous, the president of each Ayuntamiento,
without the necessity of awaiting any orders shall. convoke the citizens
of his district by the proper edict, or as the custom may be, to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vene
in order to hold the election at the time and in the manner this
constitution provides, previously giving notice to the haciendas and ran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chos
of said district that it may come to the knowledge of the inhabi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tants
thereof.
Art. 49. That the citizens may more conveniently attend, each Ayun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tamiento,
according to the locality and population of its territory, shall
determine the number of municipal assemblies to be formed within
its limits, and the public places where they shall be holden, designating
to each the places corresponding thereto.
Art. 50. They shall be presided, one by the chief of police, or the
Alcalde, and the rest by the other individuals of the Ayuntamiento, as it
shall fall to them. by lot, and in default of the latter, said corporation
shall choose for president of the respective municipal assembly, an in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitant
of the district assigned thereto, who can read and write.
Art. 51. On the aforementioned Sunday in August, the hour of the
meeting having arrived, and the citizens assembled in the place ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed,
being together, the said assembly shall commence by choosing
from among themselves, by majority of vote one secretary and two tellers,
who can also read and write.
Art. 52. The election shall remain open on both days specified in
article 48, four hours each, divided in morning and evening, and a reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ister
shall be kept in each assembly to record therein the votes of the
citizens convened to choose the district electors, entering alphabetically
the names of the voters and candidates.
Art. 53. To be eligible as district elector it shall be required to be a.
citizen in the exercise of his rights, to have attained the age of twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five
years—to be able to read and write, and to be domiciliated and resi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent
in the same district one year, immediately preceding the election.
Art. 54. Each citizen shall vote for the respective district elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors,
viva voce or in writing, in the former case the voter shall call the
name of those for whom he votes, in an audible voice, and should he
give in his vote in writing, the secretary shall read the ticket in the same
(429 )</p><pb n="430" xml:id="P0430" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/438/" /><p>320
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
manner, and enter the same in the register, indispensably in the presence
of the voter. No person shall vote for himself in this or the other elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />toral
acts under penalty of losing the right of voting.
Abt. 55. In a district where only one deputy is to be elected, eleven,
and where two or more, twenty-one electors shall be chosen.
Abt. 56. Doubts or controversies that arise whether any person or
persons present possess the qualifications required for voting shall be
decided verbally by the assembly, and the decision shall be executed
without appeal for that time and purpose only, it being understood that
the doubt shall not turn upon the provision of this constitution, or other
laws. Should there be a tie in resolving thereon, absolutory sentence
shall be given.
Abt. 51. Should complaints arise of bribery, subornation, or force
to cause the election to result in favor of particular persons, the case
shall be publicly and verbally canvassed and brought to a decision.
Should the accusation prove to be true, the offenders shall be deprived
of a voice, active and passive. False accusers shall suffer the same pen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alty.
From this decision there shall be no appeal. Doubts in regard
to the nature of the testimony shall be decided in the manner stated in
the preceding article.
Abt. 58. Municipal assemblies shall be holden with open doors, with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out
any guard and no person, of whatever class, shall appear armed
therein.
Abt. 59. The election on both days having terminated, the president,
secretary and tellers of each assembly shall proceed to count and cast up
the number of votes received by the several candidates in the register,
and sign the same, which having been done the assembly shall be dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />solved,
and any other act in which they interfere shall not only be null,
but shall be considered an offence against the public safety.—Said reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ister
shall be delivered enclosed to the secretary of the respective Ayun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tamiento.

Abt. 60. On the second Sunday of the month of August aforesaid,
each Ayuntamiento shall convene in their respective town halls in public
session. In their presence, the president, tellers and secretary of the
municipal assemblies being also present, the registers shall be opened,
and in view of all of said registers, a general list shall be formed al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />phabetically,
comprising all the candidates and number of votes they
have received.
Abt. 61. Said list, and the act of corporation that shall be writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ten
out relative to the subject, shall be signed by the president of the
Ayuntamiento, and secretary of the same, and the secretaries of the as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />semblies.
Two copies of the aforementioned list shall then be drawn
off, authorized by the same persons, one which shall be immediately
posted in the most public place, and the other delivered with the corre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sponding
official letter, signed by the president of the Ayuntamiento to
two individuals whom said board shall appoint from its own body that
they may proceed to the capital of the district to join those commissioned
(430)</p><pb n="431" xml:id="P0431" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/439/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
321
by the other Ayuntamientos, in order to make the general regulation of
the votes.
Art. 62. On the fourth Sunday in August those commissioned by
the Ayuntamientos shall present themselves, with the credentials of their
appointment, to the chief of police, and in his default, to the first al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />calde
of the capital of the district, and the former or latter, as the case
may be, presiding, they shall meet in the town halls in public session,
and, in view of all the lists, shall form a general list of the persons chosen
district electors by the citizens of their respective district, stating the
number of votes they have received, and places of their residence.
Art. 63. In order to make the said general regulation of votes, the
concurrence of four commissioners at least shall be required. In dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricts
where said number cannot meet, the Ayuntamiento of the capital
town shall choose from their own body the persons wanting to complete
the same.
Art. 64. The citizens resulting, by this general scrutiny, to have the
greatest number of votes in the list, shall be considered constitutionally
chosen as electors In case of a tie between two or more persons it shall
be decided by lot.
Art. 65. The aforementioned list, and act relative to the subject shall
be signed by the president, commissioners, and secretary of the Ayunta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />miento
of the capital of the district. Copies of both shall be drawn off
authenticated by the same persons, and forwarded by the president to the
permanent deputation of congress, to the governor of the state, and to
the Ayuntamientos within the precincts of the district.
Art. 66. Said president shall forward the corresponding official letter
forthwith to the electors chosen, in order that they may meet in the
capital of the district on the day provided by the constitution, for the
purpose of holding the electoral assembly of the same.
PARAGRAPH SECOND.
District Electoral Assemblies.
Art. 67. District electoral assemblies shall be composed of the electors
chosen by the citizens in the municipal assemblies, who shall meet in
the capital of the respective district to choose the deputy or deputies
corresponding thereto, to meet in congress as representatives of the
state.
Art. 68. Said assemblies shall be holden at the expiration of fifteen
days from making the general regulation of votes mentioned in article
62, the electors convening in the town halls or in the building con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sidered
most appropriate for so solemn an act, with open doors, and with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out
a guard, and no person, of whatever class, shall appear armed in the
said assemblies.
Art. 69. They shall be presided by the police chief and in his de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fault,
by the first alcalde of the capital of the district, commencing
their sessions by choosing from their own body, by majority of vote, a
secretary and two tellers; the president shall then cause the credentials
(431)</p><pb n="432" xml:id="P0432" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/440/" /><p>322
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
of the electors to be read, which shall be the official letters, wherein
they were notified of their appointment.
ART. 70. The president shall then inquire if there be any legal nullity
on the part of any elector for his being such; and should it be proved
in the act that there is, the elector shall loose the right of voting. The
president shall afterwards also enquire if any bribery, subornation, or
force has been used for the election of any particular person, and should
it be proved in the act that there has, the delinquents shall be de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prived
of a voice, active and passive, and false accusers shall suffer the
same penalty. Doubts that arise in either case shall be decided by the
assembly, in the manner mentioned in article 56.
Abt. 71. The electors present shall then immediately proceed to make
choice of the deputy or deputies corresponding to the district, and they
shall be elected one by one by secret scrutiny, by means of slips which
each elector shall deposit in an urn placed upon a table at the foot of
a Crucifix, after being sworn before the same, and by the president that
for deputies to the congress of the state, he will give his vote for those
citizens, who in his opinion possess the qualifications of education, in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tegrity,
probity, and well known adherence to the cause of the national
independence.
Art. 72. On conclusion of the voting, the president, tellers and secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary
shall examine the votes, and the candidate who received more than
one half of the votes shall be deputy, constitutionally elected, the presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent
declaring each election. Should no one have received the absolute
majority, the two highest candidates shall be run in a second balloting.
Should more than two persons have received a like respective majority,
they shall all be run in the second balloting, and the same shall be done
when no one has received said majority, but all an equal number of votes.
In all these cases the candidate receiving the majority of votes shall be
elected; should there be a tie, the balloting shall be repeated once only,
and should there still be a tie, it shall be decided by lot.
Abt. 73. Should one individual only have received the respective ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority,
and two or more persons an equal number of votes, but greater
than that of all the others, to decide which of them shall run in a second
balloting with the former, there shall be a second balloting between them,
and the one who should receive the most votes shall enter in competition
with the candidate who received the respective majority. In case of a
tie the balloting shall be repeated, and should there still be a tie, it
shall be decided by lot. In the second balloting between the one who
received the respective majority over all the candidates, and his rival,
the provision made in the last part of the preceding article shall be
observed.
Art. 74. When one person only has received the respective majority,
and all the rest an equal number of votes, to determine which of the
latter shall enter in competition in a second balloting with the for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mer,
the entire provision made in the preceding article with this view
( 432 )</p><pb n="433" xml:id="P0433" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/441/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
323
in respect to those between whom there was a tie shall be executed, and
to determine also which of the rival candidates shall be elected deputy,
the provision of the last part of said article shall be observed.
Art. 75. The election of deputies proper having closed, that of the
substitutes shall immediately follow in the same method and form, and
the latter having also terminated, a list containing the names of all the
deputies elected, signed by the secretary of the respective assembly, shall
be immediately posted in the most public place. The electoral act shall
be signed by the president and all the 'electors, and the former, the sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retary
and tellers, shall forward copies, authenticated by themselves, to
the permanent deputation of congress, to the governor of the state, and
to all the ayuntamientos of the district. Said assemblies, as soon as they
have performed the acts pointed out in this law, shall immediately dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />solve,
and any other in which they interfere shall be null, and further<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />more
reputed an offence against the public safety.
Art. 76. The president shall also seasonably dispatch the correspond<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
official letter to the deputies proper and substitutes, accompanied by
an attested copy of the act, to serve them as a credential of their elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.

Art. 77. No citizen shall decline discharging from any cause or pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />text,
the duties mentioned in this section.
SECTION III.
HOLDING sessions.
Art. 78. Congress shall meet every year and hold its sessions, at the
place that shall be designated by law for that purpose. When it should
find it convenient to remove to another place, it may do so, provided,
that two-thirds of all the deputies shall so agree.
Art. 79. The deputies shall present their credentials to the standing
deputation of congress that it may proceed to examine and determine
on the same, having in view the attested copies of the elections of the
electoral district assemblies.
Art. 80. On the 28th of December of the year preceding that of the
renewal of congress, the deputies newly elected and members of the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manent
deputation shall meet in public session, and the president and
secretary of said deputation shall act as such in said assembly. Said as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sembly
shall discuss the subject of the legality of the credentials and
qualifications of the deputies, and doubts that arise in regard to those
two points shall be decided by said assembly, by majority of vote, those
members of the standing deputation who have not been re-elected not
having a vote.
Art. 81: The president shall then administer to the deputies the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />responding
oath to respect the constitutive act, the constitution of this
republic, and that of- the state, and cause the same to be respected, and
fully to fulfil the duties of their trust.
28 —VOL. 1.
(433 )</p><pb n="434" xml:id="P0434" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/442/" /><p>324
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
Art. 82. The deputies shall then proceed to elect from among them<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />selves
by ballot, and majority of all the votes, a president, vice president
and two secretaries, with which the permanent deputation shall cease
in all its functions, and the members thereof immediately retiring, should
they not have been re-elected, the president of congress shall declare
that said body is solemnly and legally established.
Art. 83. For holding all other sessions, ordinary and extra, the depu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties
shall meet four days previous to that of opening the same in the
manner provided in the first part of article 80, in order to resolve, in
the same form as mentioned in the second part of said article, upon the
legality of the credentials and qualifications of the deputies that are
again presented, and being approved the deputies shall immediately be
sworn as prescribed in article 81, and they shall then proceed to make
choice of a president, vice president and secretaries in the same manner
as provided in article 82.
Art. 84. Congress shall open its ordinary sessions on the first day of
January, annually, and on the first of September, of every year following
that of the renewal of congress, it being the duty of the governor to
attend, in such important acts, who shall deliver a message in accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance
with the state of affairs, to which the president of congress shall
reply in general terms.
Art. 85. On the day following that of the opening of the ordinary
sessions, the governor shall present himself to give information to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress
in writing, of the state of the public administration, proposing the
measures or reforms that may be made in each and every department
thereof.
Art. 86. The sessions of congress shall be daily, with no other inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruption
than that of annual holidays. They shall all be public, except
those whereon subjects are to be treated requiring reserve, which may
be private.
Art. 87. The ordinary sessions of congress, commencing on the first
of January shall continue for that month, and the three following, of
February, March and April, and shall not be prorogued except for one
month at the longest, and in only two cases, first on petition of the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor,
second, should congress itself judge necessary, and in both cases
the vote of two-thirds of all the members shall be required. The ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nary
sessions commencing on the first of September shall continue for
the 30 days of said month, and from no cause, and under no pretence
shall they be prolonged. Both shall be closed with the same formalities
as prescribed for opening the same.
Art. 88. Congress, before closing its ordinary sessions, shall choose
from its own body a permanet deputation composed of three members,
proper, and one substitute which shall continue during the whole of the
interval between both terms of ordinary session. The first chosen shall
be president, and last member proper, secretary thereof.
Art. 89. When circumstances or business occur during the inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />val
between both terms of ordinary session, requiring the meeting of
(434)</p><pb n="435" xml:id="P0435" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/443/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
325
congress, it may be convoked to extra session, provided, that by unani<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mous
vote two-thirds of the members of the standing deputation, and of
the executive council, convened for that purpose, shall so agree.
Art. 90. Should the circumstances or business that occasioned the
extra convocation of congress be very weighty and urgent, the standing
deputation, convened with the council and other members present in
the capitol, shall take the necessary temporary measures, and give notice
thereof to congress as soon as it shall have convened.
Art. 91. When congress meets to hold extra sessions, the same depu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties
shall be called to concur therein, whose duty it is to attend the ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nary
sessions of that year, and they shall be exclusively engaged upon the
subject or subjects comprized in the letter of convocation; but should
they not have concluded the same by the time the ordinary sessions are to.
be opened, the extra sessions shall be closed, and the business for which
they were called, be continued in the former.
ART. 92. Holding extra sessions shall not impede the election of new
deputies at the time prescribed by this constitution.
Art. 93. The extra shall be opened and closed with the same form<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alities
as the ordinary sessions.
Art. 94. The governor shall cause all resolutions adopted by congress
on removal of its residence, or prorogation of its sessions, to be executed,,
without making observations thereon.
Art. 95. Congress in all that pertains to its internal order and govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
shall observe the rules that shall be formed by the present congress,
with power • to make therein, such reforms as it may judge neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary.

Art. 96. The deputies shall be entirely renewed every two years, and
those of the preceding congress may be re-elected, but they shall not be
obligated to accept this charge until after the interval occupied by a
deputation. The deputies of the present congress shall for this time be
excepted from the provision of this article, and shall not be re-elected to.
the next constitutional congress.
SECTION IV.
Powers of Congress, and its Permanent Deputation.
Art. 97. The following prerogatives shall belong to congress.
First,—To enact, interpret, amend or repeal the laws relative to the
administration and internal government of the state in all its branches.
Second,—Regulate the votes received by citizens at the electoral dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict
assemblies for governor, vice governor and councillors, and make
choice of the same, as the case may be.
Third,—To decide by ballot the ties that occur between two or more
persons in elections to said trusts.
( 435 )</p><pb n="436" xml:id="P0436" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/444/" /><p>326
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
Fourth,—Resolve upon doubts that arise upon said elections, and upon
the qualifications of the persons elected.
Fifth,—Examine the reasons offered by those elected for not accepting
said' offices, and resolve thereon as it shall think proper.
Sixth,—Form itself into a grand jury for declaring whether there be a
just ground of action, both £or crimes of office, and for crimes in general,
committed against the deputies of congress, the governor, vice governor,
members of the council, secretary of state, and members of the supreme
tribunal of justice of the state.
Seventh,—Render the responsibility. of the said public functionaries
effectual, and provide that it be exacted of the other officers as the case
may be.
Eighth,—Determine every year the state expenditures in view of the
pre estimates, to be presented by the executive.
Ninth.—Establish or confirm the imposts, or contributions necessary
for covering said expense in accordance with this constitution, and that
of the republic. Regulate their collection, determine their application,
and approve their distribution.
Tenth,— Examine and approve the accounts of the disposition of all
the funds of the state.
Eleventh,—Contract debts in case of need, on the credit of the state,
and designate guaranties for covering the same.
Twelfth,—Enact what is proper for the administration, preservation,
and alienation of the property of the state.
Thirteenth,—Create, suspend or abolish the public offices-of the state;
assign, diminish or augment them their salaries, recesses, or labours.
• Fourteenth,—Grant rewards or recompenses to corporations or persons
who may. have rendered signal services to the state, and decree public
honors to perpetuate the memery of great men.
Fifteenth,—Regulate the method of recruiting the men required for
the service or replacement of the companies of the standing garrison
militia, of cavalry, or of active militia, belonging to the same auxiliary
arm of defence as the former, which are destined to the defence of the
state by their institution, and approve of the allotments made among the
towns of the state, of the portions that respectively belong to them for
fulfilling that object.
Sixteenth,—Enact what is proper for the enrollment and instruction
of the civic militia of the state, and appointment of its officers agreeably
to the discipline that is now, or shall be hereafter prescribed by general
law.
Seventeenth,—Promote and encourage public knowledge and education
by laws, and the progress of the sciences, arts, and useful establishments,
removing the obstacles that retard such commendable objects.
Eighteenth,<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />-Protect
the political liberty of the press.
Nineteenth,—Intervene, and give
or withhold its consent in all those
acts and cases wherein it is provided in this constitution.
(436)</p><pb n="437" xml:id="P0437" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/445/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
327
Aet. 98. The following shall be the powers of the standing depu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tation.

First,—To watch over the observance of the constitutive act, constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
and general laws of the union, and the private laws of the state in
order to give notice to congress of the violations it may have noticed.
Second,—Convoke congress to extra session as the case may be, and in
the manner prescribed by this constitution.
Third,—Discharge the functions assigned it in articles 79 and 80.
Fourth,—Notify substitute deputies in order that they may join con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress
in their turn in lieu of the deputies proper; and in case of default
or absolute impossibility of both, communicate the corresponding orders
to the respective district, that it may proceed to a new election.
Fif th,—Receive the certified copies of the acts of election of the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />toral
district assemblies for governor, vice governor, and members of the
executive council, and deliver them to congress as soon as it. is installed.
SECTION V.
Formation and Promulgation of Laws.
Aet. 99. The form, intervals, and mode of proceeding in discussion
and in voting on projects of law or decree shall be provided in the internal
rules of congress.
Aet. 100. No project of law or decree that should be rejected accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
to the rules, shall be again proposed until the ordinary sessions of the
year following; but this shall not prevent any one or more of their arti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cles
from forming a part of other projects not rejected.
Aet. 101. One more than the half of the entire number of deputies
shall form a quorum for dictating measures and steps not possessing the
character of law or decree. For discussing and voting upon projects of
law or decree, and dictating orders of great importance, the concurrence
of two-thirds of all the members shall be required.
Aet. 102. Should a project of law or decree, after being discussed, be
approved, it shall be communicated to the governor, who, should he also
approve it, shall immediately proceed to promulgate and circulate the
same with the corresponding formalities; but should he not, he may make
thereon such observations as he may deem proper, previously hearing the
council, and shall return the same with his remarks to congress within
ten available days, reckoned from its reception.
Aet. 103. The projects of law or decree returned by the governor ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording
to the preceding article shall be discussed the second time, and
the public speaker, whom the executive should designate, may attend the
discussion. Should they be approved by two-thirds of the members pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent,
in this second discussion, they shall be again communicated to the
governor, who, without objecting, shall immediately proceed to
their formal promulgation and circulation, but should the said
(437 )</p><pb n="438" xml:id="P0438" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/446/" /><p>328
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
projects not be approved in this form, they cannot be again proposed un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />til
the sessions of the year following.
Abt. 104. Should any project of law or decree, not be returned by the
governor within the time assigned'in article 102, it shall be considered
from that very fact as sanctioned, and shall be promulgated as such,
unless congress should have closed or suspended its sessions during said
term, in which case it shall be returned on the first day of the next term
of session.
Abt. 105. Laws shall be repealed with the same formalities, and by the
same steps as they are established.
APPENDIX TO TITLE FIRST.
Election of Deputies to the General Congress.
Abt. 106. The electoral district assemblies, on the same day, and in
the same method they must perform the election of deputies to the state
congress, shall proceed to elect the individuals who are to elect the depu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties
to the general congress, choosing, for every seven thousand souls, one
person possessing the qualifications required by article 53 of this constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.
In districts wherein there proves to be an excess of population of
more than three thousand five hundred souls, for this fraction another
elector shall be chosen, and in those, whose populaion does not amount
to seven thousand, one shall be chosen notwithstanding. The election
having closed, said juntas shall forward a certified copy of their act to
the vice governor of the state, and also the corresponding attested copy to
each person elected, to serve him as a credential.
Abt. 107. The electors thus chosen shall repair to the capitol of the
state where they shall present themselves to the vice governor, or person
acting in his stead, and convening under the presidence of either three
days previous to the first Sunday of October, in public session, in the
building they consider most appropriate, they shall choose from among
themselves two tellers and a secretary that they may examine the creden<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tials,
and report on the day following whether they are in conformity to
law. A committee of three persons shall likewise be chosen, to examine
the credentials of the secretary and tellers.
Abt. 108. On the day following they shall again assemble, the minutes
shall be read, and should any defect be found in the credentials or quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fications
of the electors, the meeting shall decide without adjourning,
and the resolution thereof shall be carried into effect without appeal, for
that time and case only, it being understood that the doubt cannot turn
upon any provision in this or any other law.
Abt. 109. On the first Sunday of the aforementioned month of Oc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tober,
the electors having convened, and one more than the half of them
all being present, in the form provided by this constitution for the
election of deputies to the state congress, they shall proceed to the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of those who are to represent the state in the general congress.
(438 )</p><pb n="439" xml:id="P0439" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/447/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
329
This having been concluded, the meeting shall make the proper provision
for complying with article 17 of the federal constitution, and it shall
then dissolve.
TITLE II.
EXECUTIVE POWER OF THE STATE.
SECTION I.
The Governor.
Abt. 110. The governor of the state shall possess the following quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fications
at the time of his election.
First,—He shall be a citizen in the exercise of his rights.
Second,—Born in the territory of the republic.
Third,—Have attained the age of thirty years.
Fourth,—An inhabitant of this state, having resided five years therein,
two of which immediately preceding the election.
Abt. 111. Ecclesiastics, military and other officials of the republic, in
actual service thereof, cannot obtain the office of governor.
Abt. 112. The governor of the state shall continue four years in the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />charge
of his office, and cannot be re-elected to the same office, except on
the fourth year from having ceased in his functions.
Abt. 113. The prerogatives of the governor,, his attributes, and the
restrictions of his powers, shall be as follows.
PREROGATIVES ON THE GOVERNOR.
First,—The governor may make observations upon the laws and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />crees
of congress in the manner and form prescribed by article 102, sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pending
their publication until said congress resolves thereon, unless in
cases excepted by this constitution.
Second,—He may propose to congress such laws or amendments as he
thinks conducive to the general good of the state.
Third,—He may pardon delinquents conformably to law.
Fourth,—The governor cannot be accused for any crime whatever
committed during his term of office, and one year after, reckoned from
the date whereon he ceased in his functions, except before congress, and
after the expiration of that term, not even before congress.
ATTRIBUTES OE THE GOVERNOR.
First,—To take care that the internal order and tranquillity of the
state be preserved, and of its safety without—for both objects disposing
( 439)</p><pb n="440" xml:id="P0440" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/448/" /><p>330
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
of the militia of said state, of which he shall be commander in chief
throughout its territory.
Second,—See that the constitutive act, the federal and state constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
the laws decrees and orders of the general government, and of the
congress of said state-be fulfilled, issuing the proper -orders and decrees
for their execution.
Third,—Form, with the advice of the council, such instructions and
regulations as he deems necessary for the better government of the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partments
of the public administration of the state, which he shall trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit
to congress for approval.
Fourth,— Appoint agreeably to the constitution and laws, all the
officers of state not chosen by the people, or as otherwise provided by law.
Fifth,—Freely appoint and remove the secretary of state.
Sixth,—See that justice be promptly and fully administered by the
tribunals and courts of justice of the state, and that their decisions are
executed.
Seventh,—Take care of the administration and collection of all the
state rents, and decree their disposition according to law.
Eighth,—Suspend from office, as long as three months, and deprive
of even one-half their salary for the same length of time, after hearing
the advice of the council, all offiicers of the executive department, and
of his appointment or approval on violating his orders or decrees, trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitting
the data on the subject to the respective tribunal, should he
think there is a proper ground of action.
Ninth.—Propose to the standing deputation, ■ whenever he thinks
proper after hearing the advice of the council, the convocation of con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress
to extra session.
RESTRICTIONS OF THE POWERS OF THE GOVERNOR.
The governor shall not have power.—
First,—To command the civic militia of the state in person without
the express consent of congress or during its recess, the resolution of the<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />permanent
deputation. Whenever he commands the said militia on the
aforesaid condition, the vice governor shall discharge the duties of gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor.

Second,—Interfere in the examination of causes pending, or dispose
in any manner of the persons of those accused in criminal cases, during
the trial.
Third,—To deprive any one of his liberty or impose punishment upon
him, but when the well being and safety of the state require the arrest
of any person, he may effect it on condition of putting the persons ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rested,
within forty-eight hours, at the disposal of a competent tribunal
or judge.
Fourth,—Take possession of the property of any private individual or
corporation, or disturb him in the possession, use, or benefit thereof.
(440)</p><pb n="441" xml:id="P0441" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/449/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
331
unless it should be necessary for a purpose of manifest public utility in
the judgment of the executive council, in which case he may do so with
the concurrence of the council, and approval of congress, and during the
recess, of the permanent deputation, always indemnifying the party in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terested
agreeably to the opinion of appraisers chosen by the executive
and the said party.
Fifth.—Impede or embarrass in any manner, or under any pretence the
popular elections determined by this constitution and the laws, or that
they have their entire effect.
Sixth,—Leave the capitol to go to any other part of the state for a
longer time than one month; should he require a longer time, or should
he be under the necessity of leaving the state, he shall request licence
from congress, and during the recess, from the permanent deputation.
Art 114. For publishing the laws and decrees of the congress of the
state the governor shall use the following form:
“The Governor of the State of Coahuila and Texas, to all the' inhabi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tants
thereof: Be it known, that the Congress of the State has decreed
as follows:—
(The original words of the Jaw ot decree to be here inserted.)
Wherefore I command it to be printed, published, and duly fulfilled.
SECTION II.
Vice - Gov ern o r.
ART. 115. There shall likewise be a vice-governor in the state, having
the same qualifications as those required for governor; his term of office
four years, and he cannot be re-elected to the same office until on the
fourth year from having ceased in his functions.
Art. 116. The vice-governor shall preside over the council, but with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out
having a vote, except in case of a tie. He shall also be the police
chief of the department of the capitol; and when he officiates as gover<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nor
the office of political chief shall be discharged by a substitute, whom
he shall himself appoint provisionally with the approval of the council.
Art. 117. The vice-governor shall discharge the office of governor
during its vacancy, or when the latter in the opinion of congress or the
permanent deputation is impeded from serving.
Art. 118. When the vice-governor also fails, the councillor whom con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress
appoints shall act in the place of Governor. Should it be during
recess, the appointment shall be made provisionally, until the meeting of
congress, by the permanent deputation.
Art. 119. In case of decease or absolute impossibility during the first
two years of exercising their functions, a new governor or vice-governor
shall be chosen at the time of holding the next election for deputies to
congress.
Abt. 120. For crimes of any kind whatever, committed during his
term of office, the vice-governor can be accused only before congress.
(441)</p><pb n="442" xml:id="P0442" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/450/" /><p>332
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
SECTION III.
Executive Council.
Abt. 121. For the better discharge of the duties of his office the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor
shall have a body for consultation, to be styled Executive Council,
which shall be composed of three voters proper, and two substitutes, of
all whom one only can be an ecelesiastick.
Abt. 122. For being a member of the council the same qualifications
shall be required as for being a deputy. Those not eligible as deputies,
cannot be councillors.
Abt. 123. The council shall be renewed every two years, one voter
proper, and one substitute, the last chosen, retiring in the first, the other
members proper and the other substitute in the second instance, and so
on successively.
Art. 1.24. No councillor can be re-elected until the fourth year from
the expiration of his office.
Art. 125. When the vice-governor attends the council he shall preside
without having a vote, and in that case the vice-governor shall not at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tend.

Art. 126. The secretary of the council shall be one of the members
thereof, in the manner and form provided in its internal rules, which
the council itself shall form and present to the executive, who shall trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit
them to congress for approval.
Art. 127. The attributes of the council shall be as follows.
First.—To give the governor a written report in all business wherein
the law imposes on the latter the duty of requesting the same, and in
other matters wherein the governor himself thinks proper to consult said
body.
Second,—Watch, over the observance of the constitutive act, federal
constitution, and general laws of the union, constitution and private laws
of the state, apprizing congress of any violations it may observe.
Third,—Promote establishment of, and give activity to, all the
branches of prosperity of the state.
Fourth,—Propose nominations of three for filling those offices, wherein
the law exacts this requisite.
Fifth,—Concur with the permanent deputation agreeably to article 89,
on the convocation of congress to extra session, and meet with said depu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tation
for the temporary measures that may be necessary in those cases
mentioned in article 90.
Sixth,—Explain the accounts of all the public funds, and transmit the
same to congress for approval.	'
Art. 128. The council shall be responsible for all acts relating to the
exercise of its attributes.
( 442 )</p><pb n="443" xml:id="P0443" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/451/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
333
SECTION IV.
Election oj Governor, Vice-Governor and Councillors.
Art. 129. On the day following the election of deputies to congress
each and every electoral district junta shall choose a governor, vice gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor,
three councillors proper and two substitutes, holding said election
in the mode and manner provided in articles 71, 72, 73 and 74.
Art. 130. Said election having closed, a list signed by the secretary of
the assembly, comprising the names of the persons elected and offices for
which they were chosen, shall be immediately posted in the most public
place. The acts shall be signed by the president and electors, and at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tested
copies thereof authorized by the said president, secretary and tell<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers
shall be transmitted, enclosed in a certified sheet, to the standing
deputation.
Art. 131. On the day the first ordinary sessions of congress are opened,
the ex-president of the standing deputation shall present the aforemen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned
attested copies, and after they are read, congress shall choose a
committee from its own body, to which they shall be referred, that said
committee may review the same and report thereon on the third day.
Art. 132. On said day congress shall proceed to determine the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
made by the districts, and compute the votes.
Art. 133. The person who receives the absolute majority of votes
of the district electoral assemblies, to be computed according to the whole
number of voters composing the same, shall be governor, vice governor,
or councillor, as the election under consideration may be.
Art. 134. Should no person receive the aforesaid majority, congress
• shall elect for said offices one of the two or more individuals having the
highest number of votes; and the same shall be done when no one has said
respective majority, but all an equal number of votes.
Art. 135. Should one person only receive the respective majority, and
two or more an equal number of votes, but greater than that of all the
■others, congress shall elect one individual from among the former, to be
run in competition for the election, with the person who received the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />■spective
majority.
Art. 136. In case of tie, the balloting shall be repeated once only,
and should there still be a tie it shall be determined by lot.
Art. 137. The office of governor, vice governor and councillors shall
be discharged in preference to any other whatever in the state, and shall
successively have the same preference among themselves. Those elected
do said stations shall take possession thereof on the first of March, and
they cannot decline serving, except the deputies to congress at the time
of the election, and those who, in the judgment of said congress, are mor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ally
or physically disabled.
Art. 138. Should the governor elect from any cause, not be pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent
on said day to enter on the performance of his functions, the vice<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(443
)</p><pb n="444" xml:id="P0444" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/452/" /><p>334
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
governor newly chosen shall enter on the discharge of the office, and
should he also be absent, his default shall be supplied agreeably to arti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cle
118.
SECTION V.
SECRETARY OF STATE.
Abt. 139. The despatch of all business whatever pertaining to the
executive department of the state shall be under the charge of a secretary,,
to be styled Secretary of State.
Abt. 140. For holding said office, it shall be required to be a citizen
in the exercise of his rights, over twenty-five years of age, a native of this,
republic, an inhabitant of this state, with three years residence therein,,
and one year immediately preceding his election. Ecclesiastics cannot
hold said office.
Abt. 141. All laws, decrees, orders regulations and instruc- cir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />culated
to the towns, or directed by the governor to a particular corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
or person, as well as the copies emanating from the department shall
be authoriaed by the secretary, and without this requisite they shall not
be obeyed, or be productive of faith.
Abt. 142. The secretary shall be responsible with his person and office
for whatever he authorizes with his signature contrary to the constitutive<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />act,
the constitution and general laws of the union, or private constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
and laws of the state, and orders of the president of the republic not
manifestly opposed to said constitution and laws, without availing him
as an excuse, his having done so by order of the governor.
Abt. 143. For the internal administration of his office the rules which .
the secretary shall form, and congress approve, shall be observed.
Abt. 144. Said public officer, also the governor, vice-governor and
councillors shall cease, during their trust, to discharge the duties of any
public stations they were filling, as soon as they have taken possession of
office.
SECTION VI.
Department Police Chiefs, and Subordinate or District Chiefs.
ART. 145. In the capital of each department of the state there shall
be an officer charged with the political administration thereof, to be
styled Department Police Chief.
Abt. 146. To be a department chief it shall be required to be a citizen
in the exercise of his rights, to have attained the age of twenty-five years,
to be an inhabitant of the state, with three years residence therein, and
one of which immediately preceding his election.
Abt. 147. The governor on nomination of three by the council, sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ported
by reports from the Ayuntamientos of the respective department,
shall appoint the department chiefs, except the one in the capital.
(444 )</p><pb n="445" xml:id="P0445" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/453/" /><p>Constitution of Coaliuila and Texas.
335
Abt. 148. The chiefs of department shall be immediately subject to
the governor, and in no way to each other.
Abt. 149. In the capitol of each district, except the one where the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partment
chief resides, there shall be furthermore, a subordinate or dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict
chief, appointed by the executive on nomination of three by the
said chief of department.
Abt. 150. The subordinate or district shall possess the same qualifica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
as the department chiefs, with the difference that the domiciliation
and residence must be within the precincts of the same district; and they
shall furthermore, have some honorable way of living, sufficient to afford
them a suitable support.
Abt. 151. The term of office of the district shall be the same as that
of the department chiefs, and, on nomination by the latter, they may also
continue in office.
Abt. 152. No one can decline serving in said trusts, except in case of
re-election to the same within four years of the time of serving, or from
some other legal cause in the opinion of the governor, who shall resolve
after hearing the respective chief of department.
. Abt. 153. Both of these and the department chiefs shall be respon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sible
for all their acts of omission against the constitution and general
laws of the republic, and those of the states, the former to said chiefs of
department, under whose immediate orders they shall act, and the latter
to the governor.
Abt. 154. The attributes of both chiefs, and the manner they are to
■exercise the same, shall be detailed in the regulations for the politico<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />financial
administration of the towns.
SECTION VII.
Ayuntamientos.
ART. 155. It shall belong to the Ayuntamientos to attend carefully
to the police, and internal administration of the towns of the state, and
there shall be Ayuntamientos in all those towns where they have hereto<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore
existed.
Abt. 156. Ayuntamientos shall be established in towns where there are
none, wherein it is proper they should exist, and they shall be estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished
without fail in the district capitals, whatever be the population
thereof, and in towns which, of themselves or with the territory they em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />brace
contain a population to the amount of one thousand souls, unless
-said towns should.be annexed to another municipality, in which case,
(since from other considerations it may not be proper for them to sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />arate,)
in order that they may have an Ayuntamiento, it' shall be so de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clared
by congress, after receiving the report of the governor, and the
■despatch that shall be formed, assigning the limits that are to embrace the
new municipality.
Abt. 157. Towns that should not possess the population assigned,
and which find, it practicable being advantageously annexed to
(445)</p><pb n="446" xml:id="P0446" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/454/" /><p>336
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
another or others, shall constitute a municipality, and the Ayuntamiento
shall be established at the place most convenient in the opinion of the
executive.
ART. 158. In towns wherein Ayuntamientos cannot be established, and
which are so distant from the other municipalities that the latter cannot
attend to the internal administration thereof, the electoral juntas of that
to which they belong shall choose a commissary of police and a sindico
procurador to discharge the duties assigned them in the regulations for
the political administrations of the towns.
Art. 159. The Ayuntamientos shall be composed of the Alcalde or
Alcaldes, Sindico or Sindicos and Regidores, whose number shall be
designated in the aforementioned regulations.
Art. 160. To be a member of the Ayuntamiento it shall be required to
a citizen in the exercise of his rights, over twenty-five years of age, or
twenty-one being married, an inhabitant within the jurisdiction of the
Ayuntamiento, with three years residence therein, one year immediately
preceding their election, to have some capital or trade whereby to subsist,
and to be able to read and write.
Art. 161. Public officers receiving a salary from the state, military
and other officers of the general government in actual discharge of their
duties, and ecclesiastics, cannot be members of the Ayuntamiento.
Art. 162. The Alcaldes shall all be replaced every year, of the regi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dores,
one half their number, and sindicos procuradores the same, should
there be two; should there be only one he shall be replaced every year.
Art. 163. A person who has performed the duties of said trusts, cannot
hold any other municipal office, or be re-elected to that which he filled,
until after two years from having ceased therein.
Art. 164. The members of the Ayuntamientos shall be chosen by the
municipal electoral meetings, which shall be holden in the same manner
as the municipal meetings established for the election of deputies to
congress. The former juntas shall be convoked on the first Sunday in
December, and they shall meet and perform their duties on the second
Sunday and day following.
Art. 165. Pursuant to said meetings those citizens who have received
the greatest number of votes in the respective lists shall be considered
constitutionally elected as Alcaldes, Regidores and Sindicos. In case of a
tie between two or more persons it shall be decided by lot by the Ayunta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />miento
acting at the time of the election.
Art. 166. Should any member of the Ayuntamiento decease, or his
office become vacant from any other cause, the person receiving the high<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est
number of votes in the order of the respective list shall succeed him
in the discharge of the duties.
Art. 167. Ayuntamiental offices shall be municipal charges, which no
one can decline.
(446 )</p><pb n="447" xml:id="P0447" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/455/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
337
TITLE III.
JUDICIAL POWER.
SOLE SECTION.
Administration of Justice in general.
Art. 168. The administration of justice in civil and criminal cases shall
exclusively belong to the tribunals and courts of justice which agreeably
to the constitution should exercise the judicial power.
Art. 169. Neither congress, or the governor can remove cases pending
from an inferior to a superior court; nor can the tribunals and courts of
justice themselves open those already concluded.
Art. 170. Every inhabitant of the state shall be judged by competent
tribunals and judges, established prior to the act by which he is judged,
and in no way by special commission, or retroactive law.
Art. 171. The laws shall regulate the order and formalities to be ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />served
in suits at law. These shall be uniform in all the courts of jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice
and tribunals, and no authority can dispense therewith.
Art. 173. The tribunals and courts of justice, being authorised solely
for applying the laws, shall never interpret the same, or suspend their
execution.
Art. 173. Military men and ecclesiastics, residing in the state, shall
continue subject to their respective authorities.
Art. 174. No affair shall have more than three processes, and a like
number of determinate decisions. The law shall provide which of said
sentences shall produce a warrant of attorney, and from said sentence no
other appeal shall be admitted than that of nullity, in the form, and for
the purposes the law provides.
Art. 175. A judge who has rendered a decision in a case, in any
process thereof, cannot take cognizance'anew in any other process what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever,
or in appeal of nullity interposed in said. case.
Art. 176. Bribery, subornation and prevarication are ground for pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic
action against the magistrate or judge who should commit the same.
Art. 177. Justice shall be administered in the name of the state, in the
manner the laws prescribe.
PARAGRAPH FIRST.
Administration of Justice in Civil Matters.
ART. 178. Every inhabitant of the state shall be perfectly free to ter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />minate
his controversies, whatever be the state of the trial, by means
of arbitrators, or in any other extrajudicial manner. His agree<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(447)
</p><pb n="448" xml:id="P0448" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/456/" /><p>338
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
ments in this particular shall be strictly observed, and the decisions of
arbitrators executed, should the parties on making the mutual promise
not reserve the right of appeal.
Art. 179. Cases of a small amount shall be 'terminated by executive
measures which shall be executed without any recourse. A particular
law shall fix the sum and mode of proceeding therein.
Art. 180. In other civil and criminal matters in respect to wrongs
there shall be a trial by conciliation, and without proving that this means
has been attempted a trial by writing cannot be established, except
in cases which the law itself shall determine.
PARAGRAPH SECOND.
Administration of Justice in Criminal Matters.
ART. 181. All criminal actions, for light transgressions that should
he punished by correctional penalties, shall be decided by executive judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
without the form or shape of trial, and from the result no appeal,
or any other recourse can be interposed. The law shall assign said penal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties,
and determine the crimes to which they correspond.
Art. 182. In grave offences summary information of the fact shall be
drawn up authoritatively, without which requisite and that of the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />responding
consequent warrant that shall be notified to the accused, and
a copy thereof communicated to the jailor, no person can be a prisoner.
Art. 183. Should the judges not be able immediately to fulfil the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vision
of the preceding articles, the person arrested shall not be consid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered
a prisoner but in the light of one detained; and should the jail war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant
not be made known to him within forty-eight hours, and communi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated
to the jailor, he shall be discharged.
Art. 184. A person who gives bail in said cases, wherein it is not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pressly
prohibited by law, shall not be taken to prison, and in whatever
state of the cause it appears that corporal penalty cannot be imposed on
the prisoner, he shall be released under bail.
Art. 185. Those who have to declare in criminal matters upon their
own actions shall do so without being under oath.
Art. 186. All persons may arrest a delinquent in the act, and conduct
him to the presence of the judge.
Art. 187. The greatest care shall be taken that the jails serve only for
securing, and not for molesting the accused.
Art. 188. Criminal causes shall be public, in the manner and form
the laws provide, as soon as it is proposed to receive the declaration of
the accused in reply to the charges.
Art. 189. The confiscation of property shall forever be prohibited, and
even the seizure thereof can only be effected on proceeding in crimes in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />volving
a pecuniary responsibility, and only in proportion thereto.
(448)</p><pb n="449" xml:id="P0449" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/457/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
339
ART. 190. Torture and compulsion shall never be used, and penalties
imposed, whatever be the crimes, shall never pass to the family of him
who suffers them, but they shall have their effect solely upon the person
who deserved them.
Abt. 191. No authority of the state can issue a mandate for searching
the houses, papers, and other effects of the inhabitants thereof, except in
those cases, and in the form, the laws provides.
Art. 192. One of the main objects of attention of congress shall be to
establish the trial by jury in criminal cases, to extend the same gradu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ally,
and even to adopt it in civil cases in proportion as the advantages
of this valuable institution become practically known.
PARAGRAPH THIRD.
Inferior Courts of fustice and Superior Tribunals.
Art. 193. The inferior courts of justice shall continue in the manner
and form that shall be prescribed by law, until in the judgment of con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress
the state rents permit the establishment of learned judges, who shall
be appointed in each district.
Art. 194. In the capital of the state there shall be a supreme tribunal
divided into three halls, each composed of the magistrate or magistrates
whom the law designated, and said tribunal shall have a fiscal, who shall
despatch all the subjects of the three halls. Should the hall consist of
one minister only, said special law shall determine whether colleagues
should be appointed, and the manner and form it shall be done.
Art. 195. The two first halls shall take cognizance in the second and .
third processes of civil cases, of inferior courts of justice, and also of crim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inal
cases according as the laws determine.
Art. 196. It shall belong to the third hall,
First,—to decide the power of inferior judges.
Second,—Determine appeals of nullity, interposed from executing
judgements in first, second and third processes.
Third,—Take cognizance in all compulsive appeals interposed from
the ecclesiastical tribunals and authorities of the state.
Fourth,—Examine the lists that shall be transmitted to the same
monthly, of causes pending in first, second and third processes communi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate
a copy thereof to the governor, and provide for their publication
through the press.
Fifth,—Hear doubts of law that cur to the two first halls, and to the
primary tribunals, and communicate them to congress, through the chan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nel
of the governor, accompanied by the corresponding report.
Art. 197. Actions for transgressions in office entered against in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferior
judges, and also those formed for crimes of the same kind, and
those in general against the deputies of congress, the governor and vice
governor, counsellors, secretary of state, and members of the tribunal of
29—VOL. 1.
(449)</p><pb n="450" xml:id="P0450" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/458/" /><p>340
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
justice shall be opened and closed in all their processes before the said
supreme tribunal. The law shall mark out the other powers of the same
and its respective halls.
Art. 198. In case an action ought to be entered against the whole
tribunal, or any of its halls, congress shall appoint another special tri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bunal,
composed of the corresponding halls and the latter of the magis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trate
or magistrates considered necessary.
Art. 199. The special tribunal appointed by congress for these cases
shall take cognizance of all appeals of nullity in actions of the supreme
tribunal of justice, in those of the individuals mentioned in the preceding
article, and in subjects pertaining to the third hall.
Art. 200. To be a magistrate of fiscal it shall be required to be a citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zen
in the exercise of his rights over twenty-five years of age, a native of
this republic, and an upright and enlightened lawyer.
Art. 201. Both magistrates and fiscal shall be appointed by congress
on nomination by the executive. They shall receive a competent salary,
to be designated by law, and cannot be removed from office, except, from
a legally established cause.
Art. 202. The members of the supreme tribunal of justice shall be
responsible for all their proceedings in the discharge of their functions,
and may be accused therefor before congress by any individual of the
people whatever.
TITLE IV.
SOLE SECTION.
State Revenue.
ART. 203. The taxes of the individuals composing the state shall form
its public revenue.
Art. 204. Said taxes may be direct, general, or municipal, but of what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever
kind they are, they shall be proportionate to the expenditures they
are to cover, and to the property of the citizens.
Art. 205. Taxes can not be levied except for paying the portion cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />responding
to the state of the general disbursements of the republic, and
covering the private expense of the state. The taxes for the latter object
shall be fixed expressly, on the firstgterm of session, every year, and ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording
to the pre-estimate to be presented by the governor, and approved
by congress.
Art. 206. The present taxes shall continue until their repeal be pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished,
and said repeal cannot be decreed except by congress.
Art. 207. There shall be in the capital a general treasury for the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceipt,
custody and distribution of the whole product of the state rents.
(450 )</p><pb n="451" xml:id="P0451" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/459/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
341
Art. 308. No pay that has not been for covering expense approved by
-congress, or by special order of the governor shall be allowed the treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer
in account.
Art. 209. The business rooms of the state revenue shall be regulated
by particular instructions.
Art. 210. Congress shall choose three individuals every year from
within or without its own body, to examine the' accounts of the state
treasury, and afterwards to present or communicate the same, accompa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nied
by their report to congress for approval. Said approval, or the reso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lution
that should be adopted by congress shall be published and circu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lated
to the Ayuntamientos, in order that they may publish and circulate
the same in their districts.
TITLE V.
SOLE SECTION.
Civic Militia of the State.
Art. 211. Corps of civic militia shall be established in all the towns
■of the state, and the said corps shall compose the military force of the
■state.
Art. 212. The formation of said corps, their organization, discipline,
and internal government, shall be regulated by congress in conformity to
the provision made on the subject by the general laws of the republic.
Art. 213. Congress shall regulate the service of said militia, so that
while it is adapted to the purposes of its institution and to the best inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ests
of the state, it may be as little onerous as possible to the citizens.
Art. 214. No Coahuil-Texano can decline lending said service when
required by law, and in the manner it provides.
TITLE VI.
SOLE SECTION.
Public Education.
Art. 315. In all the towns of the state a suitable number of primary
■schools shall be established, wherein shall be taught reading, writing,
arithmetic, the catechism of the Christian religion, a brief and simple ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />planation
of this constitution, and that of the republic, the rights and
duties of man in society, and whatever else may conduce the better edu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />•cation
of youth.
(451)</p><pb n="452" xml:id="P0452" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/460/" /><p>342
Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
Art. 216. The seminaries most required for affording the public the
means of instruction in the sciences, and arts useful to the state; and
wherein, the aforementioned constitutions shall be fully explained, shall
be established in suitable places, and in proportion as circumstances go on
permitting.
Art. 217. The method of teaching shall be uniform throughout the
state, and with this view, also to facilitate the same, congress shall form
a general plan of public education, and regulate by means of statutes
and laws all that pertains to this most important object.
TITLE VII.
SOLE SECTION.
Observance of the Constitution.
Art. 218. The observance of the constitution in all its parts shall
be one of the first and most sacred duties of the inhabitants of the state
of Coahuila and Texas, and neither congress, or any other authority can
exempt them therefrom; and every coahuil-texano may demand said ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />servance,
setting forth with that view to congress or the executive.
Art. 219. For any violation of the constitution whatever, the person
who committed it shall be personally responsible. In order to render said
responsibility effective congress shall dictate the laws and decrees' it
thinks conducive to that end; and furthermore, every year in its first<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessions,
take under deliberation the infringements manifested to the
same by the permanent deputation and executive council, and adopt the
proper resolution thereon.
Art. 220. The public functionaries of the state, of whatever class, shall
make oath, on entering in possession of office, to observe, support and
defend the constitutive act, the constitution of the republic, and that of
the state, and fully and faithfully to discharge the duties of their office.
Art. 221. Propositions upon amendment, alteration, or repeal of any
one or more of its articles, shall be made in writing, and supported and
signed by one-third of the deputies.
Art. 222. The congress in whose time any of the said propositions are
made shall make no further provision, during the two years of its ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions,
than for the reading and printing of the same, with the original
reasons with which they are supported.
Art. 223. The congress following shall receive the propositions for
discussion, or reject them—and if accepted, they shall again be printed,
and circulated by the executive to be read in the proximate electoral
juntas previous to electing the deputies to congress.
(452)</p><pb n="453" xml:id="P0453" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/461/" /><p>Constitution of Coahuila and Texas.
343
Art. 224. The alterations, amendments or repeals proposed shall he
discussed in the congress that follows, and should they be approved, they
shall be immediately published as constitutional articles.
ART. 225. For the amendments, alterations, and repeals indicated, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sides
the rules prescribed in the foregoing articles, all those provided for
forming and repealing laws, shall be observed, with the exception of the
right of making observations granted the governor, which shall not be
conceded in these cases.
Given in Saltillo, on the 11th of March, 1827.
SANTIAGO del VALLE, President.
JUAN Y. CAMPOS, Vice President.
RAFAEL R. VALDES.
JOSE M. VIESCA.
F. A. GUTIERREZ.
JOSE J. de A. EOSALES.
MARIANO VARELA.
JOSE M. VALDES v GUAJARDO.
JOSE C. RAMOS, D. S.
DIONICIO ELIZONDO, D. S.
Wherefore, I command it to be printed, published, circulated, and dulv
fulfilled.
JOSE IGNACIO ARISPE.
Juan Antonio Padilla, Secretary.
(453 )</p></div></body></text>
