<text>

<body>
<div type="document">
<pb n="454" xml:id="P0454" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/462/" />

<head>COLONIZATION LAW
<lb />OF
<lb />THE STATE OF TAMAULIPAS.
</head>

<head>[No. 42.]</head>

<head>December 15th, 1826.</head>

<p><hl rend="italics">The Congress of the State of Tamaulipas enacts the following as a
General Law.</hl></p>

<p>Article 1. Foreigners, who wish to colonize vacant lands in the state,
shall be admitted, and their persons and property protected provided they
submit to the laws of the republic, and those, of the State.</p>

<p>Art. 2. For a foreigner to obtain adjudication of lands he must be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come
domiciliated in some town in the state with a capital of his own to
afford him a decent support, or with a trade or useful industrious pursuit
which he follows; or he must establish a new town with one hundred fam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ilies
at least. Should he establish himself on the northern frontier of the
state, fifty families shall be sufficient for that purpose.</p>

<p>Art. 3. In either case they shall make their petitions in writing to
the governor of the state, who shall resolve thereon with the concurrence
of his council, and audience of the fiscal of the court, of justice of the
state, making them the concessions of lands that shall be hereinafter de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />termined.</p>

<p>Art. 4. Foreigners who claim domiciliation in any of the present
towns, their petition being granted by the executive, shall be sworn by
the respective political authority to observe and to comply with the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitutive
act, the constitution and laws of the republic, and those of the
state.</p>

<p>Art. 5. After this act, the said authority shall provide that, in a book
to be denominated Register of Foreigners, shall be written the name of
the person who shall have taken the oath, mentioned in the foregoing
article, whether he be married, his age, trade, and place of his birth,
setting down also the names of the family he may have, and making rela<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of having taken the oath prescribed. Said books shall be kept in the
archives of each town.</p>

<pb n="455" xml:id="P0455" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/463/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Colonization Law of the State of Tamaulipas.</fw>

<p>Art. 6. Certificates of naturalization and of citizenship shall be grant<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed
to foreign colonists as soon as they obtain that of naturalization from
the general congress.</p>

<p>Art. 7. From the very date whereon a foreigner is thus registered he
acquires domiciliation, and may as such an inhabitant designate (denun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciar)
the vacant land he thinks best, presenting himself to that effect by
writing to the respective Alcalde, who shall decree what is proper for ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />amining,
measuring and marking out the land designated, after citing the
adjoining proprietors should there be any.</p>

<p>Art. 8. The instructive despatch being terminated, and no opponent
of right resulting, the Alcalde shall pass it to the executive of the state,
by whom the title of adjudication and ownership shall be issued to the
person interested, ordering that the Alcalde of the town of his residence
put him immediately in possession of the land granted. All these pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceedings
shall be conducted officially, and the executive shall proceed
with the audience of the fiscal of the supreme court of justice of the
state.</p>

<p>Art. 9. Opposition of right of ownership that is commenced shall go
through the steps of an ordinary civil trial between the designator and
the opponent, the former aided by an agent of the state, whom with the
citation of the fiscal the executive shall appoint. Should the opposition
be for the right of option to the ownership, the executive shall examine
and decide.</p>

<p>Art. 10. The executive shall take care to repeople by this means the
depopulated, and very particularly that the designations and judicial pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceedings
that have to be conducted on account of the same, be not par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alized.</p>

<p>Art. 11. In the same manner he shall take care that no town pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jected
by foreigners be situated within ten leagues upon the coast of the
Gulf of Mexico within the limits of the state, without previously obtain<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
the consent and approbation of the supreme executive of the union.
Beyond said line he shall also take care that, so far as the sites permit,
the new towns be established in contact with the present ones, and with
the conditions he stipulates with the empresarios.</p>

<p>Art. 12. Contracts ratified by empresarios with the excutive are guar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />anteed
by this law so far as they are in conformity to the provisions
thereof.</p>

<p>Art. 13. In the distribution of lands, in view of their diplomas issued
by the supreme executive power, military men, who, according to these
are entitled to land, shall be preferred. Among citizens not military, no
other distinction shall be made than that which is founded in their pri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vate
merit, and services rendered the country; preferring, in parity of
circumstances, a domiciliation in the place to which the lands belong.
The quantity in which the lands are to be distributed is pointed out in
the following articles.</p>

<p>Art. 14. A square of land measuring a league upon each side, or
what is the same thing, a superficies of twenty-five million square va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ras

<pb n="456" xml:id="P0456" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/464/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Colonization Law of the State of Tamaulipas.</fw>

shall be called a sitio, and this shall be the unit for enumerating one,
two or more sitios, in the same manner as the unit for counting one, two
or more labores shall be a superficies of a million square varas, or a
thousand varas on each side, which shall compose a labor. The vara for
these dimensions shall consist of three geometrical feet.</p>

<p>Art. 15. That unit taken as a standard, and observing the distinction
to be made on the distribution of lands, between grazing lands, or those
suitable for raising stock, and irrigable and temporal tillage land, this law
grants to the contractor or contractors of new towns for every hundred
families they introduce and establish in the state five sitios of grazing
land and five labores, of which one-half at least shall be temporal land;
but they shall receive only in the ratio of eight hundred families, al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />though
they shall introduce more, and no fraction not completing a hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
shall entitle them to a premium, not even proportionally. Should
the northern frontier be settled, fifty families shall suffice for enjoying
the benefit of this article.</p>

<p>Art. 16. To each family of those comprised in this contract, whose
occupation is that of cultivating the soil, one labor shall be granted;
should the family raise stock, grazing shall be added to complete a super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficies
of twenty-four million varas.</p>

<p>Art. 17. Foreigners shall have the same assignment after marrying, and
foreigners marrying natives of the country shall have one-fourth more,
and those who are entirely alone, or who do not form a part of any fam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ily,
whether foreigners or natives, contenting themselves with one-fourth
of said assignment, the sole portion that can be granted them, which shall
be completed to them when their assignment is made.</p>

<p>Art. 18. Families and unmarried men, who having emigrated sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />arately
and at their own expense, should wish to annex themselves to any
of the new settlements, may do so at any time, and their assignment of
land shall be respectfully the same as mentioned in the two foregoing ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticles;
but should they accomplish it within the first two years from the
establishment of the settlement, one labor more shall be granted to
families; and unmarried men, instead of one-fourth as pointed out in arti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cle
17th, shall have one-third. Men unmarried, and with a family shall
be considered in the light of families.</p>

<p>Art. 19. For the project of new towns, which one or more for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eigners
offer to settle with families from one hundred upwards, or from
fifty, should they have to settle on the northern frontier, the vacant and
deserted lands of the state, proposition shall be made to congress by the
executive, in order with his report to accord the contracts.
Art. 30. Adjudication and possession to new foreign settlers shall be
subject to the following rules:—</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">First,</hl>—All deserted lands to which at the expiration of fifty days from
the designation thereof for settling, the supposed owners do not appear
to prove their right, shall be considered as open for colonization.</p>

<pb n="457" xml:id="P0457" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/465/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Colonization Law of the State of Tamaulipas.</fw>

<p><hl rend="italics">Second,</hl>—That, which, having been adjudicated by this law, should be
abandoned for five years, and no successor appearing within said term
claiming a right to the same.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Third,</hl>—That, which, having been disputed in adverse trial with re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gard
to the ownership thereof, are found to be voluntarily abandoned by
the parties for three years; or where the parties have withdrawn from the
trial, without the formation of a determinate judgement deciding the
right of either, provided, that the time specified by law for the trial to
be considered as abandoned, shall expire.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Fourth,</hl>—The boundaries that are. established shall be clearly and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinctly
pointed out, expressing the bearings, and specific landmarks,
under the responsibility of the judge of survey.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Fifth,</hl>—The standing waters the lands contain shall likewise be desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated
and adjudicated with the lands.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Sixth,</hl>—Until twelve years reckoned from the date of the publication
of this law, they cannot be alienated or transferred to the ownership of
any one not born in the republic, or who resides out of the state.</p>

<p>Art. 21. The children of foreigners not born in the republic, and
domiciliated therein, may inherit them by testament, or ab intestato. in
equal portions. The portion of him who removes to his country shall be
divided among those who remain in the state, and thus indefinitely. In
regard to this matter the right of inheritance by cross lineage shall not
be in force.</p>

<p>Art. 22. All adjudication and possession of lands designated for
settling shall be made with previous citation of the adjoining proprietors.
As little detriment as practicable shall be occasioned to those who do not
appear, of themselves or by attorney, and their complaints shall not be
heard.</p>

<p>Art. 23. The new settlers shall pay to the state as an acknowledg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
thirty dollars for each sitio of grazing land, uncultivated, or wood<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />land,
that is adjudicated to them; and for those having the benefit of
running water an estimate shall be made by two competent persons,
chosen by the executive and the settler, setting out from the established
rule.</p>

<p>Art. 24. The Ayuntamientos, each in its limits, shall collect said funds
gratis by means of a commission from within or without their own body,
and shall pass them according as they are collected to the depositary or
treasurer that they may be of their funds or means, who shall give the
corresponding receipt; and without further interest than two and a half
per cent., that shall be paid him, he shall place them at the disposal
of the executive, giving him notice every month of the receipts
and remittances thereof, and of any negligence or deceit he may
notice in their collection. Of the management of the treasurer and that
of the commission, the officers themselves and commissioners shall
be responsible with their property; and moreover, the members of the
Ayuntamiento who choose them, and that this responsibility may at

<pb n="458" xml:id="P0458" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/466/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Colonization Law of the State of Tamaulipas.</fw>

all times be effectual, the said appointments hall be made viva voce, and.
notice thereof shall be immediately given to the executive.</p>

<p>ART. 25. The executive shall convoke those born in the republic for
the occupation of vacant lands. who shall be preferred to foreigners in
the order of the older. date of the designations, and, in case of equality,
the natives or inhabitants of the place to which the land designated be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />longs,
shall have the first place, those of places within the state the second,,
and those of the other states of this republic the third, and adjudication
may be made up to the amount of one hundred and twenty-five million
square varas,</p>

<p>Art. 26. Designators of lands, which, in time of the ancient govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
did not perfect their adjudication, shall present themselves to the
respective authority to continue its course according to the state thereof,,
effecting the same within the term of forty days from the date of the pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lication
of this law, and on the contrary said lands shall be considered
open to designation as vacant.</p>

<p>Art. 27. Designations that have passed to the congress of the state'
shall be returned to the executive, who shall cause them to be carried
through the steps provided by this law.</p>

<p>Art. 28. Proprietors of extensive deserted and uncultivated lands shall
likewise settle them with foreigners or Mexicans within the term of five'
years with the conditions that may suit them, and on the contrary, oppo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sition
to the designations made in conformity to this law shall not be
taken into consideration</p>

<p>Art. 29. The lands might be designated by reason of the foregoing
article shall be valued by competent persons chosen by the executive and
the proprietor, for indemnifying the proprietors, unimpeded by any re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sistance
on the part of the latter.</p>

<p>Art. 30. All land of which the proprietor makes no use for himself
shall be considered as deserted and uncultivated land.</p>

<p>Art. 31. Land acquired by virtue of this law cannot pass into mort<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />main;
more than two grants cannot be adjudicated to one individual,
and this should the increased number of those he removes demand it of
necessity. For any violation in these cases the state shall recover the
ownership thereof.</p>

<p>Art. 32. The products of rural industry of said .lands, acquired in
conformity to this law, by natives and foreigners, during the term of ten
years, reckoned from the date of possession shall be free from every tax,
direct or indirect, of whatever denomination, unless specially enacted by
congress for said new settlements.</p>

<p>Art. 33. Said new settlers shall be free to promote every kind of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dustry,
and to undertake the working of mines according to the ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances
on the subject. The machines, tools, or serviceable articles they
introduce for such objects, for the term of ten years shall not paytaxes
imposed by the state, although they be municipal.</p>

<pb n="459" xml:id="P0459" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/467/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Colonization Law of the State of Tamaulipas.</fw>

<p>Art. 34. Lots abandoned in depopulated towns, wherein they wish to
fix their residence, shall be adjudicated to them gratis by the Alcaldes
of said towns.</p>

<p>Art. 35. The inhabitants of the country known by the denomination
of Indians, shall enjoy the benefit of this law.</p>

<p>Art. 36. The executive shall appoint two approval surveyors, and in
default thereof two individuals of known education to concur in the
operations forwarded by this law, which he shall cause to be published in
a manner sufficient for it to arrive to the notice of nations that interest
themselves in colonizing.</p>
</div>
</body>
</text>
