<text>
<body>
<div type="document">
<pb n="460" xml:id="P0460" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/468/" />

<head>NATURALIZATION LAW
<lb />OF THE
<lb />GENERAL CONGRESS
</head>

<head>Principal OFFICE or Secretary of State,
<lb /><hl rend="italics">Department of Internal Relations.</hl></head>

<head>SOLE SECTION.</head>

<p><hl rend="italics">His Excellency, the President of the United States of Mexico, has
been pleased to direct me the follozving Decree.</hl></p>

<p>The President of the United States of Mexico to the inhabitants of
the Republic; be it known: that the General Congress has decreed as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows:—</p>

<p>Article 1. Every foreigner, who has resided for the term of two years
in succession within the limits of the republic, may request a certificate
of naturalization in conformity to what is prescribed in this law.</p>

<p>Art. 2. For obtaining it, he must produce legal information to the
district or circuit judge nearest the place of his residence, with citation
and audience of the promoter fiscal:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">First,</hl>—That he is a Roman Catholic, or the certificate of baptism prov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
the same.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Second,</hl>—That he has some business, useful skill or income whereby
to subsist; the witnesses being required to state what is his business, skill
or income.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Third,</hl>—That he has a good character.</p>

<p>Art. 3. Every person becoming naturalized shall present him<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />self
by writing, one year beforehand, to the Ayuntamiento of the place
in which he resides, manifesting his design in establishing himself in

<pb n="461" xml:id="P0461" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/469/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Naturalization Law of the General Congress.</fw>

the country. Au attested copy of said declaration shall accompany the
documents mentioned in the foregoing article.</p>

<p>Art. 4. He shall present himself with these documents to the governor
of the state, or principal political chief of the federal district or terri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tories
of the confederacy requesting the certificate of naturalization.</p>

<p>Art. 5. The exposition wherewith he requests his certificate of nat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uralization:—</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">First,</hl>—Shall contain an express renunciation of all submission and
obedience to any other nation or foreign government, especially the na<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
or government to which he belongs.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Second,</hl>—It shall be therein stated, that he likewise renounces every
title, token of honor, or grace he may have obtained from any govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Third,</hl>—That he will support the constitution, constitutive act and
general laws of the United States of Mexico.</p>

<p>Art. 6. These conditions having been complied with, the governor of
the state, or principal political chief of the district or territory shall issue
the certificate of naturalization agreeably to the formula annexed to this
law.</p>

<p>Art. 7. Absence to foreign countries with a passport from the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
shall not interrupt the successive residence of those who desire
to become naturalized; provided, that it does not exceed eight months.</p>

<p>Art. 8. The wife, and the children when they are not free, shall be
considered naturalized in the person of the husband.</p>

<p>Art. 9. The children of Mexican citizens, born out of the territory of
the republic shall be considered as born therein.</p>

<p>Art. 10. The right of naturalization shall not descend to the children
of those, who have never resided within the Mexican territory.</p>

<p>Art. 11. The children of foreigners not naturalized born in the Mex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ican
territory may obtain the certificate of naturalization; provided, that
within the year following, their becoming free they present themselves
to the governor of the state, district or territory wherein they wish to
reside.</p>

<p>Art. 12. Naturalization in a foreign country, and admission of office,
commission, income, or token of honor, from another government shall
deprive one of the rights of naturalization.</p>

<p>Art. 13. Every empresario, who comes with the view of colonizing,
and effects it in accordance with the general law, and private law of the
respective state, shall have a right to request a certificate of naturaliza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
which shall be granted him making oath of due obedience to the
constitution and laws.</p>

<p>Art. 14. Foreigners who come to settle upon colonizable lands shall
be considered naturalized after the expiration of one year from their es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablishment.</p>


<pb n="462" xml:id="P0462" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/470/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Naturalization Law of the General Congress.</fw>

<p>ART. 15. Foreigners, who, being in the marine service as soldiers,
sailors, or enrolled therein, declare to the political authority nearest the
place of their residence that they wish to become naturalized, making
oath before said authority to support the constitution, constitutive. act,
and general laws, and that they renounce all submission and obedience to
any other dominion or foreign government, and also, every title, token
of honor or grace that is not of the republic of Mexico.</p>

<p>Art. 16. The authorities to whom those foreigners mentioned in the
foregoing article present themselves, shall forward to the governors of
the respective states semi-annually an exact list, comprising the names,
places, of nativity, age, and married or single state of the persons, who
by virtue of said article should have become naturalized.</p>

<p>Art. 17. Certificates of naturalization shall not be granted to the sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jects,
or citizens of a nation at war with the United States of Mexico.</p>

<p>Art. 18. Those who have presented themselves to the general govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
up to the 1st of March, 1826, requesting to become naturalized,
shall be considered to have employee! the time required, complying with
the other conditions prescribed by this law.</p>

<p>Art. 19. Every year in December, the governors of the states, district,
or territory, shall transmit to the president of the republic a statement,
expressing the names, places of birth, skill or business, and age of the
persons to whom certificates of naturalization should have been granted.
A register of all the same shall be kept in the office of the Secretary
of internal relations, and in the archives of the respective governors.</p>

<p>Art. 20. Every year, on the first month of ordinary session, the sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retary
of internal relations shall transmit to both houses expressly, sepa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate
from the report, a note stating all that-should be expressed in the
reports he should have received from the governors in accordance with
the preceding article, noticing at the conclusion thereof the faults he
might observe on the part of the said governors, or others to whom it
belongs, in conformitv to this law.</p>

<p>FRANCISCO ANICETO PALACIOS,
<lb />President of the Senate.
</p>

<p>CASIMIRO LICEAGA,
<lb />President of the House of Representatives.
</p>

<p>Miguel Duque de Estrada,
<lb />Secretary of the Senate.
</p>

<p>
Jose Perez de Palacios,
<lb />Secretary of the House of Representatives.
</p>

<pb n="463" xml:id="P0463" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/471/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Naturalization Law of the General Congress.</fw>

<head>FORM</head>

<head>For Granting Certificates of Naturalization.</head>

<head><hl rend="italics">N. jV. Governor of N. or Political Chief of N.</hl></head>

<p>N. a native of N. having complied with the requisites and conditions,
provided, by the law of ------ of ------ of the general congress
regulating the manner in which the certificate of naturalization should
be granted to foreigners, and accompanying the documents that prove
the same, by virtue of the authority conferred upon me by the said law,
I do by these presents declare the aforesaid N naturalized in the United
States of Mexico.</p>

<p>(Date, place, and signature of the governor and his secretary.—<hl rend="italics">Two
rubrics.</hl>)</p>

<p>Wherefore, I order it to be printed, published, circulated and duly
fulfilled.</p>

<p>Capitol at Mexico, on the 14th day of April, 1828.</p>

<p>GUADALUPE VICTORIA.</p>

<p>To Don Juan de Dios Cañedo.</p>

<p>And I hereby communicate the same to you for your information; and
the consequent effects.</p>

<p>God and Liberty. Mexico, April 14th, 1828.</p>

<p>CANEDO.</p>

<pb n="464" xml:id="P0464" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/472/" />

<pb n="465" xml:id="P0465" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/473/" />

<head>INDEX
<lb />TO THE
<lb />LAWS AND DECREES.</head>

<div type="index">
  <list type="index">
   <item>Account of estimated expenses to be presented to the Treasurer of Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress <ref>143</ref></item>
   <item>Accusations against Inferior Judges and the Assessor, time prescribed
for their despatch</item>
   <item>Agents of the revenue established at Rio Grande, Brazzos and Nacog<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />doches</item>
   <item>Agent of Excise may contract for periodical payment of duties</item>
   <item>Alcaldes of District Capitals, channels for communicating circular
orders</item>
    <item>Alcaldes may enter houses to arrest smugglers, &amp;c</item>
    <item>“ may examine account books with respect to their legalization.</item>
    <item>Alteration of words in Decree No. 11</item>
    <item>Amendment of articles 46 and 47 in decree No. 32.</item>
    <item>Amnesty</item>
    <item>Arbitrators to give their decision within the time prescribed</item>
    <item>Argumeht and the general congress requested to repeal a certain law. .
Articles 137 and 138 of law No. 37 explained</item>
    <item>“ 142 and 143 of the financial regulations of the towns explained</item>
    <item>“ 43 of decree No. 48 ratified</item>
    <item>“ 3 of the decree of the 8th of April, 1830, how it should have been
understood</item>
    <item>Additional article to the commissioner’s instructions not to be in force in
certain contracts</item>
    <item>Assessment in decree No. 90, explanation in regard to</item>
    <item>Assessor general, appointed and resigning must serve provisionally.</item>
    <item>“ to attend the general and weekly visits of prisons</item>
    <item>Ayuntamientos, relative to the renewal of those of Monclova and Bexar.</item>
    <item>“ to continue until renewed according to the constitution.</item>
    <item>“ renewed according to the constitution</item>
    <item>“ to forward accounts to the chiefs of department</item>
    <item>“ special provisions for electing the officers of</item>
    <item>“ of Austin to appropriate a certain tax to build town halls
and a jail</item>
    <item>“ of the capital loan by the State to</item>
    <item>“ of Nacogdoches, four sitios of land granted to.</item>
    <item>Bachelors degree dispensed with on the part of J. Estrado</item>
    <item>Bangs J. M. declared a citizen</item>
    <item>And Dimitt excepted from article 1 decree No. 183</item>
    <item>Bank, grant to establish in the department of Brazos</item>
    <item>Bilbao, those entitled to its lands and waters</item>
    <item>Boring machine, J. R. Almy permitted to introduce</item>
    <item>Brown J. declared a citizen</item>
    <item>Bureau of accounts attached to the office of secretary of state</item>

</list>
</div>
<p>

PAGE.
143
95
287
118
122
159
77
150
58
34
196
301
93
111
103
241
303
139
145
89
11
44
56
74
144
183
201
223
221
139
196
296
244
83
210
194
30 —vol. 1.

<pb n="466" xml:id="P0466" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/474/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Index to the Laws and Decrees.</fw>

Cantu J. M. to take the oath of governor............................
Chambers T. J. authorized to practice as counsellor.................
Chief agents of the tobacco department, may be authorized to legalize
count books.........................................................
Church festival, prohibitions relative to...........................
Cigar manufactory, for establishing	
"	“ removing.
Civic militia, for reducing that of the state.......................
PAGE.
. 280
. 226
ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />“
thirty men of, no longer to serve in Leona Vicario ..........................
Cock pits and billiard tables, provision in regard to...............
Colleague judges all citizens of the state to serve as such when chosen...
‘ ‘ may be chosen by criminals...........................
Collector of excise at Leona Vicaria his salary fixed ...............
“ at Parras his compensation, also that of receivers.......
Colonization law of March 24th 1825..................................
“	of April 28th 1832 ..................................
Commissioners instructions of September 4th 1827.....................
‘ ‘ their pay prescribed, and article 39 of the colonization law
declared without force...................................   .
“ a second one to be appointed in the department of Nacog<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />doches
.........................................................
Commissioner to be appointed to examine land titles..................
Communications previously directed to'the vice-governor to be directed to
the governor ... ......................................................
Concurgo de Aguayo, measures in regard to that property..............
“ further provision in relation to that law............................
Confraternity permission to establish................................
Congress convoked to extra session..................................
‘ ‘ to form itself into a grand jury in certain accusations...........
“ prescribing the mode of congratulating..............................
“ and the governor to be Sworn to observe the constitution of the
republic........................................................
“ has power to resolve on certain propositions of reform.......
Contracts valid between emigrants &amp; the working men they introduce...
Consumption duty on foreign goods....................................
“ additional two per cent.............................................
70
97
15
298
212
208
63
102
83
210
211
15
189
70
106
306
310
109
232
252
115
'278
218
7
Cotton &amp;c., free from taxes......
Councillors, individuals chosen
8
22
103
14
137
181
101, 211
235
Council, what is to be considered its opinion in a particular case. .......
Counsellor taking cognizance, instead of the fiscal, to have the same com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation
.......................................................
Crimes, course to be taken in those of the civic militia..........
Criminal prosecution, certain persons under, to be discharged .... .
Curates to be solicited by the executive for the new towns in Texas
. . 179
... 176
77, 107
Custom house, fixing the rent of a building for, and prices of storage ...
Decree No. 26 declared without force........................
“ for holding a national election......................................
‘ ‘ No. 148 declared without value or force........................
‘ ‘ repealing No. 182 and re-establishing No. 146 ..................................
‘ ‘ suspending the execution of No. 228 ...........................
Deficiency of age on the part of M. Gorivar dispensed with ........................
Delinquents may be put in irons while the prisons are repairing........
Department of Bexar, divided into two districts........................
Districts of Saltillo and Parras made separate departments.............
Doyle Rev. H. permitted to establish a chapel..........................
Duty three per cent on silver...........................................
Ecclesiastical offices precaution in regard to candidates...........
Election of deputies to the general congress.........................
113
116
133
205
212
218
228
133
179
171
210
135
66
96
7

<pb n="467" xml:id="P0467" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/475/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Index to the Laws and Decrees.</fw>

Election of governor, vice-governor and councellors declared..
“ provided in case of vacancy &amp;c., in municipal offices
PAGE.
63, 169, 282
‘ ‘ course to be taken in case of non-observance of the constitution in,
Elguezabal, his resignation accepted......................................
Emigrants amount they are to pay on receiving their land titles...........
Executive council, provision in relation to that body.....................
Executive, authorized to admit counsellors at law provisionally...........
‘ ‘ to give directions to the excise collector....................
“ authorized to unite certain offices.............................
“ to sell the lands of the extinguished missions ..................................
“ dispose of an additional sum to repair the prison in the Cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />itol
..............................................................
“ dispose of municipal property to repair the prison...................
“ adopt measures to aid in repelling the Spanish invasion..........
“ regulate the bouudaries with the adjoining states................
“ contract a loan for relief of persons suffering with the small
pox................................................................ ....
“	increase or diminish the amount of certain bonds............
“	appoint lawyers to despatch the business in the assessors
office....................................................
‘ ‘ form coalitions with the other states..........................
“ solicit empresarios to make tanks and drawwells..................
“ take measures for the pursuit and extermination of robbers. .
“ designate vacant lands for situating the tribes of friendly In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dians
.............................................................
“	dispose of four hundred sitios of vacant land...............
‘ ‘	issue letters of citizenship to all foreigners who have acquired
the legal ights of citizens...............................
“ provide men for the expedition to Texas..........................
“ to exact a forced loan...........................................
“ discretianary power granted him to levy and organize the
militia............................................................
“ concerning his correspondence with the different authorities..
“ power granted him to dispose of four hundred sitios, to be un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />derstood
as subject to the general laws of the Union..............
‘ ‘ acts of M. Ramos and J. M. Gorivar at a particular period of
no force..........................................................
“ may establish his despatch out of the capital........................
Exposition on the subject of a project of a law of amnesty.............
“ on the subject of reform.............................................
98
207
281
297
44
165
180
181
186
188
104
132
149
156
252.
273.
217
227
300
281
299'
164
294
276
220
283
Ecclesiastical authorities to send a list of candidates for benefice.....
Estimate of expenses to be made out monthly in the office of secretary of
state ...................................................................
293.
312:
285
288
184
European Spaniards prohibited from holding office..............
Excise duties reduced in the departments of Monclova and Bexar
Exportation of coin tax on extended............................
Extra session to be holden.....................................
Eair provision on the sucject..................................
Fair may be holden at Monclova.................................
Festivals religious, to be solemnized by collection of alms....
Forced loan required of certain Spaniards with further measures
“ for returning...................................................
“ how appropriated..............................................
Foreigners pronibited from retailing goods.....................
Foreigners goods changed in form, &amp;c...........................
“ consumption duty on augmented................................
‘ ‘	concerning the collection of a certain duty on. ..
Form of oath to obey the constitution, &amp;c......................
“ for printing and publishing the constitution.................
‘ ‘ for issuing letters of citizenship.........................
Gigedo declared capital of the district .......................
Generals Guerrero and Pedrosa declared citizens of the state...
145
62
188
64
164
187
304
156
126
178.
137
117, 185.
59
. . 200
.. 202.
...	44
...	44
..	75
..	98
...	99

<pb n="468" xml:id="P0468" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/476/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Index to the Laws and Decrees.</fw>

. General Santa Anna recognized as president.................■	• •
Goods of a certain kind, exclusive privilege granted J. Grant for
facturing...............................................
Governor, to be received as a patron....................
“ pro tem., cloathed with extraordinary powers..........
“ his resignation not accepted..........................
“ permitted to repair to Nuevo Leon.....................
Grand jury, to be appointed by congress.................
Hacienda de San Vicente, established a town...........................
Halls of the tribunals of justice, provision on the subject...........
Hewitson and Power, eight sitios of land granted to......................
Iron and coal mines, exclusive privilege granted for working...
Income tax.....................................................
Intervening officers, provision in regard to...................
Interpreters, to be employed in criminal suits.................
PAGE.
. 280
manu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Judges
of responsibility................................................
‘ ‘ to execute judicial acts in place of Notaries......
Jurors law concerning—of April 17—1834.................
La Bahia constituted a town................................
Lancastrian schools, law for establishing..................•	■ ; ; ..  :.•
Land, acquired by virtue of the colonization law not liable for certain
247
9
33
163
195
118
89
146
230
99
123
132
223
24
253
254
112
127
debts.....................................
Land Law of March 26, 1834..................
“ in reference to the same law.............
“ relative to that of the town of Bejar
Law de ...................................................on
" dispenfed with to admit E. de la Garza as counsellor,
“ regulating contracts between masters and servants. . .
14 &amp;c., of the castilian collection to be understood as 1
36,
111
247
272
277
, 47
... 108
108, 119
... 139
198
repealed
for taxing certain lots..........................................
of April 27th 1833 on the subject of municipal property.
same law does not comprise the water for domestic use...
regulations in respect to ayuntamientos &amp;c..............•	•:...:a
of April 1, 1830—favor granted therein limited to a certain period..
of March 4, 1830—a part dispensed with.....
of 11th of January, 1834, repealed......... .....................
Letter of citizenship, granted to J. Cameron and S. Hewetson..............
“ to T. J. Chambers.......................................
“ J. Grant.................................................................................................
“ J. Bowie................................................
• • M. Muldoon............................................  :
‘ ‘ J. Power...................................
“ D. J. Toler.....................................................................
Licence, to J. M. Carabajal for printing the laws and decrees ...
Local militia, provisions on the subject.
Maize &amp;c., free from excise duties...............
Manufacturing company, grant to establish........
Medals and prizes, for preparing for pupils..............
Military men retired, exonerated from a certain tax......
Mining deputation, law for creating......................
Monclova declared the capital of the state .............. n: ......
Municipal property, for selling that of the extinguished Missions
Municipality, new one formed in that of Austin	
“	established at Matagorda.. .
“ at San Patricio and Mina......................................
Names"?/San Fernando and post of Rio Grande changed .
National effects introduced at a certain time to pay less excise duty .. ..
213
236
237
277
295
311
76
162
162
167
171
113
283
307
110
76
167
157
113
60
107, 207
.. . 181
. .. 197
.. . 242
. . . 274
. .60, 308
65
199

<pb n="469" xml:id="P0469" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/477/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Index to the Laws and Decrees.</fw>

PAGE.
Notaries not to extend their functions beyond their municipality.
Notices, prescribing the form of those given monthly by the executive...
Offer made by J. Grant accepted...................................
Officers, general government requested to remove.................
Orders and decrees, how to be communicated........................
Pastorals &amp;c., must have a permit.................................
236
141
158
138
Panoptic prisons............................................
Pablo Hernandez reinstated in the capacity of holding office. .. .
Permanent cavalry for replacing the companies of............
“ deputation; resolution of approval.......................
Phrase in article 69 Law No. 37, how to be understood.......
“ in article 1 decree 15th April 1831, how to be understood
253
130
199
42
200, 201
Plan of Jalapa, adopted by congress ..................................
“ persons comprised in article 4 of....................................
Political chief and deputation of Texas cease in their functions......
Possessions referred to by the corporation of Villa Longin, declared valid,
Prerogatives, attributes and restrictions of the governor, &amp;c.........
primary schools provisionally established . . 0. ... . .................
Provision relative to decree of April 27, 1833 ..
Public administration, certain acts of legalized......................
tranquility, measures for restoring and precerving
Proposition of B. R. Milam accepted.....................................
Qualifications for being a member of the special tribunal..............
Real estate cannot be acquired in mortmain..............................
Receivers office established at San Isidro..............................
“ the same abolished....................................................  .
Repeal of certain articles, in decree No. 105...........................
‘ ‘	of decree No. 105.
“ of law No. 47 and 88..................................................
“ No. 70................................................................
“ of articles 3, 5, 6 and 7, of decree No. 38...........................
“ of decree No. 146.....................................................
“ No. 108, 110 and 113..................................................
“ No. 158...............................................................
“ No. 50, 68, 148 and 191...............................................
“ of decrees of the 4th and 25th of April, 1832.........................
Resignation of certain offices howto be made............................
Right of petition regulations on the subject............................
Rio del Norte, exclusive privilege granted for navigating...............
Robertson S. C., term of his contract conditionally prolonged...........
Restriction in regard to the object of disposing of four hundred sitios.. . .
Resolution of the executive declared without force......................
“ relating to that proposed by S. C. Robertson..........................
Salary and Viaticum of the members of congress..........................
“ of the governor &amp;c....................................................
those of the secretaries of Ayuntamientos to be approved by the
governor ..........................................................
fixing that of the revenueofficers of Leona Vicario................
of clerks of department, chiefs augmented..........................
of the governor....................................................
112
228
137
161
8
155
123.p8
231
207
34
292
95
240
194
210
138
178
159
179
182
184
204
208
207
243
141
206
100
275
287
295
305
58
79
Savages, measures to protect the citizens from
Sessions prorogued........................
165
220
■ 235
244
270
84, 102, 122, 293
Secretary office of congress, regulation of....................
Second colony of M. de Leon annexed to the department of Bexar
Sessions to close..............................................
Slaves conditionally allowed to change their masters...........
“ Provision with regard to......................................
Smuggled tobacco for seizing, and for punishing smugglers......
23
305
310
92
78
84

<pb n="470" xml:id="P0470" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/478/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Index to the Laws and Decrees.</fw>

Smugglers, fine imposed on to be paid to the state revenue.
“ of tobacco, their punishment, &amp;c.....................
Spaniards, for banishing some of that class of persons.
“ certain points in the laws relative to, explained
Stamped paper law................................................
“ inhabitants of the new Texas colonies exempted from complying
PAGE.
. 114
. 182
.	94
. 105
9
with......................................................
State revenue, the governor in his messages to give information on....
“ treasury, for establishing..........................................
‘ ‘ territory of, divided into seven departments......................
“ inhabitants of, exonerated from a certain tax.......................
Stock, concerning certain duties on................................
Standing army, individuals of the, have not a right to vote...........
Style of address of congress, &amp;c....................................
Substitute deputies may hold municipal offices......................
Substitutes of ministers of the tribunal of justice, relative to their ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointment
... ........................................................
Substitutes of magistrates and fiscal, who to be appointed in a certain
case..................................................................
Suits against securities in the state to be terminated in the state...
Surveyors fees assigned, and old residents favored with a part of the
taxes corresponding to the state rents................................
Suspension of office of councill, and of the establishment of the treasury..
‘ ‘ of the office of fiscal, and providing for the discharge of the
97
74
85
245
176
224
197
7
102
134
141
105
146
101
duties...............................................
Tax on the exportation of coin..........................
“ on billiard tables....................................
Term additional, granted to J. L. Woodbury...............
“	to S. Power........................................
“	to J. Cameron......................................
“ to D. G. Burnet &amp; J. Belhein.............................
Term of exemption from duties allowed to cotton, prolonged
Ten sitios of land granted to the inhabitants of Guerrero. ..
Prolonged for introducing machines for iron and coal mines
- _ Teachers fund, proceeds of building lots appropriated for .
Thieves, law for punishing.................................
Timber certain towns permitted to cut on the river Sabinas
157
114, 204
... 177
... 114
... 185
... 186
... 195
... 286
... 307
... 106
... 226
..66, 177
...	92
Tobacco, provisions relative that article.....................................154,	166
Town, San Francisco and San Miguel to establish their Ayuntamiento,
“ of Nova, the capital of the district of Gio Rrande.............................
Trial by jury, law for establishing...................
Tribunal of Justice, various provisions on that subject
Trinity river, exclusive priviledge for navigating .....
Tythes, for creating a junta..............
140
150
151
“ how to be paid......................................................
Vacant lands, laws in respect to the alienation of, dispensed with for
77, 88, 219
..... 209
90
222
a
certain object ...................................................
Vice-Governor his salary when acting permanently as governor..........
“ and members of the council chosen...................................
Village of Alamo created a town.......................................
Villa Longin and the capital formed iuto one town....................
Vidaurri y Villasenor invested with the executive power..............
Visit of Ayuntamientos, for appointing an officer to perform.........
Visiter general of the state, his salary..............................
Voice of Alcalde, to what acts it refers..............................
Will of the nation, that of the state legislatures recognized as such.
Waters of certain towns to be taken and adjudicated to that of Guerrero,
276
203
32
161
177
227
122
160
113
202
242
Words, those to be omitted in certain laws........
Zavala L. and J. McMullen, their petitions acceded to
231, 209
... 229</p>

<pb n="471" xml:id="P0471" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/479/" />

<head>INDEX
<lb />TO THE
<lb />CONSTITUTION.
</head>

<p>
Preliminary provisions............................................... 313
Form of government of the state...................................... 316
Title 1. Legislative power of the state, Sec. 1st, deputies to congress. . 317
Sec. 2nd., election of deputies...................................    318
Paragraph 1st., electoral municipal assemblies....................... 319
Paragraph 2nd., etectoral district assemblies........................ 321
Sec. 3rd., holding session...................;....................... 323
Sec. 4th., attributes of congress, and its permanent deputation...... 325
Sec. 5th., formation and promulgation of laws........................ 327
Appendix to said title, election of deputies to the general congress. 328
Title 2. Executive qower of the state, Sec. 1st., governor........... 329
Prerogatives of the governor.......................................   329
Attributes of the governor........................................... 329
Restrictions of the powers of the governor........................... 330
Sec. 2nd., vice-governor...........................................   331
Sec. 3rd., executive council.......................................   332
Sec. 4th., election of governor, vice-governor and councillors....... 333
Sec. 5th., Secretary of state.......................................  334
Sec. 6th., department police chiefs, and subordinate district chiefs. 334
Sec. 7th., Ayuntamientos............................................. 335
Title 3. Judicial power, Sole Sec., administraiion of justice in general, 337
Paragraph 1st., administration of justice in civil cases............. 337
Paragraph 2nd., administration of justice in criminal cases......... 338.
Paragraph 3rd., inferior courts of justice, and superior tribunals... 338
Title 4.	Sole	Sec., state treasury................................. 340
Title 5.	Sole	Sec., civic militia of the state..................... 341
Title 6.	Sole	Sec., public education............................... 341
Title 7.	Sole	Sec., observance of the	constitution................. 342
</p>

<pb n="472" xml:id="P0472" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/480/" />
<head>ERRATA IN THE ENGLISH.</head>

<p>
RAGE.
13
44
105
ill
119
126
131
135
139
154
161
195
244
246
253
289
302
302
ART.
13
2
1
1
7
7
10
1
6
5
5
De. 192
1
11
1
1
1
1
“ only: the....
‘ ‘ Councils...
“ impediments....
" article 143..
‘ ‘ him.................
“ occupation, find......
‘ ‘ contractro...
“ widows.........
“ general Commandants
“ tusks .........
‘ ‘ Gomer........
“ The years .. .........
‘ ‘ capitol......
1 ‘ power........
‘ ‘ of private...
“ dangerous for.........
“ literal states.
“ exclusive......
read
“ only the
‘ ‘ Council
‘ ‘ impedement
“ articles 142 &amp; 143
“ them
“ occupation and find
‘ ‘ contractor
“ widowers
“ -general commandants.
‘ ‘ tasks
‘ ‘ Gomez
“ Three years
‘ ‘ capital
‘ ‘ powers
“ to private
“ dangerous; for
“ littoral states
‘ ‘ exclusively.</p>

<pb n="473" xml:id="P0473" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/481/" />

<head>OMISSIONS AND CORRECTIONS.</head>

<p>PAGE. ART.
17
17
18
18
19
20
71
72
■ 147
95
158
189
190
220
221
241
284
302
310
211
312
317
318
244
345

Merit the approbation of the executive of the Union, to whom for
that object he shall transmit all petitions, accompanied by a re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />report,
whether the petitioners be Mexicans or foreigners.
12 of which at least one half shall be temporal land.
14 receive solely of the said grazing land a superficies.
17 said executive always bearing in mind.
15 families, whether foreigners or natives, contenting.
24 The Spanish of the last part of the article corrected.
El precio de cada sitio, supuesta la condicion anterior, sera el de
cien pesos, si la tierra fuere de agostadero, ciento cinquenta, si
fuere de temporal, y doscientos cinquenta, si fuere de regadillo.
Translated thus.—Allowing the aforesaid condition, the price of
each sitio shall be one hundred dollars, should the land be graz<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
land, one hundred and fifty should it be temporal, and two
hundred and fifty should it be irrigable.
32 industry of the new settlers pay.
10 irrigable or temporal.
17 valued by competent persons according to the locality and sold.
12 are hereby favored with a part of the taxes corresponding to the
state revenue.
2	The post of Rio Grande.
3	support also two.
5	born, and not enjoying any special immunity, to act.
10 from each canal that can.
1
1
add,—Previous arrangements in opposition to the present are
hereby repealed.
of the frontier of the state.
add at the close of the same article,—From the Valle de Santa
Rosa to the interior shall be considered frontier.
6 shall by testament dispose.
3 add,—The garrison of Monclova is hereby excepted from this pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vision.

3 Article 7th of the general law of the 18th of August, and has com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pared
it with article 2 of the law of the 25th of April last, and
does not find.
4 two thousand five hundred dollars, and one thousand five hundred.
6
2
34
44
2
per annum.
he avails himself.
seven thousand.
add,—During session the deputies shall not be subject to civil
suit, or execution in case of debt.
Decree No. 268, add,—the secretary of state shall receive a salary
of two thousand five hundred dollars per annum.
19 depopulated towns.</p>

<head>INADVERTENCE IN THE ORIGINAL.</head>

<p>Page 20, Article 28, Caso los derechos, (see page 193, article 31.)</p>

<pb n="474" xml:id="P0474" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/482/" />

</div>
</body>
</text>
