<text><front /><body><div type="document"><pb n="475" xml:id="P0475" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/483/" /><p>PROCEEDINGS
OF THE
GENERAL CONVENTION
OF
DELEGATES REPRESENTING THE CITIZENS AND
INHABITANTS OF TEXAS:
HELD AT’ THE
TOWN OF SAN FELIPE, IN AUSTIN’S COLONY, THE FIRST
WEEK OF OCTOBER, ONE THOUSAND EIGHT
HUNDRED AND THIRTY-TWO.
“	The public functionaries of the State, of whatever class they may be,
shall at the time of entering upon their offices, take the oath to serve, sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain,
and defend the Constitutional Act, the general Constitution, and that
of the State, and to discharge faithfully and completely the duties of their
offices.”
“	The observance of the Constitution in all its parts, is one of the most
sacred obligations of the inhabitants of the State of Coahuila and Texas,
and no one can be absolved from it—neither the Congress nor any other
authority.”—State Constitution.
In a Republic, the people are the true conservators of the Constitution.
BRAZORIA, TEXAS.
1832</p><pb n="476" xml:id="P0476" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/484/" /><p /><pb n="477" xml:id="P0477" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/485/" /><p>INTRODUCTION AND PREPARATORY NOTE.
A devotion to written Constitutions, and a strict adherence to their
literal interpretation, has been one of the most distinguishing political
'characteristics of all Anglo-Americans. Under the influence of this sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />timent,
the Colonies of Texas, composed principally of emigrants from
" The United States or America,” were—by repeated violations of
their chartered rights, experienced in the bosom of their immediate so<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciety;
as well as a general disregard of the Constitution, by the agents of
the Federal Government—naturally driven to unite in defence of that
sacred instrument: and to second the efforts of the patriotic projectors of
The Plan OF Vera CRUZ, so far at least, as to extripate, within the
limits of their community, every unlawful obstacle to their enjoyment,
and to establish the security of their imprescriptable rights. The people
having taken up arms and effected this, the heads of the chief political
authorities of Austin’s Colony, published the following Address
TO THE PEOPLE OF TEXAS:
The Civil Wars, and infractions of the Constitution, which have un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fortunately
deranged the administration of government, in all its de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partments,
throughout the Whole Mexican Republic, since December,
1838, have extended their influence to Texas, and the people, in different
parts of the country, have been compelled to resort to such measures as
their situation would permit, to restore the Constitution, and the author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity
of the State of Coahuila and Texas, to their proper force and vigor.
These measures have heretofore been adopted by the inhabitants of each
District, without any general concert: thus exposing Texas to the danger
of confusion, which might materially affect the public tranquillity.
The late occurrences have been grossly misrepresented by the enemies
of Texas, and efforts have been made, and are continually making, to
prejudice our fellow-citizens, in other parts of the Mexican Republic,
against the people of Texas, by circulating reports that the object of the
late events was to declare this country independent of Mexico, which is
absolutely false and without any foundation in truth.
The Indians have commenced depredations on the frontiers of the Riv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers
Brazos, Colorado, Guadalupe, and San Antonio; and the scattered
situation of the settlements, imperiously requires that some measures
should be adopted for their security.
There are, indeed, many subjects, connected with the welfare of Texas,
which ought to be laid before the Constitutional Authorities of the Mexi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />-can
Nation: and these considerations of safety to ourselves, respect for the
-character of the people of Texas, the motives which have influenced them,
and the sanctity of the cause of the Constitution, as proclaimed in Vera
■Cruz, which we have espoused, have induced the Civil Authorities of the
( 477 )</p><pb n="478" xml:id="P0478" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/486/" /><p>4
Introduction and Preparatory Note.
Municipality of Austin, to recommend that the people of Texas should;
be consulted at this important crisis; which may be done by the election
of Delegates.
It is therefore recommended, that the people of each Town, Precinct,
and Civil District in Texas, elect Five Delegates, to meet at the Town of
San Felipe de Austin, on the 1st Monday in October next; and that the
Civil Authorities order an election, in their respective Districts according<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly,
with as little delay as possible.
San Felipe de Austin, 22d August, 1832.
(Signed)
(Signed)
HORATIO CHRIESMAN, 1st Alcalde.
JOHN AUSTIN, 2d Alcalde
Accordingly, Delegates were elected, who convened at San Felipe on the
day appointed, and continued their sitting during the week.
The Department was very generally represented, but owing to the
shortness of the notice given, the Convention was not so full as it other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise
would have been. The members from Goliad, did not arrive until
after the sitting was concluded; but they warmly approbated all that had
been done, and especially the objects of the Memorial and petition to the
General Government, in relation to the impolitic Law of the Qth of April,
and the separation from Coahuila. These members determined to remain,
at San Felipe some days, to see if San Antonio would not send representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
also, with. which delegation, (should there have been one) they
wished to unite in declaring their concurrence in the measures adopted
by the Convention; and also, to appoint a co-delegate to participate in the
been done, and especially the objects of the Memorial and Petition to the
Government. Members from San Antonio, however, did not arrive; and
what was intended to be done in conjunction with that representation,
was performed by the Delegation from Goliad, on their part, to the full
extent of their Commission. A meeting of the Central Standing Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee,
was held for the purpose of communicating with them; when
they formally attached their concurrence to the measures adopted by the
Convention, and chose DoN Rafael MANOHOLA, as co-delegate, to ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />company
the Missions to the General and State Governments.
The proceedings of the Convention will be found in the highest degree<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />interesting,
to every one who feels any solicitude for the character and
prosperity of the country. Such, have the greatest reason to rejoice at
the present progressive course of events, which must inevitably lead to
the disenthrallment of Texas, and place its advancement upon the desira<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble
and fair basis of its unquestionable preeminence in soil, climate, and
every thing which attracts capital and rewards industry.
We are proud to be able to say, that we never witnessed in any deliber<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ative
body, a more commendable spirit of compromise, and a greater de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gree
of union and harmony in feeling and design, than were displayed
thro the whole sitting of the Convention. Whatever differences of senti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
and opinion were evinced during the discussion and consideration of
the various subjects which were acted upon, they were happily assimilated
without heat, and the Convention may truly be said, to have dissolved,,
with one feeling—one wish—and one united resolve.
(478)</p><pb n="479" xml:id="P0479" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/487/" /><p>PROCEEDINGS
OF THE
CONVENTION OF TEXAS
. In compliance with an official request, and public notice to the authori<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties,
and inhabitants of Texas, issued by the First and Second Alcaldes,
of the Municipality of Austin, the following Members, representing the
different Districts of Texas, met in General Convention, at San Felipe de
Austin, on Monday, the 1st day of October, 1832.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF SAN FELIPE DE AUSTIN:
Stephen F. Austin, Wyly Martin, Francis W. Johnson, Luke Lesassier.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF VICTORIA:
George B. McKinstry, William H. Wharton, John Austin, Charles D.
Sayre.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF MINA:
Ira Ingram, Silas Dinsmore, Eli Mercer.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF HIDALGO:
Nestor Clay, Alexander Thompson.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF SAN JACINTO:
Archibald B. Dobson, George F. Richardson, Robert Wilson.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF VIESCA:
Jared E. Groce, William Robinson, Joshua Hadly.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF ALFRED:
Samuel Bruf, David Wright, William D. Lacy, William R. Hensley,
Jesse Burnham.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF LABACA:
William Menifee, James Kerr, George Sutherland, Hugh MeGuffin,
Joseph K. Looney.
( 479 )</p><pb n="480" xml:id="P0480" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/488/" /><p>6
Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF GONZALES:
Henry S. Brown, C. Stinnett.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF MILL CREEK:
John Connell, Samuel C. Douglass.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF NACOGDOCHES:
Charles S. Taylor, Thomas Hastings.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF AYISH BAYOU:
Philip Sublett, Donald McDonald, William McFarland, Wyatt Hanks,
Jacob Garret.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF SNOW RIVER:
Thomas D. Beauchamp, Elijah Isaacs, Samuel Looney, James Looney.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF SABINE:
Benjamin Holt, Absalom Hier, Jesse Parker.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF TENNEHAW:
William English, Frederick Foye, George Butler, John M. Bradly,
Jonas Harrison.
FROM THE DISTRICT OF LIBERTY:
Patrick C. Jack, Claiburn West, James Morgan.
The Convention was called to order by John Austin, Esq. 2nd Alcalde,
and addressed, in the name of the First and Second Alcaldes, as follows:
Gentlemen of the Convention:—The invitation for the Convention hav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
been made by the Alcaldes of this Municipality—it may perhaps be
expected that we should present to the Convention, the reasons which
influenced us to make such a request.
THE REASONS ARE THESE:
1st. The Revolution which commenced at Vera Cruz, on the 2d Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary
last, under the command of Gen. Santa Ana, reached this remote
section of the Nation, and movements of a warlike character have taken
place—the consequence of which has been, that the Military Garrisons
have all been compelled to quit the Country. These movements have
been greatly misrepresented by the enemies of Texas, and have been at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tributed
to objects entirely different from the true ones. It was, there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(
480 )</p><pb n="481" xml:id="P0481" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/489/" /><p>Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
7
fore, considered to be highly important to the interest of Texas, and of
the Nation, to .counteract these misrepresentations, by a plain statement
of facts; and that a decided declaration should be made by the people of
Texas, convened in General Convention, of our firm and unshaken adhe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion
to the Mexican Confederation and Constitution, and our readiness to
do our duty as Mexican Citizens.
2d. The 11th article of the Law of the 6th of April, 1830, which pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hibits
natives of the United States of the North, from emigrating to these
Colonies, has entirely paralized the advancement and prosperity of Texas,
and exposed it to be filled with a bad and useless population. That Law
also severs families and friends, by preventing a removal to this country of
many who remain behind in the United States, and for whose reception
in this country, preparations had been made by their relatives and friends,
who came out as pioneers for that purpose. This point was deemed by the
Alcaldes, to be one of sufficient importance to be' noticed in a Memorial
to the Government, by a Convention of Texas, praying for a repeal, or
modification of that article.
3d. The Land Business to the East of Austin’s Colony, still remains
in a very unsettled and uncertain state, and the Alcaldes were also of
opinion that this was a subject which ought to be represented to the
General Government.
4th. The Tariff, as now established, operates very injuriously against,
the agriculture and advancement of the infant settlements of Texas; and
the Alcaldes were of opinion, that it would be proper for the Convention
to represent this matter, and respectfully petition for a reduction of the
duties on such articles as could not be easily transported into the interior
as contraband, and are of indispensihle necessity to the farmers of Texas.
These four topicks embrace all that the Alcaldes had in view, at the time'
of making the request for this Convention. It is considered by us, that
it is the duty of the people of Texas, to lay their situation before the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral
Government, in order that such Legislative aid may be afforded us,
as the general good of the Nation, and of Texas, may require; and to
accompany it with a firm declaration of our unshaken allegiance to the
Mexican Constitution and Nation. All which is respectfully submitted
for the consideration of the Convention.
Several persons were then nominated for President and Secretary; and
on motion, it was ordered, that the Convention be adjourned until 3
o’clock, P. M., and then enter upon the election of Officers.
The Convention met agreeably to adjournment, and proceeded to the
election of a President and Secretary, by ballot:
THE VOTES STOOD
FOR PRESIDENT,
S. F. Austin,	31 votes
W. H. Wharton,	15 "
FOR SECRETARY,
F. W. Johnson,
C. D. Taylor,
34 votes
11 «
So S. F. Austin was elected President, and F. W. Johnson, Secretary. _
S. F. Austin, was then conducted to the Chair, and returning his thanks
to the House, he made a short address relative to the objects of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention;
which were, he said, to exercise the Constitutional right of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />senting
to the Government, the situation of the people of Texas, and to
31 —VOL. 1.
(481)</p><pb n="482" xml:id="P0482" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/490/" /><p>8
Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
ask for such Legislative aid as the Convention might deem necessary, and
especially to petition for a repeal of the 11th article of the Law of the 6th
of April, 1830, which totally paralizes the improvement of Texas, by.em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />barrassing
the emigration to it of natives of the United States of the
North: to ask for a modification of the Tariff, and an adjustment of the
land business to the East of the River San Jacinto: and to represent the
defects in the local Government, and administration of justice in Texas,
as now organized.
On motion of Mr. Bruf, it was ordered, that a committee be immediate<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly
appointed for the purpose of drafting Rules and Regulations for the
Government of this Convention.
In lieu thereof, the Rules of the Senate of the State of Missouri, were
proposed, and adopted, so far as applicable to the proceedings of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention.

On motion of Mr. Lesassier, it was resolved, that a committee of five
persons be appointed to draft a Memorial to the Federal Government,
praying the repeal of the 11th article of the Law of the 6th of April,
1830—and also to set forth to the Government, the toils, and difficulties,
and dangers encountered by the Colonists in the early settlement of
Texas:—and their respect for, and attachment to, the Constitution and
Laws of the Republic—and report to the Convention in a reasonable
time.
Whereupon, the following persons were appointed to compose said
committee:
Luke Lesassier, William H. Wharton, Jonas Harison, Geo. Sutherland,
P. C. Jack.
At the request of the mover, W. H. Wharton was appointed chairman
of said committee.
On motion of Mr. Lesassier, it was resolved, that a committee of five
be appointed to draft a petition to the Federal Government, praying a
reduction of duties on articles, of the first necessity, imported into
Texas—and also, that the committee make such an exposition as will
prove to the Government, as far as practicable, that the reduction of
duties would increase the revenue of the country.
Whereupon, the following persons were appointed to form said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee:

Charles D. Sayre, James Morgan, Jared E. Groce, Charles S. Taylor,
J. K. Looney.
On motion, George B. McKinstry, and John Austin were added.
At the request of the mover, Mr. Sayre was appointed chairman of said
committee.
On motion, the Convention adjourned until Tuesday, 9 o’clock, A. M.
TUESDAY. October 2.
The Convention met agreeably to adjournment.
On motion of Mr. Harison, it was resolved, that a committee of ten be
appointed, to take into consideration the situation of the land business
to the East of San Jacinto; and report to this Convention, such memorial
or memorials, to the State, or General Government, or to both, as the
committee deem necessary.
(482 )</p><pb n="483" xml:id="P0483" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/491/" /><p>Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
9
Whereupon, the following persons were appointed to compose said
committee:
Jonas Harison, William McFarland, William English, Philip Sublett,
Jacob Garrett, Charles S. Taylor, Benjamin Holt, Wyatt Hanks, Fred<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erick
Foye, Elijah Isaacs.
On motion, P. C. Jack, and James Morgan were added.
On motion of Mr. Hensley, it was resolved, that five members be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed
a committee, to inquire into the Indian affairs of Texas; and fix
on some plan for the protection of the frontiers.
Whereupon, the following persons were appointed to form said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee:

William R. Hensley, Samuel Looney, Nestor Clay, C. Stinnett, Jesse
Burnham.
On motion of John Austin, it was resolved, that a committee of five be
appointed, to report the best mode to regulate the Custom-House affairs
in Texas, until said offices are filled, and regulated by the General Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment—and
also to report that the Tariff be observed, until the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment
shall direct the reorganization of the Custom-House Establish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment.

Whereupon, the following persons were appointed to compose that
committee:
John Austin, Nestor Clay, William McFarland, Wyly Martin, George
Sutherland.
On motion of Mr. Lesassier, it was resolved, that a committee of five be
appointed to petition the State Government for a donation of land to
Texas;for the purpose of creating a School Fund, to provide for the future
establishment of Primary Schools—and report to this Convention in a
reasonable time.
Whereupon, the following persons were apointed to form said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee
:
Luke Lesassier, William McFarland, William Menifee, Samuel Bruff,
Thomas Hastings.
Mr. Dinsmore introduced a resolution, to take into consideration the
propriety of Texas’ petitioning for a separate State Government—which
was laid on the table.—Leave was obtained by Mr. Dinsmore to withdraw
his resolution.
On motion, the Convention adjourned until Wednesday, 11 o’clock,
A. M.
WEDNESDAY, October 3.
The Convention met agreeably to adjournment.
On motion of Air. McFarland, it was resolved, that a committee, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed
of two members from each district, be appointed, to roport the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pediency
or inexpediency of petitioning for a State Government; and that
they be authorized to report such petition, or otherwise.
On motion of Mr. Clay, the Yeas and Nays were called for, on the fore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />going
resolution.
( 483 )</p><pb n="484" xml:id="P0484" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/492/" /><p>10
Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
YEAS.
F. W. Johnson,
L. Lesassier,
G. B. McKinstry,
William H. Wharton,
Charles S. Taylor,
Ira Ingram,
Silas Dinsmore,
Eli Mercer,
Robert Wilson,
Joshua Hadly,
Samuel Bruit,
William Menifee,
James Kerr,
Hugh McGuffin,
J. K. Looney,
Thomas Hastings,
Hyman Hantz,
Philip Sublett,
D. McDonald,
William McFarland,
Wyatt Hanks,
Thomas D. Beauchamp,
Elijah Isaacs,
Samuel Looney,
Benjamin Holt,
A. Hier,
Jesse Parker,
William English,
Frederick Foye,
John M. Bradley,
Claibourn West,
James Morgan,
H. S. Brown,
C. Stinnett,
John Connell,
Samuel C. Douglass.
NAYS.
Wyly Martin,
John Austin,
Nestor Clay,
Alexander Thompson,
A. B. Dobson,
George Sutherland,
Yeas, 36--------Nays, 12.
George F. Richardson,
Jared E. Groce,
William Robinson,
W. R. Hensley,
Jesse Burnham,
George Butler.
Whereupon, the following persons were appointed to compose said’
committee:
From the District of San Felipe de Austin:—Wyly Martin, Luke Le<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sassier.

From the District of Victoria:—W. H. Wharton, John Austin.
From the District of Mina:—Silas Dinsmore, Eli Mercer.'
From the District of Hidalgo:—Nestor Clay, A. Thompson.
From the District of San Jacinto:—A. B. Dobson, George F. Richard<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son.

From the District of Viesca:—J. E. Groce, Wm. Robinson.
From the District of Alfred:—W. R. Hensley, J. Burnham.
From the District of Laibaca:—W. Menifee, G. Sutherland.
From the District of Nacogdoches:—C. S. Taylor, H. Hantz.
From the District of Ayish-Bayou:—William McFarland, W. Hanks.,
From the District of Snow-River:—E. Isaacs, S. Looney.
From the District of Sabine:—B. Holt, A. Hier.
From the District of Tennehaw:—G. Butler, J. M. Bradly.
From. the District of Liberty:—
From the District of Goma,les:<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />C.
West, James Morgan.
From the District of Mill-Creek :
H. S. Brown, C. Stinnett.
—J. Connell, S. C. Douglass.
(484)</p><pb n="485" xml:id="P0485" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/493/" /><p>Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
.11
On motion of Mr. McFarland, it was resolved, that a committee of
seven members be appointed, to recommend some uniform mode of or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganizing
the militia of Texas.
Whereupon, the following persons were appointed to compose said
committee:
William McFarland, W. Hanks, N. Clay, J. E. Groce, J. Austin, George
Sutherland.—On motion, F. W. Johnson; and J. K. Looney were added
to said committee.
On motion of Mr. Beauchamp, it was resolved, that a committee of five
members be appointed, to petition to the State Government to pass a law
authorizing the people of Texas (whose native language is English) to
have all their transactions, and obligations, written in the English lan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />guage,
except those which have an immediate connection with Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment.

Whereupon, the following were appointed to compose said committee:
Thomas D. Beauchamp, Jared E. Groce, James Kerr, C. S. Taylor, Ira
Ingram.
On motion of Mr. Taylor, it was resolved, that a committee of five be
appointed to memorialize the State Government, on the subject of lands
granted to, and petitioned for, by the North American tribes of Indians—
so as to remove much anxiety evinced by them, which is founded on mis,
representation.
Whereupon, the following members were appointed to form said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee:

Charles S. Taylor, W. McFarland, Jonas Harison, Wyly Martin, John
Austin.—On motion, P. Sublett, J. M. Bradly, and W. Hanks were added.
On motion of Mr. Beauchamp, the Convention adjourned until 3
o’clock P. M. .
The Convention met agreeably to adjournment.
Mr. Groce, Chairman of the committee to whom was referred the reso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lution
on the Tariff, reported the following petition.
To the General Congress of the United Mexican States:
The inhabitants of Texas, assembled in general Convention, by means
of delegates, at the town of San Felipe de Austin, respectfully represent,
that the duties on article's of the first necessity to the inhabitants, which
are not, and cannot be, manufactured in Texas, for several years to come,
are so high as to be equivalent to a total prohibition: that many other
articles which are prohibited by the Tariff, are of the first necessity to the
settlers of Texas; and as the people, in this section of the Republic, are
yet almost without resources, and are generally farmers who make their
support by cultivaing the land, and have no manufacturing establish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments
yet erected within the limits of Texas—they' respectfully petition
the General Government, to grant for three years, the privilege of of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troducing
free of duty, such articles as are indispensible to the prosperity
of Texas; among which, this Convention beg leave to enumerate the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing,
viz: Provisions, Iron &amp; Steel, Machinery, Farming Utensils, Tools
of the various Mechanic Arts, Hardware &amp; Hollow-ware, Nails, Waggons
and Carts, Cotton Bagging and Bale Rope, coarse Cotton Goods and
Clothing, Shoes &amp; Hats, Household &amp; Kitchen Furniture, Tobacco for
( 485 )</p><pb n="486" xml:id="P0486" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/494/" /><p>12
Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
chewing in small quantities, Powder, Lead &amp; Shot, Medicines, Books &amp;
Stationary.—The foregoing articles include the principal imports made
use of, and wanted by the inhabitants of Texas; many of them are pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hibited,
and on those which are allowed to be introduced, the duties are
so high that they amount to a prohibition. The trade to Texas is small,
and the resources limited, but if fostered by a liberal policy on the part
of the general Government, it will, in a few years, yield a revenue of no
small importance.
(Signed)
J. E. GROCE, Chairman.
Which, after being read, was laid on the table.
On motion of Mr. Dinsmore, it was ordered that the report of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee
on the Tariff be taken up and acted upon by the Convention.
Mr. Dinsmore then moved to amend the report by substituting the
word money for that of resources; so as to read—are yet almost without
money.—Question submitted, and decided in the negative.
On motion of Mr. Lesassier, the report was adopted, without amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment.

Mr. Wharton, chairman of of the commtitee on the repeal of the 11th.
Article of the law of the 6 th. of April 1830, reported a memorial to the
National Congress, praying for a repeal of said article, which was unani<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mously
adopted.
To the Federal Congress of Mexico:
Your memorialists, representatives of all the Anglo-Americans in Tex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />as,
in general Convention met, taking advantage of that sacred and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />publican
privilege, of making known their wants and grievances, which is
guarantied to them by the Constitution of their adopted country, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spectfully
represent, that they have viewed, and still view, with senti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments
of the deepest regret and mortification, the passage and the present
existence of the 11th Article of the law of the 6th. of April 1830. This
law is obnoxious to your memorialists, for many reasons. Independent of
its withering influence on all the hopes of Texas, it implies a suspicion of
our fidelity to the Mexican Constitution. Such suspicion we humbly
conceive to be utterly unwarranted; and we will endeavor to prove it so,
by taking a re-view of our conduct from the passage of the first Coloniza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
law up to the present period.
In the year 1823, the Congress of the Mexican Nation invited the citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zens
of the United States of the North to become inhabitants of Texas,
giving to each family one setio of land for so doing. This donation of
land, sounds largely at a distance. Considering, however, the difficulties
with which the taking possession of it was environed, it will not be
thought so magnificent a bounty, nor so entire a gratuity. Had these
lands have been previously pioneered by the enterprize of the government,
and freed from the insecurities which beset a wilderness trod only by
savages; had they have been in the heart of of an inhabited region, and
accessible to the comforts and necessaries of life; had the government
have been deriving an actual revenue from them; could it have realized a
capital from the sale of them, then we admit that the donation would
have been unexampled in the history of national liberty. But how dif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferent
from all this, was the real state of the. case? The lands in question,
( 486 )</p><pb n="487" xml:id="P0487" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/495/" /><p>Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
13
were situated in a wilderness of which the Government had never taken
possession.—They were not sufficiently explored to obtain that knowledge
of their character and situation, which would be necessary to a sale of
them. They were in the occupancy of savages. They were shut out from
all commercial intercourse with the world, and inaccessible to the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />monest
comforts of life; nor were they brought into possession and cul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tivation,
without much toil and privation, and patience and enterprize,
and loss of lives from Indian hostilities and other causes. Under the
smiles of a beneficent Heaven, however, the untiring perseverance of the
immigrants, in a great degree, triumphed over all natural obstacles; it
reduced the forest into cultivation, made the desert smile, established
commercial intercourse with the rest of the world, and expelled the sav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ages,
by whom the country was infested.
From this, it must appear that the lands of Texas, altough nominally
given, were in fact really, and dearly bought.—It may here be premised,
that a gift of lands by a nation to foreigners, on condition of their becom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
citizens, is immensely different from a gift, or sale, from oue individ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ual
to another.—In the case of individuals, the donor, or seller, loses all
further claims upon the lands parted with. But in this case, the Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
only gave wild lands that they might be redeemed from a state of
nature, that the obstacles to a first settlement might be overcome, and
that they might be placed in a situation to augment the physical strength,
and the power, and the revenue of the nation.—Is it not obvious, that
Mexico now holds the same jurisdiction over the Colonized lands of Tex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />as,
that all nations hold over nineteen-twentieths of their Territory?—
For the first six or seven years after the commencement of our settlements
in Texas, we gratefully admit, that our enterprize was animated, and our
hardships alleviated, by the kindness and liberality of the Mexican Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment.
We insist, however, that this beneficent disposition of the Gos
eminent, was followed by gratitude, and loyalty on our part.
The only portion of our conduct, during this period, that could be
tortured into any thing like disloyalty, was the Fredonian disturbance,
at Nacogdoches, in 1826. And when it is considered by whom these
disturbances were originated, and by whom quieted, instead of exciting
the suspicion of Government, we respectfully conceive that, that transac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
should have confirmed its confidence in our patriotism.
The disturbance alluded to, originated with some fifteen or twenty
infatuated individuals. The great mass of the settlers, were opposed to
their mad design, which they testified by capturing the conspirators, and
putting them in custody, before the arrival of a single Mexican soldier.
Was there any thing in this calculated to awaken the suspicions of
Government ?
Bad and desperate men, there will always be found, in every commu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nity.
There will always likewise be, a portion capable of being easily
misled; and is it not really a matter of astonishment, that in this in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stance,
the bad, the desperate, the dissatisfied, and the misguided, were
limited to so insignificant a number?
Excepting this disturbance, which was opposed by ninety-nine hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dreths
of the settlers, and which was quieted by their zeal and patriotism,
we repeat it, that up to the passage of the Law of the 6th of April, 1830,
our conduct was orderly and patriotic.
( 487 )</p><pb n="488" xml:id="P0488" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/496/" /><p>14
Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
The passage of this law, was a mortifying and melancholy occurrence
for Texas. It -was mortifying to us, because it must have been founded
on a suspicion that we were disposed to rebel: such suspicions did us great
injustice—for we had uniformly exhibited strong proofs of our attach<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
to the Constitution.—It was a melancholy event for us, for it blasted
all our hopes, and was enough to dishearten, all our enterprize.
It was peculiarly mortifying, because it admitted into Texas all other
nations, except our friends and countrymen of the United States of the
North: except the fathers and brothers of many of us, for whom we had
emigrated to prepare comforts and homes, and whose presence, to glad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />den
our firesides, we were hourly anticipating. Yes! this law closed the
door of emigration on the only sister Republic, -worthy of the name, which
Mexico can boast of, in this New World. It closed the door on a people,
•among whom, the knowledge and foundations of National Liberty, are
more deeply laid, than among any other on the habitable Globe.—It
closed the door upon a people who would have brought with them to
Texas, those ideas of Republican Government, in which, from birth,
they had been educated and practised.—In short, it closed the door upon
a people who, generously and heroically, aided Mexico in her revolution<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary
struggle; and who were the first and foremost to recognize, and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />joice
at the obtainment of her Independence.—-Is it for a moment to be
supposed, that the European parasites of power, to whom, now alone, the
door of emigration is left open*—that those who have been taught from
infancy to disbelieve in the natural equality of mankind—who are un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />acquainted
with Constitutions, even in name—who, politically speaking,
have never been accustomed to think or legislate for themselves—who
reverence the arm of Monarchical rule—who pay adulation at the feet
of an hereditary nobility—and who have contemplated Republics, only
in theory, and at a distance—is it, we repeat, to be supposed, that immi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grants
of this description, will contribute more to the advancement of
liberty, and the welfare of the Republic, than emigrants from that land
of liberal sentiments, that Cradle of Freedom, that Mother of Constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional
Heroes, the United States of the North? If such be the fact, habit
and education must go for nothing, and all experience is set at naught,
and contradicted.
Your memorialists having, as they trust, and respectfully conceive,
-hown to your Honorable Bodies, that their conduct, up to the passage
of the Law of the 6th of April, was orderly and patriotic, -will now turn
your attention, to their conduct since that period.
This law was sufficient to goad us on to madness, in as much as it
blasted all our hopes, and defeated all our calculations; in as much as it
showed to us, that we were to remain scattered, and isolated, and un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />happy
' tenants of the wilderness of Texas, compelled to gaze upon the
resources of a lovely and fertile region, undeveloped for want of popula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
and cut off from the society of fathers and friends in the U. S. of
the North—to prepare homes and comforts suited to whose age and in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />firmities,
many of us had -patiently submitted to every species of priva<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.
But what was our conduct? As peaceful citizens, we submitted.
The wheels of Government were not retarded in their operation by us.
“The mass of Europeans are here alluded to.—Many Republicans among
them are brilliant exceptions to these remarks.
( 488 )</p><pb n="489" xml:id="P0489" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/497/" /><p>Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
15
_Not a voice, nor an arm was uplifted. We had confidence in the correct
intentions of Government, and we believed and hoped, that when the
momentary excitement of the day had subsided, a returning sense of jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bice
and liberality, would give this obnoxious law, a brief duration. For
more than two years we have remained in this peaceful—this unmurmur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
attitude. About this time, the heroic and patriotic Gen. Santa Ana
arose, as the vindicator of Liberty and the. Constitution. We had confi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence
in the purity of his motives. We believed that the evils which he
battled to redress, were of an alarming and crying magnitude, of no less
a magnitude, than an utter disregard of the Constitution, on the part of
the vice-president and his ministers—with Gen. Santa Ana we united, as
fellow labourers in the same sacred cause, prefering rather to perish in
defence of the violated charter of our rights, than to live in acquiescence
to acts of arbitrary and unconstitutional power. What we have done in
this matter, is known to government and to the world. It was all in de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fence
of rights, liberties and guaranties that were spumed and tram<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pled
upon.
Here, we would ask, what was there in all this, to induce a suspicion of
our disloyalty to the Constitution? Was it our remaining quiet for more
than two years after the passage of the Law of the 6th of April? Was it
in declaring for the Constitution, and in hazarding all we held dear, in
its defence? Would it not have been as easy to have taken advantage of
the troubles of the interior, and to have declared, and battled for, inde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pendence?
Was ever a time more opportune and inviting? Why did
we not then declare for independence? Because, in the honest sincerity
of our hearts, we assure you, and we call Almighty God to witness the
truth of the assertion, that we did not then, that we do not now wish for
independence. No! there is not an Anglo-American, in Texas, whose
heart does not beat high for the prosperity of the Mexican Republic; who
does not cordially and devoutly pray, that all parts of her territory will
remain united to the end of time; and that she will steadily and rapidly
advance, in arts, and in arms, and in agriculture, and in commerce, and
in manufactures, and in learning, and in virtue, and in freedom, and in all
that can add to the splendour and happiness of a great nation. As an
evidence that we wished not for independence, nor for a coalescence with
the United States of the North, your memorialists would respectfully
.refer your Honorable Bodies to the. following fact:
A short time since, it was rumoured amongst us, that the President of
the United States of the North, expressed a determination to make the
Naches, instead of the Sabine river, the line between the two Republics.—
This, hitherto unheard of claim, provoked the indignation of every in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitant
of Texas, and our constituents have, with one voice, called upon
us to memorialize your Honorable Bodies, on the subject of the injustice
of such a demand. May it please your Honorable Bodies, your memor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ialists
trust that they have conclusively shown, that the whole tenor of
their conduct has been characterized by good order and patriotism.
The destroying influence of the Law of the 6th of April, 1830, upon
the prospects of Texas, has been only incidentally attended to—that ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fect
of the law, being too obvious to require expatiation or argument.
This law is, likewise, as injurious to the National Revenue at large, as to
us individually: for it is evident that the greatness, the power, the wealth,
(489 )</p><pb n="490" xml:id="P0490" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/498/" /><p>16
Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
and the independence of a nation, depend upon a proper development of
its resources. Can the resources of Texas be properly developed with this
law hanging over it? We believe not. We believe under such circum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stances,
it would remain the comparative wilderness it now is.
Experience shows, that native Mexicans will not settle in it. But should
they do so, it would nothing augment the physical force of the nation:
for it would only be taking population from one part of the Republic,
to place them in another. Will Europeans settle it? We believe Euro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peans,
of the right description to benefit the country, will not—for thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sands
of reasons. Our hopes then, for a development of the resources of
Texas, are naturally turned, to the United States of the North: to a peo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ple
who have been trained in the school of Republicanism; whose Consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tutions
are adapted to the climate, and who have been brought up to the
cultivation of such articles as will always be the staples of Texas.—
Against them, alone, however, the door is closed; which, we contend, is
equally injurious to us, and to the National Revenue. Another point of
view, in which the Law of the 6th of April is objectionable, and has been
productive of numberless difficulties, is this: the garrisons with which all
parts of Texas, have been lately crowded, must have grown out of this
law, and have been sent here to enforce it. They. could not have been
sent here for our protection; for when they came, we were able to protect
ourselves; and at the commencement of the settlements, when we were
few, and weak,and scattered, and defenceless,not a garrison—no; not a sol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dier,
came to our assistance. In the presence and vicinity of these garri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons,
the Civil arm has generally been paralized and powerless; for many
of the officers were law-despisers, who set the political authorities at de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fiance,
brought them into contempt, and trespassed, in every respect, upon
the rights and privileges of their fellow-citizens. When all of these things
are considered, we cannot but believe, that the former characteristic jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice
and liberality of your Honorable Bodies, will return to our aid, and
bring about an immediate repeal of this, to us, ever to be deprecated
measure.
That justice, that liberality, we now most respectfully, and solemnly,,
and unanimously, and confidently invoke.
(Signed)
W. H. WEARTON, Chairman.
On motion of Mr. Lesassier, the Convention adjourned until to-morrow,.
11 o’clock, A. M.
THURSDAY, October 4.
The Convention met agreeably to adjournment.
W. D. C. Hall appeared and took his seat.
Mr. McFarland, Chairman of the committee on the expediency, or in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />expediency
of petitioning for a State Government, for Texas, made a
Report; which was, on motion of Mr. Wharton, referred to a select com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee
of three, for revision.
Messrs. McFarland, Wharton and Lesassier, were appointed to compose
said committee.—On motion of Mr. Clay, it was ordered, that S. F. Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin,
Esq. be added to said committee.
Samuel Hoit, a member from the district of Mina, appeared and took
his seat.
( 490 )</p><pb n="491" xml:id="P0491" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/499/" /><p>Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
17
On motion of Mr. Wharton, it was resolved, that the President recom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mend
to the Convention, a suitable person as translator of its proceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings;
and that the President supervise the translations, when made.
Whereupon, the President recommended Mr. ALEXANDER Greaves,
as translator, who was unanimously appointed by the Convention.
On motion, the Convention adjourned until Friday, 9 o’clock, A. M.
FRIDAY, October 5.
The Convention met agreeably to adjournment.
Mr. McFarland, chairman of the select committee, to -whom was re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred
the memorial for the admission of Texas into the Union as a State,
reported the memorial with an amendment; which was adopted, and is as
follows:
To the Sovereign General Congress of the Republic of Mexico:
The inhabitants of all Texas, met in General Convention, at the Town
of San Felipe dle Austin, by means of delegates, for the purpose of making
known their wants to the Government—most respectfully represent, that
they desire the separation of Texas from Coahuila, believing such separa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
indispensable to their mutual happiness and prosperity; and that, ul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />timately,
such division would produce the most happy results to the
Mexican Republic.
Coahuila being so distant from the population of Texas, and so widely
variant from it in interests—the rights and wants of the people of Texas,
cannot be properly protected and provided for, under the present organi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zation,
admitting the several Departments of the Government of the State
to be prompted by the utmost purity of intention, in their efforts for the
administration of justice.
Coahuila and Texas, are dissimilar in soil, climate and productions, in
common interests, and partly in population—the representatives of the
former, are numerous, and those of the latter few—in consequence of
which, any law passed peculiarly adapted for the benefit of Texas, has
only to be the effect of a generous courtesy. Laws happily constructed
for the benefit of Coahuila, and conducive to its best interests, might be
ruinous to Texas—such are the conflicting interests of the two countries.
For instance, the unconstitutional law, prohibiting any but native Mexi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cans
from retailing merchandize—which extends to the exclusion of nat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uralized
citizens, from any participation in that employment.
Another reason, which should interest the sympathies of the Republic,
and enlist the aid of the Government, in favor of Texas, is its locality
being adjoining the territory of a powerful nation, whose established pol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />icy
towards the aborigines, has a tendency to flood Texas with Indian
emigrants, of a character dangerous in the extreme. The wide extent of
wilderness, forming a nutural boundary between Texas and Coahuila,
places an indispensable barrier in the way of Coahuila’s extending the
efficient means of defence she might wish. This circumstance alone,
demands that all the energies of Texas should be embodied, to prevent
that calamity which threatens this favoured country, and which, nothing
short of a well regulated government of a free, unshackled, and inde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pendent
State, can provide against.
(491 )</p><pb n="492" xml:id="P0492" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/500/" /><p>18
Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
For these reasons, and many others, which the General Congress will
readily conceive, and in view of the decree of the 7th of May, 1824, al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing
the people of Texas, so soon as their situation would permit to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pear
as a distinct state, to report to Congress for their resolution—also,
in connection with the 11th section of the Federal Constitution, guaran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tying
them a representative in Congress, whatever may be their popula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion;
and considering duly, the benefits that would result, both to Texas
and to the nation, we entertain no doubts of the favorable reception of
this petition.—The people of Texas, present the strongest assurances of
their patriotic attachment to the Constitution, and to the Republic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pledging
all and every interest in life, for the support of their declaration.
Therefore, they most respectfully petition, that that part of the Mexi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />can
Republic, known by the name of Texas, shall become a separate state
of the Confederacy, to be placed upon an equal footing with any of the
States of the Union.
(Signed)
• W. McFARLAND, Chairman.
John Austin, chairman of the committee relative to the Custom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />House
Department, made their report.
Mr. Hensley moved the following amendment to said report; to add,
after the words “general Tariff,”—talcing from such officers bonds, with
good and sufficient security, to pay over the money collected according to
law. The emendment was received.
The report, as amended, was adopted, and read as follows:
Report of the Committee on the subject of the Custom-House.
The Committee is of opinion, that this Convention should not inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fere
with the Tariff regulated by the General Government; but recom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mend
that officers be appointed at the several Ports—viz.—Matagorda,
Brazoria, and Galvezton Bay, by the Alcalde of the respective Jurisdiction,
to collect tonnage duty on foreign vessels, in accordance with the regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of the general Tariff, taking such officer’s bond, with good and suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient
security, to pay over the money according to law; and requiring
them to make a report quarterly to the Alcalde of the Jurisdiction in
which they reside. And that the method of ascertaining the tonnage of
vessels which may enter the ports of Texas, shall be by showing the
Registers of said vessels, to the officer directed to receive the dues.
(Signed)
JOHN AUSTIN, Chairman.
On motion of Mr. Harison, leave of absence was granted to Mr. Mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cer,
on account of extreme indisposition.
Mr. Lesassier, chairman of the committee to petition the State Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment
for a donation of land, as a School Fund, presented their report.
Mr. Bruf moved that the blank in said report be filled with twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five
leagues.—Mr.' Groce moved that it be filled with one hundred leagues;
and Mr. Ingram that it be filled with one hundred and fifty.
Mr. Wharton moved that this report be laid on the table indefinitely;
which was negatived—the yeas and nays were as follows:
YEAS,—Geo. B. McKinstry, William H. Wharton, John Austin,
Charles D. Sayre, Ira Ingram, A. B. Dobson, George F. Richardson, Jared
E. Groce, W. R. Hensley, James Kerr, J. K. Looney, Hyman Hartz,
(492)</p><pb n="493" xml:id="P0493" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/501/" /><p>Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
19
Thomas D. Beauchamp, Samuel Loonev, A. Hier, George Butler, John
Connell—17.
NAYS—Wyly Martin, F. W. Johnson, L. Lesassier, Silas Dinsmore,
Samuel Hoit, Alexander Thompson, Robert Wilson, William Robinson,
Joshua Hadly, Samuel Bruf, Jesse Burnham, William Menifee, George
Sutherland, Hugh McGuffin, Charles S. Taylor, Thomas Hastings, Philip
Sublett, D. McDonald, W. McFarland, Wyatt Hanks, Jacob Garret, Elijah
Isaacs, Benjamin Holt, Jesse Parker, William English, Frederick Foye,
John M. Bradley, Jonas Harison, Patrick C. Jack, Claiborne West, James
Morgan, H. S. Brown, C. Stinnett, Samuel C. Douglass—34.
The several motions to fill the blank were withdrawn by the movers:
and, on motion of Mr. Wharton, it was ordered that said blank be filled,
by asking the Government to make such a donation as it may think
proper.
The President called Mr. Lesassier to the chair, and retired on account
of indisposition.
The report of the committee for a donation of land was adopted as
amended.
To His Excellency, the Governor. and the Honorable, the Legislature
of the Free and Sovereign State of Coahuila and Texas:
The inhabitants of Texas, represented by delegates, chosen for the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose
of making known their wants to that Supreme Government, and
assembled in General Convention, in the Town of San Felipe de Austin,
respectfully represent that, from the commencement of the settlement of
Texas, up to the present time, no step has been taken to encourage public
education, and to create a fund exclusively devoted to that object.—They
would respectfully suggest, that intelligence is the main pillow of repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lican
institutions, and that without it no Republic can be long-lived—
that in every well regulated community, where free principles predomi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nate,
education among every class of society, has occupied the attention
of the patriot statesman—that the Government of the State of Coahuila
and Texas, heretofore, so liberal, and ever munificent in grants of lands
to individuals, will, it is hoped, be equally so, in the grant of land for
so useful and patriotic an object as will be the dissemination of knowl<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />edge
through every part of society. Under these considerations, your
memorialists pray a grant of as many leagues of land, for the promotion
of education, as the Legislature, in its liberality, shall think proper to
bestow: to be made to Texas as the foundation of a fund for the future
encouragement of Primary Schools, in Texas, in which will be taught the
Castilian and English Languages: and they further pray, that the said,
grant be made to the Ayuntamientos in Texas, for the use and benefit of
the people in Texas, and for the object aforesaid, with the express condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
that the said lands shall not be sold or otherwise disposed of, until
the voice of the people of Texas, be taken thereon; and your memorialists
conclude with a declaration of their attachment to the Republic of Mex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ico,
and of their devotion to the Federal Constitution, and also of that of
Coahuila and Texas.
(Signed)
L. LESASSIER, Chairman.
( 493 )</p><pb n="494" xml:id="P0494" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/502/" /><p>20
Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
On motion of Mr. Bruff, the Convention adjourned until 3 o’clock,
P. M.
The Convention met agreeably to adjournment—Mr. Lesassier in the
chair.
On motion of Mr. Ingram, it was ordered that a committee be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed,
to take into consideration the expediency and importance, of
appointing a Central Committee of Vigilance, Safety, and Correspond<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence,
in the Town of San Felipe de Austin; as also the expediency and
importance of appointing permanent Sub-Committees, in all the districts
and sections of Texas, for the purpose of circulating information of events
of importance to the interest of the people, throughout every settlement
in the country; and furthermore, instructed to report the names of said
Central and Sub-Committees, for the consideration of this Convention;
and authorised to report the general duties of said Committees.
Whereupon, the following persons were appointed to compose said
committee:
Ira Ingram, G. B. McKinstry, Robert Wilson, J. K. Looney, James
Kerr.
Mr. Taylor, chairman of the committee, on the subject of the claims
of the North American Tribes of Indians, in Texas, made the following
report, which was accepted:
To the Ayuntamiento of Nacogdoches:
The people of Texas, met in General Convention, with anxiety make
known, that they view with regret and concern, the present unfortunate
situation of the North American Tribes of Indians residing in Texas,
and much deplore the transactions which have occasioned it; and in as
much, as a portion of our affairs, in relation to government, are in the
same condition, it will be convenient for us, and perhaps not an improper
duty, to inquire into and apply for a redress of the Indian grievances.
It is known that the Cherokees claim by way of grant, a tract of coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />try
situated about 30 miles to the N. W. of Nacogdoches; which claim
they have been told, is worth about as much as the paper it is written on.
— The Shawnees also, as well as others, have settled in the country, and
have been promised possessions. The promise is still protracted.
When the Indian, inclined as he is to believe a promise made, eventual<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly
must be fulfilled, becomes frequently the dupe of craftiness and oppres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion,
he naturally becomes discontented, unfriendly and hostile; and in
the present instance might be made troublesome to us.
The Indians’ repeated request to obtain their rights, are unattended to,
because an accredited agent of the Government has been illegally sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended
by a military officer, who in continuance of his system of decep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
and conciliation, and with a mew to enlist their aid, declared to the
Cherokees, (at the time we began to evince a disposition of throwng from
our necks, the insupportable weight of Military oppression)—"The
Americans grasping for land, intend making the attempt of driving all
my countrymen from this State, and an extirpation of you all will soon
follow.”
But the conflict at an end, some of our fellow-citizens explaining to
them the true causes which impelled us to arms; and they seeing a large
-lumber of our native Mexican fellow-citizens had taken up arms in our
( 494 )</p><pb n="495" xml:id="P0495" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/503/" /><p>Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
21
behalf, they seemingly became convinced that we fought for justice to
ourselves, and with respect to the rights of every Indian.
But unfortunately just at this time, and while they were being told the
Government would put them in possession of their lands, one or two of
our fellow-citizens, without authority, run off, and included in a survey,
part of the Cherokee claim or grant; consequently creating, by such an
act, a disposition on the part of those Indians, to credit any gross mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />representation
made to them; and to give to former apprehensions the
guise of truth, and they are now losing past confidence in all individual
protestations or advice;—like the wrecked bark, which having crossed a
wide expanse of ocean, is in sight of her destined port, but without the
friendly sails that propelled her, and without any visible aid, or proba<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble
chance of assistance!
Under these circumstances, we most respectfully solicit your Honorable
Body, to investigate the affairs, and learn the wishes of the North Amer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ican
Tribes of Indians, in relation to their lands, so that they may become
assured of our friendship, by active steps taken in their behalf, and to the
end, that they may not be intruded upon unlawfully or unjustly.
And lastly, we beg the Ayuntamiento, of Nacogdoches, will make
known to the Indians that the disposition of the people of Texas is, to as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sist
them in obtaining good titles to, and possession of land, and not to
deprive them of that which they already claim.
C. W. TAYLOR, Chairman.
(Signed)
Mr. Ingram, chairman of the committee, recommending central and
sub-committees throughout Texas, made their report; which was adopted,
and reads as follows:
Me. PRESIDENT:—The Committee to whom was referred the consid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eration
of the question of establishing standing Central and Sub-Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittees
of safety, vigilance, &amp;c. throughout Texas—having given the sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject
their best attention, beg leave to report:—
That they deem such organization both expedient and important; that
it is the only one which the recommendatory powers of this Convention
can adopt, to protect so extended and scattered a population as that of
Texas, and to give its inhabitants, in case of emergency, the benefit of
the means within their control.
Your committee is of opinion, the general duties of such Central and
Sub-Committees, would be best discharged by keeping up a regular and
stated correspondence with each other, on- all subjects relating .to the
peace and safety of the frontier—and on all relating to the tranquility
■of the interior; and they should endeavor, by a conciliating, patriotic and
magnanimous policy, to impress upon the public mind, the high import<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance
of making every sacrifice but the sacrifice of honor and principle, to
the all-important and transcendent object of united counsels. United,
our strength and resources are more than adequate to our defence in any
possible event. Disunited, we may become an easy pray, even to a hand<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful
of cowardly invaders.
Your committee would recommend, that it be the duty of the sub-com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittees
to notify the civil and military authorities, most contiguous to
them, of the approach of danger, in the shortest time practicable, in all
■cases; and that it be the duty of the central committee, on receiving simi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(495
)</p><pb n="496" xml:id="P0496" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/504/" /><p>22
Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
lar information, to circulate it to the civil and miltiary authorities
throughout the country, thro, or by means of the sub-committees, or
otherwise, as shall most expedite its transmission. It is further recom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mended,
that the central committee have power, on application of the
people, to appoint sub-committees in such place and neighborhoods as
may not be accommodated by this report.
Your committee bg leave further to recommend, that a circular be
prepared by the president of this convention, to be signed by him and
countersigned by the secretary, and that one or more copies thereof be
sent to the central committee, and at least one to each sub-committee;,
and furthermore, that in the absence, inability, or indisposition of the
chairman of any such sub-committee to act, that each any every other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />member
of the same, be authorized to receive, open, and answer all des<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />patches,
from whatever source, addressed to said committee or their
chairman as chairman of the same. It is further recommended, that all
vacancies be filled by the central committee, or by its majority, on nomi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation
of the committee in which such vacancy may have occurred, pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided
a nomination be sent in; but where none is received in a reasonable<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />time
after the vacancy occurs, then your committee would recommend,
that the central committee proceed to fill such vacancy without delay.
Your committee recommend, that the central committee have power to
call a Convention of Delegates from all Texas, at such time and place as
they think proper. That the central committee be instructed to furnish
the delegate elected by this convention to go to Mexico, with a letter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />embracing
such matters of fact as maybe connected with the object of
his mission; and with such arguments connected therewith, as may in
their opinion be calculated to aid the said delegate in the discharge of his
high and important trust.
Your committee recommend for the consideration of the Convention,,
the following list of names for the Central and Sub-Committees:
CENTRAL COMMITTEE :
Francis W. Johnson, James B. Miller, Stephen F. Austin, Lewis L.
Veeder, Robert Peebles, Wyly Martin, Wm. Pettis.
SUB-COMMITTEES :
For the District of Sabine:---<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Holt.

For the District of Tennehaw:—
For the District of Nacogdoches:
tings.
McMahon,
Smith, Benjamin:
G. Butler, E. Rains, Jonas Harison.
—C. S. Tayor, H. Hartz, Thomas Has<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />For
the District of Cow Bayou:—
Garnder.
For the District of San Jacinto :
son, Wm. P. Harris.
Claiborne West, G. A. Patillo, David
D. G. Burnett, George E. Richard<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />For
the District of Mina:—Samuel Hoit, Robert H. Williams, Eli Mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cer.

For the District of Snow-River:—Samuel Lewis, Ephraim Thompson,.
Major Dailey.
(496 )</p><pb n="497" xml:id="P0497" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/505/" /><p>Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
23
For the District ofAyish-Bayou:—John G. Love, Baily Anderson, Isaac
W. Barron.
For the District of Anahuac:—James Morgan, G. M. Patrick, J. C.
Eeed.
For the District of Liberty:—P. C. Jack, H. B. Johnston, A. B. Harden.
For the District of Labaca:—Hugh McGuffin, G. Sutherland, John An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />drews.

For the District of Gonzales:—Eli Mitchell, H. S. Brown, Thomas E.
Miller.
For the District of Alfred:—William Robinson, W. E. Hensley, Samuel
Bluff.
For the District of Hidalgo:—Nestor Clay, A. Thompson, John P.
. Cole.
For the District of Victoria:—John Austin, Charles D. Sayre, George
B. McKinstry, Charles B. Stewart, W. D. C. Hall.
For the District of Viesca:—Jesse Grimes, Francis Holland, John Bow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man.

For the District of Bastrop:—E. Andrews, T. G. Gazley, Bartlett Sims..
All of which is respectfully submitted.
(Signed)
IEA INGRAM, Chairman.
John Austin, chairman of the committee, to whom was referred the'
subject of recommending an uniform mode for oganizing the Militia of
Texas, made the following report, which was adopted:
The committee to whom was referred the reporting of an uniform
mode of organizing the militia of Texas, report as follows:
1st. The committee recommend the plan or regulation made by the
Ayuntamiento of Austin, which ordains—
Article 1. The Militia of the Municipality shall be organized into one
regiment, to be composed of two battalions, and twelve companies.
Art. 2. The companies shall be formed as follows:—the west side of
the Brazos river, within the Precinct of Victoria, shall form one com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany
district; the precinct of San Jacinto one; that of Viesca, one; that
of Hidalgo, one; that of Bastrop, one; that of Alfred, one; that of Mina,
one; that of Labaca, one; that of San Felipe, one; that of Gonzales, one;
and that of Mill Creek, one.
Art. 3. Each company shall be composed of one Captain, three Lieu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenants,
four Sergeants, three Corporals, one Quarter-master Corporal,
and the number of men within the district.
Art. 4. The Field Officers and Staff, shall consist of one Colonel, one
Lieutenant-Colonel, one Major, one First Adjutant, one Second Adjutant,
one Quarter-Master, one Surgeon, and one Surgeon’s mate. The Colonel
may appoint the non-commissioned officers of his staff, as he may think
proper.
Art. 5. The first battalion shall be composed of the districts of San
Felipe, Mill Creek, Hidalgo, Viesca, Alfred and Bastrop, to be numbered
from, one to six, in the order they stand in the article.
Art. 6. The first battalion shall be composed of the companies on the
west and east side of the Brazos in the Precinct of Victoria, and of the
Districts of Mina, San Jacinto, Labaca, and Gonzales, to be numbered
from one to six, in like manner.
Art. 7. Every man within the Municipality, able to bear arms, over the
32—vol. i.
(497)</p><pb n="498" xml:id="P0498" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/506/" /><p>24
Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
age of sixteen and under fifty years, shall be liable to militia duty, and
shall arm himself with gun and equipments.
Art, 8. The elections for officers and non-commissioned officers, shall
be held in each company district, the second Saturday of October next.
The alcalde shall give notice in each district, and appoint a central place
for holding each election, and a person who shall preside, aided by two
tellers and a secretary, to be appointed, by the militia present, at the open<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
of the polls. The election shall commence at 10 o’clock, A. M. and
close at 4 o’clock, p. M.
Art. 9. The militiamen shall, at the same time, vote for a Colonel, a
Lieutenant-Colonel, and Major. The staff officers of the regiment, shall
be appointed by the field officers.
Art. 10. The returns of the elections, shall be made within ten days
from the time they are held, by the respective presidents, tellers, and sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retaries,
to the President of the Ayuntamiento; which body shall issue a
certificate to each of the officers and non-commissioned officers who are
elected. A record of the same shall be made, and a book kept for that
purpose in the archives of the Ayuntamiento.
Art. 11. All vacancies shall be supplied by elections ordered by the
commandant of the regiment, on receiving notice thereof.
Art. 12. Any officer, or non-commissioned officer, who removes out
of the limit of the district for which he was elected, shall lose his com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission
by such removal.
Art. 13. The penalty for non attendance of a company muster, shall
not exceed fifty dollars for officers, and ten dollars for non-commissioned
officers and privates.
Art. 14. Ungentlemanly conduct, or disobedience of orders, or neglect
of duty by officers, shall be punished by cashiering, suspension for a time,
.reprimand or fine, at the discretion of the court martial.
Art. 15. Disrespect to superiors, neglect of duty, or disobedience of
■orders, by non-commissioned officers or privates, shall be punished by
arrest under guard, public reprimand, or fine, at the discretion of the
court martial: provided, that in actual service, the officer in command
can resort to such punishment as the exigency may require; but always
on his own responsibility, as liable to punishment himself, should a com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />petent
court martial decide that such punishment was excessive, or im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />properly
executed or applied.
Art. 16. Sleeping on post or deserting it, shall be punished at the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cretion
of the court martial.
Art. 17. There shall be general, regimental and special court martials.
Art. 18. The general court martial shall be convened by the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mandant
of the regiment, except when the charges are against said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mandant,
in which case it shall be convened by the Ayuntamiento, and
shall try all charges against officers, including the commander of the
rigiment, and all offences committed by officers, non-commissioned offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers
and privates, when the punishment is death. This court shall be
composed of not less than five, nor more than thirteen members, to be
nominated by the commandant of the regiment, or should he be ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cused,
then by the Ayuntamiento.
Art. 19. The regimental court martial shall be convened by the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mandant
of the regiment. and shall be composed of three commissioned
■officers, to be nominated by him. This court shall try all charges against
(498 )</p><pb n="499" xml:id="P0499" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/507/" /><p>Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
25
non-commissioned officers and privates, except when the punishment is
death. Two or more of such regimental courts may be convened at the
same time, in different places, to impose fines for non attendace at com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany
musters, or refusing to obey a draft, or other disobedience or neg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lect
of duty.
Art. 20. Special court martials may be convened by an officer in com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mand
of the regiment, or a detachment, when in actual service. These
courts shall have the same power as the regimental court martial.
Art. 21. It shall be discretionary with the commandant of the regi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
to order company, battalion and regimental musters, when ever he
may deem it necessary, and to form regulations for classing and drafting
the militia.
Art. 22. One volunteer uniform company may be raised in each bat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />talion,
which shall not exceed fifty men in the aggregate. Such company
shall be subject to the orders of the commandant of the regiment or bat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />talion,
and the rules prescribed in this regulation, but may form bye-laws
for their own internal regulations.
Art, 23. It shall be the duty of the field officers, to suggest to the
Ayuntamiento, such amendments to this regulation, as experience may
indicate as necessary.
2nd. The committee recommend, that the Districts of Nacogdoches,
Ayish Bayou, Tennehaw, Snow River, and Sabine form one regiment.
3rd. That the District of Liberty, and the inhabitants east of said
settlement, on the Sabine river, and those of Cow-Bayou, form one bat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />talion.

4th. This committee request the Ayuntamiento of Nacogdoches, to
organize its militia agreeably to this plan, and also the Ayuntamiento
of Liberty, and make return of the officers elected, to the Ayuntamiento
of Austin.
5th. The committee recommend, that a Brigadier-General be elected,
to take command of the whole militia,
6th. That so soon as may be, after the organization of the militia, the
Ayuntamiento of Austin shall order an election for Brigadier-General,
by the commissioned officers of the two regiments.
" (Signed)	JOHN AUSTIN, Chairman.
On motion of Mr. Harison, it was resolved, that a committee of two
persons be appointed to represent to the Legislature of Coahuila and
Texas the necessity of appointing a Surveyor-General for Texas, and that
said committee recommend Francis W. Johnson, as a qualified person to
fill that post:
Whereupon, Jonas Harison, and Luke Lesassier were appointed to
compose said committee.—On motion, S. F. Austin was added.
Mr. Hensley, chairman of the committee, relative to the protection of
Austin’s and Dewitt’s Colonies aginst Indian depredations, made the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing
report, which was accepted:
To the Honorable, the Convention, now in Session:
Gentlemen:—In accordance with the trust reposed in your commit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tee;
appointed for the purpose of making inquiry into the Indian affairs
(499 )</p><pb n="500" xml:id="P0500" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/508/" /><p>26
Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
of Texas, and to fix on some plan for the protection of the frontiers, beg
leave respectfully to report:
1st. That, from the best information that we can obtain, we find the
Indians are daily committing some depredations on the frontier of our
country; such as murdering our citizens, stealing our horses, &amp;c.
2nd. That we are of the opinion, the best mode of defending our fron<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tier,
is that immediately after the organization of the militia of Austin’s
and Dewitt’s Colonies, the first battalion be required to furnish forty
men, properly officered, to serve on our frontier for the term of forty
days.
3rd. That in anticipation of the expiration of the time of said detach<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
the second battalion be required to furnish the same quota of men,
to serve a like term of forty days; and so alternately, each battalion of
said. regiment furnishing its quota of forty men, in anticipation of the
close of the term of those in service.
W. E. HENSLEY, Chairman.
(Signed)
Mr. Menifee moved, that the sense of the Convention be taken, whether
there shall be one or two delegates sent to Saltillio, and Mexico, to bear
the mission of this Convention.
Whereupon, it was resolved by the Convention, that only one delegate
should be sent.
On motion of Mr. Hoit, it was resolved, that no new business be ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted
before the Convention after this day.
On motion of Mr. Kerr, it was resolved, that the Central Committee
be requested to correspond with the inhabitants of San Antonio, Labahia,
and Victoria, to inform them of the proceedings of this Convention, and
to solicit them to cooperate to procure a repeal of the 11th article of the
Law of the 6th of April, 1830: and also, invite those districts of country,
to concur with us to procure a State Government for Texas.
On motion of Mr. Kerr, the Convention adjourned until Saturday,
9 o’clock A. M.
SATURDAY, October 6.
The Convention met agreeably to adjournment.
Wyly Martin moved, that the Convention now proceed, in compliance
with the resolution adopted yesterday, to the election of a suitable person
to bear the mission of this Convention, to the State and General Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments:
and he recommended W. H. WEARTON for that service.
Whereupon, the Convention proceeded to said election, vive voce, and
Mt. Wharton was unanimously elected.
Mr. Wharton, in his place, presented the Convention his thanks for
their confidence.
On motion of Mr. Hoit, it was resolved, that a committee of five per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons
be appointed, to devise ways and means to defray the expenses of
the Delegate to Mexico.
Whereupon, Messrs. Hoit, Groce, Harison, Morgan, and Kerr, were
appointed said committee.—On motion, it was ordered, that S. F. Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin,
W. D. C. Hall and C. S. Taylor be added to said committee.
On motion of Mr. Jack, it was resolved, that this Convention proceed
to recommend to the people of Texas, a suitable person as Brigadier Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(500)
</p><pb n="501" xml:id="P0501" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/509/" /><p>Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
27
eral. Captain WYLY Martin was, thereupon, unanimously recommend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed
as a suitable person for that office.
On motion of Mr. Lesassier, the Convention adjourned until 4 o’clock
P. M.
The Convention met agreeably to adjournment.
Mr. Harison, chairman of the committee to whom was referred the
situation of the land business east of the San Jacinto, made the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
report, which was unanimously adopted.
To His Excellency, the Governor of the State of Coahuila and Texas:
The inhabitants of Texas, convened in General Convention of Dele<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gates,
in the Town of San Felipe de Austin, for the purpose of represent<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
their situation to the Government, respectfully set forth to your ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cellency:
that from the year 1821, up to the present time, a number of
industrious citizens have settled in the district of country between the
San Jacinto, and Sabine Rivers; and that the settlers have made ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tensive
and valuable improvements in farms, mills, cotton gins, and ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chinery;
and having uniformly been obedient to the Constitution, in the
year 18.28, grants of land were made to them by the government, and
Don Juan Antonio Padilla was appointed Commissioner to issue the
titles. Unfortunate circumstances prevented the said Commissioner from
completing the objects of his commission, and the business remained in
suspense. In 1831, Don Jose Francisco Madero was appointed Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner
by the government for the same purpose, but unfortunately he
was arrested by military authority, and prevented from issuing the titles.
These repeated delays and embarrassments have defeated the paternal
intentions of the government, in favor of the inhabitants of that remote
section of the State, who still remain in the most cruel uncertainty as to
their land titles. Relying on the grants made in 1828, and the Coloniza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
Laws, they have made, as has been said, important improvements;
and if fostered by the government, will be an efficient defence of the
frontier against Indians, or other enemies. The uncertainty of their
situation, causes an uneasiness among the inhabitants, and cannot be
favorable to the public tranquility, and is in the highest degree prejudi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial
to the prosperity of the country. The number of inhabitants is suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient
for the establishment of new’ Ayuntamientos. The organization
of the local government in that section of the State, is very defective.
There are but two Ayuntamintos between the San Jacinto and, Sabine
Rivers; one at Nacogdoches, and one at Liberty, on the Trinity. The
greatest inconveniences and evils may arise from such a state of things;
for a large portion of the inhabitants are almost without any local gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment.

Influenced by these reasons, and the most firm and decided attach<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
and adhesion to the Constitution of the Republic, and of the State,
and the most sincere desire for our country’s prosperity, this Convention
respectfully petition, that your Excellency will be pleased to appoint a
Commissioner, duly authorized to give titles of possesion to the inhabi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tants
living between said San Jacinto and Sabine Rivers: and to estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish
the Ayuntamientos in conformity to the Laws of Colonization.
(Signed)
J. HARISON, Chairman.
(501)</p><pb n="502" xml:id="P0502" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/510/" /><p>28
Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
Mr. Holt, chairman of the committee to whom was referred the sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject
of ways and means to defray the expences of the Delegate to Mexico,
made the following report, the recommendations of which were adopted:
The committee to whom was referred the resolution in relation to a
supply of means to defray the expenses of a Delegate, on his mission to
the Mexican Congress, and devise ways by which the same may be raised,
have had the subject matter under consideration, and have unanimously
agreed, that the sum of $2000 will be necessary: and propose to the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention,
that said sum be raised by subscription from the people.
That one person be appointed from each Precinct, whose duty it shall
be to obtain subscriptions, and when obtained to forward them to Walter
C. White, Esq. whom we propose to be appointed Treasurer-General,
whose duty it will be to obtain subscriptions at San Eelipe de Austin, and
also to receive such sums as may be forwarded to him by said Precinct
Treasurers, and pay the same over to Wm. H. Wharton, Esq. or order,
when called on. The committee would further recommend, that the
delegates from each precinct nominate to the President of this Conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
a suitable person to obtain said subscriptions, and that the President
issue his letter of appointment accordingly. The committee would fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ther
recommend, that the Precinct Treasurers be instructed to make re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turn
of what money they have ,collected, on or before the first day of De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cember
next; and also continue a monthly return, until they are in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formed
by the Treasurer-General the required sum of $2000 is collected.
All of which is respectfully submitted.
(Signed)	S. HOIT, Chairman.
On motion of Mr. McFarland, it was ordered, that the following be
added as an amendment to the report of the committee, to whom was
referred the subject of reporting some uniform mode of organizing the
' militia of Texas:
Resolved, that an election of company and regimental officers be held
on the first Saturday in November next.
On motion of Mr.Bruf, it was resolved, that the Secretary be directed
to make out a fair statement of the proceedings of this Convention, and
transmit them to the printing office in Brazoria for publication, and the
Ayuntamiento pay the expence.
"Mr. Harison, chairman of the committee on the appointment of a
Surveyor-General, made the following report, which was received by the
Convention:
The committee to whom was referred the subject of petitioning the
Government to create a Surveyor-General for Texas, and to recommend
E. W. Johnson for that station, beg leave to report, that as the subject is
of great importance, and accompanied with much detail, in setting forth
the proper fees of compensation for surveying, and the various duties of
said office, they, therefore, ask that the discharge of the duties of this
committee be postponed until after the adjournment of the. Convention;
and that they then have the power to draw up a suitable petition to Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment,
and also, draft a law calculated to effect the object desired, in
time to forward by our Representative to Congress.
(Signed)	J- HARISON, Chairman.
( 502)</p><pb n="503" xml:id="P0503" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/511/" /><p>Proceedings of the Convention of Texas.
29
Mr. Beauchamp, chairman of the committee to whom was referred the
subject of petitioning the State Government for a law authorising the
people of Texas to transact their business in the English language, except
such as relate to the Government, made a report, which was rejected.
On motion of Mr. Taylor, it was resolved, that a deputation of four
persons be appointed Commissioners to assist the Ayuntamiento of Nac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ogdoches
in their inquiries into the affairs of the North American Tribes
of Indians: and that William McFarland, Thomas Hastings, James Brad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />shaw,
and Elisha Clapp, form said Commission.
The following persons were recommended and appointed District
Treasurers.
District of Alfred, William Robinson; Gonzales, Eli Mitchell; San
Jacinto, George F. Richardson; Hidalgo, Thomas S. Saul; Mill Creek,
A. Kuykendall; Mina, R. R. Royall; Labaca, J. Kerr; Viesca, Jesse
Grimes; Bastrop, B. Sims; Liberty, W. Shaw; Cow Bayou, Geo. A.
Patillo; Anahuac, G. M. Patrick; Nacogdoches, John S. Roberts; Ayish
Bayou, B. Lindsey; Snow Biver, S. Lewis; Tennehaw, John English;
Victoria, Asa Brigham; Sabine, Major McMahon.
The President having retired for a moment;
On motion of Mr. Hoit, it was resolved, that the thanks and approba<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of the Convention be presented to Col. S. F. Austin, for the very
able, dignified and impartial manner in which he has sustained the duties
of the chair.
Resolved, that the thanks and approbation of the Convention be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sented
to F. W. Johnson, Esq. for the able and faithful discharge of his
duties as Secretary.
On motion of Mr. Kerr, the Convention adjourned sine die.
(Signed)
F. W. JOHNSON, Secretary.
S. F. AUSTIN, President.
(503)</p><pb n="504" xml:id="P0504" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/512/" /><p /></div></body></text>
