<text>
<front>
<pb n="505" xml:id="P0505" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/513/" />
<head>JOURNALS
<lb />OF THE
<lb />CONSULTATION
<lb />HELD AT
<lb />SAN FELIPE DE AUSTIN,</head>

<head>OCTOBER 16, 1835.</head>

<head>PUBLISHED BY ORDER OF CONGRESS.</head>

<head>HOUSTON.
<lb />1838
</head>

</front>
<pb n="506" xml:id="P0506" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/514/" /><p />

<body>
    <div type="document">
<pb n="507" xml:id="P0507" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/515/" />


<head>JOURNALS.</head>

<p>Council Hall, December 35, 1835.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That this revised Journal of the Proceedings of the Conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
be handed over to the printer for pubheation.</p>

<p>Agreeably to a resolution of the Convention, Mr. Mitehell was ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed
to superintend the printing of the journal.</p>

<p>Passed at San Felipe de Austin, Dec. 25, 1835.</p>

<p>
JAMES W. ROBINSON,
<lb /><hl rend="italics">Lieutenant Governor, ex officio President of the General Council.</hl>
</p>

<head>COLUMBIA MEETING.</head>

<p>At an adjourned meeting of the citizens of Columbia, held in the town
of Columbia, on Saturday the fifteenth day of August, Wm. H. Wharton,
Esq. was called to the chair, and Wm. T. Austin appointed secretary,
when the following resolutions were adopted.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That a consultation of all Texas, through her representatives,
is indispensable.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That a committee composed of fifteen persons, <hl rend="italics">to be called a
Committee of Safety and Correspondence for the jurisdiction of Columbia,</hl>
be elected, and that they be instructed to prepare an address to all the
jurisdictions of Texas, requesting them to co-operate with us in the call
of a consultation of all Texas.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the committee communicate with all Texas in the most
prompt manner, by sending confidential agents to each jurisdiction, and
that said committee keep the people constantly advised of all political
intelligence of general interest, and that they continue to act until dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />placed
by the people or the consultation.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That we hold ourselves bound to pay our proportion of all
expenses incurred by said committee, in sending expresses, printing, &amp;c.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That we invest the committee of safety and correspondence
as our agents, with full power to represent the jurisdiction of Columbia,
to use the most efficient means to call a consultation, and to use all means
in their power to secure peace, and watch over our rights.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That we will not give up any individual to the military
authorities.</p>

<p>In compliance with the second resolution, the following gentle<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men
were elected a committee of safety and correspondence: John A.
Wharton, W. D. C. Hall, Henry Smith, Silas Dinsmore, James F. Perry,
John G. M’Neel, Robert H. Williams, Wm. H. Jack, F. A. Bingham,
John Hodge, Wade H. Bynum, B. T. Archer, Wm. F. Austin, P. Ber<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trand,
and Isaac T. Tinsley.</p>

<pb n="508" xml:id="P0508" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/516/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the proceedings of this meeting be published in the
Texas Republican.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the thanks of this meeting be given to the chairman and
secretary.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That this meeting adjourn.</p>

<p>WILLIAM H. WHARTON, <hl rend="italics">Chairman.</hl></p>
<p>Wm. T. Austin, <hl rend="italics">Secretary.</hl></p>

<p>Agreeably to the foregoing resolution, the citizens of the several muni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cipalities
of Texas elected delegates to meet in general consultation on
the fifteenth day of October, who this day convened.</p>

<p>CONVENTION Room, San Felipe de Austin.</p>

<p>October 16, 1835.</p>

<p>The members having come to order, Mr. Royal, of Matagorda was
called to the chair, and Samuel Whiting appointed secretary.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Everitt,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the members present their cetificates of election, to the
meeting, when the following gentlemen presented their certificates.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">From the Municipality of Bevil:</hl></p>

<p>John Bevill, Wyatt Hanks, Thomas Holmes, S. H. Everett, John H.
Blount.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">From the Municipality of San Augustine:</hl></p>

<p>A. Houston, Jacob Garrett, Wm. N. Sigler, A. E. C. Johnson.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">From the Municipality of Harrisburg:</hl></p>

<p>Lorenzo de Zavala, Clement C. Dyer, Wm. P. Harris.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">From the Municipality of Matagorda:</hl></p>

<p>Ira R. Lewis, R. R. Royal, Charles Wilson.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">From the Municipality of Viesca:</hl></p>

<p>J. G. W. Pierson, J. L. Hood, S. T. Allen, A. G. Perry, J. W. Parker,
Alexander Thompson.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">From the Municipality of Nacogdoches:</hl></p>

<p>Wm. Whitaker, Sam. Houston, Daniel Parker, James W. Robinson,
N. Robins.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">From the Municipality of Columbia:</hl></p>

<p>John A. Wharton, Henry Smith, Edwin Waller, J. S. D. Byrom.</p>

<pb n="509" xml:id="P0509" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/517/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<p><hl rend="italics">From the Municipality of Austin:</hl></p>

<p>Wyly Martin, Thomas Barnett.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. D. Parker, the chairman was requested to com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />municate
to the house such letters and documents as have been received
from the army; whereupon,</p>

<p>The chairman read to the house all such letters and documents as
were in his possession.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Martin, the house adjourned until to-morrow morn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing.</p>

<head>October 17, 1835.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment, and proceeded to business.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. D. Parker, seconded by Mr. John A. Wharton, the
following preamble and resolutions were unanimously adopted.</p>

<p>Whereas, there is not a sufficient number of members present to form
a quorum of the consultation, owing to the members being absent in the
army; therefore,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the members present adjourn until the first day of next
month, or as soon as a quorum can meet at this place, so as to afford an
opportunity to those who may desire it to join the army in the defence
of their country.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That those who cannot join the army may remain here, with
the permission to unite with the Council of Texas, and to have access
to all the intelligence in possession of the Council relative to the present
crisis.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That they he requested to transmit all the information of
importance to the several municipalities by which they have been dele<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gated,
and whatever else which of right they ought to do. Whereupon,
the Consultation adjourned.</p>

<p>E. E. ROYAL, <hl rend="italics">Chairman.</hl></p>

<p>SAM’L Whiting, <hl rend="italics">Secretary.</hl></p>

<head>San Filipe de Austin, Nov. 1st, 1835.</head>

<p>The General Consultation met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>Mr. Royal, the chairman, called the house to order.</p>

<p>The roll having been called, the following members appeared and took:
their seats:</p>

<p>From the municipality of Bevil—John Bevil, S. H. Everitt, Wyatt
Hanks.</p>

<p>From the municipality of San Augustine—William N. Sigler, A. Hous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton,
A. E. C. Johnson.</p>

<p>From the municipality of Nacogdoches—Sam Houston, James W. Rob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inson,
Dan’l Parker.</p>

<p>From the municipality of Columbia—John A. Wharton, J. S. D. By<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rom,
Edwin Waller.</p>

<p>From the municipality of Austin—Wiley Martin, Randall Jones,
Thomas Barnett.</p>

<p>From the municipality of Liberty—Henry Millard, Claiborne West.</p>

<pb n="510" xml:id="P0510" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/518/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<p>From the municipality of Harrisburg-—Lorenzo De Zavala, M. W.
Smith, Wm. P. Harris, John W. Moore.</p>

<p>From the municipality of Matagorda—R. R. Royall, Cha’s Wilson.</p>

<p>From the municipality of Mina—D. C. Barrett, R. M. Williamson.</p>

<p>On motion, the house adjourned to ten o’clock to-morrow morning.</p>

<head>NOvEMBER 2nd, 1835, 10 o’clock, A. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment. Several additional members
appeared and took their seats.</p>

<p>A quorum not being present, the house adjourned to nine o’clock to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />morrow
morning.</p>

<head>NOvEMBER 3rd, 1835, 9 o’clock, A. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment. There being a quorum pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent,</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. S. Houston, the house proceeded to an election of
president and other officers.</p>

<p>Whereupon, B. T. Archer was elected president, and P. B. Dexter,
secretary.</p>

<p>Mr. Archer, on taking the chair, delivered the following address:</p>

<p>Gentlemen—I return you my thanks for the honor you have conferred
on me. The duties which devolve on the members of this body are ardu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ous
and highly important; in fact, the destinies of Texas are placed in
your hands; and I hope that you are now assembled, in every way pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pared
to discharge those duties in a manner creditable to yourselves and
beneficial to your country. I call upon each and all of you to divest your<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />selves
of all party feelings, to discard every selfish motive, and look alone
to the true interest of your country. In the words of the Hebrew pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />phet,
I would say, “Put off your shoes, for the ground upon which you
stand is holy.” The rights and .liberties of thousands of freemen are in
your hands, and millions yet unborn may be affected by your decisions.</p>

<p>The <hl rend="italics">first</hl> measure that will be brought before the house, will be a de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />claration
in which we will set forth to the world the <hl rend="italics">causes</hl> which have
impelled us to take up arms, and the <hl rend="italics">objects</hl> for which we fight.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Secondly.</hl> I will suggest for your consideration the propriety of es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablishing
a provisional government, the election of a governor, lieuten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ant
governor and council; and I would recommend that these officers
be clothed with both legislative and executive powers. This measure I
conceive absolutely necessary to prevent Texas from falling into the
labyrinth of anarchy.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Thirdly.</hl> The organization of the military requires your immediate
attention. You have an army in the field whose achievements have al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ready
shed lustre upon our arms, they have not the provisions and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />forts
necessary to continue their services in the field; give them char<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />acter
or their victories, though they are achieved not without danger and
glory, will, nevertheless, be unproductive of good; sustain and support
them and they will do honor to you, and render incalculable services to
their country; but neglect them, Texas is lost. The adoption of a code
of military laws is indispensable; without discipline and order in the
ranks, your armies will be mobs, more dangerous to themselves than to
their adversaries, and liable at all times to be routed and cut to pieces
by a handful of regulars. I know the men that are now in the field; there

<pb n="511" xml:id="P0511" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/519/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

never were better materials for soldiers; but without discipline they can
achieve nothing. Establish military laws, and like the dragon’s teeth
sown by Cadmus, they will produce armed men. It will be necessary
to procure funds in order to establish the contemplated government, and
to.carry on the war in which we are now engaged; it will, therefore, be our
duty to elect agents to procure those funds. I have too high an opinion
of the plain practical sense of the members of this body, to think for a
moment, that they will elect any but some of our most influential citizens
to this important post. Without funds, however heroically your armies
may fight, however wisely your councils may legislate, they will erect
but a baseless fabric that will fall of its own weight.</p>

<p>There are several warlike and powerful tribes of Indians, that claim
certain portions of our lands. Locations have been made within the
limits they claim, which has created great dissatisfaction amongst them;
some of the chiefs of those tribes are expected here in a few days; and I
deem it expedient to make some equitable arrangement of the matter
that will prove satisfactory to them.</p>

<p>Permit me to call your attention to another subject. Some of our
brethren of the United States of the north, hearing of our difficulties,
have generously come to our aid, many more ere long will be with us;
services such as they will render, should never be forgotten. It will be
proper for this convention to secure to them the rights and privileges of
citizens, to secure to them their land “in head rights,” and place them
on the same footing with those of our citizens who have not yet obtained
from government their lands; and in all other respects to place them
on an equal footing with our most favored citizens. Again, the path
to promotion must be open, they must know that deeds of chivalry and
heroism will meet their rewards, and that you will throw no obstruction
in their pathway to fame.</p>

<p>Some fraudulent sales or grants of land, by the late government of
Coahuila and Texas, will require your attention. The establishment of
mails, and an express department, is deemed necessary to promote the
interest of the country; besides other minor matters that have escaped
my observation in this cursory review.</p>

<p>Finally, Gentlemen and friends, let me call your attention from these
details to the high position which you now occupy; let me remind
you that the eyes of the world are upon you; that battling as we are
against the despotism of a military chieftain, all true republicans, all
friends to the liberties of man, are anxious spectators of the conflict, or
deeply interested in the cause. Let us give evidence that we are the
true descendants of that band of heroes, who sustained an eight years’
war against tyranny and oppression and gave liberty to a new world.
Let our achievements be such that our mother country, when she reads
the bright page that records them, shall proudly and joyfully exclaim,
these are my sons! their heroic deeds mark them as such.</p>

<p>Again, gentlemen, let me admonish you that “the ground on which
you stand is holy,’’that your decisions will affect the rights and liberties
of thousands of freemen, and destinies of millions yet unborn, and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />haps
the cause of liberty itself. I do not view the cause in which we
are engaged, as that of freemen fighting alone against military despotism;
I do not view it as Texas battling alone for her rights and her liberties;
I view it in a more nobler, more exalted light, I view it as the great

<pb n="512" xml:id="P0512" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/520/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

work of laying the corner stone of liberty in the great Mexican
republic.</p>

<p>On motion, Mr. Pettus was appointed sergeant-at-arms of the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention,
with the privilege (in the event of his having more important
duties to perform,) of appointing a deputy.</p>

<p>The following resolution, offered by Mr. S. Houston, was unanimously
adopted:</p>

<p>Whereas, The general Convention of all Texas, assembled, have learned,
with great pleasure, that a detachment of the army of the people, under
the command of Col. James Bowie and Capt. J. W. Fannin, on the
morning of the th of October, encountered a detachment of the army
of General Cos, consisting of about four hundred men, cavalry and in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fantry,
while their force only consisted of ninety-two, rank ond file, near
the mission of Conception, and obtained a complete victory over them.
While the loss of the Anglo-Americans was one man dangerously wound<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed;
and the loss of the enemy, sixteen found dead on the field of battle,
with the supposed loss of sixteen more borne off. Therefore,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the thanks of the convention be rendered to Gen. Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin,
Col. James Bowie and Capt. J. W. Fannin, with the troops engaged
in the action, as a tribute due to their heroism, gallantry and valor, in the
defence of the rights of Texas and constitutional liberty.</p>

<p>Mr. E. Hall, agent of a committee in New-Orleans, presented certain
documents, which were read, and on motion of Mr. Wharton, ordered
that they be laid on the table.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Robinson, a committee of five was appointed to take
into consideration the communications from the New-Orleans commit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tee;
and Messrs. J. A. Wharton, S. Houston, Robinson, Royal and D.
Parker were appointed on that committee, with instructions to report
thereon.</p>

<p>Mr. Royal asked and obtained leave to read a report from the general
council, containing an exhibit of the proceedings of that body.</p>

<head>San Felipe de Austin, Nov. 1st, 1835.</head>

<p>To the honorable Consultation of the chosen delegates of all Texas, in
general convention assembled—</p>

<p>The general council begs leave to report, that now on the organiza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of your honorable body the duties of the council terminate, and it
is with much satisfaction that we surrender into your hands the records
of our proceedings. In the discharge of its duties, it became necessary
for the council to take the responsibility of acts of magnitude, if in
doing so we have transcended the authority that was intended to be dele<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gated
to us, we hope that the liberality of your assembly will attribute
it to motives of rendering important, if not indispensable, aid to the cause
in which Texas is engaged.</p>

<p>As the most trivial acts of the council are on record, and too numerous
to be couched in this report, it will present to your consideration at the
moment, the most important acts, and those incurring the greatest re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sponsibility,
that you may improve or reform as your wisdom may ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prove.</p>

<p>On the fourteenth of October, Mr. Sims Hall was commissioned as con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tractor
of the army, from whose report there are reasons to believe that
upwards of one hundred beeves and a considerable quantity of corn meal

<pb n="513" xml:id="P0513" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/521/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

are on the way, or repairing to headquarters; and as connected with this
subject, we will also inform you that supplies of sugar, coffee, bacon,
blankets, shoes, tent clothes, &amp;c., have been forwarded from Columbia,
Brazoria and Matagorda. But as winter is approaching, high water and
bad roads may be expected, we, therefore, recommend that a. large quan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tity
be forwarded to head quarters or some convenient point.</p>

<p>We have reasons to believe that one eighteen pounder, and a twelve
pounder of artillery are on the way, with a fair proportion of powder
and ball.</p>

<p>We have authorised the raising of twenty-five volunteer rangers, to
range between Colorado and Brazos, on the frontier settlements; twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five
between Brazos and Trinity rivers, and thirty-five east of the Trinity
river; promising each volunteer one dollar and twenty-five cents per day.</p>

<p>The council has made provisions for the collection of the public dues;
on file marked G. This it will be necessary to take up and revise.</p>

<p>The council has ordered to be carried into effect, by subscription under
certain regulations, a mail route from San Felipe de Austin to Canton<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
Jessup, in the United States, to head quarters of the army or to
Bexar and to Velasco. This subject should, at a suitable time, be taken
up, and branch routes be ordered. These resolutions are on file marked
H; and to carry the project into effect, the council appointed John Rice
Jones, post master general.</p>

<p>On the twenty-sixth of October the council drafted an address to the
people of the United States of the north, which was forwarded to the
editors at Natchitoches for publication, and will be found on file mark<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed
M.</p>

<p>On the twenty-seventh the council passed a resolution, requiring the
suspension of the proceedings of the various land offices, for reasons
therein stated, which will be found on file marked N, copies of which,
have been ordered to be served on all the land commissioners.</p>

<p>We authorised a contract for a loan of one hundred thousand dollars
of the citizens of New Orleans, and appointed T. F. McKinney an agent
to repair to New Orleans, and to carry it into effect, under instructions
on file marked O.</p>

<p>On the thirty-first, the council received a number of letters from
Thomas F. McKinney, and other gentlemen of the lower country, urging
the necessity of the council granting letters to certain persons therein
named, to cruise for Mexican armed vessels; which was granted and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missions
issued, and a copy on file marked P, and accompanied with in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structions
marked G.</p>

<p>Our finances arising from the receipts of dues for lands, as will
appear on file in Mr. Gail Borden’s report, marked F, which were in his
hands, is fifty-eight dollars and thirty cents; this money has been ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hausted,
and an advance by the president of the council of thirty-six dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars.
There were also several hundred dollars in the hands of Mr. Money,
the alcalde of the Municipality of Austin; upon this money several ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vances
have been made by Mr. Cochran, and probably will nearly cover
the amount of the money in the alcalde’s hands; as such, you may consider
that at this moment, the council is out of funds.</p>

<p>Two Mexican officers, prisoners of war, are now on parole of honor,
having the privilege of the town of San Felipe; it will be necessary that

<pb n="514" xml:id="P0514" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/522/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

the president or some appointed authority of your body have observation
over them, as may be usual or necessary.</p>

<p>As some days may pass by before the consultation organize, a proper
authority to receive and despatch expresses, the council is of opinion
should be attended to, and the council is of opinion that you should
appoint a committee for that purpose.</p>

<p>With considerations of high regard, &amp;c.</p>

<p>
<lb />R. R. ROYAL,
<hl rend="italics">President of the general council of Texas.</hl></p>

<p>A. Houston, <hl rend="italics">Secretary.</hl></p>

<p>On motion of Mr. S. Houston, the report from the general council was
received, and a vote of thanks was unanimously tendered to the gentle<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men
composing the general council, for the faithful and able discharge
of the arduous duties devolved on them.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Royal, it was</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the address of this house be “The Consultation of the
Chosen Delegates of all Texas, in General Convention assembled.”</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. J. A. Wharton,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the president appoint a committee of twelve, composed
of one member from each jurisdiction, to make a declaration, setting
forth to the world the causes that impelled us to take up arms, and the
objects for which we fight.</p>

<p>In pursuance of the above resolution, the chair appointed the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing,
viz:</p>

<!-- TODO Verify Editorial Decision to complete repeated values. -->
<list>
    <item>From the jurisdiction of Columbia, J. A. Wharton.</item>
    <item>From the jurisdiction of Austin W. Menifee.</item>
    <item>From the jurisdiction of Matagorda, R. E. Royal.</item>
    <item>From the jurisdiction of Harrisburg, L. de Zavala.</item>
    <item>From the jurisdiction of Washington, Asa Mitchell.</item>
    <item>From the jurisdiction of Gonzales, W. S. Fisher.</item>
    <item>From the jurisdiction of Mina, R. M. Williamson.</item>
    <item>From the jurisdiction of Nacogdoches, S. Houston.</item>
    <item>From the jurisdiction of San Augustine, A. Houston.</item>
    <item>From the jurisdiction of Bevil, W. Hanks.</item>
    <item>From the jurisdiction of Liberty, H. Millard.</item>
    <item>From the jurisdiction of Viesca, S. T. Allen.</item>
</list>

<p>On motion of Mr. S. Houston, it was unanimously</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the general consultation of all Texas approve of the
disposition of the troops which arrived at Brazoria, under the conduct of
Mr. E. Hall, from New Orleans, and that their most cordial thanks be
presented to Mr. E. Hall, the committee, and the citizens of Louisiana,
who so promptly and efficiently rendered their generous and manly as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sistance
in our struggle for liberty against arbitrary power and despot<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ism.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. S. Houston, it was ordered that two copies of the
above resolution be handed to Mr. E. Hall; one to be retained by himself,
and the other to be by him presented to the committee.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Barrett is was</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That a committee of three be appointed 'to contract with a
printer for "the general consultation of all Texas, in convention as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sembled,”
and report the same to this body.</p>

<pb n="515" xml:id="P0515" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/523/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<p>Whereupon, Messrs. Barrett, Everitt, and Roberston were appointed
that committee?</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Harris, it was</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That a committee of five be appointed to draft rules and
regulations for the government of the general consultation of all Texas,
in convention assembled, during its deliberations; and in pursuance of
the above resolution, the president nominated the following members as
composing said committee: Messrs, Harris, Barrett, Martin, Barnett, and
Wharton.</p>

<p>On motion the house adjourned until nine o’clock to-morrow morning.</p>

<head>San Felipe. de AUSTIN, nine o’clock, A. M.,<lb/>November 4, 1835.</head>

<p>The house met, pursuant to adjournment. The proceedings of yester<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day
being read, the house proceeded to business.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. J. A. Wharton, one thousand copies of the proceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings
of yesterday, with the address of the president on his being con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducted
to the chair, were ordered to be printed.</p>

<p>Mr. Harris, from the committee appointed to draft rules and regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
for the government of the consultation .during its deliberations, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ported
the following, which were adopted.</p>

<p>To the honorable, the general consultation of all Texas, in convention
assembled.</p>

<p>Your committee, to whom was committed the duty of drafting rules
for the government of this body, make report of the following rules and
regulations for your consideration; as follows:</p>

<head>RULE I.</head>

<p>The president shall take the chair after every adjournment, precisely
at the hour to which the house has adjourned; at which time the mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers
shall all be in their places.</p>

<head>RULE II.</head>

<p>The president shall cause the journals of the preceding day to be read
every morning on the meeting of the convention.</p>

<head>RULE III.</head>

<p>The president shall preserve decorum and order, may speak to points
of order, and shall decide all questions of order, subject to an appeal to
the house by any two members; on which appeal, no member shall speak
more than once, unless by leave of the house.</p>

<p>Questions shall be distinctly put by the president, affirmatively and
negatively, to the house, and if he doubt, or a division be called for, the
house shall divide; those in the affirmative of the question shall first
rise from their seats, and afterwards the negative. If a count be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired,
the president shall name two members, one from each side to
perform that duty, and report the same to the president, who shall state
the same to the house.</p>

<pb n="516" xml:id="P0516" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/524/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<head>RULE IV.</head>

<p>The president shall examine and correct the Journal before it be read;
he shall have a general direction of the hall; he shall have the right
to name any member to perform the duties of the chair; but such sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution
shall not extend beyond an adjournment.</p>

<head>RULE V.</head>

<p>All committees shall be appointed by the president, unless otherwise
directed by the house; in which case they shall be chosen by ballot.</p>

<head>RULE VI.</head>

<p>In case of any disorderly conduct of spectators, the president shall
have power to order them to be dispersed.</p>

<head>RULE VII.</head>

<p>When any member is about to speak in debate, or deliver any matter
to the house, he shall rise from his seat and respectfully address himself
to “Mr. President,” and shall confine himself to the question in de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bate,
and avoid personality.</p>

<head>RULE VIII.</head>

<p>If any member, in speaking or otherwise, transgress the rules of the
house, the president shall, or any member may, call him to order; in which
case the member so called to order, shall immediately sit down, unless
permitted to explain; and the house shall, if appealed to, decide on the
case, but without debate. If there be no appeal, the decision of the chair
shall be final; and if in favor of the member called to order, he shall
have the liberty to proceed; if otherwise, and the case requires it, he
shall be liable to the censure of the house.</p>

<head>RULE IX.</head>

<p>When two or more members happen to rise at the same time, the presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent
shall name the member who is first to speak.</p>

<head>RULE X.</head>

<p>No member shall speak more than once to the same question, until
every member choosing to speak, shall have spoken; nor shall any mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber
speak more than twice to the same'question, without leave of the
house.</p>

<head>RULE XI.</head>

<p>Every member who shall be in the house when the question is put, <hl rend="italics">shall</hl>
give his vote, unless the house shall, for special reasons excuse him.</p>

<pb n="517" xml:id="P0517" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/525/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<head>RULE XII.</head>

<p>When a motion is made and seconded, it shall be stated by the presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent,
or being in writing, shall be handed to the secretary, and be read
aloud before debate; and every motion shall be reduced to writing if the
president or any member desire it.</p>

<head>RULE XIII.</head>

<p>After a motion is stated by the president, or read by the secretary, it
shall be deemed in the possession of the house, but may be withdrawn at
any time, before decision or amendment.</p>

<head>RULE XIV.</head>

<p>When a question is under debate, no motion shall be received, except
to adjourn; and a motion to adjourn shall be always in order, but shall
be decided without debate.</p>

<head>RULE XV.</head>

<p>The yeas and nays shall be taken and entered upon the journal of the
house, when requested by any two members present.</p>

<head>RULE XVI.</head>

<p>Every resolution which may be presented by any committee or mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber,
shall lie upon the table for one day, if required by any member pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent,
and shall be separately considered by the house.</p>

<head>RULE XVII.</head>
<p>It shall be the duty of the sergeant-at-arms, or his deputy, to attend
the house during its sittings, to execute the commands of the house from
time to time, together with all such process issued by authority thereof,
as shall be directed to him by the president.</p>

<head>RULE XVIII.</head>

<p>It shall be the duty of the secretary to keep a book, in which he shall
seasonably record the motions, resolutions, rules and decisions of the
house, and to do and perform all such other acts appertaining to his
office, as may be required of him by the president of the convention.</p>

<head>RULE XIX.</head>

<p>The president shall not be permitted to vote upon any question be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore
the house, unless when the members are equally divided, and then
he shall give the casting vote.</p>

<pb n="518" xml:id="P0518" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/526/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<head>RULE XX.</head>

<p>Two thirds of a majority of the members elect shall constitute a quo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rum
to do business.</p>

<p>
W. P. HARRIS, Chairman.
<lb />D. C. BARRETT,
<lb />WYLEY MARTIN,
<lb />THOMAS BARNETT.
</p>

<p>November 3d, 1835.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Royal,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That it shall be the duty of the secretary, to take charge of
the papers and records of the committee of safety of Austin; provide a
copy of the resolutions of Columbia; receive the papers and records of
the council, and keep them till called for by the competent authority.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Parker, the following was added to the rules of the
house:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That after reading the proceedings of the preceding day, the
standing committee’s reports shall be the order of the day.
On motion of Mr. Martin,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the secretary be authorised to provide the ncessary sta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tionery
for the use of the house, and charge it to the general consulta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>

<p>Mr. John A. Wharton, from the committee to whom was referred “the
making a declaration setting forth to the world the causes that im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pelled
us to take up arms, and the objects for which we are fighting,”
made a report.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Parker, the house adjourned to two o’clock, P. M.</p>

<head>two o’clock, p. m.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment, and resumed the considera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of Mr. Wharton’s resolution calling for a “declaration setting forth
to the world the causes that impelled us to take up arms, and the objects
for which we fight.” After some time spent in consideration of the
above, the house, on motion of Mr. Williamson, adjourned to nine o’clock
to-morrow morning.</p>

<head>SAN Felipe de AUSTIN, Nov. 5, 1835, 9 o’clock, a. m.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment; the journals of yesterday’s
proceedings being read, the house proceeded to the order of the day, the
consideration of Mr. Wharton’s resolution.</p>

<p>Elijah Collard, from the jurisdiction of Washington, presented his cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate
of election as a delegate to this coniultation and took his seat.</p>

<p>Mr. Parker obtained the floor and addressed the house on the subject
before it.</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett offered some remarks in reply to Mr. Wharton, and in favor
of a declaration under the constitution of 1824. He asked and obtained
leave to submit his further views in writing; and on leave being granted,
his communication was referred to the committee of twelve.</p>

<p>Mr. Mitchell moved that Mr. Barrett be added to the committee of

<pb n="519" xml:id="P0519" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/527/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

twelve; which was objected to, for the reason that one member only from
each jurisdiction constituted that committee.</p>

<p>Mr. Eobinson addressed the house at length in favor of a declaration
of independence, but gave way for a motion from Mr. Everitt to adjourn,
which was agreed to, and the house adjourned until two o’clock, P. M.</p>

<head>TWO o’clock, P. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>The following gentlement appeared and took their seats: from the
jurisdiction of Washington, Jesse Grimes; from Miesca, A. G. Perry,
J. G. W. Pierson and Alexander Thompson; from Nacogdoches, William
Whitaker, and from San Augustine, Henry Augustin.</p>

<p>Mr. Everitt on leave from the house offered the following:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That Lieutenant Colonel Sandoval, who is now in this town,
a prisoner of war, be discharged on his parole of honor. Ordered to lie
on the table one day.</p>

<p>Mr. S. Houston offered a resolution instructing the committee of
twelve to draw a declaration in favor of the constitution of 1824, which
was opposed by Mr. Wharton, and was withdrawn by the mover.</p>

<p>Mr. Eobinson closed his remarks on Mr. Wharton’s resolution.</p>

<p>Mr. Wood addressed the house in favor of a declaration under the
constitution of 1824.</p>

<p>On a call from the house the president left the chair, and being re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quested,
he gave his opinions in relation to the character of the declara<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
which should be adopted as a foundation for a provisional govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment.
After which, on motion of Mr. S. Houston, the house adjourned
to half past eight o’clock to-morrow morning.</p>

<head>San Felipe de Austin, Nov. 6th, 1835.
<lb />HALF PAST EIGHT O’CLOCK, A. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment, the proceedings of yesterday
being read.</p>

<p>The house took up the resolution offered yesterday by Mr. Everett,
asking for the release of Lieutenant Colonel Sandoval on his parole of
honor.</p>

<p>Mr. Wharton opposed the object of the resolution, which after some
discussion, and the yeas and nays being demanded, was decided as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows,
viz: Yeas, Messrs. Everitt, Zavala, 2; Nays, Messrs. Allen, Augus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin,
Barrett, Barnett, Burnham, Bevil, Byrom, Collard, Clements, Coe,
Davis, Dyer, Fisher, Fuqua, Grimes, Harris, A. Houston, Hodges, Hanks,
Horton, Fiardin, Jones, Kellogg, Lester, Mitchell, Moore, Miller, Meni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fee,
Millard, Panner, Pierson, D. Parker, Perry, Eobinson, Royall,
son, Whitaker, Williamson, 45. Therefore the resolution was rejected.</p>

<p>Mr. Williamson asked leave to read his resolutions proposing a plan on
which to found a provisional government; which was not granted; but the
resolutions were referred to the committee of twelve.</p>

<p>Mr. Wharton asked leave of the house to offer some further remarks
on his report, which, on a division being called for, was granted by the
casting vote of the president.</p>

<p>Mr. Royal asked and obtained leave to read from Mattel in reply to Mr.
Wharton.</p>

<pb n="520" xml:id="P0520" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/528/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<p>Mr. Everitt obtained the floor, and addressed the house in favor of a
declaration under the constitution 1824.</p>

<p>Mr. Hoxie, from the jurisdiction of Washington, presented his cred<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />entials,
and took his seat.</p>

<p>Mr. Mitchell called for the previous question.</p>

<p>The president, by request, explained to members, who had taken their
seats since the debate on Mr. Wharton’s report, what was the question
before the house.</p>

<p>Mr. Williamson again asked leave to read to the house his plan of a
provisional government. Leave was granted.</p>

<p>The previous question being again called for, it was put in the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
form, as suggested by Mr. S. Houston: “All in favor of a provisional
government, upon the principles of the constitution of 1824, will say
aye.”</p>

<p>Whereupon the vote stood as follows:</p>

<p>Ayes, thirty-three; noes, fourteen.</p>

<p>The president again put the question in another form: “All in favor
of a declaration of independence will say aye.”</p>

<p>Whereupon the vote stood as follows:</p>

<p>Ayes, fifteen; nays, thirty-three.</p>

<p>Mr. Wood moved to enter the ayes and noes on the journal; which
motion, after some remarks by Mr. Wharton, he withdrew.</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett, from the committe to whom was committed the duty of
contracting with a printer, made a report, which was read and adopted.</p>

<p>By vote of the house, the rule was suspended in this case, and Mr.
Mitchell offered the following resolution:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That as the enemy is near us, and the land office and public
records are in imminent danger, that they be taken into possession, and
safely guarded from enemies and fire.</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett moved its reference to a special committee, with instruc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
to report on the meeting this afternoon. Whereupon, the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
members were appointed that committee: Messrs. Mitchell, Parmer,
Jones, Barrett and D. Parker, to report on the meeting of the house
this afternoon.</p>

<p>By vote of the house, the rule was suspended in this case, and Mr.
Parmer offered the following:</p>

<p>Whereas, there are many soldiers who have volunteered their services
to defend their country, have fallen sick on the way to the field, and as
many in that situation may suffer, therefore be it</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That this body make some provisions to bear their expenses
until they join the army, or return to their homes.</p>

<p>And be it also</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That a committee of five be appointed to provide for the
necessities of our army and troops on the road generally, with authority
to borrow money, or originate other debts for that purpose.</p>

<p>Which resolutions were adopted, "and the following members appointed
by the chair to compose that committee, viz:</p>

<p>Messrs. Millard, Royall, Clements, Harris and Williamson.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Barrett, the house adjourned until two o’clock this
afternoon.</p>

<pb n="521" xml:id="P0521" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/529/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<head>Two o’clock P. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>Mr. Clements offered the following resolution:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the route of the rangers who are employed, or may be
employed, to protect our frontier, shall be extended from the Colorado
river,their present limits, to the settlements on the Guadaloupe river,&amp;c.;
and that a proportionate number of mem be appointed for that purpose,
equal to that employed on the balance of the frontier,</p>

<p>Which, on motion of Mr. Perry, was laid on the table one day.</p>

<p>The committee to whom was referred the subject for providing for the
necessities of the army, beg leave to report that they have received from
Thos. F. McKinny, by the hands of Dr. C. B. Stewart, a loan of five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
dollars, of which they have expended, in payment of drafts on the
authorities, the sum of two hundred and thirty-eight dollars, as will ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pear
by the accompanying account, which leaves a balance in the hands
of Dr. Stewart of one hundred and sixty-two dollars, and one hundred left
with Messrs. Robert Mills &amp; Co., of Brazoria, leaving a balance on hand,
in all, of two hundred and sixty-two dollars. Paid to express twenty dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars
after making out the account, leaves two hundred and forty-two dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars.</p>

<p>HENRY MILLARD, <hl rend="italics">Chairman.</hl></p>
<p>R. R. Royal, <hl rend="italics">Secretary.</hl></p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Everitt, the committees to whom several matters
were referred, were permitted to withdraw from the house, and attend to
the duties of their several committees.</p>

<p>There being no business before the house, on. motion of Mr. Everitt it
stood adjourned until seven o’clock this evening.</p>

<head>Seven o’clock, p. m.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>It being announced to the house that the president was seriously in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />disposed,</p>

<p>Whereupon Mr. Royal was called to the chair.</p>

<p>Mr. J. W. Parker, from the jurisdiction of Viesca, appeared and took
his seat.</p>

<p>Mr. Wharton, from the committee of twelve, reported progress, and
asked leave to sit again, which was granted.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. S. Houston, the house adjourned to nine o’clock to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />morrow’
morning.</p>

<head>San Felipe de Austin, 7th Nov. 1832.
<lb /><hl rend="italics">Nine o’clock A. M.</hl></head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>The president being able to resume his duties, took the chair, and
called the house to order.</p>

<p>The minutes being read of yesterday’s proceedings,</p>

<p>Mr. Wharton asked and obtained leave to retire for a few minutes, with
the committee of which he was chairman.</p>

<p>Mr. Wharton, with the committee of twelve, to whom was referred the
duty “to make a declaration, setting forth to the world the causes that
impelled us to take up arms, and the objects for which we fight,” having
returned, made report.</p>

<pb n="522" xml:id="P0522" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/530/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<p>The report being read, Mr. Wharton moved that it be submitted to the
house, section by section.</p>

<p>The first section being read,</p>

<p>Mr. Parker moved that the word “republican” be inserted before prin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciples,
so as to read “republican principles;” which amendment was con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curred
in by the house.</p>

<p>The several sections of the report having been separately submitted,
they were unanimously adopted, as follows:</p>

<head>"DECLARATION OF THE PEOPLE OE TEXAS IN GENERAL
CONVENTION ASSEMBLED.”</head>

<p><hl rend="italics">Whereas,</hl> General Antonio Lopez de Santa Anna, and other military
chieftains, have, by force of arms, overthrown the federal institutions of
Mexico, and dissolved the social compact which existed between Texas
and the other members of the Mexican confederacy; now the good people
of Texas, availing themselves of their natural rights,</p>

<head>SOLEMNLY DECLARE,</head>

<p>1st. That they have taken up arms in defence of their rights and
liberties, which were threatened by the encroachments of military despots,,
and in defence of the republican principles of the federal constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of Mexico, of eighteen and twenty-four.</p>

<p>2d. That Texas is no longer morally or civilly bound by the compact
of union; yet, stimulated by the generosity and sympathy common to a
free people, they offer their support and assistance to such of the mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers
of the Mexican confederacy as will take up arms against military des<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />potism.</p>

<p>3d. That they do not acknowledge that the present authorities of the
nominal Mexican republic have the right to govern within the limits of
Texas.</p>

<p>4th. That they will not cease to carry on war against the said authori<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties
whilst their troops are within the limits of Texas.</p>

<p>5th. That they hold it to be their right during the disorganization of
the federal system, and the reign of despotism, to withdraw from the
union, to establish an independent government, or to adopt such meas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ures
as they may deem best calculated to protect their rights and lib<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erties,
but that they will continue faithful to the Mexican government so
long as that mation is governed by the constitution and laws that were
formed for the government of the political association.</p>

<p>6th. That Texas is responsible for the expense of her armies now in
the field.</p>

<p>7th. That the public faith of Texas is pledged for the payment of any
debts contracted by her agents.</p>

<p>8th. That she will reward, by donations in lands, all who volunteer
their services in her present struggle, and receive them as citizens.
These declarations we solemnly avow to the world, and call God to
witness their truth and sincerity, and invoke defeat and disgrace upon
our heads, should we prove guilty of duplicity.</p>

<p>Mr. Mitchell, from the committee appointed in pursuance of a resolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
<pb n="523" xml:id="P0523" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/531/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

offered by him yesterday, reported progress, and asked and obtained
leave to sit again.</p>

<p>Mr. Royal moved that five hundred copies of the report from the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee
of twelve be printed.</p>

<p>Mr. Everitt proposed, as an amendment, one thousand be substituted,
for five hundred, which being accepted by the mover, Mr. Royal, was
adopted by the house.</p>

<p>Mr. S. Houston moved that each member of this consultation sign the
declaration made by the committee of twelve, (which, on the suggestion
of the President, was laid over till the report be enrolled) as soon as en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rolled.</p>

<p>Mr. Clements called up his resolution, offered yesterday, which being
read, Mr. Perry proposed an amendment, which was accepted. Mr. Whar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton
moved its reference to a special committee.</p>

<p>Mr. Perry suggested, that as the permanent council had already acted
on this subject, it might not, perhaps, be necessary.</p>

<p>On the suggestion of Mr. Royal, both the original resolution, as offered
by Mr. Clements, and the amendment proposed by Mr. Perry, were with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />drawn,
and the following, embracing both, was offered by Mr. Clements:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That a committee of five be appointed to report amendments
to the acts of the council on the subject of rangers on the frontiers, and
to extend the line from the Colorado to the Cibollo river.</p>

<p>Whereupon the following members were appointed that committee:
Messrs. D. Parker, Clements, Lester, Perry and Martin.</p>

<p>The rule of the house being suspended in this case, Mr. Millard sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted
the following:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That a committee of twelve, one from each municipality rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resented
in this consultation, be appointed by the president to draw up
and submit a plan or system of a provisional government for all Texas;
which was adopted.</p>

<p>In pursuance of the above, the president named the following members
to compose that committee: Messrs. Millard, Jones, Wilson, Dyer, Hoxie,
Lester, H. Smith, Arrington, Thompson, Eobinson, Everitt and A. Hous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton.</p>

<p>Mr. Millard asked and obtained leave to retire with the committee of
which he was chairman.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. W. Smith, the house adjourned to two o’clock p. M.</p>

<head>Two o’clock P. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. S. Houston, in order to afford to the several com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittees
time to prepare their reports,</p>

<p>The house adjourned until to-morrow morning 9 o’clock.</p>

<head>San Felipe de- Austin, Nov. 8, 1835.
<lb /><hl rend="italics">Nine o'clock A. M.</hl></head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>The journals of yesterday were read and corrected.</p>

<p>Col. D. B. Macomb presented his credentials, and took his seat.</p>

<p>Mr. S. Houston moved that the members present sign “the declara<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
setting forth the causes of our taking up arms,” reported by the
committee, and adopted by the house yesterday, and that such members

<pb n="524" xml:id="P0524" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/532/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

as were then not present, should be requested to put their signature to it
at any convenient opportunity hereafter, which was concurred in by the
house.</p>

<p>Mr. Wharton, from the committee to whom was referred the communi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cations
from “the committee at New Orleans, on the affairs of Texas,”
and the letter from A. C. Allen, making proposals to fit out an armed
vessel, made the following reports, which were adopted:</p>

<p>Your committee, to whom was referred the papers and documents re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived
from the committee at the city of New Orleans, presented by Mr.
E. Hall, have had the same under consideration, and beg leave</p>

<head>TO REPORT:</head>

<p>That the communications from the committee of New Orleans, of
which Wm. Christy and James Ramage, Esqrs., were the acting members,
contain information of the most important and flattering nature. The
committee informs us that one company of fifty men, well armed and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided,
will leave there on the 21st ultimo, to go via Natchitoches—an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />other,
numbering sixty-five, would accompany Mr. Hall; “and a vessel
well furnished and manned, by about one hundred and fifty efficient emi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grants,
would sail about the 27th ultimo for Tampico, under the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mand
of Gen. Mexia.” The committee, in conclusion, say to us, “with
such acquisitions to your present force and resources,we trust that matters
will be brought to a speedy and glorious termination. God be with you.”
Mr. Hall in his statement to this committee says, “that the amount sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed
by the citizens of New Orleans, previous to his leaving, was about
seven thousand dollars—three thousand five hundred of which was ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended
by him in arming and equipping, &amp;c., one hundred men, and fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nishing
provisions, saddles, bridles, &amp;c. to sixty-five of that number, called
the Volunteer Grays, who accompanied him to Brazoria, and immediately
repaired to Goliad. The fifty men sent to Nacogdoches were furnished
with arms and equipments, only trusting to the inhabitants of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />try
through which they may pass, for further necessary supplies; “and
that seventy-eight barrels of navy bread, two barrels of beans and two
barrels of pork, for the use of the army, to be forwarded as the conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
may deem proper,” were left in the hands of E. Andrews, Esq. at
Brazoria. He further states that, that “the committee at New Orleans
were daily receiving subscriptions, which are probably augmented to ten
or fifteen thousand dollars, to be expended in further supplies of arms,
ammunition, &amp;c. &amp;c. There are also volunteer companies being formed
for the service of this country, and are only waiting for communications
from your convention to tender their immediate services.</p>

<p>Your committee, therefore, recommend the adoption of the following
resolution:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Be it resolved by the consultation of the chosen delegates of all Texas in
general convention assembled.</hl> That the following letter be signed by the
president and secretary, and be forwarded by Mr. E. Hall to the commit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tee
at the city of New Orleans.</p>

<head>SAN FELIPE de AUSTIN, Nov. 6 th, 1835.</head>

<p><hl rend="italics">Gentlemen:</hl> We received your communication of the twentieth ultimo,
and accompanying papers, by Mr. E. Hall, and for them this convention
is happy to learn that the patriotic and liberal citizens of the city of New

<pb n="525" xml:id="P0525" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/533/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

Orleans have so generously extended their munificent hand, in timely aid
of their brethren in Texas, who are now battling under the walls of San
Antonio for constitutional liberty and the rights of man, as did their
forefathers of the north on Bunker’s Hill and on Charlestown plains, and
as your own brave citizens did against a mercenary soldiery, who fought
for “booty and beauty.”</p>

<p>This consultation of the chosen delegates of all Texas in general con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention
assembled, deeply impressed with a sense of gratitude for the
succor that has been sent, and for the sympathy that has been manifested
for our citizens who are threatened by the military despot of Mexico,
that unless they yield unconditional submission they shall feel the iron
rod of unrelenting oppression, tender their most grateful acknowledge<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments
to the citizens of your city for their kindness and fraternal feel<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
and interposition, and we trust that no act of ours will ever cause a
blush of shame upon their cheek at the remembrance of the early support.
they gave the cause of free institutions in Texas.</p>

<p>Any who embark in our cause, in the army or navy, shall be liberally
rewarded in land and money, and in the blessings of a grateful and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />deemed
people. We would solicit a continuance of your kind offices, until
we are delivered from the unhallowed grasp of our oppressors, and put in
undisputable possession of our inalienable rights. And we would respect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fully
suggest, that in sending us any supplies of men, money or muni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
of war, that you direct them not to land west of the bay of Mata<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gorda,
and perhaps the mouth of the Brazos river would be the most ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visable
point to land whatever support our friends may send, to enable us
to defend the rights guaranteed by the constitution of 1824.</p>

<p>The address of the president' of the convention, on taking the chair,
which is herewith transmitted, will give you and through you, the citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zens
of Louisiana, a succinct view of the objects for which this body has
assembled.</p>

<p>Signed by order of the consultation of the chosen delegates of all Tex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />as,
in general convention assembled.</p>

<p>The committee to whom was referred the letter of Mr. A. C. Allen, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining
proposals to arm, man and fit out a vessel mounting nine guns,
and fifty stand of small arms, with fifty volunteers on board and four
months provisions, to cruise off our coast as a privateer; have had the
same under consideration, and beg leave to</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Report,</hl> That they view the protection and defence of our seaboard of
the greatest importance in the present crisis; they would, therefore, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spectfully
recommend the adoption of the following resolutions:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Be it resolved</hl> By the consultation of the chosen delegates of all Texas
in general convention assembled, That the proposal of Mr. A. C. Allen,
to cruise off our coast, with such vessel as he may think proper to arm and
man as a privateer be accepted by this convention, and that all the au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority
vested in this body be given and granted unto the said Allen
to cruise as aforesaid.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Be it further resolved,</hl> That the president of the convention inform Mr.
Allen of the acceptance of his proposal, and that a suitable commission
will be placed in his hands on his application to the executive.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Be it further resolved,</hl> That the thanks of this convention be tendered
to Mr. Allen, for his patriotism and devotion in our struggle for constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuional

<pb n="526" xml:id="P0526" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/534/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

liberty, and that the president cause a copy of the foregoing resolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
to be communicated to Mr. Allen.</p>

<p>Mr. Millard from the committee of twelve to whom was committed the
duty “to draw up or submit a plan or system for a provisional govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
for all Texas,” reported progress, asked and obtained leave to sit
again.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. A. Houston,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That there be a person appointed to translate such documents
or proceedings of this house as may be required. Mr. Zavala tendered
his services under the above resolution, which were accepted.</p>

<p>The president presented certain papers and letters from officers of the
army of the people, which Mr. Wharton, by request of the chair, read to
the house, and then moved their reference to to the military committee,
which was concurred in.</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett moved that Governor Zavala be requested to translate into
Spanish the declaration for a provisional government, and that five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
copies thus translated be printed for distribution among our Mexican
fellow citizens of the republic. Which motion was concurred in.</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett moved an adjournment until nine o’clock to-morrow morn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing;
but before the motion was put Mr. Williamson moved that Mr.
Macomb be added to the military committee, which was agreed to.</p>

<p>The question was then put on adjournment, whereupon a division was
called for, and was decided as follows, ayes 27, noes 22; so the house ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />journed
to nine o’clock to-morrow morning.</p>

<head>San Felipe de Austin, Nov. 9 th, 1835.
<lb />NINE o’clock, A. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment, the journals of yesterday’s
proceedings were read.</p>

<p>Mr. Zavala desired the secretary to omit in the proceedings of this body
the title of governor, by which he had heretofore been distinguished.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Robinson, the secretary was directed to erase from
before the name of any member of this house any title which may have
been given, when such title may appear on the journals' of this consulta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>

<p>Mr. Parker from the committee to whom was referred the resolution
of Mr. Clements respecting the rangers, made report, which was read and
adopted, as follows:</p>

<p>The committee to whom was referred the resolution of Mr. Clements,
on the subject of a line of rangers from the Neches river to the Colorado,
has had the same under consideration, and beg leave to report the follow
ing resolution:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That we recognise the acts of the general council on that
subject, sufficient for the present emergency. That said line of rangers
be extended from the Colorado river to the Cibollo, with a company of
twenty rangers under the superintendance of G. W. Davis, who shall be
governed by the same resolutions and instructions of the other superin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tendant
heretofore given: and that the said George W. Davis, make his
place of rendezvous at the place known by the big spring or head of St.
Mark’s river.</p>

<p>From the information before your committee, they recommend that
the acts of Silas M. Parker, in the organization of the company of rangers

<pb n="527" xml:id="P0527" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/535/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

under his superintendance, before they reached the proper place of ren<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dezvous,
be recognized; and that the said S. M. Parker be authorized to
add ten more men to the- company, by and under the former authority
and rules.</p>

<p>Your committee further recommend that the said superintendant be
authorised to draw upon John Lott, at Washington, (with whom there is
a considerable quantity of ammunition deposited,) for ammunition suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient
to supply their several companies, or at such other plac'es as public
ammunition may be deposited.</p>

<p>DANIEL PARKER, <hl rend="italics">Chairman.</hl></p>

<p>Mr. Millard from the committee of twelve, to whom was committed
the duty "to draw up and submit a plan or system for a provisional gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment
for all Texas,” stated to the house that the business of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee
had been entrusted to two sub-committees, both of which were
ready to report through their respective chairmen.</p>

<p>Whereupon, Mr. Henry Smith read to the convention the plan for the
civil department of the government, and Mr. A. Houston read the plan
for the proposed military arrangement. These comprising the entire
report, were submitted to the house by the chairman.</p>

<p>Mr. Parmer moved, that that part of the report relating to the mili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary
department, he laid on the table until two o’clock, P. M.</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett thought it advisable to pursue the same course in relation
to the proposed civil arrangement. Whereupon a division being called
for, the ayes were thirty-three; so the entire report was ordered to lie on
the table until two o’clock P. M.</p>

<p>Mr. S. Houston moved, that the chairman of each sub-committee, under
the committee of twelve, read again to the house the report of his par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticular
department of the proposed government, which was agreed to,</p>

<p>Mr. Hanks submitted the following: <hl rend="italics">Whereas,</hl> a portion of the settlers
on Red River, within the limits of the state of Texas, who have not been
notified of the proceedings growing out of the invasion of our constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional
rights, by a lawless usurper General Santa Anna.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Be it resolved,</hl> That these people be invited to co-operate with us in
the declaration proclaimed by this consultation, and that a copy of this
declaration be furnished them, and to all the states of the Mexican re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public.</p>

<p>An amendment was offered by Mr. Barrett,, to add “and to each muni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cipality
of the department of Bexar.”</p>

<p>Messrs. Robinson and Williamson urged its adoption by the house.</p>

<p>Mr. S. Houston asked and obtained leave to read part of a certain
printed circular.</p>

<p>Mr. Martin urged the propriety of its being received.</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett moved the following amendment, which was accepted by
the mover of the original resolution, Mr. Hanks, “and to the people of
each municipality of the department of Bexar.”</p>

<p>Whereupon the question was then put, as respects the resolution and
its amendment, and was unanimously adopted.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Robinson,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That a committee of five be appointed to enquire into the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pediency
of authorizing an agent to purchase arms, ammunition, &amp;c., and

<pb n="528" xml:id="P0528" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/536/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

to invite volunteers to come to our aid, with power to report by resolution
or otherwise, which was adopted.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Jones,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the volunteers now in service under the command of
general Stephen F. Austin, who continue in service until the reduction of
San Antonio, or until they receive an honorable discharge, shall be enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled
to fifteen dollars per month, from the time they left their homes until
they return to them.</p>

<p>Mr. Parmer proposed the substitution of twenty for fifteen, which was
accepted.</p>

<p>Mr. Royal offered the following amendment.</p>

<p>"And shall also receive such other donations of land as this govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
shall vote them for their patriotism, and be remunerated for all
losses of private property or money expended in the service of our coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />try,”
which was also accepted.</p>

<p>The resolution, with amendments, by rule of the house was laid on the
table for one day.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Williamson, the house adjourned until 2 o’clock,
P. M.</p>

<head>Two o’clock p. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. J. W. Parker,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> 'That the president be requested to authorize Mr. S. M. Parker
to engage ten rangers in addition to his present number, (twenty-five)
under the regulations adopted by the general council, also to empower
Mr. G. W. Davis to raise twenty rangers, agreeably to the resolutions and
arrangements made by this convention, which was adopted.</p>

<p>Mr. Whitaker moved a reconsideration of the above, which was
agreed to.</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett moved that the original resolution be referred to the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee
which reported on this subject this morning, but which, on the
suggestion of Mr. Martin, he withdrew.</p>

<p>Mr. D. Parker then moved that the President cause to be made out or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ders
in pursuance of the report and resolutions on this subject, received
and adopted by this house this morning, which was concurred in.</p>

<p>The order of the day was then called up, being the consideration of
the report of the committee of twelve, when Mr. Everitt moved its sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pension,
in order to afford the minority of that committee an opportunity
to read their report.</p>

<p>Whereupon a division being called for, the vote was for suspension,
twenty, and against, twenty-one, so the house proceeded to the considera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of the report of the committe of twelve.</p>

<p>Mr. Henry Smith having read the preamble to the report,</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett moved to strike it out. The question was then put, when
a division was called for, and it was ordered to be stricken out.</p>

<p>Mr. Collard moved that the report be referred to a committee of five,
which was agreed to.</p>

<p>The president wished that the house would elect that committee.
On motion, the rnle in this case was suspended, and the following per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons
were appointed the committee by the house: Messrs. Barrett, Hanks,
Williamson, D. Parker, and Zavala.</p>

<pb n="529" xml:id="P0529" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/537/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<p>On motion of Mr. S. Houston, the committee were permitted to with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />draw
from the service of the house, to prepare and submit their report
as soon as possible.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. H. Smith, <hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> that the consultation of the
chosen delegates of all Texas, in general convention assembled, viewing
with the highest sense of gratitude the disinterested, bold, manly pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />triotic,
and energetic measures adopted by our friend, captain E. Hall,
late of New Orleans, for the purpose of aiding Texas in her struggle for
constitutional liberty, therefore,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Be it resolved,</hl> That, as a tribute of respect to captain Hall, for his kind
interposition in our behalf, that he is hereby authorized to locate one
league of land on any of the public domain of Texas, not otherwise appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated;
and that a copy of these resolutions be furnished to captain E.
Hall, signed by the president and secretary of this body, which resolutions
were unanimously adopted.</p>

<p>Mr. Robinson, from the committee to whom was referred the subject
“of the propriety and expediency of authorizing an agent to purchase
arms, &amp;c.,” made the following report, which was read and adopted.</p>

<p>Your committee to. whom was referred the resolution to enquire into
the expediency of authorizing an agent to purchase arms, ammunition,
&amp;c., and to invite volunteers to come to our aid, with leave to report by
resolution or otherwise, have had the same under consideration, and are
ready to report,</p>

<p>That the safety of our country requires that additional supplies of
cannon, mortars, ammunition, and suitable equipages are indispensably
necessary; and that an agent ought to be immediately appointed for that
purpose, and that they therefore advise the adoption of the following
resolution.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Be it resolved,</hl> by the consultation of the chosen delegates of all Texas,
in general convention assembled, that Mr. E. Hall, the agent of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee
of New Orleans, be, and he is hereby authorized to purchase two
long eighteen pound cannon, with all the necessary equipage, completely
mounted on carriages, suitable for the field service, with two hundred
rounds of powder, and round ball for each cannon; and that he be au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized
to purchase one twelve inch howitzer, well mounted, with the
necessary equipage for field service, with two hundred bombshells, suit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able
to the calibre of the same: and that he be authorized to call upon
the committee at New Orleans, for money to pay for the same; and that
he be instructed to return to this country, with the said supplies, with
all possible despatch; and that the president of this convention be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quested
to cause a copy of the foregoing resolutions to be transmitted to
Mr. Hall.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. S. Houston, the house adourned until eight o’clock
to-morrow morning.</p>

<head>Sax Felipe de Austin, Eight o’clock,
<lb/><hl rend="italics">November</hl> 10, 1835.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>The Journals of yesterday’s proceedings being read,</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett, from the special committee of five, to whom was referred
the report of the committee of twelve, made report.</p>

<pb n="530" xml:id="P0530" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/538/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<p>The plan of the civil and military department of the proposed pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visional
government having been read,</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. M’Comb, it was <hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the house go into
committee of the whole, for the purpose of considering said report, when</p>

<p>Mr. Martin was called to the chair. After some time the committee
rose, and through their chairman, Mr. Martin, reported progress.</p>

<p>Mr. M. W. Smith moved that the reports of the committees of twelve
and five be referred to a select committee of five.</p>

<p>Mr. S. Houston opposed the re-committing of said report to a commit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tee
of five: was lost.</p>

<p>Mr. Whitaker moved, and it was Resolved, That the house go again
into a committee of the whole, for the purpose of considering the reports
of the committees of twelve and five, upon the subject of a plan of a
provisional government.</p>

<p>Mr. Robinson was called to the chair, and after some time spent in dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cussion,
the committee rose, and through their chairman reported that
they had adopted the report of the committee of five, as the basis whereon
to report the plan of a provisional government of Texas, founded upon
the declaration of this body of seventh November instant.</p>

<p>On motion the house adjourned until eight o’clock to-morrow morning.</p>

<head>San Felipe de Austin, Nov. 11, 1835.
<lb />Eight o’clock, A. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>The journal of the proceedings of yesterday was read.</p>

<p>Mr. Robinson, from the committee of the whole house, to which had
been referred the reports of the committees of twelve and five, made re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port,</p>

<p>That they had had the same under consideration, and begged leave to
offer the following to the house, viz: that they had adopted the report
of the committee of five, as the basis whereon the plan of a provisional
government for Texas, founded upon the declaration of this body of the
seventh inst., which he now reported and offered to the house.</p>

<p>The house then took up the report from the committee of the whole,
when the first section of the civil department being read, was adopted.</p>

<p>The second section was read, amended, and adopted.</p>
<p>The third section was read, amended, and adopted.</p>
<p>The fourth section was read and adopted.</p>
<p>The fifth section was read, amended, and adopted.</p>
<p>The sixth section was read, amended, and adopted.</p>
<p>The seventh section was read and adopted.</p>
<p>The eighth section was read and adopted.</p>
<p>The ninth section was read and adopted.</p>
<p>The tenth section was read, amended, and adopted.</p>
<p>The eleventh section was read and adopted.</p>
<p>The twelfth section was read and adopted.</p>
<p>The thirteenth section was read and adopted.</p>
<p>The fourteenth section was read, and on motion was divided, so that</p>
<p>the question should be taken on each clause, separately.</p>
<p>Before the question was put on the adoption, the house, on motion of
Mr. Williamson, adjourned to half past two o’clock, P. M.</p>

<pb n="531" xml:id="P0531" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/539/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<head>PAST TWO o’clock, P. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>The question was resumed upon the fourteenth section of the report
of the committee of the whole.</p>

<p>The first clause was read and adopted.</p>

<p>An amendment offered to the second clause, by Mr. Williamson, was
rejected.</p>

<p>Mr. D. Parker moved that the latter clause of this section be not acted
upon by this house before to-morrow morning at nine o’clock, which mo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
was lost.</p>

<p>The latter clause of the fourteenth section was again read, and on mo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of Mr. Mitchell adopted.</p>

<p>Mr. S. Houston moved that the fourteenth section be so amended as
to require the commissioners to be appointed under that section, to de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mand
and take in charge all public documents, particularly those in the
hands of the political chief of the department of Nacogdoches; and that
the said political chief cease his functions immediately; which was con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curred
in.</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett offered an amendment, which was received.</p>

<p>The fifteenth section was read and adopted.</p>

<p>The sixteenth section was read and adopted.</p>

<p>The seventeenth section was read and adopted.</p>

<p>Mr. D. Parker offered an amendment to this section, which was lost.
Mr. Eobinson offered the following as an additional section, to be
called section eighteenth, which was adopted, viz:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Section 18.</hl> All grants, sales, and conveyances of lands, illegally or
fraudulently made by the legislature of the state of Coauhila and Texas,
located or to be located within the limits of Texas, are hereby solemnly
declared null, void, and of no effect.</p>

<p>Mr. Everitt offered an additional section, to be called section nineteen,
which was adopted, as follows:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Section 19.</hl> That all persons who leave the country in its present crisis,
with a view to avoid a participancy in its present struggle, (without per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission
of the alcalde or judge of their municipality,) shall forfeit all or
any lands they may hold or have claim to, for the benefit of this govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment:
provided, nevertheless, that widows and minors are not included in
this provision.</p>

<p>Mr. A. Houston offered an additional section, to be called section
twenty, fixing the time and place of the re-assembling of the consultation,
which was adopted.</p>

<p>The report of the military department was then taken up.</p>

<p>The first section was read and adopted.</p>

<p>The second section was read and adopted.</p>

<p>The third section was read, and the amendment offered by Mr. Parmer
being rejected, was adopted.</p>

<p>The fourth section was read and adopted.</p>

<p>The fifth section was read, amended and adopted.</p>

<p>The sixth section was read, amended and adopted.</p>

<p>The seventh section was read and adopted.</p>

<p>The eighth section was read and adopted.</p>

<p>The ninth section was read, amended and adopted.</p>

<p>The tenth section was read, amended and adopted.</p>

<pb n="532" xml:id="P0532" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/540/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<p>The eleventh section was read, amended and adopted.</p>

<p>The twelfth section was read, amended and adopted.</p>

<p>Mr. S. Houston, from the select committee of three, to whom was re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred
our relations with the Cherokee Indians and their associate bands,
made report.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Barrett, it was received and adopted.</p>

<p>Mr. S. Houston moved its recommitment, that a declaration may be
drawn up, as recommended in the report, to be signed by the members
of this consultation.</p>

<p>Mr. Hanks from the committee to whom was referred the resolution
having for its object an invitation to the settlers on Red River to join in
our declaration of the 7th November, made the following report, which
was read, amended and adopted, as follows, viz:</p>

<p>The committee to whom was referred the matter in regard to a portion
of our settlers on Red River, within the limits of Texas, as also of that
portion of Texas not represented in this convention,</p>

<head>REPORT:</head>

<p>That as the settlement on Red River is remote from the other settle-,
ments in Texas, that they he formed into a separate municipality, and
that they be invited to send delegates to this convention, which is to meet
on the first day of March next, and that they elect immediately, and send
a member to the council of Texas.</p>

<p>And further recommend, that they co-operate with the governor and
council, and that they forthwith raise and .send into the field, in defence
of their rights, a reasonable proportion of men. And that the people in
the department of Bexar, and all other parts of Texas, not represented
in this body, be invited forthwith to send delegates to the council, and
also to- the convention, to sit on the first day of March next. And that
all parts of Texas that have not raised troops, and sent them to the aid
of their countrymen, that they be immediately requested to do so.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Parmer.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the district of Tenehaw be set off into a municipality,
and that the town of Nashville be their seat of justice.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That there be an ayuntimiento elected immediately after the
passage of this resolution : and that Messrs. Jonathan Tucker and Jonas
Harris be appointed to hold their elections.</p>

<p>Which resolutions were adopted.</p>

<p>The resolution offered by Mr. Jones, on the ninth instant, was then
called up, together with the amendments which had been accepted, and
was adopted.</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett submitted the following:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Whereas,</hl> the publishers of the “Telegraph and Texas Register” repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent
that they have not exceeding three hundred subscribers; which, ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitting
all to be responsible, would not amount to thirty dollars per
week; that from a suspension of business their subscription list amounts
to little; that for the intelligence of the army, and the information of
what is doing in Texas, they have sent a considerable number to the prin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cipal
cities of the United States: therefore</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That, for the purposes above mentioned, the convention au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorize
the said publishers to continue to forward fifty numbers to the

<pb n="533" xml:id="P0533" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/541/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

army, and the same number to the principal cities in the United States,
and to furnish each member with a paper during the session of this body;
and that the expenses of the same be paid by the public, at subscription
prices.</p>

<p>Ordered to lie on the table one day.</p>

<p>The house, on motion of M. W. Smith, adjourned to nine o’clock to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />morrow
morning.</p>

<head>San Felipe de AUSTIN, 12th Nov. 1835.
<lb /><hl rend="italics">Nine o’clock A. M.</hl></head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>The journals of proceedings of yesterday were read.</p>

<p>The resolution offered yesterday, by Mr. Barrett, respecting the sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scription
to the Telegraph and Texas Register, was called up, and, on
motion of Mr. Wharton, was laid on the table until to-morrow.</p>

<p>The president communicated to the house certain propositions from
M. B. Lamar, of Columbus, Georgia; which were laid on the table.</p>

<p>Mr. Wharton asked and obtained leave to read to the house a letter
addressed to the president of the consultation; which was laid on the
table.</p>

<p>Mr. Macomb offered the following:</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the major general of the army, under the direction of
the governor and council, be required to put in a state of immediate
defence, against the incursions of the enemy, the posts of Galveston Bay,
Velasco, and Matagorda Bay.</p>

<p>Which was ordered to lie on the table.</p>

<p>Mr. Perry proposed a substitute for that clause of the fourteenth sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
relating to land offices in the plan for a provisional government.
Which was laid on the table until two o’clock P. M.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Everitt, the house went into an election for officers
for the provisional government.</p>

<p>The rule, in this case, being suspended,</p>

<p>Mr. Martin nominated for governor, S. F. Austin.</p>

<p>Mr. Parmer nominated for governor, Henry Smith.</p>

<p>Mr. Everitt nominated for lieutenant governor, J. W. Robinson.</p>

<p>When there appeared for Henry Smith, for governor, 31
<lb />For S. F. Austin " 22
<lb />For J. W. Robinson, lieut. do. 55
</p>

<p>Whereupon Mr. Henry Smith was declared duly elected governor, and
J. W. Robinson, lieutenant governor.</p>

<p>Mr. S. Houston asked and obtained leave to read a letter from an
officer in the army.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Wharton, the house adjourned for fifteen minutes.
The house again met at the expiration of the time for which it ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />journed.</p>

<p>When, on motion of Mr. Everitt, they went into an election for major
general.</p>

<p>The rule, in this case, being suspended,</p>

<p>On motion of M. W. Smith, S. Houston was elected major general of
the armies of Texas.</p>

<p>Whereupon, General Houston, in an eloquent address, thanked the

<pb n="534" xml:id="P0534" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/542/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

house for the evidence just given of their confidence in his patriotism
and abilities.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. A. Houston,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That there be three commissioners appointed by this body, as
agents of the United States of North America, to be commissioned by the
governor and council; who shall delegate them such powers, and give
them such instructions, as the governor and council may deem expedient.</p>

<p>Which was adopted.</p>

<p>The rule in this case being suspended, Messrs. B. T. Archer, W. H.
Wharton and S. F. Austin, were duly elected commissioners under the
foregoing resolution.</p>

<p>The president in a very appropriate address tendered to the house his
acknowledgements for this additional evidence of their confidence in his
zeal, talents and integrity. He then communicated to the house several
letters from the army and from the United States.</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett, at the request of the president, (the lobbies being closed,)
read a letter addressed to him by General S. F. Austin. And on motion
of Mr. Barrett, the several letters were referred to a special committee of
five, with instructions to report to the house as soon as possible.</p>

<p>Which was concurred in; whereupon, Messrs.. Barrett, A. Houston,
Martin, Macomb and Williamson, were appointed that committee. Mr.
Zavala was then added to the committee.</p>

<p>On-motion, the house adjourned to half past two o’clock, P. M.</p>

<head>HALF PAST TWO O’CLOCK, P. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment: leave of absence was granted
to Mr. Augustine, for the remainder of the session.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Perry, the house proceeded to the election for the
members of the general council; when it appeared that the following per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons
were duly elected members of the general council, for their respect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ive
municipalities, as follows:</p>

<!-- TODO review editorial decision to include repeated information that wasn't in the origianl -->
<list>
    <item>From the municipality of San Augustine, A. Houston.</item>
    <item>From the municipality of Austin, Wm. Menifee.</item>
    <item>From the municipality of Nacogdoches, Dan’l Parker.</item>
    <item>From the municipality of Washington, Jesse Grimes.</item>
    <item>From the municipality of Viesca, A. G. Perry.</item>
    <item>From the municipality of Mina, D. C. Barrett.</item>
    <item>From the municipality of Liberty, Henry Millard.</item>
    <item>From the municipality of Tenehaw, Martin Parmer.</item>
    <item>From the municipality of Gonzales, J. D. Clements.</item>
    <item>From the municipality of Matagorda, R. R. Royal.</item>
    <item>From the municipality of Harrisburg, W. P. Harris.</item>
    <item>From the municipality of Columbia, E. Waller.</item>
    <item>From the municipality of Bevil, W. Hanks.</item>
</list>

<p>The oath of office was then administered by the president of the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sultation
to the officers of the provisional government.</p>

<p>Whereupon, the convention adjourned for fifteen minutes, to afford an
opportunity to the governor and council to organize. The house again
met after the expiration of the time for which they had adjourned.</p>

<p>The substitute for the fourteenth section of the civil department of
the provisional government, offered by Mr. Perry, was rejected. The

<pb n="535" xml:id="P0535" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/543/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

amendment offered by Mr. Barrett, “That the archives of the different
municipal officers and judges be handed over to their several successors,
and that the papers and archives of the political chiefs of the depart<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments
of Brazos and Nacogdoches, be forthwith transmitted to the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor
and council for their disposal; was, on motion of Mr. S. Houston,
adopted.</p>

<p>Mr. M. W. Smith offered a resolution, having for its object a modifica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of the fourteenth section, as far as that section relates to land of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fices,
as follows, which was rejected:</p>

<p>The ayuntamiento’s of jurisdictions wherein there may be land offices
established, shall take charge of the papers of the same, and the same
safely keep, during the effect of what is heretofore provided, and report
thereon to the governor and council.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Waller; whereas, the late jurisdiction of Brazoria
was changed in name, to that of Columbia, and the seat of justice removed
to the town of Columbia, by the congress of Coahuila and Texas, contrary
to the wishes, inclinations and interests of a large majority of the citizens
of that jurisdiction; therefore,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Be it resolved,</hl> That the name of the said jurisdiction be changed, and
hereafter called and known by its former name, and the seat of justice es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablished
in the town of Brazoria. Which resolution was adopted.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Whitaker, the consultation will refuse, hereafter,
any matter which the governor and council can act upon.</p>

<p>The following persons were appointed commissieners under the four<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth
section, to take in charge, examine and safely keep the papers and
documents relating to the land offices:</p>

<p>Department of Brazos, Messrs. Mitchell, Wharton, Dyer.</p>

<p>Department of Nacogdoches, Messrs. A. E. C. Johnson, S. H. Everitt,
J. Leplesser.</p>

<p>The house, on motion, adjourned to eight o’clock this evening.</p>

<head>Eight o’clock, evening.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett, to whom had been referred certain letters, reported pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress,
and asked, and had leave to sit again.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Waller, <hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That an express be forthwith sent
to the army, requesting the members elect, as commissioners to represent
us in the United States of North America, W. H. Wharton and S. F. Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin,
to repair immediately to this place for the purpose of accepting their
commissions. Which was agreed to.</p>

<p>Mr. Hanks was appointed to carry an express to the army.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. S. Houston, <hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> by the consultation of the
chosen delegates of all Texas, in general convention assembled, That the
thanks of this body be returned to the army of the people, for their perse<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />verance,
firmness, patriotism and courage in defending the liberties of
Texas, and in resisting the encroachments of despotism; and that the
president cause a copy of the foregoing resolution to be communicated to
the army.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. W. Smith, the house adjourned until eight o’clock
to-morrow morning.</p>

<pb n="536" xml:id="P0536" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/544/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<head>San Felipe de Austin, Nov. 13th, 1835.
<lb />Eight o’clock, A. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment, the journals of the proceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings
of yesterday were read.</p>

<p>Mr. Barrett, from the select committee to whom was referred sundry
papers and letters, made the following report: which was unanimously
adopted.</p>

<p>To the honorable the consultation of all Texas, in general convention
assembled—</p>

<p>The select committee, to whom was referred the several letters from
General Austin, and other officers of the colonial army, near Bexar, and
sundry other communications and documents, connected with our mili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary
operations; respectfully reports—</p>

<p>That the communications of General Stephen F. Austin, of the fifth
instant, presents several matters interesting and important in our present
attitude of resistance against the destroyers of our constitution, and the
principles of a military despotism. The subjects are first presented for
your consideration, upon which your committee deem it proper to report.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">First.</hl> The granting letters of marque and reprisal to cruisers upon
the high seas by the “provisional government of Texas.” This conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
in adopting the declaration of the seventh of November, have or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganized
this power, and by the provisions of the resolution constituting a
provisional government, have vested this authority in the governor and
general council; consequently these requires no further action upon the
subject by this house during its present session.</p>

<p>The <hl rend="italics">second</hl> contemplates an expedition from New Orleans against Mata<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moras.
This subject your committee regards as important, and concur
with the views of the commanding general, as to its certain effects of crip<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pling
the enemy and distracting his movements. Your committee, how<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever,
from documents now in their possession, have it in their power to
inform this house, that a small force of one hundred and fifty men, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manded
by General Mexia, armed and equipped at his own expense, has
sailed from New Orleans for the port of Tampico, or Matamoras, and that
a descent from that quarter, from whatever source, in the opinion of your
committee, will produce the consequences of annoying the enemy at one
unexpected point, and prevent reinforcements being sent to Bexar.
Should further operations, hereafter, seem expedient in aiding the enter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prise
of General Mexia, it enters into the duties of the governor and coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil
of Texas.</p>

<p>Your committee feel bound to report to this house, the grateful emo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
induced by the disinterested off'er of Major Francis F. Belton, of
the United States army, to become the inspector of cannon, arms and
other military stores, to be purchased at New Orleans and Mobile, for the
use of Texas; and recommend that his services be accepted, and a vote
of thanks be passed and recorded upon the journals of this house, and that
a copy thereof be forwarded by the president to Major Belton; at the
same time informing him. of the appointment of Capt. E. Hall, an expe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rienced
officer, who is now engaged in performing the same duties, upon
a similar offer, who will be united with him.</p>

<p>Your committee in reporting the magnanimous and generous patriot<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ism
of Stephen F. Austin, J. W. Fannin and B. F. Smith, in their

<pb n="537" xml:id="P0537" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/545/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

prompt and voluntary offer, to place their lands and other property at
the disposal of this house, to he used as sureties for raising funds in aid
of their suffering country, at war with the enemies of their rights and
liberties; rejoice in seeing such noble acts recorded with the proceedings
of this body, in such time of difficulty and danger, and recommend a
letter of thanks, expressive of the grateful sense of this house, for offers
so benevolent and liberal, and that this house accept their several offers,
to be used only when imperiously demanded in the most extreme emer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gency.</p>

<p>Your committee, before closing their report, would respectfully call the
attention of this house to the army now in the field. This force is com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed
of volunteers from every rank of citizens in the country, whose
services generally commenced before the assembling of this house, and as
their movements have hitherto been regulated by officers of their own
choice, no obligation can be imposed upon them to submit to the control
of the provisional government; advisory communications are all that can
be made to them, nevertheless, your committee recommends that every
honorable inducement .should be held out for their continuance in their
country’s service, at any rate until a regular army be ready to take the
field, and should Bexar so long hold out against their efforts. Already
have this house passed resolutions for their individual compensation,
when the resources of the country will permit. The land offices have been
closed, that no advantage should be taken over the soldier in the field in
making his selection of lands; the gratitude of this body, as the repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the people of all Texas, has been twice expressed and entered
upon the journals of the house, and every effort used to afford supplies of
ammunition and provisions within the power of the late council, and
of this body; these efforts we recommend to be continued, and that this
house recommend the members of the army to elect such officers as are
wanting, and that all the officers report themselves to the governor and
council for commissions; that their respective ranks be known of record
for purposes obviously necessary for their future compensation, and that
of the soldiers under them, who may receive discharges from their re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective
officers, that they may be fully known when a grateful country
shall be able to express her thanks in bounties more substantial than mere
words. Your committee recommend that the army be encouraged to
persevere, with the assurance that every exertion will be used by the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visional
government, to aid, comfort and support it which it has within
its power, and will co-operate in forwarding its operations.</p>

<p>Your committee would suggest, that much encouragement is afforded
for perseverance in military operations, from the unsettled state of the
Mexican government. The apprehension of resistance from the citizens
of the republic, is admitted in a late report of a committee of congress,
contained in their plan of a form of government, intended to be enforced
upon the people by the exertion of military power, against their consent.
This disposition will prevent the usurper, Santa Anna, from reinforcing
the troops now arrayed against Texas; and gives hopes of a co-operation
of our Mexican brethren, in the glorious cause of liberty and the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
in which Texas has set the noble example.</p>

<p>D. C. BARRETT, <hl rend="italics">Chairman of the Committee.</hl></p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Committee Boom, Nov. 13th,</hl> 1838.</p>

<pb n="538" xml:id="P0538" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/546/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<p>On motion of Mr. Mitchell, Robert Peebles was appointed a commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner
under the fourteenth section of the act providing for a. govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
called the “provisional government,” in the place of Mr. John A.
Wharton.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. S. Houston, the house took up the ordinances estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lishing
a provional government for Texas; whereupon, after several
amendments were made, it was, on motion of Mr. Macomb, adopted.</p>

<p>On motion, Messrs. Barrett, Kellogg and Allen, were appointed a com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee
of enrollment, and were permitted to retire with the secretary to
enroll the ordinance just adopted by this convention.</p>

<p>On motion, the house adjourned to six o’clock this evening, to obtain
the signatures of the members to the ordinance just past establishing
a provisional government; also to receive and sign the declaration, pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pared
on a resolution from this house, passed the eleventh instant, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />specting
the “Cherokee Indians and their associate bands.”</p>

<head>Six o’clock, P. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>On motion, the members were called to sign the ordinance “establish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
a provisional government” by municipalities.</p>

<p>The following is the ordinance thus signed by every member present:</p>

<head>Convention Hall, San Eelipe de Austin,
<lb /><hl rend="italics">November 13th,</hl> 1835.</head>

<p>To the honorable the consultation of the chosen delegates of all Texas,
in general convention assembled—</p>

<p>Your committee of three to whom was committed the charge of enroll<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
the plan and powers of the provisional government of Texas, as finally
adopted by this house, respectfully submit the following for your consid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eration
and adoption:</p>

<p>
D. C. BARRETT, <hl rend="italics">Chairman.</hl>
<lb />A. G. KELLOGG,
<lb />S. T. ALLEN.
</p>

<head>ARTICLE I.</head>

<p>That there shall he and there is hereby created, a provisional govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
for Texas; which shall consist of a governor, a lieutenant governor
and a council, to be elected from this body: one member from each mu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nicipality,
by the majority of each separate delegation present, and the
governor and lieutenant governor shall be elected by this body.</p>

<head>ARTICLE II.</head>

<p>The lieutenant governor shall be president of the council, and perform
the duties of governor in case of death, absence or from other inability
of the governor, during which time a president “pro tem.” shall be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed,
to perform the duties of the lieutenant governor in council.</p>

<pb n="539" xml:id="P0539" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/547/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<head>ARTICLE III.</head>

<p>The duties of the general council shall be to devise ways and means, to
advise and assist the governor in the discharge of his functions; they shall
pass no laws, except such as in their opinion the emergency of the country
requires, ever keeping in view the army in the field, and the means neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary
for its comfort and support, they shall pursue the most effective and
energetic measures to rid the country of her enemies, and place her in
the best possible state of defence. Two thirds of the members elect of
the general council shall form a quorum to do business; and in order that
no vacancy shall happen in the council, if any member, from death or
other casualty, shall be incapacitated to act, the governor shall immediate<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly,
on information thereof, notify the member elected to fill vacancies,
and on his default, any member who has been elected to this body from
the same jurisdiction. The governor and council shall be authorised to
contract for loans, not to exceed one million of dollars, and to hypothe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate
the public land, and pledge the faith of the country for the security
•of payment. That they have the power to impose and regulate imposts
and tonnage duties, and provide for their collection under such regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
as may be the most expedient.</p>

<p>They shall have power, and it is hereby made the duty of the governor
and council to treat with the several tribes of Indians concerning their
land claims, and if possible to secure their friendship. They shall estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish
post offices and post roads, and regulate the rates of postage, and ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point
a postmaster general, who shall have competent powers for con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducting
this department of the provisional government, under such rules
and regulations as the governor and council may prescribe. They shall
have power to grant pardons, remit fines, and to hear and judge all cases
usual in high courts of admiralty, agreeably to the law of nations.</p>

<p>They shall have power to appoint their own secretary, and other officers
of their own body; also, that they have the power to create and fill such
offices as they may deem proper: Provided nevertheless, That this power
does not extend to officers heretofore rejected by this house.</p>

<p>That the governor and council have power to organize, reduce or in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />-crease
the regular forces, as they may deem the emergencies of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />try
require.</p>

<head>ARTICLE IV.</head>

<p>The governor, for the time being, and during the existence of the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visional
government, shall be clothed with full and ample executive pow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers,
and shall be commander-in-chief of the army and navy, and of all the
military forces of Texas, by sea and by land; and he shall have full power,
by himself, by and with the consent of the council, and by his proper
-commander, or other officers, from time to time, to train, instruct, exer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cise
and govern the militia and navy, and for the special defence and
safety of the country, to assemble in martial array, and put in warlike
attitude, the inhabitants thereof, and to lead and conduct them by his
proper officers; and with them to encounter, repel, resist and pursue, by
force of arms, as well by sea as by land, within or without the limits of
Texas; and also to destroy, if necessary, and conquer, by all proper ways,
and enterprizes, and means, whatever, all and every such person or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(

<pb n="540" xml:id="P0540" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/548/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

sons as shall, at any time, in a hostile manner, attempt or enterprize the
destruction of our liberties or the invasion, detriment or annoyance of the
country; and his proper officers use and exercise over the army and navy,
and the militia in the actual service, the law martial, in times of war,
invasion or rebellion, and to take and surprise, by all honorable ways and
means consistent with the laws of nations, all and every such person or
persons, with their ships, arms, ammunition and goods, as shall, in a hos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tile
manner, invade, or attempt the invading or annoying our adopted
country. And that the governor be clothed with all these and all other
powers which may be thought necessary by the permanent council, cal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />culated
to aid and protect the country from her enemies.</p>

<head>ARTICLE V.</head>

<p>There shall be constituted a provisional judiciary in each jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
represented, or which may hereafter be represented in this house,
to consist of two judges, a first and second, the later only to act in the
absence or inability of the first, and be nominated by the council, and
commissioned by the governor.</p>

<head>ARTICLE VI.</head>

<p>Every judge so nominated and commissioned, shall have jurisdiction
over all crimes and misdemeanors recognized and known to the common
law of England; he shall have power to grant writs of “habeas corpus”
in all cases known and practised to, and under the same laws; he shall
have power to grant writs of sequestration, attachments or arrest, in all
cases established by the “civil code” and “code of practice” of the state
of Louisiana, to be regulated by the forms thereof; shall possess full tes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tamentary
powers in all cases, and shall also be made a court of record
for conveyances, which may be made in English, and not on stamped
paper, and that stamped paper be, in all cases dispensed with; and shall
be the “'notary public” of their respective municipality. All office fees
shall be regulated by the governor and council; all other civil proceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings
at law shall be suspended until the governor and general council
shall otherwise direct, each municipality shall continue to elect a sheriff,
alcalde, and other officers of ayuntamientos.</p>

<head>ARTICLE VII.</head>

<p>All trials shall be by jury; and, in criminal cases, the proceedings shall
be regulated and conducted upon the principles of the common law of
England, and the penalties prescribed by said laws, in case of convic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
shall be inflicted, unless the offender should be pardoned, or fine
remitted: for which purpose a reasonable time shall be allowed to every
convict, to make his application to the governor and council.</p>

<head>ARTICLE VIII.</head>

<p>The officers of the provisional government, except such as are elected
by this house, or the people, shall be appointed by the general council,
and all officers shall be commissioned by the governor.</p>

<pb n="541" xml:id="P0541" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/549/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<head>ARTICLE IX.</head>

<p>All commissions to officers shall be in the name of the people "free and
sovereign,” and signed by the governor and secretary: and all pardons
and remissions of fines granted, shall be signed in the same manner.</p>

<head>ARTICLE X.</head>

<p>Every officer and member of the provisional government, before enter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
upon the duties of his office, shall take and subscribe the following
oath of office: “I, A. B., do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I will support
the republican principles of the constitution of Mexico of 1824, and obey
the declarations and ordinances of “the consultation of the chosen dele<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gates
of all Texas in general convention assembled,” and the ordinances
and decrees of the provisional government; and I will faithfully perform
and execute the duties of my office, agreeably to law, to the best of my
abilities, so help me God.”</p>

<head>ARTICLE XI.</head>

<p>On charges and specifications being made against any officer of the
provisional government for malfeasance or misconduct in office, and
presented to the governor and council, a fair and impartial trial shall be
granted, to be conducted before the general council; and if, in the
opinion of two-thirds of the members, cause sufficient be shown, he shall
be dismissed from office by the governor.</p>

<head>ARTICLE XII.</head>

<p>The governor and council shall organize and enter upon their duties
immediately after the adjournment of this house, and hold their sessions
at such times and places as in their opinion will give the most energy
and effect to the objects of the people, and to the performance of the
duties assigned to them.</p>

<head>ARTICLE XIII.</head>

<p>The general council shall appoint a treasurer, whose duties shall be
clearly defined by them, and who shall give approved security for his
faithful performance.</p>

<head>ARTICLE XIV.</head>

<p>That all land commissioners, empresarios, surveyors, or persons in any<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise
concerned in the location of lands, be ordered forthwith to cease
their operation during the agitated and unsettled state of the country,
and continue to desist from further locations until the land office can be
properly systematized by the proper authoritiy, which may hereafter be
established; that fit and suitable persons be appointed to take charge of
all the archives belonging to the different land offices, and deposit the
same in safe places, secure from the ravages of fire, or the devastation of
enemies; and that the persons so appointed be fully authorized to carry

<pb n="542" xml:id="P0542" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/550/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

the same into effect, and be required to take and sign triplicate schedules
of all the books, papers, and documents found in the several land offices,
one of which shall be given to the governor and council, one left in the
hands of the land officer of the land office, the other to be retained by the
said person; and they are enjoined to hold the said papers and docu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments
in safe custody, subject only to the order of the provisional gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment,
or such competent authority as may be hereafter created; and
the said persons shall be three from each department, as commissioners,
to be forthwith appointed by this house to carry this resolution into full
effect, and report thereof to the government and council, (and that the
said political chiefs immediately cease their functions.) The different
archives of the different primary judges, alcaldes, and other municipal
officers of the various jurisdictions shall be handed over to their success<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ors
in office, immediately after their election or appointment; and the
archives of the several political chiefs of the departments of Nacogdoches,
Brazos, and Bexar, shall be transmitted forthwith to the governor and
council for their disposition.</p>

<head>ARTICLE XV.</head>

<p>All persons now in Texas, and performing the duties of citizens, who
have not acquired their quantum of land, shall be entitled to the benefit
of the laws on colonization, under which they emigrated; and all persons
who may emigrate to Texas during her conflict for constitutional liberty,
and perform the duties of citizens, shall also receive the benefits of the
law under which they emigrated.</p>

<head>ARTICLE XVI.</head>

<p>The governor and council shall continue to exist as a provisional gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment,
until the re-assembling of this consultation, or until other
delegates are elected by the people, and another government established.</p>

<head>ARTICLE XVII.</head>

<p>This convention when it may think proper to adjourn, shall stand ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />journed
to meet at the town of Washington, on the first day of March
next, unless sooner called by the executive and council.</p>

<head>ARTICLE XVIII.</head>

<p>AU grants, sales, and conveyances of land, illegally and fraudulently
made by the legislature of the state of Coahuila and Texas, located or to
be located within the limits of Texas, are hereby solemnly declared null,
void, and of no effect.</p>

<head>ARTICLE XIX.</head>

<p>All persons who leave the country in its present crisis, with a view to
avoid a participation in its struggle, without permission from the alcalde
or judge of their municipality, shall forfeit all or any lands they may hold
or may have a claim to, for the benefit of this government; provided,
nevertheless, that widows and minors are not included in this provision.</p>

<pb n="543" xml:id="P0543" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/551/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<head>ARTICLE XX.</head>

<p>All monies now due, or that may hereafter become due, on lands lying
within the limits of Texas, and all public funds or revenues, shall be at
the disposal of the governor and general council, and the receipt of the
treasurer shall be a sufficient voucher for any and all persons who may
pay monies into the treasury; and the governor and council shall have
power to adopt a system of revenue to meet the exigencies of the state.</p>

<head>ARTICLE XXI.</head>

<p>Ample power and authority shall be delegated, and are hereby given
and delegated to the governor and general council of the provisional gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment
of all Texas, to carry into full effect the provisions and resolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
adopted by the consultation of the chosen delegates of all Texas,
in general convention assembled, for the creation, establishment, and
regulation of the said provisional government.</p>

<head>OF THE MILITARY.</head>

<p>ARTICLE 1. There shall be a regular army created for the protection
of Texas during the present war.</p>

<p>ART. 2. The regular army of Texas shall consist of one major general,
who shall be commander in chief of all the forces called into public ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vice
during the war.</p>

<p>Art. 3. The commander-in-chief of the regular army of Texas shall
be appointed by the convention and commissioned by the governor.</p>

<p>Art. 4. He shall be subject to the orders of the governor and council.</p>

<p>Art. 5. His staff shall consist of one adjutant general, one inspector
general, one quartermaster general, one paymaster general, one surgeon
general, and four aids-de-camp, with their respective ranks as in the
United States army, in time of war to be appointed by the major general
and commissioned by the governor.</p>

<p>Art. 6. The regular army of Texas shall consist of men enlisted for
two years, and volunteers for and during the continuance of the war.</p>

<p>Art. 7. The regular army of Texas, while in the service, shall be gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erned
by the rules, regulations and discipline in all respects applicable
to the regular army of the United States of America, in time of war, so
far as is applicable to our condition and circumstances.</p>

<p>Art. 8. The regular army of Texas shall consist of eleven hundred
and twenty men, rank and file.</p>

<p>Art. 9. There shall be a corps of rangers under the command of a
major, to consist of one hundred and fifty men, to be divided into three
or more detachments, and which shall compose a battalion under the
commander-in-chief, when in the field.</p>

<p>Art. 10. The militia of Texas shall be organized as follows: all able
bodied men, over sixteen, and under fifty years of age, shall be subject to
militia duty.</p>

<p>Art. 11. Every inhabitant of Texas coming within purview of the
preceding article shall, on the third Monday of December next, or as soon
thereafter as practicable, assemble at each precinct of their municipality.

<pb n="544" xml:id="P0544" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/552/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

and proceed to elect one captain, one first lieutenant, and one second
lieutenant, to every fifty-six men.</p>

<p>Art. 12. When said election shall have taken place, the judges shall
certify to the governor forthwith, the names of the respective officers
elected, who shall as. soon as practicable make out and sign, and trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit
commissions for the same; that if there shall be found to exist in any
municipality, more than three companies, the captain or commandants,
on giving due notice thereof, shall call together the subalterns of said
companies and proceed to elect one major, if of four companies; one
lieutenant colonel, if of five or more companies; one colonel for the
command of said companies, which shall constitute a regiment of said
municipality; that if there shall be found to exist more than one regi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
in said municipality, the whole number of field and company offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers
shall, on due notice, proceed to elect a brigadier general out of their
number, who shall command the whole militia in the said municipality.</p>

<p>BRANCH TURNER ARCHER,
<lb />President.
</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of Austin:</hl></p>

<p>Wyly Martin, R. Jones, Jesse Burnam, William Menifee.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of Nacogdoches:</hl></p>

<p>Sam. Houston, James AV. Robinson, William Whitaker, Daniel Parker,
William N. Sigler.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of Washington:</hl></p>

<p>Philip Coe, E. Collard, Jesse Grimes, Asa Mitchell, Asa Hoxey.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of Harrisburg:</hl></p>

<p>Lorenzo de Zavala, C. C. Dyer, John AV. Moore, M. W. Smith, David
B. Macomb.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of Liberty:</hl></p>

<p>George M. Patrick, Wm. P. Harris, Henry Millard, J. B. AVoods, A. B.
Hardin.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of Gonzalez:</hl></p>

<p>Wm. S. Fisher, J. D. Clements, Geo. W. Davis, James Hodges, William
W. Arrington, Benjamin Faqua.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of Tenehaw:</hl></p>

<p>Martin Parmer.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of Columbia:</hl></p>

<p>Henry Smith, John A. Wharton, Edwin AValler, John S. D. Byror.</p>

<pb n="545" xml:id="P0545" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/553/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of San Augustine:</hl></p>

<p>A. Houston, William N. Sigler, A. E. C. Johnson, A. Horton, A. G.
Kellogg.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of Mina:</hl></p>

<p>D. C. Barrett, J. S. Lester, R. M. Williamson.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of Matagorda:</hl></p>

<p>R. E. Royal, Chas. Wilson.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of Bevil:</hl></p>

<p>S. H. Everitt, John Bevil, Wyatt Hanks.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of Viesca:</hl></p>

<p>Sami. T. Allen, A. G. Perry, J. G. W. Pierson, Alexander Thompson,
Jas. W. Parker.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Municipality of Jefferson:</hl></p>

<p>Claiborne West.</p>

<p>P. B. DEXTER, <hl rend="italics">Secretary.</hl></p>

<p>On motion of Mr. John A. Wharton,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the thanks of the chosen delegates of all Texas, in gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral
convention assembled, he tendered to Capt. John M. Collingsworth,
and his associates in arms, for their gallant and patriotic conduct in tak<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
Goliad, and that the secretary furnish them with a copy of the same;
which was unanimously adopted.</p>

<p>The following persons were appointed, under the 14th section of the
organic law, as commissioners for the department of Bexar, viz: Messrs.
Kerr, Sutherland, Linn and Williamson.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Wharton, it was</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the governor and council be empowered to issue writs
of election to fill the vacancies that may occur in this body, and for the
representation of those jurisdictions not yet represented, or to cause a
new election in toto for delegates to the convention of the first of March
next.</p>

<p>On motion, the salaries of the officers of the provisional government
were fixed: governor, fifteen hundred dollars; lieutenant governor, twelve
hundred and fifty dollars; members of council, per diem, three dollars,
and three dollars for every twenty-five miles travel, from and to their
place of residence; secretary of convention, six dollars; door-keeper, two
dollars.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. A. Houston, it was</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the members of this convention take a certificate from
the secretary of the time of their services and the distance of travelling.</p>

<pb n="546" xml:id="P0546" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/554/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<p>Mr. Wharton, from the committee to whom was referred the letter from
Messrs, McKinny &amp; Williams, made report and read a letter.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. S. Houston, the whole was referred to the general
council.</p>

<p>The committee of three, whose duty it was made to report a declaration
in conformity to the report adopted by this consultation, respecting the
Cherokee Indians and their associate bands, and whose duty it was made
to report a declaration, in conformity to the report adopted by this house,
reported the following declaration, which was read and adopted, on mo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />toin
of Mr. Barrett:</p>

<head>BE IT SOLEMNLY DECREED,</head>

<p><hl rend="italics">That we,-the chosen delegates of the consultation of all Texas, in gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral
convention assembled, SOLEMNLY declare,</hl></p>

<p>That the Cherokee Indians, and their associate bands, twelve tribes in
number, agreeably to their late general council in Texas, have derived
their just claims to lands included within the bounds hereinafter men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned,
from the government of Mexico, from whom we have also derived
our rights to the soil by grant and occupancy.</p>

<p>We solemnly declare, that the boundaries of the claims of the said In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dians
to land is as follows, to wit: lying north of the San Antonio road and
the Neche,s, and west of the Angeline and Sabine rivers.</p>

<p>We solemnly declare, that the governor and general council, imme<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diately
on its organization, shall appoint commissioners to treat with the
said Indians, to establish the definite boundary' of their territory', and
secure their confidence and friendship.</p>

<p>We solemnly declare, that we will guarantee to them the peaceable
enjoyment of their rights to their lands, as we do our own.</p>

<p>We solemnly declare, that all grants, surveys and locations of lands
within the bounds hereinbefore mentioned, made after the settlement
of the said Indians, are, and of right ought to be, utterly null and void;
and that the commissioners issuing the same be, and .are hereby, ordered
immediately to recall and cancel the same, as having been made upon
lands already appropriated by the Mexican government.</p>

<p>We solemnly declare, that it is our sincere desire that the Cherokee In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dians,
and their associate bands, shall remain our friends in peace and
war; and if they do so, we pledge the public faith for the support of the
foregoing declarations.</p>

<p>We solemnly declare, that they are entitled to our commiseration and
protection, as the just owners of the soil, as an unfortunate race of people
that we wish to hold as friends, and treat with justice, deeply and sol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />emnly
impressed with these sentiments, as a mark of sincerity, your com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mittee
would respectfully recommend the adoption of the following reso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lution.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the members of this convention, now present, sign this
declaration and pledge of the public faith, on the part of the people of
Texas.</p>

<p>Done in convention at San Eelipe de Austin, this 13th November, A.
D. 1835.</p>

<p>B. T. ARCHER, <hl rend="italics">President.</hl></p>

<pb n="547" xml:id="P0547" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/555/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>


<list>
    <item>John A. Wharton,</item>
    <item>Sam Houston,</item>
    <item>Charles Wilson,</item>
    <item>James Hodges,</item>
    <item>John Bevil,</item>
    <item>Alex. Thompson,</item>
    <item>D. C. Barrett,</item>
    <item>J. Burnam,</item>
    <item>A. Horton,</item>
    <item>Dan’l Parker,</item>
    <item>John S. D. Byrom,</item>
    <item>A. G. Perry,</item>
    <item>C. C. Dyer,</item>
    <item>J. D. Clements,</item>
    <item>James W. Parker,</item>
    <item>G. W. Davis,</item>
    <item>A. E. C. Johnson,</item>
    <item>Martin Parmer,</item>
    <item>S. H. Everitt,</item>
    <item>Philip Coe,</item>
    <item>Claiborne West,</item>
    <item>J. S. Lester,</item>
    <item>Joseph L. Hood,</item>
    <item>Asa Hoxy,</item>
    <item>Asa Mitchell,</item>
    <item>R. M. Williamson,</item>
    <item>A. Houston,</item>
    <item>John W. Moore,</item>
    <item>Samuel T. Allen,</item>
    <item>James W. Robinson,</item>
    <item>Jesse Grimes,</item>
    <item>Wyly Martin,</item>
    <item>David B. Macomb,</item>
    <item>E. Collard,</item>
    <item>M. W. Smith,</item>
    <item>William Menifee,</item>
    <item>William N. Sigler,</item>
    <item>William W. Arrington,</item>
    <item>William S. Fisher,</item>
    <item>J. G. W. Pierson,</item>
    <item>R. Jones,</item>
    <item>Lorenzo de Zavala,</item>
    <item>Edwin Waller,</item>
    <item>William P. Harris,</item>
    <item>William Whitaker,</item>
    <item>Albert G. Kellogg,</item>
    <item>George M. Patrick,</item>
    <item>R. R. Royall,</item>
    <item>Benjamin Fuqua,</item>
    <item>Wyatt Hanks,</item>
    <item>Henry Millard,</item>
    <item>A. B. Hardin,</item>
    <item>Henry Smith,</item>
</list>

<p>P. B. DEXTER, <hl rend="italics">Secretary.</hl></p>

<p>On motion, the house adjourned to nine o’clock to-morrow.</p>

<head>San Felipe de Austin, Nov. 14, 1835.
<lb />Nine o’clock, A. M.</head>

<p>The house met pursuant to adjournment.</p>

<p>The journal of yesterday’s proceedings was read.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Wharton, Mr. Wood’s resolution was struck from
the journal, together with the proceedings had thereon.</p>

<p>Mr. C. West was sworn as a member of the general council, from the
jurisdiction of Jefferson.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Johnson,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the consultation of all Texas in general convention as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sembled,
recommend to the army of the people to abandon the proposed
seige of San Antonio, and that they fall back upon La Bahia and Gon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zales,
and place themselves in a condition of safety, by leaving a suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient
number of men, and the balance of the army be furloughed to their
homes, to join the army by the first of March, or so soon as the emergen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cies
of the country may require.</p>

<p>Which was refused to be considered by the house.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. Robinson,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the thanks of this body be given to the president of this
convention for the able and dignified manner he has discharged the ardu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ous
duties of presiding over this body.</p>

<pb n="548" xml:id="P0548" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/556/" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Journals of the Consultation.</fw>

<p>Which resolution was unanimously adopted.</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the thanks of this house be tendered to the secretary for
the faithful, prompt and efficient discharge of his duty.</p>

<p>Which was also unanimously adopted.</p>

<p>On motion of Mr. M. W. Smith,</p>

<p><hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That this house now adjourn to meet on the first day of
March next, unless sooner called by the governor and council; and that
all the members of this body, who can repair to San Antonio to assist
our fellow citizens in the field.</p>

<p>Whereupon the house adjourned.</p>

<p>P. B. DEXTER, <hl rend="italics">Secretary.</hl></p>

</div>
</body>
</text>
