<text>

<front>

<pb n="815" xml:id="P0815" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/823/" />

<head>THE GOLIAD
<lb />DECLARATION OF INDEPENDENCE</head>

<head>DECEMBER 20, 1835</head>

<head>BRAZORIA.</head>

<head>1835</head>


<pb n="816" xml:id="P0816" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/824/" />
</front>
<body>
<div type="document">

<pb n="817" xml:id="P0817" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/825/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="3" />

<head>DECLARATION OE INDEPENDENCE,</head>

<head>MADE AT GOLIAD, DECEMBER 20, 1835.</head>


<p>Solemnly impressed with a sense of the danger of the crisis to which
recent and remote events have conducted the public affairs of their
country, the undersigned prefer this method of laying before their fel<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />low-citizens,
a brief retrospect of the light in which they regard both
the present and the past, and of frankly declaring for themselves, the
policy and the uncompromising course which they have resolved to pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sue
for the future.</p>

<p>They have seen the enthusiasm and the heroic toils of an
army bar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tered
for
a capitulation, humiliating in itself, and repugnant in the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />treme
to the pride and honor of the most lenient, and no sooner framed
than evaded or insultingly violated.
They have seen their camp thronged, but too _ frequently, with those
who were more anxious to be served by, than to serve their country—with
men more desirous of being honored with command than capable of
commanding.</p>

<p>They have seen the energies, the prowess, and the achievements of a
band worthy to have stood by Washington and receive command, and
worthy to participate of the inheritance of the sons of such a Father,
frittered, dissipated, and evaporated away for the want of that energy,
union, and decision in council, which, though it must emanate from the
many, can only be exercised efficiently when concentrated in a single
arm.</p>

<p>They have seen the busy aspirants for office running from the field to
the council hall, and from this back to the camp, seeking emolument
and not service, and swarming like hungry flies around the body politic.
They have seen the deliberations of the council and the volition of
the camp distracted and paralyzed, by the interference of an influence
anti-patriotic in itself, and too intimately interwoven with the paralyzing
policy of the past, to admit the hope of relief from its incorporation with
that which can alone avert the evils of the present crisis, and place the<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />affairs
of the country beyond the reach of an immediate reaction.</p>

<p>They have witnessed these evils with bitter regrets, with swollen hearts,
and indignant bosoms.</p>

<p>A revulsion is at hand. An army, recently powerless and literally im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prisoned,
is now emancipated. From a comparatively harmless, passive,
and inactive attitude, they have been transferred to one pre-eminently
commanding, active, and imposing. The North and East of Mexico will
now become the stronghold of centralism. Thence it can sally in what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever
direction its arch adviser may prefer to employ its weapons. The

<pb n="818" xml:id="P0818" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/826/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="4" />
<fw type="header" place="top">The Goliad Declaration of Independence.</fw>

counter-revolution in the interior once smothered, the whole fury of the
contest will be poured on Texas. She is principally populated with
North-Americans. To expel these from its territory, and parcel it out
among the instruments of its wrath, will combine the motive and the
means for consummating the schemes of the President Dictator. Al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ready,
we are denounced, proscribed, outlawed, and exiled from the
country. Our lands, peaceably and lawfully acquired, are solemnly pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nounced
the proper subject of indiscriminate forfeiture, and our estates
of confiscation. The laws and guarantees under which we entered the
country as colonists,tempted the unbroken silence, sought the dangers of
the wilderness, braved the prowling Indian, erected our numerous im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provements,
and opened and subdued the earth to cultivation, are either
abrogated or repealed, and now trampled under the hoofs of the usurper’s
cavalry.</p>

<p>Why, then, should we longer contend for charters, which, we are
again and again told in the annals of the past, were never intended for
our benefit? Even a willingness on our part to defend them, has pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />voked
the calamities of exterminating warfare. Why contend for the
shadow, when the substance courts our acceptance? The price of each
is the same. War—exterminating war—is waged: and we have either to
fight or flee.</p>

<p>We have indulged sympathy, too, for the condition of many whom, we
vainly flattered ourselves, were opposed, in common with their adopted
brethren, to the extension of military domination over the domain of
Texas. But the siege of Bexar has dissolved the illusion. Nearly 'all
their physical force was in the line of the enemy and armed with rifles.
Seventy days’ occupation of the fortress of Goliad, has also abundantly
demonstrated the general diffusion among the Creole population of a
like attachment to the institutions of their ancient tyrants. intellectu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ally
enthralled, and strangers to the blessings of regulated liberty, the
only philanthropic service which we can ever force on their acceptance,
is that of example. In doing this, we need not expect or even hope for
their co-operation. When made the reluctant, but greatly benefited re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cipients
of a new, invigorating, and cherishing policy—a policy tender<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
equal, impartial, and indiscriminate protection to all; to the low and
the high, the humble and the well-born, the poor and the rich, the ig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />norant
and the educated, the simple and the shrewd—then, and not
before, will they become even useful auxiliaries in the work of political
or moral renovation.</p>

<p>It belongs to the North-Americans of Texas to set this bright, this
cheering, this all-subduing example. Let them call together their wise
men. Let them be jealous of the experienced, of the speculator, of
every one anxious to serve as a delegate, of every one hungry for power,
or soliciting office; and of all too who have thus far manifested a willing<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness
to entertain or encourage those who have already tired the patience
of the existing Council with their solicitations and attendance. Those
who seek are seldom ever the best qualified to fill an office. Let them
discard, too, the use of names calculated only to deceive and' bewilder,
and return like men to the use of words whose signification is settled
and universally acknowledged. Let them call their assembly, thus made
up, a Convention; and let this convention, instead of declaring for “the

<pb n="819" xml:id="P0819" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/827/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="5" />
<fw type="header" place="top">The Goliad Declaration of Independence.</fw>

principles” of a constitution, for “the principles” of Independence, or
for those of Freedom and Sovereignty, boldly, and with one voice, pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />claim
<hl rend="italics">the Independence of Texas.</hl> Let the convention frame a constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
for the future government of this favored land. Let them guard
the instrument securely, by the introduction of a full, clear, and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prehensive
bill of rights. Let all this be done as speedily as possible.
Much useful labor has already been performed; but much is yet required
to complete the work.</p>

<p>The foregoing, we are fully aware, is a blunt, and in some respects a
humiliating, but a faithful picture. However much we may wish, or
however much we may be interested, or feel disposed to deceive our
enemy, let us carefully guard against deceiving ourselves. We are in more
danger from this—from his insinuating, secret, silent, and unseen influ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence
in our councils, both in the field and in the cabinet, and from the
use of his silver and gold, than from his numbers, his organization, or
the concentration of .his power in a single arm. The gold of Philip pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chased
what his arms could not subdue—the liberties of Greece. Our
enemy, too, holds this weapon. Look well to this, people of Texas, in the
exercise of suffrage. Look to it, Counselors, your appointments to of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice.
Integrity is a precious jewel.</p>

<p>Men of Texas! nothing short of independence can place us on solid
ground. This step will. This step, too, will entitle us to confidence, and
will procure us credit abroad. Without it, every aid we receive must
emanate from the enthusiasm of the moment, and with the moment, will
be liable to pass away or die forever/ Unless we take this step, no for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eign
power can either respect or even know us. None will hazard a rup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture
with Mexico, impotent as she is, or incur censure from other powers
for interference with the internal affairs of a friendly State, to aid us in
any way whatever. Our letters of marque and reprisal must float at the
mercy of every nation on the ocean. And whatever courtesy or kindred
feeling may do, or forbear to do, in aid of our struggle, prosecuted on
the present basis, it would be idle and worse than child-like to flatter
ourselves with the hope of any permanent benefit from this branch of
the service, without frankly declaring to the world, as a people, our in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dependence
of military Mexico. Let us then take the tyrant and his
hirelings at their word. <hl rend="italics">They</hl> will not know us but as enemies. Let us,
then, know them hereafter, as other independent States know each other
—as “enemies in war, in peace, friends.” Therefore,</p>

<p>1.	Be it <hl rend="italics">Resolved,</hl> That the former province and department of Texas
is, and of right ought to be, <hl rend="italics">a free, sovereign and independent State.</hl></p>

<p>2.	That as such, is has, and of right ought to have, all the powers,
faculties, attributes, and immunities of other independent nations.</p>

<p>3.	That we, who hereto set our names, pledge to each other our lives,
our fortunes, and our sacred honor, to sustain this declaration—relying
with our entire confidence upon the co-operation of our fellow-citizens,
and the approving smiles of the God of the living, to aid and conduct
us victoriously through the struggle, to the enjoyment of peace, union,
and good government; and invoking his malediction if we should either
equivocate, or, in any manner whatever, prove ourselves unworthy of
the high destiny at which we aim.</p>

<pb n="820" xml:id="P0820" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/828/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="6" />
<fw type="header" place="top">The Goliad Declaration of Independence.</fw>

<p>Done in the town of Goliad, on Sunday, the 20th day of December,
in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and thirty-five.</p>

<list>
    <item>Wm. G. Hill,</item>
    <item>Joseph Bowman,</item>
    <item>Geo. W. Welsh,</item>
    <item>J. D. Kilpatrick,</item>
    <item>Wm. E. Howth,</item>
    <item>Albert Pratt,</item>
    <item>Alvin Woodward,</item>
    <item>D. M. Jones,</item>
    <item>J. C. Hutchins,</item>
    <item>E. B. W. Fitzgerald,</item>
    <item>Hugh McMinn,</item>
    <item>Wm. Robertson,</item>
    <item>Horace Stamans,</item>
    <item>Peter Hynes,</item>
    <item>Dugald McFarlane,</item>
    <item>H. F. Davis,</item>
    <item>Francis Jones, .</item>
    <item>G. W. Pain,</item>
    <item>Allen White,</item>
    <item>Joseph Cadle,</item>
    <item>W. H. Living,</item>
    <item>Victor Loupy,</item>
    <item>Sayle Antoine,</item>
    <item>Michael Kelly,</item>
    <item>Geo. W. Cash,</item>
    <item>Charles Malone,</item>
    <item>C. J. O’Connor,</item>
    <item>Edward McDonough,</item>
    <item>Wm. Gould,</item>
    <item>Charles Messer,</item>
    <item>Isaac Robinson,</item>
    <item>John Shelly,</item>
    <item>Patrick O’Leary,</item>
    <item>Timothy Hart,</item>
    <item>James St. John,</item>
    <item>John Bowen,</item>
    <item>Michael O’Donnell,</item>
    <item>Nathaniel Holbrook,</item>
    <item>Alexander Lynch,</item>
    <item>J. W. Baylor,</item>
    <item>H. George,</item>
    <item>Benj. J. White,</item>
    <item>R. L. Bedding,</item>
    <item>James W. Scott,</item>
    <item>Lewis Powell,</item>
    <item>John Pollan,</item>
    <item>James Duncan,</item>
    <item>David George,</item>
    <item>Gustavus Cholwell,</item>
    <item>John James,</item>
    <item>Morgan Bryan,</item>
    <item>Thomas O’Connor,</item>
    <item>Henry J. Moris,</item>
    <item>James O’Connor,</item>
    <item>Spirse Dooley,</item>
    <item>E. Brush,</item>
    <item>W. Redfield,</item>
    <item>Albert Silsbe,</item>
    <item>Wm. Haddon,</item>
    <item>James Elder,</item>
    <item>John J. Bowman,</item>
    <item>Thomas Todd,</item>
    <item>Jeremiah Day,</item>
    <item>Wm. S. Brown,</item>
    <item>Benjamin Noble,</item>
    <item>M. Carbajal,</item>
    <item>T. Hanson,</item>
    <item>John Johnson,</item>
    <item>Edmund Quirk,</item>
    <item>Robert McClure,</item>
    <item>Andrew Devereau,</item>
    <item>Charles Shingle,</item>
    <item>J. B. Dale,</item>
    <item>Ira Ingram,</item>
    <item>John Dunn,</item>
    <item>Walter Lambert,</item>
    <item>Miguel Aldrete,</item>
    <item>William Quinn,</item>
    <item>B. H. Perkins,</item>
    <item>Benj. J. White, Jr.,</item>
    <item>Edward St. John,</item>
    <item>D. H. Peeks,</item>
    <item>Philip Dimitt,</item>
    <item>Francis P. Smith,</item>
    <item>T. Mason Dennis,</item>
    <item>C. A. Parker,</item>
    <item>C. M. Dispallier,</item>
    <item>Jefferson Ware,</item>
    <item>David Wilson,</item>
    <item>William Newland,</item>
    <item>J. T. Bell.</item>
</list>

<p>I hereby certify the foregoing to be a true copy of the original in my
possession.</p>

<p>Ira INGRAM, <hl rend="italics">Secretary.</hl></p>

<p>Town of Goliad, December 22, 1835.</p>

</div>
</body>
</text>
