<text>
    
<front>

<pb n="1063" xml:id="P1063" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1071/" />

<head>THE
<lb />DECLARATION OF INDEPENDENCE
<lb />MADE BY THE
<lb />DELEGATES OF THE PEOPLE OF TEXAS
<lb />IN
<lb />General Convention, at Washington,
<lb />On March 2nd, 1886.
</head>

</front>

<body>
    
<div type="document">

<p>When a government has ceased to protect the lives, liberty and
property of the people, from whom its legitimate powers are de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rived,
and for the advancement of whose happiness it was insti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuted:
and so far from being a guarantee for their inestimable and
inalienable rights, becomes an instrument in the hands of evil
rulers for their oppression. When the federal republican constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of their country, which they have sworn to support, no longer
has a substantial existence, and the whole nature of their govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
has been forcibly changed, without their consent, from a
restricted federative republic, composed of sovereign states, to a
consolidated central military despotism, in which every interest
is disregarded but that of the army and the priesthood, both the
eternal enemies of civil liberty, the ever ready minions of power,
and the usual instruments of tyrants. When, long after the spirit
of the constitution has departed, moderation is at length so far
lost by those in power, that even the semblance of freedom is
removed, and the forms themselves of the constitution dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />continued,
and so far from their petitions and remonstrances

<pb n="1064" xml:id="P1064" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1072/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="4" />
<fw type="header" place="top">The Declaration of Independence.</fw>

being regarded, the agents who bear them are thrown into dun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />geons,
and mercenary armies sent forth to enforce a new govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
upon them at the point of the bayonet.</p>

<p>When, in consequence of such acts of malfeasance and abduc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
on the part of the government, anarchy prevails, and civil so<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciety
is dissolved into its original elements, in such a crisis, the first
law of nature, the right of self-preservation, the inherent and in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alienable
right of the people to appeal to first principles, and take
their political affairs into their own hands in extreme cases, enjoins
it as a right towards themselves, and a sacred obligation to their
posterity, to, abolish such government, and create another in its
stead, calculated to rescue them from impending dangers, and to
secure their welfare and happiness.</p>

<p>Nations, as well as individuals, are amenable for their acts to
the public opinion of mankind. A statement of a part of our griev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ances
is therefore submitted to an impartial world, in justification
of the hazardous but unavoidable step now taken, of severing our
political connection with the Mexican people, and assuming an in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dependent
attitude among the nations of the earth.</p>

<p>The Mexican government, by its colonization laws, invited and
induced the Anglo American population of Texas to colonize its
wilderness under the pledged faith of a written constitution, that
they should continue to enjoy that constitutional liberty and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />.
publican government to which they had been habituated in the
land of their birth, the United States of America.</p>

<p>In this expectation they have been cruelly disappointed,
inasmuch as the Mexican nation has acquiesced to the late changes
made in the government by General Antonio Lopez de Santa Anna,
who, having overturned the constitution of his country, now offers,
as the cruel alternative, either to abandon our homes, acquired by
so many privations, or submit to the most intolerable of all tyranny,
the combined despotism of the sword and the priesthood.</p>

<p>It hath sacrificed our welfare to the state of Coahuila, by which
our interests have been continually depressed through a jealous and
partial course of legislation, carried on at a far distant seat of gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment,
by a hostile majority, in an unknown tongue, and this
too, notwithstanding we have petitioned in the humblest terms for
the establishment of a separate state government, and have, in ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cordance
with the provisions of the national constitution, present<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed
to the general congress a republican constitution, which was,
without a just cause, contemptuously rejected.</p>

<pb n="1065" xml:id="P1065" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1073/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="5" />
<fw type="header" place="top">The Declaration of Independence.</fw>

<p>It incarcerated in a dungeon, for a long time, one of our citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zens,
for no other cause but a zealous endeavour to procure the
acceptance of our constitution, and the establishment of a state
government.</p>

<p>It has failed and refused to secure, on a firm basis, the right of
trial by jury, that palladium of civil liberty, and only sale guar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />antee
for the life, liberty, and property of the citizen.</p>

<p>It has failed to establish any public system of education, al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />though
possessed of almost boundless resources, (the public do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />main,)
and although it is an axiom in political science, that unless
a people are educated and enlightened, it is idle to expect the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinuance
of civil liberty, or the capacity for self government.</p>

<p>It. has suffered the military commandants, stationed among us,
to exercise arbitrary acts of oppression and tyranny, thus trampling
upon the most sacred rights of the citizen, and rendering the mili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary
superior to the civil power.</p>

<p>It has dissolved, by force of arms, the state congress of Coahuila
and Texas, and obliged our representatives to fly for their lives
from the seat of government, thus depriving us of the fundamental
political right of representation.</p>

<p>It has demanded the surrender of a number of our citizens, and
ordered military detachments to seize and carry them into the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terior
for trial, in contempt of the civil authorities, and in defiance
of the laws and the constitution.</p>

<p>It has made piratical attacks upon our commerce, by commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
foreign desperadoes, and authorizing them to seize our vessels,
and. convey the property of our citizens to far distant parts for con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fiscation.</p>

<p>It denies us the right of worshiping the Almighty according to
the dictates of our own conscience, by the support of a national
religion, calculated to promote the temporal interest of its human
functionaries, rather than the glory of the true and living God.</p>

<p>It has demanded us to deliver up our arms, which are essential
to our defence—the rightful property of freemen—and formidable
only to tyrannical governments.</p>

<p>It has invaded our country both by sea and by land, with the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tent
to lay waste our territory, and drive us from our homes; and
has now a large mercenary army advancing, to carry on against us
a war of extermination.</p>

<p>It has, through its emissaries, incited the merciless savage, with
the tomahawk and scalping knife, to massacre the inhabitants of
our defenceless frontiers.</p>

<pb n="1066" xml:id="P1066" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1074/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="6" />
<fw type="header" place="top">The Declaration of Independence.</fw>

<p>It has been, during the whole time of our connection with it,
the contemptible sport and victim of successive military revolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions,
and hath continually exhibited every characteristic of a weak,
corrupt, and tryannical government.</p>

<p>These, and other grievances, were patiently borne by the people
of Texas, until they reached that point at which forbearance ceases
to be a virtue: We then took up arms in defence of the national
constitution. We appealed to our Mexican brethren for assistance:
our appeal has been made in vain; though months have elapsed, no
sympathetic response has yet been heard from the interior. We
are, therefore, forced to the melancholy conclusion, that the Mexi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />can
people have acquiesced in the destruction of their liberty, and
the substitution therefor of a military government; that they are
unfit to be free, and incapable of self government.</p>

<p>The necessity of self-preservation, therefore, now decrees our
eternal political separation.</p>

<p>We, therefore, the delegates, with plenary powers, of the people
of Texas, in solemn convention assembled, appealing to a candid
world for the necessities of our condition, do hereby resolve and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clare,
that our political connection with the Mexican nation has
forever ended, and that the people of Texas do now constitute a
free, sovereign, and independent republic, and are fully invested
with all the rights and attributes which properly belong to inde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pendent
nations; and, conscious of the rectitude of our intentions,
we fearlessly and confidently commit the issue to the supreme
Arbiter of the destinies of nations.</p>

<p>In witness whereof we have hereunto subscribed our names.</p>

<p>RICHARD ELLIS,
<lb />President and Delegate from Red River.</p>

<p>ALBERT H. S. Kimble, Secretary.</p>

<list>
    <item>C. B. Stewart,</item>
    <item>James Collinsworth,</item>
    <item>Edwin Waller,</item>
    <item>A. Brigham,</item>
    <item>John S. D. Byrom,</item>
    <item>Francis Ruis,</item>
    <item>J. Antonio Navarro,</item>
    <item>William D. Lacy,</item>
    <item>William Menifee,</item>
    <item>John Fisher,</item>
    <item>Matthew Caldwell,</item>
    <item>John S. Roberts,</item>
    <item>Robert Hamilton,</item>
    <item>Collin McKinney,</item>
    <item>A. H. Latimore,</item>
    <item>James Power,</item>
    <item>Sam. Houston,</item>
    <item>Edward Conrad,</item>
    <item>Martin Palmer,</item>
    <item>James Gaines,</item>
    <item>William Clark, jun.,</item>
    <item>Sydney 0. Pennington,</item>

<pb n="1067" xml:id="P1067" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1075/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="7" />
<fw type="header" place="top">The Declaration of Independence.</fw>

    <item>William Motley,</item>
    <item>Lorenzo de Zavala,</item>
    <item>George W. Smyth,</item>
    <item>Stephen H. Everett,</item>
    <item>Elijah Stepp,</item>
    <item>Claiborne West,</item>
    <item>William B. Leates,</item>
    <item>M. B. Menard,</item>
    <item>A. B. Hardin,</item>
    <item>John W. Bunton,</item>
    <item>Thomas J. Gazley,</item>
    <item>R. M. Coleman,</item>
    <item>Sterling C. Robertson,</item>
    <item>George C. Childress,</item>
    <item>Baily Hardiman,</item>
    <item>Robert Potter,</item>
    <item>Charles Taylor,</item>
    <item>Samuel P. Carson,</item>
    <item>Thomas J. Rusk,</item>
    <item>William C. Crawford,</item>
    <item>John Turner,</item>
    <item>Benjamin Briggs Goodrich,</item>
    <item>James G. Swisher,</item>
    <item>George W. Barnet,</item>
    <item>Jesse Grimes,</item>
    <item>E. O. Legrand,</item>
    <item>David Thomas,</item>
    <item>S. Rhoads Fisher,</item>
    <item>John W. Bower,</item>
    <item>J. B. Woods,</item>
    <item>Andrew Briscoe,</item>
    <item>Thomas Barnett,</item>
    <item>Jesse B. Badgett,</item>
    <item>Stephen W. Blount.</item>
</list>

<p>I do hereby certify that I have carefully compared the foregoing
Declaration, and find it to be a true copy from the original filed in
the archives of the Convention.</p>

<p>Given under my hand this 17th day of March, 1836.</p>

<p>Attest,
<lb />H. S. KIMBLE,
<lb />Secretary of the Convention.
</p></div></body></text>
