<text>
    
<front />
<body>
    <div type="document">
<pb n="1069" xml:id="P1069" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1077/" />
<head>CONSTITUTION
<lb />OF THE
<lb />REPUBLIC OF TEXAS.</head>

<p>We, the people of Texas, in order to form a government, estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish
justice, ensure domestic tranquility, provide for the common
defence and general welfare; and to secure the blessings of liberty
to ourselves, and our posterity, do ordain and establish this con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution.</p>

<head>ARTICLE 1.</head>

<p>SECTION 1. The powers of this government shall be divided into
three departments, viz: legislative, executive and judicial, which
shall remain forever separate and distinct.</p>

<p>Sec. 2. The legislative power shall be vested in a senate and
house of representatives, to be styled the congress of the republic of
Texas.</p>

<p>Sec. 3. The members of the house of represntatives shall be
chosen annually, on the first Monday of September each year, until
congress shall otherwise provide by law, and shall hold their offices
one year from the date of their election.</p>

<p>Sec. 4. No person shall be eligible to a seat in the house of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
until he shall have attained the age of twenty-five years,
shall be a citizen of the republic, and shall have resided in the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty
or district six months next preceding his election.</p>

<p>Sec. 5. The house of representatives shall not consist of less
than twenty-four, nor more than forty members, until the popula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
shall amount to one hundred thousand souls, after which time
the whole number of representatives shall not be less than forty,
nor more than one hundred: Provided, however, that each county
shall be entitled to at least one representative.</p>

<pb n="1070" xml:id="P1070" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1078/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="10" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

<p>Sec. 6. The house of representatives shall choose their speaker
and other officers, and shall have the sole power of impeachment.</p>

<p>Sec. 7. The senators shall be chosen by districts, as nearly equal
in free population (free negroes and Indians excepted,) as prac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticable;
and the number of senators shall never be less than one
third nor more than one half the number of representatives, and
each district shall be entitled to one member and no more.</p>

<p>Sec. 8. The senators shall be chosen for the term of three years,
on the first Monday in September; shall be citizens of the republic,
reside in the district for which they are respectively chosen at least
one year before the election; and shall have attained the age of
thirty years.</p>

<p>Sec. 9. At the first session of congress after the adoption of this
constitution, the senators shall be divided by lot into three classes,
as nearly equal as practicable; the seats of the senators of the first
class shall be vacated at the end of the first year; of the second
class, at the end of the second year; the third class, at the end of
the third year, in such a manner that one-third shall be chosen each
year thereafter.</p>

<p>Sec. 10. The vice president of the republic shall be president
of the senate, but shall not vote on any question, unless the senate
be equally divided.</p>

<p>Sec. 11. The senate shall choose all other officers of their body,
and a president pro tempore, in the absence of the vice president,
or whenever he shall exercise the office of president; shall have the
sole power to try impeachments, and when sitting as a court of im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peachment,
shall be under oath; but no conviction shall take place
without the concurrence of two thirds of all the members present.</p>

<p>Sec. 12. Judgment in cases of impeachment shall only extend
to removal from office, and disqualification to hold any office of
honor, trust or profit under this government; but the party shall
nevertheless be liable to indictment, trial, Judgment and punish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
according to law.</p>

<p>Sec. 13. Each house shall be the judge of the elections, qualifica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
and returns of its own members. Two thirds of each house
shall constitute a quorum to do business, but a smaller number may
adjourn from day to day, and may compel the attendance of absent
members.</p>

<p>Sec. 14. Each house may determine the rules of its own
proceedings, punish its members for disorderly behavior, and with

<pb n="1071" xml:id="P1071" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1079/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="11" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

the concurrence of two thirds, may expel a member, but not a
second time for the same offence.</p>

<p>Sec. 15. Senators and representatives shall receive a compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
for their services, to be fixed by law, but no increase of com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation,
or diminution, shall take effect during the session at
which such increase or diminution shall have been made. They
shall, except in case of treason, felony, or breach of the peace, be
privileged from arrest during the session of congress, and in going
to and returning from the same; and for any speech or debate in
either house they shall not be questioned in any other place.</p>

<p>Sec. 16. Each house may punish, by imprisonment, during the
session, any person not a member, who shall be guilty of any dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />respect
to the house, by any disorderly conduct in their presence.</p>

<p>Sec. 17. Each house shall keep a journal of its proceedings, and
publish the same, except such parts as in its judgment require
secrecy. When any three members shall desire the yeas and nays
on any question, they shall be entered on the journals.</p>

<p>Sec. 18. Neither house, without the consent of the other, shall
adjourn for more than three days, nor to any other place than that
in which the two houses may be sitting.</p>

<p>Sec. 19. When vacancies happen in either house, the executive
shall issue writs of election to fill such vacancies.</p>

<p>Sec. 20. No bill shall become a law until it shall have been read
on three several days in each house, and passed by the same, unless,
in cases of emergency, two thirds of the members of the house
where the bill originated shall deem it expedient to dispense with
the rule.</p>

<p>Sec. 21. After a bill shall have been rejected, no bill containing
the same substance shall be passed into a law during the same ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />.
sion.</p>

<p>Sec. 22. The style of the laws of the republic shall be, “Be it
enacted by the senate and house of representatives of the republic
of Texas, in congress assembled.”</p>

<p>Sec. 23. No person holding an office of profit under the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
shall be eligible to a seat in either house of congress, nor
shall any member of either house be eligible to any office which
may created, or the profits of which shall be increased during his
term of service.</p>

<p>Sec. 24. No holder of public monies or collector thereof,
shall be eligible to a seat in either house of congress, until he

<pb n="1072" xml:id="P1072" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1080/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="12" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>


shall have fully acquitted himself of all responsibility, and shall
produce the proper officer’s receipt thereof. Members of either
house may protest against any act or resolution, and may have
such protest entered on the journals of their respective houses.</p>

<p>Sec. 25. No money shall be drawn from the public treasury
but in strict accordance with appropriations made by law; and no
appropriations shall be made for private or local purposes, unless
tiro thirds of each house concur in such appropriations.</p>

<p>Sec. 26. Every act of congress shall be approved and signed by
the president before it becomes a law; but if the president will not
approve and sign such act, he shall return it to the house in which
it shall have originated, with his reasons for not approving the
same, which shall be spread upon the journals of such house, and
the bill shall then be reconsidered, and shall not become a law un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />less
it shall then pass by a vote of two thirds of both houses. If
any act shall be disapproved by the president, the vote on the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />consideration
shall be recorded by ayes and noes. If the president
shall fail to return a bill within five days (Sundays excepted) after
it shall have been presented for his approval and signature, the
same shall become a law, unless the congress prevent its return
within the time above specified by adjournment.</p>

<p>Sec. 27. All bills, acts, orders, or resolutions, to which the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />currence
of both houses may be necessary, (motions or resolutions
for adjournment excepted,) shall be approved and signed by the
president, or being disapproved, shall be passed by two thirds of
both houses, in manner and form as specified in section twenty.</p>

<head>ARTICLE II.</head>

<p>Sec. 1. Congress shall have power to levy and collect taxes and
imposts, excise and tonage duties: to borrow money on the faith,
credit, and. property of the government, to pay the debts and to
provide for the common defence and general welfare of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public.</p>

<p>Sec. 2. To regulate commerce, to coin money, to regulate the
value thereof and of foreign coin, to fix the standard of weights
and measures, but nothing but gold and silver shall be made a
lawful tender.</p>

<p>Sec. 3. To establish post offices and post roads, to grant charters
of incorporation, patents and copy rights, and secure to the authors
and inventors the exclusive use thereof for a limited time.</p>

<pb n="1073" xml:id="P1073" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1081/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="13" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

<p>Sec. 4. To declare war, grant letters of marque and reprisal,
and to regulate captures.</p>

<p>Sec. 5. To provide and maintain an army and navy, and to make
all laws and regulations necessary for their government.</p>

<p>Sec. 6. To .call out the militia to execute the law, to suppress
insurrections, and repel invasion.</p>

<p>Sec. 7. To make all laws which shall be deemed necessary and
proper to carry into effect the foregoing express grants of power,
and all other powers vested in the government of the republic, or in
any officer or department thereof.</p>

<head>ARTICLE III.</head>

<p>Sec. 1. The executive authority of the government shall be
vested in a chief magistrate, who shall be styled the president of
the republic of Texas.</p>

<p>Sec. 2. The first president elected by the people shall hold his
office for the term of two years, and shall be ineligible during the
next succeeding term; and all subsequent presidents shall be elected
for three years, and be alike ineligible; and in the event of a tie,
the house of representatives shall determine between the two high<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est
candidates by a vive voce vote.</p>

<p>Sec. 3. The returns of the elections for president and vice pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ident
shall be sealed up and transmitted to the speaker of the
house of representatives, by the holders of elections of each county;
and the speaker of the house of representatives shall open and pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish
the returns in presence of a majority of each house of congress.</p>

<head>ARTICLE IV.</head>

<p>Sec. 1. The judicial powers, of the government shall be vested
in one supreme court, and such inferior courts as the congress may,
from time to time, ordain and establish. The judges of the supreme
and inferior courts shall hold their offices for four years, be eligible
to re-election, and shall, at stated periods, receive for their ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices
a compensation, not to be increased or diminished during the
period for which they were elected.</p>

<p>Sec. 2. The republic of Texas shall be divided into convenient
judicial districts, not less than three, nor more than eight. There
shall be appointed for each district a judge, who shall reside in the
same, and hold the courts at such times and places as congress may
by law direct.</p>

<p>Sec. 3. In all admiralty and maritime cases, in all cases affecting
ambassadors, public ministers or consuls, and in all capital cases,
the district courts shall have exclusive original jurisdiction, and
orignal jurisidiction in all civil cases when the matter in contro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />versy
amounts to one hundred dollars.</p>

<pb n="1074" xml:id="P1074" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1082/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="14" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

<p>Sec. 4. The judges, by virtue of their offices, shall be conserva<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors
of the peace, throughout the republic. The style of all pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess
shall be, “the republic of Texas;" and all prosecutions shall be
carried on in the name and by the authority of the same, and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clude,
“against the peace and dignity of the republic.”</p>

<p>Sec. 5. There shall be a district attorney appointed for each dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict,
whose duties, salaries, perquisites, and term of service shall be
fixed by law.</p>

<p>Sec. 6. The clerks of the district courts shall be elected by the
qualified voters for members of congress, in the counties where
the courts are established, and shall hold their offices for four years,
subject to removal by presentment of a grand jury, and conviction
of a petit jury.</p>

<p>Sec. 7. The supreme court shall consist of a chief justice and as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sociate
judges; the district judges shall compose the associate
judges, a majority of whom, with the chief justice, shall constitute
a quorum.</p>

<p>Sec. 8. The supreme court shall have appellate jurisidiction
only, which shall be conclusive, within the limits of the republic;
and shall hold its sessions annually, at such times and places as
may be fixed by law: Provided, that no judge shall sit in a case
in the supreme court tried by him in the court below.</p>

<p>Sec. 9. The judges of the supreme and district courts shall be
elected by joint ballot of both houses of congress.</p>

<p>Sec. 10. There shall be in each county a county court, and such
justices’ courts as the congress may, from time to time, establish.</p>

<p>Sec. 11. The republic shall be divided into convenient counties,
but no new county shall be established, unless it be done on the
petition of- one hundred free male inhabitants of the territory
sought to be laid of and established; and unless the said territory
shall contain nine hundred square miles.</p>

<p>Sec. 12. There shall be appointed for each county, a conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ient
number of justices of the peace, one sheriff, one coroner, and
a sufficient number of constables, who shall hold their offices for
two years, to be elected by the qualified voters of the district or
county, as congress may direct. Justices of the peace and sheriffs
shall be commissioned by the president.</p>

<p>Sec. 13. The congress shall, as early as practicable, introduce,
by statute, the common law of England, with such modifications as
our circumstances, in their judgment, may require; and in all crim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inal
cases, the common law shall be the rule of decision.</p>

<pb n="1075" xml:id="P1075" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1083/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="15" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

<head>ARTICLE V.</head>

<p>Sec. 1. Ministers of the gospel being, by their profession, dedi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated
to God and the care of souls, ought not to be diverted from
the great duties of their functions: therefore, no minister of the
gospel or priest of any denomination whatever, shall be eligible to
the office of the executive of the republic, nor to a seat in either
branch of the congress of the same.</p>

<p>Sec. 2. Each member of the senate and house of representatives
shall, before they proceed to business, take an oath to support the
constitution, as follows;</p>

<p>"I, A. B., do solemnly swear [or affirm, as the case may be] that,
as a member of this general congress, I will support the constitution
of the republic, and that I will not propose or assent to any bill,
vote, or resolution, which shall appear to me injurious to the peo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ple.”</p>

<p>Sec. 3. Every person who shall be chosen or appointed to any
office of trust or profit shall, before entering on the duties thereof,
take an oath to support the constitution of the republic, and also
an oath of office.</p>

<head>ARTICLE VI.</head>

<p>Sec. 1. No person shall be eligible to the office of president
who shall not have attained the age of thirty-five years, shall be
a citizen of the republic at the time of the adoption of this con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution,
or an inhabitant of this republic at least three years im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mediately
preceding his election.</p>

<p>Sec. 2. The president shall enter on the duties of his office
on the second Monday in December next succeeding his election,
and shall remain in office until his successor shall be duly qualified.</p>

<p>Sec. 3. The president shall, at stated times, receive a compen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation
for his services, which shall not be increased or diminished
during his continuance in office; and before entering upon the du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties
of his office, he shall take and subscribe the following oath or
affirmation: “I, A. B., president of the republic of Texas, do sol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />emnly
and sincerely swear (or affirm, as the case may be) that I will
faithfully execute the duties of my office, and to the best of my
abilities preserve, protect, and defend the constitution of the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public.”</p>

<p>Sec. 4. He shall be commander-in-chief of the army and navy
of the republic, and militia thereof, but he shall not command in
person without the authority of a resolution of congress. He shall
have power to remit fines and forfeitures, and to grant reprieves
and pardons, except in cases of impeachment.</p>

<pb n="1076" xml:id="P1076" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1084/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="16" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

<p>Sec. 5. He shall, with the advice and consent of two-thirds of
the senate, make treaties; and with the consent of the senate, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point
ministers and consuls, and all officers whose offices are estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished
by this constitution, not herein otherwise provided for.</p>

<p>Sec. 6. The president shall have power to fill all vacancies that
may happen during the recess of the senate; but he shall report the
same to the senate within ten days after the next congress shall
convene; and should the senate reject the same, the president shall
not re-nominate the same individual to the same office.</p>

<p>Sec. 7. He shall, from time to time, give congress information
of the state of the republic, and recommend for .their consideration
such measures as he may deem necessary. He may, upon extra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ordinary
occasions, convene both houses, or either of them. In
the event of a disagreement as to the time of adjournment, he may
adjourn them to such time as he may think proper. He shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive
all foreign ministers. He shall see that the laws be faithfully
executed, and shall commission all the officers of the republic.</p>

<p>Sec. 8. There shall be a seal of the republic, which shall be
kept by the president, and used by him' officially; it shall be called
the great seal of the republic of Texas.</p>

<p>Sec. 9. All grants and commissions shall be in the name, and by
the authority of the republic of Texas, shall be sealed with the
great seal, and signed by the president.</p>

<p>Sec. 10. The president shall have power, by and with the ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vice
and consent of the senate, to appoint a secretary of state and
such other heads of executive departments as may be established by
law, who shall remain in office during the term of service of the
president, unless sooner removed by the president, with the ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vice
and consent of the senate.</p>

<p>Sec. 11. Every citizen of the republic who has attained the age
of twenty-one years, and shall have resided six months within the
district or county where the election is held, shall be entitled to
vote for members of the general congress.</p>

<p>Sec. 12. All elections shall be by ballot, unless congress shall
otherwise direct.</p>

<p>Sec. 13. All elections by joint vote of both houses of congress
shall be viva voce, shall be entered on the journals, and a majority
of the votes shall be necessary to a choice.</p>

<p>Sec. 14. A vice president shall be chosen at every elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
for president, in the same manner, continue in office for the

<pb n="1077" xml:id="P1077" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1085/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="17" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

same time, and shall possess the same qualifications of the president.
In voting for president and vice president, the electors shall dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinguish
for whom they vote as president, and for whom as vice
president.</p>

<p>Sec. 15. In cases of impeachment, removal from office, death,
resignation, or absence of the president from the republic, the vice
president shall exercise the powers and discharge the duties of
the president until a successor be duly qualified, or until the presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent,
who may be absent or impeached, shall return or be ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quitted.</p>

<p>Sec. 16. The president, vice president, and all civil officers of
the republic, shall be removable from office by impeachment for,
and on convicition of, treason, bribery, and other high crimes and
misdemeanors.</p>

<head>SCHEDULE.</head>

<p>Sec. 1. That no inconvenience may arise from the adoption of
this constitution, it is declared by this convention that all laws now
in force in Texas, and not inconsistent with this constitution, shall
remain in full force until declared void, repealed, altered, or ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pire
by their own limitation.</p>

<p>Sec. 2. All fines, penalties, forfeitures and escheats, which have
accrued to Coahuila and Texas, or Texas, shall accrue to this re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public.</p>

<p>Sec. 3. Every male citizen, who is, by this constitution, a citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zen,
and shall be otherwise qualified, shall be entitled to hold any
office or place of honor, trust, or profit under the republic, anything
in this constitution to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>

<p>Sec. 4. The first president and vice president that shall be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed
after the adoption of this constitution, shall be chosen by
this convention, and shall immediately enter on the duties of their
offices, and shall hold said offices until their successors be elected
and qualified, as prescribed in this constitution, and shall have the
same qualifications, be invested with the same powers, and perform
the same duties which are required and conferred on the executive
head of the republic by this constitution.</p>

<p>Sec. 5. The president shall issue writs of election directed
to the officers authorized to hold elections of the several coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties,
requiring them to cause an election to be held for president,
vice president, representatives, and senators to congress, at the
time and mode prescribed by this constitution, which election
shall be conducted in the manner that elections have been hereto<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore
conducted. The president, vice president, and members

<pb n="1078" xml:id="P1078" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1086/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="18" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

of congress, when duly elected, shall continue to discharge the
duties of their respective offices for the time and manner pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed
by this constitution, until their successors be duly qualified.</p>

<p>Sec. 6. Until the first enumeration shall be made, as directed
by this constitution, the precinct of Austin shall be entitled to one
representative; the precinct of Brazoria to two representatives; the
precinct of Bexar two representatives; the precinct of Colorado one
representative; Sabine one; Gonzales one; Goliad one; Harrisburg
one; Jasper one; Jefferson one; Liberty one; Matagorda one; Mina
two; Nacogdoches two; Red River three; Victoria one; San Augus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tine
two; Shelby two; Refugio one; San Patricio one; Washington
two; Milam one; and Jackson one representative.</p>

<p>Sec. 7. Until the first enumeration can be made, as described
by this constitution, the senatorial districts shall be composed of
the following precincts: Bexar shall be entitled to one senator; San
Patricio, Refugio and Goliad one; Brazoria one; Mina and Gonzales
one; Nacogdoches one; Red River one; Shelby and Sabine one;
Washington one; Matagorda, Jackson and Victoria one; Austin and
Colorado one; San Augustine one; Milam one; Jasper and Jefferson
one; and Liberty and Harrisburg one senator.</p>

<p>Sec. 8. All judges, sheriffs, commissioners, and other civil
officers shall remain in office, and in the discharge of the powers
and duties of their respective offices, until there shall be others ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed
or elected under the constitution.</p>

<head>GENERAL PROVISIONS.</head>

<p>Sec. 1. Laws shall be made to exclude from office, from the
right of suffrage, and from serving on juries, those who shall here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after
be convicted of bribery, perjury, or other high crimes and mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demeanors.</p>

<p>Sec. 2. Returns of all elections for officers who are to be com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioned
by the president, shall be made to the secretary of state
of this republic.</p>

<p>Sec. 3. The presidents and heads of departments shall keep
their .offices at the seat of government, unless removed by the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission
of congress, or unless in cases of emergency in time of war,
the public interest may require their removal.</p>

<p>Sec. 4. The president shall make use of his private seal until
a seal of the republic shall be provided.</p>

<p>Sec. 5. It shall be the duty of congress, as soon as cir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cumstances

<pb n="1079" xml:id="P1079" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1087/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="19" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

will permit, to provide by law, a general system of edu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation.</p>

<p>Sec. 6. All free white persons who shall emigrate to this re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public,
and who shall, after a residence of six months, make oath,
before some competent authority that he intends to reside perma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nently
in the same, and shall swear to support this constitution,
and that he will bear true allegiance to the republic of Texas, shall
be entitled to all the privileges of citizenship.</p>

<p>Sec. 7. So soon as convenience will permit, there shall be a
penal code formed on principles of reformation, and not of vindic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive
justice; and the civil and criminal laws shall be revised, di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gested,
and arranged under different heads; and all laws relating to
land titles shall be translated, revised and promulgated.</p>

<p>Sec. 8. All persons who shall leave the country for the purpose
of evading a participation in the present struggle, or shall refuse
to participate in it, or shall give aid or assistance to the present
enemy, shall forfeit all rights of citizenship, and such lands as they
may hold in the republic.</p>

<p>Sec. 9. All persons of color who were slaves for life previous
to their emigration to Texas, and who are now held in bondage,
shall remain in the like state of servitude: provided, the said slave
shall be the bona fide property of the person so holding said slave
as aforesaid. Congress. shall pass no laws to prohibit emigrants
from bringing their slaves into the republic with them, and holding
them by the same tenure by which such slaves were held in the
United States; nor shall congress have power to emancipate slaves;
nor shall any slave holder be allowed to emancipate his or her slave
or slaves without the consent of congress, unless he or she shall send
his or her slave or slaves without the limits of the republic. No
free person of African descent, either in whole or in part, shall be
permitted to reside permanently in the republic, without the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent
of congress; and the importation or admission of Africans or
negroes into this republic, excepting from the United States of
America, is forever prohibited, and declared to be piracy.</p>

<p>Sec. 10. All persons (Africans, the descendants of Afri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cans,
and Indians excepted,) who were residing in Texas on the
day of the declaration of independence, shall be considered citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zens
of the republic, and entitled to all the privileges of such.
All citizens now living in Texas, who have not received their
port' on of land, in like manner as colonists, shall be entitled to
their land in the following proportion and manner: Every head
of a family shall be entitled to one league and labor of land: and

<pb n="1080" xml:id="P1080" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1088/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="20" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

every single man of the age of seventeen and upwards, shall he
entitled to the third part of one league of land. All citizens who
may have previously to the adoption of this constitution, received
their league of land as heads of families, and their quarter of a
league of land as single persons, shall receive such additional quan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tity
as will make the quantity of land received by them equal to
one league and labor, and one third of a league, unless by bargain,
sale, or exchange, they have transferred or may henceforth transfer
their right to said land, or a portion thereof, .to some other citizen
of the republic: and in such case, the person to whom such right
shall have been transferred shall be entitled to the same, as fully
and amply as the person making the transfer might or could have
been.—No alien shall hold land in Texas, except by titles emanating
directly from the government of this republic. But if any citizen
of this republic should die intestate or otherwise, his children or
heirs shall inherit his estate, and aliens shall have a reasonable time
to take possession of and dispose of the same, in a manner here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after
to be pointed out by law. Orphan children whose parents
were entitled to land under the colonization laws of Mexico,
and who now reside in the republic, shall be entitled to all the
rights of which their parents were possessed at the time of their
death. The citizens of the republic shall not be compelled to reside
on the land, but shall have their lines plainly marked.</p>

<p>All orders of survey legally obtained by any citizen of the repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic,
from any legally authorized- commissioner, prior to the act of
the late consultation closing the land offices, shall be valid. In all
cases the actual settler and occupant of the soil shall be entitled,
in locating his land, to include his improvement, in preference to
all other claims not acquired previous to his settlement, according
to the law of the land and this constitution—provided, that noth<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
herein contained shall prejudice the rights of any other citizen
from whom a settler may hold land by rent or lease.</p>

<p>And whereas, the protection of the public domain from un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />just
and fraudulent claims, and quieting the people in the enjoy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
of their lands, is one of the great duties of this convention;
and whereas the legislature of Coahuila and Texas having pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed
an act in the year 1834, in behalf of general John T. Mason
of New York, and another on the 14th day of March, 1835, un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der
which the enormous amount of eleven hundred leagues of
land has been claimed by sundry individuals, some of whom re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />side
in foreign countries, and are not citizens of the republic,—

<pb n="1081" xml:id="P1081" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1089/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="21" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

which said acts are contrary to articles fourth, twelfth, and fif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth
of the laws of 1824 of the general congress of Mexico, and
one of said acts, for that cause has, by said general congress of
Mexico, been declared null and void: It is hereby declared that
the said act of 1834, in favor of John T. Mason, and of the 14th
of .March, 1835, of the said legislature of Coahuila and Texas,
and each and every grant founded thereon, is, and was from the
beginning, null and void; and all surveys made under pretence
of authority derived from said acts, are hereby declared to be
null and void: and all eleven league claims, located within twenty
leagues of the boundary line between Texas and the United States
of America, which have been located contrary to the laws of Mex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ico,
are hereby declared to be null and void. And whereas many
surveys and titles to lands have been made whilst most of the peo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ple
of Texas were absent from home, serving in the campaign
against Bexar, it is hereby declared that all the surveys and loca<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
of land made since the act of the late consultation closing
the land offices, and all titles to land made since that time, are,
and shall be null and void.</p>

<p>And whereas the present unsettled state of the country and the
general welfare of the people demand that the operations of the
land office, and the whole land system shall be suspended until
persons serving in the army can have a fair and equal chance with
those remaining at home, to select and locate their lands, it is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by
declared, that no survey or title which may hereafter be made
shall be valid, unless such survey or title shall be authorized by this
convention, or some future congress of the republic. And with a view
to the simplification of the land system, and the protection of the
people and the government from litigation and fraud, a general
land office shall be established, where all the land titles of the
republic shall be registered, and the whole territory of the republic
shall, he sectionized, in a manner hereafter to be prescribed by law,
which shall enable the officers of the government or any citizen,
to ascertain with certainty the lands that are vacant, and those
lands which may be covered with valid titles.</p>

<p>Sec. 11. Any amendment or amendments to this consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution,
may be proposed in the house of representatives or senate,
and if the same shall be agreed to by a majority of the members
elected to each of the two houses, such proposed amendment or
amendments shall be entered on the journals, with the yeas and
nays thereon, and referred to the congress then next to be chosen,
and shall be published for three months previous to the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion;

<pb n="1082" xml:id="P1082" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1090/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="22" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

and if the congress next chosen as aforesaid, shall pass said
amendment or amendments by a vote of two-thirds of all the
members elected to each house, then it shall be the duty of said
congress to submit said proposed amendment or amendments to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />the
people, in such manner and at such times as the congress
shall prescribe; and if the people shall approve and ratify such
amendment or amendments by a majority of the electors quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied
to vote for members of congress voting thereon, such amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
or amendments shall become a part of this constitution:
Provided, however, that no amendment or amendments be referred
to the people oftener than once in three years.</p>

<head>DECLARATION OF RIGHTS.</head>

<p>This declaration of rights is declared to be a part of this consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution,
and shall never be violated on any pretence whatever. And
in order to guard against the transgression of the high powers which
we have delegated, we declare that every thing in this bill of rights
contained, and every other right not hereby delegated, is reserved
to the people.</p>

<p>First. All men, when they form a social compact, have equal
rights, and no men or set of men are entitled to exclusive public
privileges or emoluments from the community.</p>

<p>Second. All political power is inherent in the people, and all
free governments are founded on their authority, and instituted
for their benefit: and they have at all times an inalienable right
to alter their government in such manner as they may think proper.</p>

<p>Third. No preference shall be given by law to any religious de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nomination
or mode of worship over another, but every person shall
be permitted to worship God according to the dictates of his own
conscience.</p>

<p>Fourth. Every citizen shall be at liberty to speak, write, or pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish
his opinions on any subject, being responsible for the abuse of
that privilege. No law shall ever be passed to curtail the liberty
of speech or of the press: and in all prosecutions for libels, the truth
may be given in evidence, and the jury shall have the right to de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />termine
the law and fact, under the direction of the court.</p>

<p>Fifth. The people shall be secure in their persons, houses,
papers, and possessions, from all unreasonable searches and seiz<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ures,
and no warrant shall issue to search any place or seize any
person or thing, without describing the place to be searched or

<pb n="1083" xml:id="P1083" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1091/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="23" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

the person or thing to be seized, without probable cause, supported
by oath or affirmation.</p>

<p>Sixth. In all criminal prosecutions the accused shall have the
right of being heard, by himself, or council, or both; he shall have
the right to demand the nature and cause of the accusation, shall
be confronted with the witnesses against him, and have compulsory
process for obtaining witnesses in his favor. And in all prosecu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
by presentment or indictment, he shall have the right to a
speedy and public trial, by an impartial, jury; he shall not be com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pelled
to give evidence against himself, or be deprived of life, lib<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty,
or property, but by due course of law. And no freeman shall
be holden to answer for any criminal charge, but on presentment
or indictment by a grand jury, except in the land and naval forces,
or in the militia when in actual service in time of war or public
danger, or in cases of impeachment.</p>

<p>Seventh. No citizen shall be deprived of privileges, outlawed,
exiled, or in any manner disfranchised, except by due course of the
law of the land.</p>

<p>Eighth. No title of nobility, hereditary privileges or honors, shall
ever be granted or conferred in this republic. No person holding
any office of profit or trust shall, without the consent of congress,
receive from any foreign state any present, office, or emolument
of any kind.</p>

<p>Ninth. No person, for the same offence, shall be twice put in
jeopardy of life or limbs.- And the right of trial by jury shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />main
inviolate.</p>

<p>Tenth. All persons shall be bailable by sufficient security, un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />■
less for capital crimes, when the proof is evident or presumption
strong; and the privilege of the writ of “habeas corpus” shall not
be suspended, except in case of rebellion or invasion the public
safety may require it.</p>

<p>Eleventh. Excessive bail shall not be required, nor excessive
fines imposed, or cruel or unusual punishment inflicted. All courts
shall be open, and everv man for anv injurv done him in his lands,
goods, person, or reputation, shall have remedy by due course of
law.</p>

<p>Twelfth. No person shall be imprisoned for debt in consequence
of inability to pay.</p>

<p>Thirteenth. No person’s particular services shall be demanded,
nor property taken or applied to public use, unless by the consent
of himself or his representative, without just compensation being<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />made
therefor according to law.</p>

<pb n="1084" xml:id="P1084" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1092/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="24" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

<p>Fourteenth. Every citizen shall have the right to bear arms
in defence of himself and the republic. The military shall at all
times and in all cases be subordinate to the civil power.</p>

<p>Fifteenth. The sure and certain defence of a free people is a
well regulated militia;'and it shall be the duty of the legislature
to enact such laws as may be necessary for the organizing of the
militia of this republic.</p>

<p>Sixteenth. Treason against this republic shall consist only in
levying war against it, or-adhering to its enemies, giving them aid
and support. No retrospective or ex-post facto law, or-laws im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pairing
the obligation of contracts, shall be made.</p>

<p>Seventeenth. Perpetuities or monopolies are contrary to the
genius of a free government, and shall not be allowed; nor shall
the law of primogeniture or entailments ever be in force in this
republic.</p>

<p>The foregoing constitution was unanimously adopted. by the dele<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gates
of Texas, in convention assembled, at the town of Washing<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton,
on the seventeenth day of March, in the year of our Lord one
thousand eight hundred and thirty-six, and of the Independence
of the Republic, the first year.</p>

<p>In witness whereof, we have hereunto subscribed our names.</p>

<p>RICHARD ELLIS,
<lb />President and Delegate from Red River.</p>

<p>Albert H. S. Kimble, Secretary,</p>

<list>
    <item>C. B. Stewart,</item>
    <item>James Collinsworth,</item>
    <item>Edwin Waller,</item>
    <item>A. Brigham,</item>
    <item>John S. D. Byrom,</item>
    <item>Francis Ruis,</item>
    <item>J. Antonio Navarro,</item>
    <item>William D. Lacy,</item>
    <item>William Menifee,</item>
    <item>John Fisher,</item>
    <item>Matthew Caldwell,</item>
    <item>William Motley,</item>
    <item>Lorenzo de Zavala,</item>
    <item>George W. Smyth,</item>
    <item>Stephen H. Everett,</item>
    <item>Elijah Stepp,</item>
    <item>Claiborne West,</item>
    <item>John S. Roberts,</item>
    <item>Robert Hamilton,</item>
    <item>Collin McKinney,</item>
    <item>A. H. Latimore,</item>
    <item>James Power,</item>
    <item>Sam. Houston,</item>
    <item>Edward Conrad,</item>
    <item>Martin Palmer,</item>
    <item>James Gaines,</item>
    <item>William Clark, jun.,</item>
    <item>Sydney 0. Pennington,</item>
    <item>Samuel P. Carson,</item>
    <item>Thomas J. Rusk,</item>
    <item>William C. Crawford,</item>
    <item>John Turner,</item>
    <item>Benjamin Briggs Goodrich,</item>
    <item>James G. Swisher,</item>

<pb n="1085" xml:id="P1085" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1093/" />
<pb ed="unknown" n="25" />
<fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Republic of Texas.</fw>

    <item>William B. Leates,</item>
    <item>M. B. Menard,</item>
    <item>A. B. Hardin,</item>
    <item>John W. Bunton,</item>
    <item>Thomas J. Gazley,</item>
    <item>R. M. Coleman,</item>
    <item>Sterling G. Robertson,</item>
    <item>George C. Childress,</item>
    <item>Baily Hardiman,</item>
    <item>Robert Potter,</item>
    <item>Charles Taylor,</item>
    <item>Georges W. Barnet,</item>
    <item>Jesse Grimes,</item>
    <item>E. O. Legrand,</item>
    <item>David Thomas,</item>
    <item>S. Rhoads Fisher,</item>
    <item>John W. Bower,</item>
    <item>J. B. Woods,</item>
    <item>Andrew Briscoe,</item>
    <item>Thomas Barnett,</item>
    <item>Jesse B. Badgett,</item>
    <item>Stephen W. Blount.</item>
</list>

<p>I do hereby certify that I have carefully compared the foregoing
Constitution, and find it to be a true copy from the original filed
in the archives of the Convention. .</p>

<p>Given under my hand this 17th day of March, 1836.</p>

<p>Attest,
<lb />H. S. KIMBLE,
<lb />Secretary of the Convention.</p>

</div>
</body>
</text>
