<text><front /><body><div type="document"><pb n="1343" xml:id="P1343" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1351/" /><p>LAWS
OF THE
REPUBLIC OF TEXAS
IN TWO VOLUMES.
PRINTEDZBY Order of the Secretary of State.
VOLUME II.
HOUSTON.
1838</p><pb n="1344" xml:id="P1344" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1352/" /><p /><pb n="1345" xml:id="P1345" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1353/" /><p>LAWS
OF THE
REPUBLIC OF TEXAS.
JOINT RESOLUTION
To. suspend the operation of the Land Office until the further
tion of congress
Resolved by the senate and house of representatives of the
ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />re-

public of Texas in congress assembled. That so much of an act
entitled “an act supplementary to an act establishing a general land
office for the republic of Texas,” passed 26th December, 1836, as
provided for the opening of the land office on the first day of
October, 1837, and for the appointment of officer under said law,
be, and the same is hereby suspended until the further action of
congress.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Sept. 30, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON..
JOINT RESOLUTION
Making an appropriation to pay the public printers.
- Resolved by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas in congress assembled, That the secretary of
the treasury be required to execute and deliver to Cruger &amp;
85—vol. i.
( 1345 )</p><pb n="1346" xml:id="P1346" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1354/" /><p>4
Laws of the Bepuhlic of Texas.
Moore, the proprietors of the press engaged in printing for the
government, a draft upon the collector of the port of Galveston,
payable at sight, for the sum of one thousand dollars.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Oct. 12, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Making appropriation of moneys for the use of the Hospital.
Be it resolved by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the sum of one
thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated out of
any moneys in the Treasury or in the hands of the officers of the
custom-houses, to be expended under the direction of the secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary
of war, to provide for the comforts of the sick soldiers, who
.now are, or hereafter may be, in the hospital at this place.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Oct. 15, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Locating permanently the seat of Government.
Resolved "by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in Congress assembled, That there shall be
elected by Joint vote of both houses of congress, five commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners
(any three of whom shall constitute a quorum for the
transaction of business) whose duty it shall be forthwith to
proceed to select a site for the permanent location of the seat
of government of this republic; and that they be required to
(1346)</p><pb n="1347" xml:id="P1347" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1355/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
5
give public notice of their appointment, and receive such propo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sitions
for the sale of lands as may be made to them, not less than
one, nor more than six leagues of land; and also examine such
places as they may think proper on vacant lands; and that they be
authorized to enter into conditional contracts for the purchase of
such locations as they may think proper, subject to ratification or
rejection by this congress, and that they be required to report to
congress, by.the 15th November, the different selections, with an ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curate
and full description of the same, to congress, and that in
making the selections, they be confined to the section of country
between the Trinity and Guadalupe rivers, and that they select
no place over one hundred miles north of the upper San Antonio
road, nor south of a direct line running from the Trinity to the
Guadalupe river, crossing the Brasses at Eort Bend.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Oct. 19, 1837.
SAM, HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Authorizing Wm. G. Cooke to sign the name of the president to
the promissory notes of the government.
Whereas, in consequence of the recent attrck of sickness, and the
consequent indisposition of his excellency the president of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public,
and the disabled situation of his excellency’s right arm
from a former wound, aggravated by his present sickness, he is
now unable to attend to the laborious duty of signing the promis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sory
notes of the government, authorized by the last session of con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress,
by an act passed the 9th of June, 1837, which being princi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pally
for small sums will amuunt to some thousands; and whereas,
the necessary and pressing wants of the country require that the
issue of such notes should immediately commence: therefore, ■
Sec. 1. Resolved by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That Wm. G.
( 1347 )</p><pb n="1348" xml:id="P1348" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1356/" /><p>6
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
Cooke be, and he is hereby authorized and empowered to sign the
name of the president to the promissory notes of the government.
Sec. 3. Be it further resolved, that Wm. G. Cooke shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled
to five dollars per day for the time he is occupied in per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />forming
the duties above named, and that he proceed forthwith
to sign said notes.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Oct. 23, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of W. S. Hendrick.
Resolved by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas in congress assembled, That the sum of one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
and sixty-two dollars be allowed to W. S. Hendrick, for ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tra
services rendered the first congress as door-keeper, and that
this resolution be a sufficient voucher to the auditor of public ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />counts
to allow and audit the same.
JOSEHH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Oct. 25, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Regulating Elections.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
the chief justice and associates in each county of the republic
shall designate election precincts at the most suitable places for
(1348)</p><pb n="1349" xml:id="P1349" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1357/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
7
holding elections in their several counties. And it shall be the
duty of the chief justices of the counties to issue writs of election
to the several precincts established, appointing a presiding officer in
each to hold the election, stating specifically in the writs the officer
or officers to be elected, and the day on which the election shall
take place.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That each presiding officer shall
appoint three judges of the election and two clerks, who shall be
sworn, before entering upon the duties of their offices, to conduct
the election without partiality or prejudice, and agreeably to law:
and in the event that the judges and clerks thus appointed shall
fail to attend, or refuse to act, then it shall be lawful for the voters,
at the house of opening the polls to appoint judges and clerks to
supply such vacancies: and if there be no justice of the peace pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent,
the presiding officer shall swear the other managers, and one of
them shall administer the oath to him, which shall be as legal as if
done by a judicial officer.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That each of the clerks shall write
the name of each voter at the time of his voting, making two lists
of the names of the electors, one of which shall be delivered to the
chief justice of the county, with the returns of the election, to be
kept as a record, and the other to be retained by the presiding offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cer
of the election..
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the polls shall be kept open
from nine o’clock to twelve in the forenoon, and from one to five in
the afternoon, the presiding officer making proclamation at the
door of the house at the time of opening and closing the polls.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That immediately after closing
the polls, the officers of the election shall proceed to count the
votes and make out a complete return, which shall be sealed up and
delivered to the chief justice of the county by the presiding officer
or one of the judges of the election upon oath: a duplicate of which
return shall be kept by the presiding officer.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the chief justice shall
give at least ten days’ notice (except in cases of vacancy, when
immediate notices shall be given to the different precincts, upon
the receipt of the president’s proclamation for filling said va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cancy,)
of every election, by an advertisement published in a
newspaper, if any be printed in the county: or if there be no pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />per
published in the county, then by an advertisement in manu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(
1349 )</p><pb n="1350" xml:id="P1350" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1358/" /><p>8
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
script, in each precinct, stating the names of the several presiding
officers appointed in the county, the places of holding the election,
the day on which the election will he held, and the officer or offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers
to he elected. The writs of election issued by the chief justice,
shall require the presiding officer, or one of the judges or clerks of
the election, to deliver the returns to him at the county seat, at
some time specified therein, not exceeding ten days from the day of
holding the election; and upon the receipt of the returns, the chief
justice, in the presence of the returning officer, shall examine the
several documents, and immediately execute and deliver to the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son
or persons having the greatest number of votes, a certificate of
election.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That no officer of an election shall
examine any vote, or unfold any ticket presented by a voter.
Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That when a man shall offer his
vote, unless some officer of the election will vouch for his qualifica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
as an elector, he shall take oath that he is legally qualified
according to the constitution and laws, to vote for members of Con- ■
gress.
Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That regular enlisted soldiers,
and volunteers for during the war, shall not be eligible to vote for
civil officers.
Sec. 10. And be it further enacted, That no person shall be
permitted to contest any election unless within ten days after the
return day. The person intending to contest, shall cause the person
having a certificate of election to be notified thereof, and a state<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
in writing delivered to him, containing the grounds up<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />on
which he relies to sustain the contest, or in case the candidate
elect can not be found, then the notice and statement to be left at
his usual place of abode. Ko ex-parte statements or testimony shall
be received as evidence in any contested election, without the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent
of the opposite party.
Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That this act shall take effect
and be in force from and after its passage: provided, however, that
nothing herein contained shall affect elections in depopulated coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties.
And be it further enacted, that if any person in this repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic
shall, after the passage of this act, vote for a member or mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers
of congress more than one time in the same day, such person
shall be liable to indictment, and upon conviction before any com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />petent
tribunal, shall forfeit and pay for every such offence not
less than fifty, nor more than one hundred dollars; to go to the
county treasury.
(1350 )</p><pb n="1351" xml:id="P1351" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1359/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
9
Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That in senatorial districts, now
or hereafter to be established, consisting of two or more counties,
congress shall from time to time designate and determine the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty
whose chief justice shall issue the necessary certificate to the sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ator
elect. And the chief justices of the other county or counties
composing the senatorial district shall seal up and deliver the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turns
of the election, from the several precincts of their respective
counties, for senator, duly authenticated, and hand them to the
chief justice of the county so designated by congress within ten
days after said returns are received by him or them; and that the<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />county
of Refugio, in the senatorial district composed of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties
of San Patricio, Refugio, and Goliad; the county of Mina, in
the district composed of the counties of Mina and Gonzales; the
county of Shelby, in the district composed of the counties of Shelby
and Sabine; the county of Jackson, in the district composed of the
counties of Matagorda, Jackson, and Victoria; the county of Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin,
in the district composed of the counties of Austin and Colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rado;
the county of Jasper, in the district composed of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties
of Jasper and Jefferson; the county of Harrisburg, in the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict
composed of the counties of Harrisburg and Liberty; the
county of Nacogdoches, in the district composed of the counties of
Nacogdoches and Houston, shall be, and the same are hereby desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated
as the counties whose chief justices shall give the certificates
to the senators elect from the respective districts, and receive the
returns from the other counties in the aforesaid districts.
Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That if at the time of any elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
for civil officers, a portion of the citizens of any county shall
be absent from home, in the service of their country, they shall
choose three managers from among themselves, who shall hold the
election, under the same rules and regulations herein prescribed,
who shall seal up the returns of said election, and send them to the
chief- justice of their respective counties, who shall receive the
same.
Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That in case of a tie between any
two or more candidates for representatives in congress, the chief
justice of the county in which such tie shall occur, shall decide be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween
the candidates having the highest number of votes.
Sec. 15. Be it further enacted. That in case of a tie be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween
any two or more candidates for senator to congress, if the
county in which such tie shall occur be entitled to a senator,
then and in that case, the chief justice of such county shall decide
(1351 )</p><pb n="1352" xml:id="P1352" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1360/" /><p>10
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
the tie; but if the senatorial district in which a tie occurs, be com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed
of two or more counties, then the chief justice of the county
authorized to give a certificate to the senator elect, shall decide the
tie.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President of the senate pro tem.
Approved, October 26, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Requiring the chief justice of the county of Brazoria to issue writs'
of election.
Resolved by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas in congress assembled, That the chief justice of
the county of Brazoria is hereby authorized and required to issue
writs of election, giving ten days notice, for an election to be held at
all the precincts of said county, in order that it may be ascertained
whether a majority of the people of said county desire a continu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance
of the seat of justice at the town of Brazoria, or its removal
to the town of Columbia.
Resolved, that said election shall be held on the 20th of the en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />suing
November, and the returns be made as soon as practicable
to the speaker of the house of representatives.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Oct. 31, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
. Authorizing an Appropriation for the Post Office.
Be it enacted by the senate and house of representatives of
the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That the sum of ten
thousand dollars is hereby appropriated for the use of the post
( 1352 )</p><pb n="1353" xml:id="P1353" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1361/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
11
office department, and that the post master general is hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized
to draw for the amount on the secretary of the treasury,
out of any unappropriated monies in the treasury.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Nov. 4, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
To authorize the secretary of war to- grant discharges.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That the secretary
of war be and he is hereby authorized to grant discharges to all
officers and soldiers who are now on furlough, for the time they
have served; provided they will relinquish their claims to pay and
bounty lands for that portion of the term for which they have en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />listed,
enrolled or commissioned, and have not yet served.
Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That the provisions of the
first section of this act remain in force for the term of sixty days
from its passage.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Nov. 2, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Granting letters of Marque and Reprisal.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas in congress assembled, That they cordially
concur in the immediate granting of Letters of Marque and
Reprisal against the commerce and government of Mexico,
( 1353 )</p><pb n="1354" xml:id="P1354" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1362/" /><p>12
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
as promulgated in the proclamation of his excellency the President
of this republic, under date of 15th September, 1837.
Resolved, That his excellency, the President of this republic, is
hereby authorised and required to grant commissions to all appli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cants
who offer sound and sufficient security that they will con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duct
themselves in strict accordance with the established laws
of nations, and the special laws of this republic, on the subject of
privateering; which said commissions shall not be revoked or an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nulled
during the contest between Texas and Mexico, except by a
decree of a court of Admiralty, founded on mal feasance in office,
or other sufficient cause. Provided, however, That nothing herein
contained shall prevent his excellency from suspending the cruis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
or naval operations of any privateer guilty, in his opinion of
mal feasance, until a trial can be had before a court of competent
jurisdiction.
Resolved, that the secretary of the navy cause these resolutions
to be published for one month in the Texas Telegraph; also in some
of the public journals of the United States of the North.
Resolved, That the government of Texas hereby relinquishes
her right to the 10 per cent, usually paid by privateers, and will
claim no more than two and a half per cent, for the purpose of de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fraving
the expense of adjudication, &amp;c.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Nov. 2, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To incorporate the town of Shelbyville, and granting further pow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers
to the corporations of San Augustine and Nacogdoches.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the senate and house of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
all the qualified voters for members of congress, who may have
resided within the town of San Augustine, six months preceding
any election, for any officer of that corporation, or who may
(1354)</p><pb n="1355" xml:id="P1355" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1363/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
13
own real estate in said town, shall be entitled to vote for any officer
of said corporation, or to hold any office therein. And the said
body corporate are hereby authorised and empowered to make any
law or laws which they may deem necessary to be made and enacted
for the benefit of the inhabitants of said corporation, not contrary
to the laws and constitution of this republic.
Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That the town of Shelbyville
in the county of Shelby, be incorporated with the same powers and
privileges, which are granted and conferred by an act to incorpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate
the town of Nacogdoches, and other towns therein named,
passed the thirty-first day of May, one thousand eight hundred and
thirty-seven, and on the town of San Augustine by this act.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Nov. 2, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
For augmenting the Navy, and making an appropriation
therefor.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the
president, by and with the advice and consent of. the senate, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point
an agent, when in his discretion he may think proper, whose
duty it shall be to repair to some seaport of the United States of the
north, for the purpose of buying or building, arming, and equip<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ping,
for the public service of Texas, one ship or brig, about five
hundred tons burthen, to mount eighteen guns; two barques or
brigs, about three hundred tons burthen, mounting twelve guns
each; and three schooners, about one hundred and thirty tons bur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />then,
mounting five or seven guns each: and that the said vessels
be fitted and furnished with such artillery and armament as is best
adapted to vessels of their class.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the sum of two hundred
and eighty thousand dollars is hereby appropriated for the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1355
)</p><pb n="1356" xml:id="P1356" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1364/" /><p>14
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
pose of buying or building, arming and equipping said vessels; and
that the secretary of the treasury furnish said agent with a draft
for the above appropriated sum of two hundred and eighty thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand
dollars on Messrs. Gilmer &amp; Burnley, the commissioners to
negotiate a five million loan for this republic: and that the public
faith is also solemnly pledged for its payment.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That said agent be entitled to a
compensation of three hundred and fifty dollars per month, and
that he give bond and security for the faithful performance of his
duty, in the sum of five thousand dollars.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Nov. 4, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Regulating the proceedings before justices of the peace.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That from and
after the passage of this act, all civil proceedings before justices of
the peace, shall be had in. a summary manner, and without the for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mality
of a petition in writing; and it shall be sufficient, except in
cases of attachment, sequestration, and other extraordinary meas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ures,
for the justice to insert within the body of the citation, or
endorse on the back thereof, the nature of the cause of action.
Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That, if any party, against
whom judgment shall be rendered by any justice of the peace, shall
fail to appeal from, or stay such judgment within three days from
the rendition thereof, then it shall be lawful for execution to issue.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
/President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Nov. 4, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1356 )</p><pb n="1357" xml:id="P1357" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1365/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
is
JOINT RESOLUTION
Requiring the Secretary of War to execute certain duties.
Resolved, by the senate. and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the secretary of war
be required forthwith to proceed to execute the duties of his office
as required of him by an act of congress, entitled “an act supple<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mentary
to an act to establish a general land office for the republic
of Texas.”
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Vetoed by the president, and passed by a constitutional majority
of the house of representatives.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
Vetoed by the president, and passed by a constitutional majority
of the senate.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
October 27, 1837.
AN ACT
To provide for auditing contingent expenses of both Houses of
Congress, and making appropriation therefor.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the
auditor of public accounts be, and he is hereby authorized to audit
any accounts which may be authorized by a resolution of either
house of congress, upon the complainant presenting a copy of said
resolution, certified by the secretary or clerk of the house in which
the resolution may have been adopted, and the certificate of the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son
authorized by said resolution to contract such debt or debts,
that the account is correct and just, and to draw on the contingent
fund of both houses of congress for the amount.
(1357 )</p><pb n="1358" xml:id="P1358" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1366/" /><p>16
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That two thousand dollars be,
and the same is hereby appropriated to defray the contingent ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses
of both houses of congress.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVEEITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Nov. 2, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT EESOLUTION
For the relief of Holland, Coffee and Co.
Eesolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas in Congress assembled, That the sum of six hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
and ninety-one dollars be allowed to. Holland, Coffee and Co.,
for moneys by them expended in purchasing Texian prisoners from
the Indians, and that the same be paid in the .promissory notes of
the government.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President of the senate pro tem.
Approved, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To provide for the appointment of Notaries Public.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That there shall be
a notary public for each of the ports of entry of this republic, to be
appointed by the president, by and with the advice and consent of
the senate, who shall hold his office for two years, unless sooner re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moved
by the president, and shall receive the same fees as are now
allowed by law to the several chief justices for the performance of
notarial acts.
(1358)</p><pb n="1359" xml:id="P1359" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1367/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
17
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the several notaries public
shall have a seal of office, and all certificates or other acts by by
them performed, shall be signed by the said notaries, and the seal
of office thereunto affixed.
Approved, Nov. 16, 1837.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
To appoint a Committee on Printing.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas in Congress assembled, That a joint committee of
two be appointed by each house of congress, to contract with some
competent person or persons to print the laws of the consultation
and the convention, together with all the laws which have been en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />acted
since the declaration of independence, and also the journals
-of the special and regular session of congress, for the years 1836 and
1837; and the said committee.are required to enquire what progress,
if any, has been made in the above business, and report their pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceedings
to this Congress.
Approved, Nov. 18, 1837.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To incorporate the town of Brazoria.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
the citizens of the town of Brazoria, be, .and they are hereby
( 1359 )</p><pb n="1360" xml:id="P1360" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1368/" /><p>18
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
declared a body politic and corporate by the name and title of “the
Corporation of the town of Brazoria/’ and by that name may sue
and be sued, implead and be impleaded, and may hold, and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose
of real and personal estate in said town.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That all that tract of land, known
as the old and new town of Brazoria, shall be the limits and boun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />daries
of said town.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted. That an election shall be held
in said town on the first Monday in January of every year for a
mayor, a constable and eight aldermen; the election shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducted
by the mayor and two aidermen, and the persons so elected
shall continue in office for one year or until their successors are
qualified. The mayor so elected shall be commissioned by the
chief justice of the county of Brazoria, and shall have all the powers
of an ordinary justice of the peace, in all matters and cases aris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
under the criminal laws of the country, and shall be authorised
and empowerd, to enforce and carry into effect such bye-laws and
ordinances as the corporation of said town shall from time to time
ordain, for the better regulation of the police thereof.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That no person shall be eligible
to any of said offices or to vote, who is not a citizen and a free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holder
or householder in said town.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the mayor shall be presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent
of the board of aidermen, that a majority of the members<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of
said board shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness,
and that said board may enact such bye-laws for the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
of said town, not inconsistent with the law of the land, as may
be deemd proper, and inflict such fines, not exceeding one hundred
dollars, as may be considered necessary.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the board of aldermen shall
have entire control over the streets of said town, may order new
streets to be laid out, and old ones discontinued at their discre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion:
Provided, however, that no new street be opened nor old one
discontinued, except by unanimous consent of the board; and the
board in such acts shall be governed by the law of the land, relative
to roads and highways.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That all free males between
the the ages of eighteen and forty five years, and all male slaves
over sixteen and under sixty years of age, shall be liable to
work on the streets; that such persons shall not be compelled to
work more than ten days in any one year, and they shall be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />empt
from other road duty. The board shall impose such fines<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(
1360 )</p><pb n="1361" xml:id="P1361" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1369/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
19
on defaulters as they may think necessary, in which they shall he
governed generally by the law of the land.
Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the board of aidermen shall
have power to levy a tax on all persons and property, both real
and personal in said town: Provided, however, that the tax on real
property, shall not in any one year exceed twelve per cent. ad va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lorem,
on such property, and no tax shall be levied on real estate
unless by consent of two thirds of the aidermen present, and it
shall be levied at the beginning of each year, and be assessed and
collected by an officer to be appointed by the board in the same
manner as the state tax is collected: and the board shall also have
power to levy a tax on all taverns, tippling houses, and billiard
tables in said town.
Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That all the public property in.
said town, shall belong to said corporation, and the board of aider<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men
may dispose of it in such manner as the best interest of said
town may require.
Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That the board of aidermen
shall have power to constitute and appoint such officers with the
regulation of their compensation as may be considered necessary,
and the officers so appointed may be removed at the pleasure of
the board, and may be required to give bond with security to the
mayor in such penalty as may be deemed requisite, and shall per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form
such duties as may be enjoined upon them, and shall be lia<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble
for such fines for neglect of duty as may be imposed on them.
Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That all offences against the
bye-laws be prosecuted before the mayor in a summary manner,
and execution may issue returnable forthwith, and the constable
shall execute all writs directed to him by the mayor.
Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That if the office of alderman of
said town shall become vacant by death, resignation or removal
from the town, the board shall have power to appoint a successor;
and should the office of mayor become vacant from either of the
above mentioned causes or otherwise, the chief justice of the
county of Brazoria be, and he is hereby authorised to issue forth<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />with
a writ for a new election to be held on a day mentioned in
said writ, and if the election required to be held on the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day
in January of every year, shall not be held on that day, it
may be holden at any time, by giving five days notice, and all
elections for mayor and aldermen shall commence at ten o’clock
A. M., and close at 2 P. M.
Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That the constable shall
86—vol. 1.
(1361 )</p><pb n="1362" xml:id="P1362" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1370/" /><p>20
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
give bond and security as other constables, shall be commissioned
in the same manner, shall have the same power, and be entitled
to the same fees as other constables.
Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That the board of aidermen
shall make such compensation to the mayor, and allow him such
fees as they may deem proper.
Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That all laws heretofore passed
relative to the town of Brazoria, shall be, and the same are hereby
repealed, so far as relates to the town of Brazoria, and this act
shall go. into effect from and after its passage: Provided, however,
that the mayor and aldermen, elected under the old charter which
is hereby repealed, be, and continue in office and exercise all the
powers granted by this act until the qualification of their succes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sors,
who may be elected at the first regular election under this
act.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVEEITT, .
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, Nov. 16, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT EESOLUTION
Requiring the auditor to audit the accounts of Nelson Jones.
Eesolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the auditor of pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic
accounts, is hereby authorised and required to audit the ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />counts
of Nelson Jones, for three hundred and sixty-four dollars.
And further, That the. said Nelson Jones, is entitled to twelve
hundred and eighty acres of land as a bounty, for services as a
soldier in this republic.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVEEITT,
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, Nov. 16, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1362 )</p><pb n="1363" xml:id="P1363" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1371/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
21
AN ACT
Appropriating money for the purchase of a house for the use of
the President.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the
sum of six thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated
for'the purchase of a house for the use of his excellency the
president of thst republic, and that the treasurer of this republic
is hereby required to pay six thousand dollars of the promissory
notes of the government to E. R. Lubbock, upon his executing a
title for his house, and the lot upon which it stands, on Main
street.
Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That the further sum of.
two thousand dollars is hereby appropriated for the purpose of
completing and furnishing the house in a suitable manner to make
it comfortable, to be drawn for from the treasury by drafts drawn
by the president’s private secretary in favor of the persons who
may finish or furnish his house.
Sec. 3. And be it further enacted, That so much of an act lo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cating
temporarily the seat of government, as appropriated fif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teen
thousand dollars for the erection of public buildings, be, and
the same is hereby repealed.
JOSEPH ROWE,
President of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Nov. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To incorporate the city of Richmond, and the towns of San Felipe
de Austin and Lagrange.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of represen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
the citizens of the city of Richmond, be and they are hereby
declared a body politic and corporate, by the name and style
of “the corporation of the city of Richmond,” and by that name
(1363 )</p><pb n="1364" xml:id="P1364" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1372/" /><p>22
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
may sue and be sued, implead and be impleaded, and may hold
and dispose of real, personal and mixed estate in said city.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That all that tract of country
known as the city of Richmond shall be known as the limits and
boundaries of said city.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the chief justice of the
county shall order an election to be held in said city, under the
superintendence of some justice of the peace, on the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day
of January next, for a mayor, a constable and eight aldermen:
and an election shall be held on the first Monday in January
of every year thereafter for the aforesaid officers, which election
shall be conducted by the mayor or two aidermen, and the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons
so elected shall continue in office for one year, or until their
successors are qualified; the mayor so elected shall be commissioned
by the chief justice of the county of Fort Bend, and shall have
all the powers of an ordinary justice of the peace in all matters
and cases arising under the criminal laws of the country, and shall
be authorized and empowered to enforce and carry into effect any
bye-laws and ordinances, the corporation from time to time shall
ordain for the better regulation of the police thereof.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That no person shall be eligible
to any of said offices or to vote, who. is not a citizen and free<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holder
or householder in said city.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the mayor shall be presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent
of the board of aidermen, that a majority of said board shall
constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, and that said
board may enact such bye-laws for the government of said city,
not inconsistent with the laws of the land, as may be deemed
proper, and inflict such fines not exceeding one hundred dollars,
as may be considered necessary.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the board of aidermen shall
have entire control over the streets of said city, and may order<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />new
ones to be laid off, and old ones to be discontinued at their
discretion: Provided however, that no new streets be opened on
old ones discontinued except by unanimous consent of the board,
and the board in such acts shall be governed by the laws of the
land relating to roads and highways.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That. the board of alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men
shall have power to levy a tax on all persons, property, real
and personal in said city; Provided, that the tax on real prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty
shall not in any one year exceed ten per cent, ad valorem
on such property, and no tax shall be levied on real estate, un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(
1364)</p><pb n="1365" xml:id="P1365" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1373/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
23
less by consent of two thirds of the aldermen present, and it shall
be levied at the beginning of each year, and be assessed and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected
by an officer appointed by the board, in the same manner
as the state tax is collected, and the board shall also have power
to levy a tax on all taverns, tippling houses and billiard tables in
said city.
Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That all the public property in
said city shall belong to said corporation, and the board of aider<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men
may dispose of it in such manner as the best interest of the
city may require.
Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That the board of aidermen shall
have power to constitute and appoint such officers with the regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lation
of their compensation as may be considered necessary, and
the officers so appointed may be removed at the pleasure of the
board, and may be required to give bond with security to the
mayor in such penalty, as may be deemed requisite, and shall per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form
such duties as may be enjoined upon them, and shall be lia<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble
to such fines for neglect of duty as may be imposed on them.
Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That all offences against the
bye-laws be prosecuted before the mayor in a summary manner,
and execution may issue returnable forthwith, and the constable
shall execute all writs directed to him by the mayor.
Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That if the office of aidermen
of said city shall become vacant by death, resignation or removal
from said city, the board shall have power to appoint a successor,
and should the office of mayor become vacant from either of the
above mentioned causes, or otherwise, the chief justice of the
county is hereby authorized to issue a writ for a new election, to
be held on a day mentioned in said writ, and if the election re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired
to be held on the first Monday in January of each year,
shall not be held on that day it may be held at any time, by giving
five days notice, and all elections for mayor or aldermen shall com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mence
at ten o’clock A. M. and close at two P. M.
Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, .That the constable shall give
bond and security as other constables, shall be commissioned in
the same manner, shall have the same vower, and shall have the
same fees as the other constables.
Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That the board of aidermen
shall make such compensation' to the mayor, and allow him such
fees as they may deem proper.
Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That the town of San Pe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1365
)</p><pb n="1366" xml:id="P1366" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1374/" /><p>24
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
lipe de Austin shall be organized in the same manner as the city
of Richmond, and be governed by the provisions of this act.
Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That the town of La Grange,
in the county of Red River, is hereby incorporated with all the
powers and privileges of the cities of Richmond and San Felipe
de Austin.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Nov. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of Ellen O’Donnovan.
Resolved, By the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That Ellen O’Donnovan,
be, and she is hereby authorized to take possession of a stock of
goods belonging to the estate of her decease husband, upon her
giving bond for the duties thereon, for the sum of two hundred
and fifty dollars.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Nov. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Fixing the Salary of Indian Commissioners.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas in congress assembled, That the sum of five
dollars per day be allowed to all Indian Commissioners, appoint<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed
by the president, according to law, while in actual service,
( 1366 )</p><pb n="1367" xml:id="P1367" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1375/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
25
going to, and returning from, any place to hold or attempt to hold
a treaty.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro. tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 1, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of Manuel Carabajal.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas in congress assembled, that the president of the
republic be, and he is hereby authorized to pay to Manuel Cara<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bajal,
a sum not exceeding twelve hundred dollars as a compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
for compiling the laws of Coahuila and Texas, upon his de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />livery
to the secretary of state a copy of the aforesaid laws,
and that the president be authorized to draw upon the secretary
of the treasury for such sum.
JOSEPH ROWE, •
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro. tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 1, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Amendatory to the several acts and ordinances granting Bounty
Lands.
Whereas, much difficulty exists in reconciling the various con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />flicting
laws granting bounty lands to the soldiers and officers who
have served in the army, and the allowance does not bear an equal
proportion in many cases to the services rendered, for remedy
whereof,
( 1367 )</p><pb n="1368" xml:id="P1368" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1376/" /><p>26
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the
laws in existence granting bounty lands to those who have served
in the army be so amended as to grant to all who have served
three months in the army, three hundred and twenty acres of land;
to all who have served for six months, six hundred and forty acres;
to all who have served for nine months, nine hundred and sixty
acres, and to all who have served twelve months or upwards, twelve
hundred and eighty acres.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That in all cases where war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rants
for bounty lands have been issued by the secretary of war,
for less amounts of land than that specified in the first section of
this act, it shall be his duty to issue warrants for the additional
quantities allowed by this act.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 4, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION,
Allowing the Secretary of War an additional Clerk.
Resolved by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the secretary of war,
be, and is hereby authorized to employ an additional clerk more
than he has now in his office for the term of six months, who shall
receive the same pay as the other assistant clerk of his office re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceives.

JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 4, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1368 )</p><pb n="1369" xml:id="P1369" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1377/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
27
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of John Buchanan.
Be it resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the sum of one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
and sixty dollars shall be, and the same is hereby required to
be paid out of any moneys in the treasury not otherwise appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated,
to John Buchanan, for his services as secretary rendered
the government, ad interim; and the auditor is hereby required to
allow the said claim, of the said John Buchanan, and give a draft
therefor, whenever the same may be presented for the amount men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned
in this resolution.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 9, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of John M. Clifton.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas in congress assembled, that the first auditor be
instructed to audit the accounts of J. M. Clifton, for fourteen hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
and thirty-four dollars, thirty-nine cents for his expenses in
enlisting and mustering into the service of Texas ninety-seven men
in the spring of eighteen hundred and thirty-seven.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 9, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1369 )</p><pb n="1370" xml:id="P1370" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1378/" /><p>28
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
For the relief of Edmund P. Crosby.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the auditor be and
he is hereby instructed to audit the amount of Edmund P. Crosby’s
account, say three hundred and fifty-one dollars and twenty-five
cents, in duplicate, (as the original certificate has been lost,) for ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices
in the navy, upon the said Crosby proving to the satisfaction
of the auditor, that the original has been lost, and that the account
is just.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIEABEAU B. LAMAE
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 9, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT EESOLUTION,
Making appropriations for the General Land Office, and to de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fray
the contingent expenses of both houses of congress.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That the sum
of five hundred dollars, be and the same is hereby appropriated for
the purpose of procuring stationery for the general land office, and
paying the contingent expenses of the same, and the treasurer is
hereby authorized and required to issue promissorv notes for that
amount to the commissioner of the general land office.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the sum of five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
dollars, be, and the same is hereby appropriated for the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chasing
of stationery for the use of both houses of congress, and
that the treasurer is hereby authorized and required to pay over
to the respective clerk and secretary the above sum, and that
the clerk and secretary be required to produce the vouchers
shewing what disposition they may have made of the above sum
(1370)</p><pb n="1371" xml:id="P1371" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1379/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
29
at the next' meeting of congress, and all individuals holding claims
coming within the pervue of this bill, present their accounts to
the committee on contingent expenses.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For .the relief of John Woodruff.
Resolved by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas in congress assembled, that the treasurer be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structed
to pay to John Woodruff, the sum of one hundred and
twenty-three dollars and twenty-six cents out of the promissory
notes.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To incorporate the Colorado Navigation Company.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That there
shall be established a company under the name and style of the
“Colorado Navigation Company,” with a capital stock of one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
and twenty-five thousand dollars, with the privilege of en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />larging
or increasing the same to two hundred and fifty thousand
dollars, to be divided into shares of one hundred dollars each,
for the purpose of clearing out a channel susceptible of navigation
by steam boats or other craft for the Colorado river.
(1371 )</p><pb n="1372" xml:id="P1372" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1380/" /><p>30
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That hooks shall be opened on
the first day of February next, to receive subscriptions for said
capitol stock at the following places, to wit:—At the town of Mata<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gorda,
at the house of E. Mercer, in Colorado- county, at the towns
of Columbus, La Grange and Mina, under the superintendance of
three commissioners at each place, to wit: at the town of Mata<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gorda
J. T. Belknap, A. L. Clements and S. Mussiana; house of E.
Mercer, Thomas Rabb, E. Mercer and William Heard; town of
Columbus, J. W. E. Wallace, Robert Brotherton and Stephen
Townsend; town of La Grange, J. H. Moore, N. W. Eastland and
Andrew Rabb; town of Mina, John G. McGehee, Richard Vaughn
and Russel Craft; and shall continue open twenty days, and the
said commissioners shall immediately thereafter transmit to the
commissioners at Matagorda an account of the subscriptions taken
at each place, and the said commissioners at Matagorda shall im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mediately
on the receipt of the subscriptions, take an account of
the whole subscriptions taken, and if more than one hundred and
twenty-five thousand dollars shall have been subscribed for, the
said commissioners shall deduct the amount of such excess from
the largest subscriptions, in such manner that no subscription shall
be reduced in amount whilst any remain larger, and in case of
such deductions the said commissioners shall cause lists of such
apportioned subscriptions to be made out, that the subscribers may
thereby ascertain the number of shares apportioned to them re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spectively,
and that in case a less amount than one hundred and
twenty-five thousand dollars, shall have been subscribed for, the
books may again be opened by and under the superintendence of
the commissioners at the town of Matagorda, should they deem it
advisable to do so, and be re-opened at such time and places as may
be determined upon by said commissioners.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That five per cent, of the capital
stock shall be paid at the times of subscribing, the balance to be
paid at such time as the directors may call for the same, by giving
at least thirty days notice in some one newspaper; provided, that
there shall not be an amount exceeding twenty-five dollars on a
share called for at any one time; and provided further, that in
case of failure of payment being made as aforesaid, the directors
shall have the right to forfeit to the use of said company the
amount paid on such stock.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the subscribers to said
company, their successors and assigns shall be, and are hereby
(1372 )</p><pb n="1373" xml:id="P1373" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1381/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
31
created a corporation under the name and style of “The Colorado
Navigation Company,” and under that name shall be capable to
contract, to buy, and receive all kinds of property, moveable and
immoveable that may be necessary for said corporation, and to
negotiate, grant, sell and dispose of the same, to borrow money on
the faith of this charter, and also to pledge such property real and
personal for the payment of the same, as in their opinion may best
conduce to the interest of said company. To sue and be sued, to
have a common seal and to establish such ordinances, rules and
regulations as they may think necessary and practicable for the use
and protection of the same, not contrary to the constitution
and laws of the republic of Texas; provided, however, that this
section shall not be so construed as to enable the company to hold
more land than may be necessary to carry into effect the objects of
this act; and provided further, that none of the funds of said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration
shall be used in purchasing lands, and all lands owned
by the corporation shall be sold within five years from and after
the passage of this act.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That for the management of said
company there shall be five directors annually elected, at the office
of said company at the town of Matagorda, by the qualified stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders
of the capital stock of said company, by a plurality of
votes then and there given: each share shall be entitled to one vote,
and votes allowed by proxy.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the
commissioners at the town of Matagorda, after one hundred and
twenty-five thousand dollars of stock shall have been subscribed
for, to advertise in some newspaper, that an election will take place
at the office of said company at the town of Matagorda for the
aforesaid directors, appointing the day for said election, which shall
not take place at a shorter period than thirty days from the date
of said advertisement.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the directors so elected shall
elect a president from their own body, and said president and direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors
shall serve as such until their successors shall be duly elected
and qualified.
Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the annual election for
directors after the first election, shall be held on the first
Monday in January in each year, and at their first meeting after
their election, they shall proceed to elect from their own body a
president, to hold his office for the same period as which the
directors were elected; provided, always that in case at any
(1373 )</p><pb n="1374" xml:id="P1374" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1382/" /><p>32
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
time it should so happen, that an election of directors or of presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent
of said company should not be so made, as to take effect in
the way required by this act, the said company shall not from that
cause be deemed to be dissolved, but it shall be lawful at any other
time to hold said election, and the manner of holding the same
shall be regulated by the rules and ordinances of this company, and
until said election be made the directors and president of the said
company for the time being shall continue in office; and provided,
also that in case of death, resignation, absence from the republic,
non-acceptance or removal, the vacancies shall be supplied by the
board of directors.
Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That no one shall be eligible to
the office of director,' who is not the bona fide owner of firm shares
of the capital stock’ of said company, and shall have held the same
at least one month previous to their election.
Sec. 10. And be it further enacted, That the corporation is
hereby invested with all the rights and powers necessary for the
accomplishment of the objects for which they are incorporated.
Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That said company shall com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mence
opening the channel of said river and improving the naviga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
thereof within nine months, and complete the same sufficient
for the passage of steam boats or other crafts, at least fifty miles
up the said river, from the town of Matagorda, within four years
from the passage of this act, and in case of non-compliance with
this section, this charter shall be deemed forfeited; provided, how<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever,
that if an invasion of the country prevents said company from
progressing with the work, that so much- time as may be lost by
reason of said invasion shall be added to the time specified in this
section for the commencement and completion of the same.
Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That after the said company
shall have finished said work as required in section eleven, that is,
rendered the Colorado river susceptible of navigation fifty miles
above the town of Matagorda, the company shall have the
power to levy, receive and collect such tolls upon all steam
boats or other craft, and upon all freight carried up or down said
river, as may be determined upon by said company; provided,
that no part of the capital of said company shall be em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployed
for any other purpose or project, except for the removal
of obstructions in the river and the navigation of the same,
and for an attempt at such project the charter shall be forfeited;
(1374)</p><pb n="1375" xml:id="P1375" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1383/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
33
and provided also, that the charges or tolls shall be upon terms
of equality to all persons who may wish to navigate the river.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved. Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Creating the county of Montgomery.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That all that
part of the county of Washington, lying east of the Brazos, and
southeast Navisota rivers, shall constitute and form a new county
to be known and designated by the name of Montgomery county.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said county of Mont<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gomery
shall be included in the third judicial district, and the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict
courts thereof shall be holden at the county seat of said coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty,
on the fourth Mondays of April and October in each and every
year, and the county courts for said county shall commence and be
holden on the second Mondays of February, May, August and No<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vember,
in each year.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That James Mitchell, Pleasant
Gray, William Robinson, Elijah Collard, Charles Garnett, Joseph
L. Bennet, B. B. Goodrich, D. D. Dunham, and Henry Fanthorpe,
be, and they are hereby appointed commissioners, with power and
authority (any five of them concurring) to select a proper place for
the seat of justice for said county, and to obtain by purchase upon
the faith and credit of the county, or receive by donation such
quantity of land as will be sufficient for the erection of public
buildings, and for defraying such other necessary expenses of said
county as said commissioners may deem expedient and that the land
so purchased or donated shall be under the superintendance and
control of the board of commissioners of said county.
Seg. 4. Be it further enacted, That the said county of
Montgomery, shall be entitled to one representative in congress,
(1375)</p><pb n="1376" xml:id="P1376" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1384/" /><p>34
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
and that the counties of Washington and Montgomery shall consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tute
a senatorial district.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the said county of Mont<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gomery
shall be organized in conformity with the several acts or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganizing
the district and inferior courts, and in case any suit or
suits are now pending in any of the courts of Washington county,
wherein the defendant or defendants were residing in that part of
Washington county lying east of the Brazos and Navasoto rivers,
at the commencement of said suit or suits, it shall be lawful on
application of the defendant or defendants in open court, for the
court of Washington county to grant a removal of said suit or suits
to the proper court of Montgomery county, and it shall be the duty
of the clerk to furnish either party a copy of the records in such
suit or suits.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the lower line of the county
of Montgomery shall commence at the mouth of Lake creek, thence
in a direct line to the head of Pond creek, and thence in a direct
line to the mouth of Beeson’s creek, thence up the Brazos river to
the mouth of the Navasoto river.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Regulating the time of holding District Courts of Brazoria, Mata<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gorda
and Jackson counties.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That the district
courts in and for the county of Brazoria, shall hereafter be allowed
to continue their regular sessions for the period of three weeks and
no longer.
Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That the district courts, in
and for the county of Matagorda, shall hereafter commence
on the third Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and
September, and continue in session one week and no longer, and
(1376 )</p><pb n="1377" xml:id="P1377" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1385/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
35
in the county of Jackson, on the fourth Mondays after the fourth
Mondays in March and September, and continue one week and no
longer.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of S. Hatch.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That it shall be the duty
of the auditor of public accounts to allow Sylvenus Hatch the
amount of five hundred and sixty-two dollars and fifty cents, for
iron furnished the army, which doth appear from a certificate of
the person that received the same, and countersigned by P. Cald<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />well,
quarter master, which was referred to the committee on
claims and accounts of the house of representatives, and by them
mislaid or lost.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate;.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To establish the county of Fayette.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
the territory embraced within the following boundaries, shall
87 —VOL. 1.
(1377 )</p><pb n="1378" xml:id="P1378" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1386/" /><p>36
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
constitute one of the counties of this republic, and be called the
county of Fayette: beginning at Grassmeyer’s ferry on the Colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rado,
thence in a north easterly direction at right angles with the
general course of the river Colorado, to the divide between the
waters of Colorado and the Brazos; thence down said divide, in a
southeasterly direction to the southwest corner of a league of land
granted to Wm. Burnett; thence southwestwardly crossing Colorado
river, where the upper line of a league of land granted to J. Duty,
corners upon the same; thence continuing the same course to the
Lavacca, at the upper corner of the league of land granted to Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liam
Ponton; thence up the Lavacca with the line between Austin
and Dewitt’s colony to the head of said stream; thence in a north<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />easterly
direction to the place of beginning, so as to leave Gras<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />meyer’s
in the county of Mina.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the seat of justice for said
county shall be, and is hereby established at the town of La Grange,
on the east side of the Colorado river, near the La Bahia crossing
of the same.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That immediately after the pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age
of this act there shall be a chief justice appointed for said coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty,
who shall proceed to organize the same, in accordance with the
laws, in such cases made and provided.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the county court for said
county shall be held on the third Mondays in February, May, Au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gust
and November; and the district courts shall be held on the
third Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September
in each year, and shall continue in session until all the business
before said courts shall be finished.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the county of Fayette be at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tached
to, and form a part of the third judicial district.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the county of Fayette be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled
to one representative, and be attached to the senatorial dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict
of Mina and Gonzales.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the returns of the election
for senator shall be made to the chief justice of the county of Mina,
who shall issue the corresponding certificate to the person elected.
JOSEPH BOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIBABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1378 )</p><pb n="1379" xml:id="P1379" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1387/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
37
AN ACT
Incorporating the city of San Antonio and other towns therein
named.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the citizens
of San Antonio in the county of Bexar, be, and they are hereby
declared a body politic and corporate, by the name and title of the
city of San Antonio, and by that name may sue and be sued, plead
and be impleaded, and may hold and dispose of real and personal
estate in said city.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the bounds and limits of
said city, and within which the said corporation shall exercise law<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful
jurisdiction, shall include and' comprehend all that tract of land
originally granted to and composing said city, with its precincts.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the qualified voters of said
city shall elect members to form a city council, consisting of one
mayor, or president, and eight aidermen, and also a treasurer and a
collector; the mayor and aldermen shall appoint one or more con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stables
as may be necessary, and shall regulate their salary or fees,
and also a clerk or secretary, who shall possess a competent knowl<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />edge
of the Castilian and English languages, and whose salary and
fees shall likewise be fixed by said council, shall give good and suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient
security to be approved by the chief justice of the county,
for the faithful discharge of their duties and of the trusts reposed
in them; the amount of their bonds if forfeited to be paid into the
city treasury.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the first election under this
act, shall take place on the first Monday in March, one thousand
eight hundred and thirty-eight, and every following year on the
first Monday in January, and public notice thereof, shall be given
at least eight days proceeding said election, in the first instance by
the chief justice of the county, or during his absence or indisposi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
by one of the associate justices, under whose direction the first
election shall be held, and ever afterwards under that of the mayor
and two aidermen, who with the remainder of the council, shall
exercise the functions of their office until their successors are duly
sworn in: each member of said council and all officers appointed by
it, shall take an oath of office in the accustomed form.
( 1379 )</p><pb n="1380" xml:id="P1380" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1388/" /><p>38
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That no person shall be a member
of said council nor be entitled to vote for any member thereof, who
is not either a householder or owner of real estate within the boun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />daries
of said corporation, and who has not resided therein at least
six months previous to an election, and paid up his city taxes.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the mayor as president with
a majority of the council, shall constitute a quorum for the transac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of business; they shall have power to enact and enforce such
ordinances and regulations as they may deem necessary for the bet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter
government of their city and its precincts; Provided, the same
shall not conflict with the constitution and laws of the republic;
they shall also form bye-laws to regulate their own proceedings,
and shall have entire control in all that relates to the police of the
city, such as paving and cleaning the streets, regulating the mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />kets,
removing nuisances, and' procuring for the city a supply of
wholesome water; for these and such like purposes they are au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorised
to levy equitable and. moderate taxes, on all fixed and
moveable property within their jurisdiction, and recover the
amount of the same by the most summary process: the poorest class
of citizens who may be exempt from direct taxation, shall be obliged
•to contribute by their manual labor towards all works of public
utility, the quantity of said labor to be equally apportioned and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived
in lieu of pecuniary contribution or vice versa. The council
is authorized to inflict moderate fines for infractions or disobedi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence
of its ordinances, and recover the same by summary proceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings;
Provided, that in all cases, either of unequal taxation, undue
demand for labor or excessive fines, the parties aggrieved shall have
the right to appeal to the county court.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the said council are also
authorized to grant licenses to persons retailing spirituous liquors,
to keepers of billiard tables and others; Provided, that no gaming
establishment, nor any other contrary to law shall be sanctioned or
covered by such licenses. .
Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the said council in conjunc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
with the justices of the county courts are hereby empowered
and authorised to sell and alienate such public lots or par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />.
eels of land as may lie within their jurisdiction, and to
which there is no legal claimant or title, and also to dispose of
such houses or other buildings as may have formerly been the
property of the corporation of said city, and the council may
sue for and recover all debts, forfeitures, &amp;c. accruing or due to
(1380 )</p><pb n="1381" xml:id="P1381" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1389/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
39
the said corporation, the proceeds of such sales to be appropriated
to the erection or repairs of a court house, jail and other such pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic
edifices as may be deemed most fit, and to the erection and en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dowment
of a public school.
Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That the mayor and aidermen of
said council shall be commissioned by the chief justice of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty
to act as justices of the peace, exercising the same powers and
entitled to the same fees as other magistrates of the same class.
Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the special duty
of said council to promote by every equitable means, the establish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
of a common schools, male and female within the limits of
the corporation in which the English language shall be taught, and
the children of the poor class of citizens invited and received gratis.
Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That the town of Victoria be,
and the same is hereby incorporated, and shall have the same power
and be governed by the same rules and regulations as are enacted
in the act of incorporation and government of the city of San An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tonio,
with the exception of having but five aldermen instead of
eight.
Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That the town of Gonzales be,
and the same is hereby incorporated, and shall have the same power
and be governed by the same rules, that are enacted for the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporation
and government of the city of San Antonio.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dee. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To create a board of Medical Censors for the republic of Texas.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
there shall be elected by joint vote of both houses of congress,
one physician of each and every senatorial district in this re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1381)
</p><pb n="1382" xml:id="P1382" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1390/" /><p>40
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
public, who shall be a resident citizen of the same at the time of
his election, which men when so elected shall form a board of medi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cal
censors for the republic, and may continue in office during good
behavour, whose duty it shall be to grant license to practice medi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cine
and surgery in this republic.
Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That the said board of medi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cal
censors shall meet annually at the seat of government on the
second Monday of November, then and there to transact the several
duties herein required of them, and the said board shall at their
first meeting, elect from their own body a president and a secretary,
who shall hold their office for a term of one year or until their suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessor
shall be duly qualified.
Sec. 3. And be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of
' said board of censors at their first meeting to adopt rules and regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations
for their government and to establish the method of taking
evidences of qualification, and granting licenses to applicants
therefor, to practice medicine and surgery any where in this re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
upon satisfactory evidence of qualification being produced
to the board in such manner as the said board may hereafter adopt:
giving due weight to usual credentials, reputation established by
experience, and the test of examination under the direction of said
board.
Sec. 4. And be it further enacted, That one third of said board
shall form a quorum to transact business, shall have power to fill
vacancies, and by a vote of two thirds of the members present may
expel a member.
Sec. 5. And be it further enacted, That all licenses to practice
medicine and surgery, or either, shall be signed by the president of
the board, and countersigned by the secretary thereof except the
temporary licenses: and for such licenses the applicant shall pay
the sum of twenty dollars, and any charge for medical services shall
not be recoverable in any court of law or equity in this republic,
after the first day of June next, unless the person rendering such
services were furnished at the time with a license in manner as
herein prescribed for and required.
Sec. 6. And be it further enacted, That to prevent delay and
inconvenience a single member of the board of 'medical cen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sors
may grant temporary licenses to applicants therefor, and
make report thereof to the next meeting of the said board for
confirmation, or further evidence of qualification to be given by
the applicant: Provided, that a temporary license shall not con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue
in force longer than one month after the next meeting of
(1382 )</p><pb n="1383" xml:id="P1383" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1391/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
41
the board, and that a temporary license shall in no instance be
granted by a censor after the applicant has been refused a license
by said board of censors, and the applicants shall not be charged
any pay for said temporary license.
Sec. 7. And be it further enacted, That no person shall be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed,
or hold a commission in the army or navy for any office
in the medical staff of the army of this republic any time after the
first of June next, unless he be furnished with a license to practice
medicine and surgery as herein provided.
Sec. 8. And be it further enacted, That said board shall enter '
on a book to be kept by them for that purpose the names of each
and every person they shall license to practice medicine or surgery,
and the time of granting the same, together with the names of the
board present, and shall publish the same in some newspaper at the
seat of government within thirty days thereafter.
Sec. 9. And be it further enacted, That all moneys which may
be paid for licenses to the said board of censors shall be the prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty
of the same, and may be used by them in any manner they
may think proper.
Sec. 10. And be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty
of the president of the republic, so soon as the board of medical
censors herein created shall be elected, to notify them thereof and
commission them, as well as such others as may be duly made
agreeably to the act, upon being notified thereof by the president
of said board of medical censors.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
To Compensate the Commissioners appointed to select a site for
the seat of Government.
Resolved by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas in congress assembled, That each of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners
appointed to receive propositions to locate the seat of
(1383 )</p><pb n="1384" xml:id="P1384" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1392/" /><p>42
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
government, examine sites &amp;c. &amp;c., be authorized to receive five
dollars per day while in employment in the discharge of that duty,
and that the certificate of the speaker of the house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
be a sufficient voucher for the same, and the auditor is hereby
required and instructed to audit and allow such claims on the
presentation of such certificate of the speaker of the house of rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives,
to be paid in civil list.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved; Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To define the boundaries of the county of Gonzales.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the boundaries of
the county of Gonzales be, and the same are hereby established in
-th manner following, viz: beginning on the west bank of the La<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bacca
river, at the lower corner of a tract of land deeded to Andrew
Kent, thence on a direct line to the crossing of the La Bahia road,
on the Guadaloupe river, thence continuing the same direction the
distance of fifteen miles from said river to a point for the south
west corner, thence on a direct line to the crossing of the road
leading from Gonzales to San Antonio, on the western branch of
the Sandies; thence continuing the same direction to the upper
San Antonio road, thence with said road to the north east corner
of Dewitt’s colony, thence with the line of said colony to the place
of beginning. <pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />JOSEHH
ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1384)</p><pb n="1385" xml:id="P1385" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1393/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
43
AN ACT
To provide for the punishment of Crimes and Misdemeanors com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted
by slaves and free persons of color.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That from and
after the passage of this act, the following shall be considered as
capital offences when committed by a slave or free person of color,
to wit: Insurrection or any attempt to excite it, poisoning Or at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tempting
to poison, committing a rape or attempting it on any
free white female, assaulting a free white person, with intent to
kill, or with a weapon likely to produce death, or maiming a free
white person, arson, murder, burglary, every and each of which
offences shall be triable in the district courts and upon conviction
shall be punished with death.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That it shall not be lawful for
any free person of color, to inveigle or entice away from their owner
or master, any slave or slaves, nor to aid or assist any slave or slaves
in leaving this republic, without the consent of the owner of such
slave or slaves: nor shall it be lawful for any free person of color
to conceal or render aid or assistance to any runaway slave, with
the intent to prevent the return of such runaway to his or her
owner, and upon conviction of any of the foregoing offenses be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore
the district courts, such free person of color shall be fined in
a sum equal to the value of such slave or slaves, and on failure to
pay the said fine shall be sold as a slave for life.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That all other crimes and mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demeanors,
known to the common law of England, committed by
slaves, shall be triable before the county courts, and on conviction
shall be punishable at the discretion of said court, so as not to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tend
to life or limb.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That upon complaint made upon
oath to any member of the county court,, of any offence not capital
having been committed by any slave, it shall be the duty of said
court forthwith to call a special term of said court for the trial of
such slave, and when any such special term may be called, it shall
be the duty of the county court in conjunction with the sheriff to
draw fifteen jurors, in the usual way to attend such term, and if
any of them should fail to attend, or from challenges the number
of twelve should not be had, it shall be made up from the by<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />standers.

(1385 )</p><pb n="1386" xml:id="P1386" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1394/" /><p>44
Laws of the liep-ublic of Texas.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That it shall not be necessary in
such cases, that a bill be found by a grand jury, but the party shall
be required to proceed to trial upon a charge made out and signed
by the person lodging the information setting forth the offence with
which such slave stands charged.
Sec. 6. Be it, further enacted, That if any slave or free person
of color shall use insulting or abusive language to, or threaten any
free white person, upon complaint thereof before any justice of
the peace, such justice shall cause such negro to be arrested, and
upon conviction, the slave or. free person of color, shall be pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ished
by stripes not exceeding one hundred nor less than twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five.

JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Concerning the public Archives.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That it shall
be the duty of every person or persons, who may have in his or
their possession or control any titles or documents whatever, which
relate to lands, and which by the laws now or hereafter existing
in Texas, have been and are considered “Archives,” to deliver the
same to the commissioner of the general land office, on his order,
within sixty days after the final passage of this act.
Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That any and all persons
comprehended within the meaning and provisions of the first sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of this act, who shall fail or refuse to comply with the duties
herein required, shall be taken and considered as guilty of a
high misdemeanor, and shall upon conviction thereof, before
the district court, be fined not less than one thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars,
nor more than five thousand dollars at the discretion of the
court, and in default of payment, shall be committed until said
(1386 )</p><pb n="1387" xml:id="P1387" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1395/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
45
fine is paid, and the person so offending in addition to the aforesaid
fine, shall forfeit all land he may own in this republic and be for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever
incapable of acquiring any, and shall neither vote nor be
eligible to any office civil or military under this government.
Sec. 3. And be it further enacted, That at the end of the sixty
days from and after the final passage of this act, or at any time
thereafter upon information being given, it shall be the duty of
the commissioner of the general land office to'notify the district
attorney of all those who may have offended against its provisions,
and it shall be the duty of the district attorney of the proper dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict
to commence and institute prosecutions against all persons so
offending in the premises, and they shall be held in close custody,
without bail or mainprize until the archives which may be in their
control or possession are delivered over to the proper officers, and
his receipt obtained therefor.
Sec. 4. And be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of
all grand jurors and civil officers of this republic to be aiding and
assisting in carrying into-effect the provisions of this act and to
give information of all violations of the same which may come to
the knowledge of any or either of them.
Sec. 5. And be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of
the secretary of state, forthwith after the final passage of this act,
to have it published in the Texas Telegraph and transmit copies
thereof to the chief justices of the several counties of this republic.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved. Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Authorizing the Treasurer of the Republic to issue Change Notes.
Sec. 1. Be it resolved, by the senate and house of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That
the treasurer of the republic is hereby authorized to issue change
(1387)</p><pb n="1388" xml:id="P1388" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1396/" /><p>46
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
notes of the several denominations of one, two, and three dollars
to an amount not exceeding ten thousand dollars, signed by his
chief clerk, redeemable by himself on presentation in the promis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sory
notes of the government, authorized by an act passed June 9,
1837.
Sec. 2. Be it further resolved. That the said treasurer shall be
required to reserve, in the treasury at all times, an amount of
promissory notes equal to the issue of said change notes, for the
redemption.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To clear out the rivers Attoyac, Angelina and Neches.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That for the
purpose of clearing out and improving the navigation of the rivers
Attoyac, Angelina and Neches, the county courts of the several
counties contiguous to and adjoining the said rivers, are hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized
and directed to appoint three commissioners from each of
said counties, whose duty it shall be to examine said streams, and
to make a minute of the expenses necessary to open the same, to
remove all the obstructions to the navigation thereof, and to report
the same to the county courts of their respective counties, as early
as may be practicable.
SEC. 2. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of each
of the said county courts on the receipt of the report of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners
to make an estimate and valuation of the lands border<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
on the said rivers, and that they be authorized to assess and
collect from the proprietors of such lands a tax not to exceed two
cents per acre, which tax shall be collected in the same manner, and
under the same penalties as are prescribed for the collection of the
general tax on lands.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the
several commissioners to be appointed by the county courts afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1388
)</p><pb n="1389" xml:id="P1389" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1397/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
47
said, to examine each of the said rivers, and report to the highest
point on the same, that it may be practicable to render them navi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gable
by steam boats of the smallest class, it being the intention of
this law to render the said water courses as extensively beneficial
as possible, and the county courts shall endeavor to remove the ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structions
to the navigation of said rivers as far as may be prac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticable.

Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That for the more certain com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pletion
of the work herein intended, it shall be the duty of the
county court to employ a sufficient number of competent men to
execute the same, and to appoint one supervisor for each county,
whose duty it shall be to superintend said work and the workmen
employed on the same, within their respective counties; and the
said supervisor shall be responsible to, and under the direction of
the said county court, and removeable by them at pleasure.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the
chief justice of each county to make a full report tri-annually to
the secretary of state, of the proceedings of the court under this
act, and of the progress made in the removal of the obstructions
to the navigation of the rivers aforesaid, and the said chief justice,
together with each of the associate justices, shall be responsible to
the executive for all, the moneys which may come into their hands,
from the assessment of taxes as herein before authorized.
JOSEPH EOWE,
President of the house of representatives.
MIEABEAU B. LAMAE,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN AOT
To prevent the issuing of individual Printed or Lithographed
Notes.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of of
the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That from and after
thirty days from the passage of this act, it shall be unlaw<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful
for any person or persons, to either issue or put in circulation
( 1389 )</p><pb n="1390" xml:id="P1390" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1398/" /><p>48
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
any printed or lithographed promissory notes of any denomination
whatever, or any other printed or lithographed note, bill or paper,
purporting to represent the value of money and intended for cir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />culation;
and any person violating the provisions of this act, shall
on conviction before any justice of the peace, or other court of this
republic, be fined in a sum not less than five dollars nor more than
fifty dollars for each offence, and it is hereby made the duty of all
grand juries of this republic to enquire into and present all persons
offending against the provisions of this act, and any person within
ten days after the passage of this act, who shall present in payment
of debt or for purchase of any property whatever any of the above
promissory notes, shall be on conviction fined not less than five dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars
nor more than fifty dollars.
JOSEPH ROWE, .
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON. .
AN ACT
To define the boundaries of the county of Shelby.
Seo. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the- republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
the following limits shall compose the boundaries of the county of
Shelby, from and after the passage of this act, viz: the line
beginning at the mouth of the Small Bayou which empties into
the Sabine river, just below the town of Hamilton, and running
up that Bayou to the crossing of the road leading from Hamil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton
to San Augustine, thence on that road to a point opposite
Buckley’s, thence on a direct line including Buckley’s house to
a house lately built by J. Rowe, thence on a direct line to a
point right on the road leading from J. M. Bradley’s to San Au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gustine,
one and a half miles distant from said Bradley’s,
thence on a direct line to Kerr’s ferry on the Attoyac river,
thence up that river to its source, or to the crossing of Tram<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mel’s
trail; but if the said trail should cross above the head waters
( 1390 )</p><pb n="1391" xml:id="P1391" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1399/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
49
of that river, then the said line shall run due west, from its head
waters to said trail; thence on that trail to the Sabine river, thence
up that river to the Cherokee crossing of the same, thence on the
road leading to Jonesborough to the Big Cypress Bayou, thence
down that bayou to Lake Sodo, thence east to the boundary line
between this Republic and the United States of the north, thence
along said line south to the Sabine river, thence down the said river
to the beginning point.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dee. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To define the boundaries of the county of Washington.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That all that
district of country within the following described boundary be,
and compose the county of Washington, (to wit:) beginning at the
mouth of Caney creek, on the west bank of the Brazos river; thence
up said creek to its most northwestern source; thence in a western
direction, to the south east corner of the league of land granted to
Harman Hensely on Mill creek; thence west on the ridge dividing
the waters of Cummings creek, of the Colorado, and the waters of
New Years and Yegua creeks of the Brazos; thence north along said
ridge with the eastern boundary of the counties of Fayette and
Mina to the old San Antonio road; thence east with said road to
the Navasoto river; thence down said river to its mouth; thence
down the river Brazos to the place of beginning.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1391 )</p><pb n="1392" xml:id="P1392" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1400/" /><p>50
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
To incorporate the town of Matagorda.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zens
of the towns of Matagorda, the City of Hamilton and the town
of Sabine, both on the Sabine river, be, and they are hereby incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porated
as bodies politic with the same powers and privileges as are
conferred upon the town of Brazoria, by an act passed at the extra
session of this congress.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Eor the purchase of the Steamer Pulaski.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the president be and
is hereby instructed to purchase and arm for the national defence
of this republic, the marine steamer Pulaski, and the necessary sum
for so doing is hereby appropriated out of any unappropriated
money in the treasury.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1392 )</p><pb n="1393" xml:id="P1393" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1401/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
51
AN ACT
To pay the officers and soldiers of the Army and Navy,
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That two hundred
and fifty thousand dollars, of the promissory notes authorized to
be issued by an act passed on 9th of June, 1837, are hereby ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pressly
appropriated for the payment of arrearages now due the
officers of the army and navy, and the soldiers and sailors of the
same.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That every person entitled to the
payment provided by thisact, shall, when he presents his drafts
to the treasurer, take an oath that said draft or drafts were
originally issued to him, and that since, he has not sold, alienated
or pledged the same to any person, and that he is now the bona
fide and sole owner of it or them. If there be any endorsement or
appearance of endorsement on any draft, the holder shall be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired
to produce satisfactory proof to the treasurer that the said
draft has never been sold or transferred.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That if the situation of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
should be such as to require a greater issue of the promis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sory
notes than the amount appropriated by an act passed the 9th
of June, 1837, that the president be, and he is hereby required to
have issued one hundred and fifty thousand dollars of the promis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sory
notes of the government, of the same character and no more:
and also that the treasurer, or his chief clerk, is hereby authorized
to administer the oath prescribed in the second section of this act.
And further provided, that the president be authorized to appoint
a proxy to sign his name to the above notes.
JOSEPH ROWE.
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON..
88—vol. i.
(1393)</p><pb n="1394" xml:id="P1394" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1402/" /><p>52
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
Supplementary to “an act to pay the officers soldiers and sailors
of the Army and Navy.”
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the benefits
of the above recited act is intended to be extended to all officers,
.soldiers and sailors who may now be, or have been heretofore en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gaged
in the defence of the country, either in the army or navy.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the benefits of this act shall
be extended to those who rendered actual, personal, and only for
personal services in the army and navy, and only that portion of
them who are the original holders of said claims.
JOSEPHROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To define the boundaries of the counties of San Augustine and
Sabine.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the
boundary line of the county of San Augustine, shall begin on the
Attoyac river, at the line of the county of Shelby, and run on that
line to the line of the county of Sabine; thence on that line
to the crossing of the road over the Pollygotch bayou, near
Mr. Sneeds; thence on a direct line to Mr. Pressnalls; thence south<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />west
to the road leading from San Augustine to Zavala; thence on
that.road to the line of the county of Jasper; thence on that line
to the Angelina river; thence up that river to the mouth of the
Attoyac; thence up the west bank of that river to the beginning
point.
(1394 )</p><pb n="1395" xml:id="P1395" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1403/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
53
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That all the territory lying west
of the Sabine river, south of Shelby, east'of San Augustine county,
and north of Jasper county, and not included in any other county,
shall constitute and compose the countv of Sabine.
• JOSEPH BOWE,
•Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Creating the county of Fannin.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That all the
territory included within the following limits to wit: Beginning
at the mouth of the Bois d’Arc creek, thence up said creek to the
crossing thereof, at the residence of Carter Cliffts; thence south to
a point thirty miles in a straight line from the place of beginning;
thence westwardly and northwardly to Red River, so as to include
all the territory within the aforesaid bounds, and east of the cross
timbers, thence clown Red river to the place of beginning, be and
the same is hereby created into a new county to be called the county
of Fannin.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said county shall be
organized, in conformity with the provisions of “an act creating
the county of Houston,” and that the first court of said county shall
be held at the residence of Jacob Black, on the last Monday in
January, 1838; and thereafter on the first Monday in March, June,
October and December, in each year, and shall remain in session
each term until the business before the said court shall be dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed
of.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That said county shall be and the
same is hereby included in the first judicial district, and the district
courts of said county shall be held on the second Mondays after
the first Mondays in March and September in each year.
( 1395 )</p><pb n="1396" xml:id="P1396" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1404/" /><p>54
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted. That it shall be the duty of the
county court of said county at the first term thereof to appoint
two commissioners from the lower, and two commissioners from
the upper end, and one commissioner from the centre of said coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty
whose duty it shall be to locate the permanent seat of justice for
said county; and said commissioners after being sworn, shall pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed
to locate the same as near the centre of said county, with a
view to future divisions and the constitutional size of the same,
as a sufficiency of water, timber, and other conveniences may be
found, who shall receive from the treasury of said county such
compensation as may be allowed them by the county court thereof;
whose duty it shall be, so soon as the seat of justice is located, to
remove all the public records of said county to said place, and hold
their courts at such place.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That said county of Fannin, and
the county of Red river shall constitute and compose one senatorial
district.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Locating permanently the seat of Justice for the county of
Brazoria.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled. That Brazoria in the county
of Brazoria be, and the same is hereby declared to be the perma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nent
seat of justice for said county.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
. Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1396 )</p><pb n="1397" xml:id="P1397" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1405/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
55
AN ACT
To define the boundaries of Jasper county.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas in congress assembled. That the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
boundaries shall be the permanent bounds of Jasper county;
beginning on the Sabine river, at the northeast corner of Jefferson
county; thence along the north' line of said- county to the Neches
river; thence up said river to old fort Terran, thence in a direct
line to the mouth of Big Bear creek; thence up said creek to Jones’
bridge; thence in a direct line from Bear creek in a direct line to
McKims; thence in a direct line to Bevil’s ferry, on the Sabine.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the chief justice of Jasper
county shall issue an order for an election, to be held on the last
Monday in January, 1838, to elect three commissioners for select<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
a proper site for the permanent seat of justice for said county;
and said commissioners immediately after being notified of their
election shall forthwith proceed to select such place as is in their
opinion the best calculated for a county seat of said county, and
report the same to the chief justice of said county.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That if the commissioners should
select a place on private property, then they shall buy or receive
it as a donation to the courts so much land as may be necessary for
a county seat, and divide it off into suitable sized lots for building
on, and sell the same on a credit of six and twelve months, the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser
giving bond and security until final payment, and the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds
to be paid into the county treasury for the use of said county.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1397)</p><pb n="1398" xml:id="P1398" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1406/" /><p>56
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
Creating the county of Robertson.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That all that sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of country lying and situated in the following boundaries be,
and the same is hereby set apart and constituted a new county, to
be known and called by the name of “Robertson,” viz: the line
beginning on the Brazos river, at the county line of the county of
Washington, and running on that line easterly to the Trinity river:
thence up that river to the northern edge of the Cross Timbers;
thence due west to the Brazos river; thence down that river to the
beginning point.
Sec. 2.. Be it further enacted, That the said county of Robert<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son
shall be organized in conformity with an act, entitled “an act,
to organize the inferior courts, and defining the powers and juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction
of the same;” and it shall be the duty of the chief justice
of the county of Robertson forthwith after his qualification, to give
at least ten days public notice in such places in the said county as
he may deem necessary, to hold an election for the seat of justice
for said county, in which election all persons qualified to vote for
members of the general congress, and residing within said county,
shall be entitled to a vote.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the said county of Robertson
shall be attached to the senatorial district of Milam, and be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled
to one representative in congress, and that the county courts
for the said county of Robertson, shall commence and be holden on
the third Mondays of February, May, August and November in
each and every year; and that the said county shall belong to the
third judicial district, and a district court shall commence and be
holden at the county seat of said county, on the Monday next suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding
the fourth Mondays of the months of April and October in
each and every year.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
. SAM. HOUSTON.
(1398 )</p><pb n="1399" xml:id="P1399" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1407/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
57
JOINT RESOLUTION
Requiring the auditor to audit the accounts of Geo. W. Bonnel.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas in congress assembled, That the auditor of public
accounts be, and he is hereby required to audit the accounts of
George W. Bonnet, amounting to eight hundred and seventy-five
dollars, for expenditures made by. him in recruiting and bringing
into the service of this republic a company of volunteers in the
year 1836.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To sustain the Currency of the Country.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That from and after the
passage of this act, nothing but gold and silver or promissory notes
of this government, shall be received in payment of duties on goods
imported into this republic, nor shall any bank notes be received in
payment of any dues to the government of Texas.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1399 )</p><pb n="1400" xml:id="P1400" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1408/" /><p>58
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
To prohibit the further sale of Land Scrip.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the
president be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue his
proclamation forthwith recalling our agent sent to the United
States for the Sale of land scrip, and forbidding the sale of any
more.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted,. That the said agent be required
forthwith to return to. the secretary of the treasury all the land
scrip in his possession, and should he fail or refuse to do so, four
months after the first day of January next, he shall be considered
guilty of a high misdemeanor, and on conviction before any court
shall be fined in a sum not less than five thousand dollars, nor more
than twenty thousand dollars, which fine shall go to the use of the
republic, and shall be liable and subject with his securities, to be
sued on his bond also.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That all sales of land scrip made
by said agents after receipt of the president’s proclamation shall be
null and void.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1831.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To require the district Judges to reside permanently in their proper
districts, and for other purposes.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
it shall be the duty of each district judge to reside permanent<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly
in his district, unless absent on official duties or by special
(1400 )</p><pb n="1401" xml:id="P1401" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1409/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
59
leave of the president, which special leave shall not extend beyond
two months in each year, and shall not interfere with the regular
terms of the court, and any judge for a violation of the provisions
of this section, and for absenting himself from any term of a court,
where, by law he is required to attend, shall be liable to be fined in
the sum of one thousand dollars, upon motion before the supreme
court, reasonable notice being given to the party of such motion,
and shall also be liable to an action for damages by any party ag<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grieved
by reason of such absence, or failure to attend the court.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of Anson Jones.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the first auditor be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired
to audit the accounts of Dr. Anson Jones, for the sum of
fourteen hundred and sixty-five dollars thirty-three and one-third
cents, for his sendees as apothecary general, from the 6th of Octo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber
1836, to the 10th May, 1837; also two hundred and ten dollars
expended by him for the rent of a store house from 1st July 1836,
to the 1st day of February, 1837.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved. Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1401)</p><pb n="1402" xml:id="P1402" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1410/" /><p>60
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of Charles Durocha.
Resolved, by the senate and .house or representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the auditor be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired
to audit an account of Charles Durocha, the sum of one
hundred and two dollars to be paid out of the funds to be appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated
for the payment of the civil list.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU. B. LAMAR,
President, of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
To select a Committee of five &amp;c. to locate the seat of Government.
Sec. 1. Resolved, By the senate and house of representatives of
the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That they will elect
a joint committee of five, two from the senate and three from the
house of representatives, to be elected by their different houses,
to whom shall be referred all propositions for the location of a
permanent seat of government, that the said committee be instruct<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed
forthwith after the adjournment of congress, to repair to that
section of country in which it is proposed to locate the seat of gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment,
and examine, and make plots of the different places pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed
as proper for the seat of government, and to visit and exam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ine
such other places as may be proposed for the seat of govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,
and prepare plots and descriptions of all such place with the
conditions on which they can.be had by the government, and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port
thereon on the first Monday of the next meeting of congress.
Sec. 2. And be it further resolved, That said committee,
shall receive the same pay as if in actual session of congress, for
the time they are serving on said committee, and they are here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1402)
</p><pb n="1403" xml:id="P1403" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1411/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
61
by instructed to make contracts on the most favorable terms they
can, subject in all cases to the ratification or rejection of congress.
Sec. 3. And be it further enacted, That the said committee shall
have power to make reservation of all vacant lands which may be
situated within nine miles of any point which the committee may
think proper to designate as suitable locations for the seat of gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment,
and due notice of said reservation shall be forthwith given
in at least three public newspapers, and no county surveyor shall
survey any land in the said reservation, until after said reservation
shall be relinquished by congress; Provided, that it shall not be law<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful
for said committee, to make such reservations in more than five
different places.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAE,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 14, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Precluding aliens from being appointed to office.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That from and after the
passage of this act, it shall not be lawful for the president or either
of the heads of departments to appoint any person to any civil
office, (consuls to foreign ports excepted,) unless such person shall
have residence at least six months in the republic, and is a citizen
of the same: nor shall any alien be appointed to any military office
in this republic, except in case of invasion, or the prosecution on
our part of offensive warfare against Mexico.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVEEITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
( 1403 )</p><pb n="1404" xml:id="P1404" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1412/" /><p>62
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
Entitled “an act to reduce into , one act, and to amend the several
acts relating to the establishment of a General Land Office.”
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That there
shall be, and is hereby established a General Land Office for the
Republic of Texas, to be located at the seat of government, or at
such place as may hereafter be designated by law, the chief officer
of which shall be called the Commissioner of the General Land
Office, which said officer shall be appointed by the president by
and with the advice and consent of the senate, shall enter into bond
with three or more securities, payable to the president or his suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors
in office, in the penalty of fifty thousand dollars, condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned
for the faithful performance of the duties of his office; said
bond and securities to be approved by the president and senate,
which bond shall be filed in the office of the secretary of state, and
shall hold his office for'the term of three years. Provided, the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions
of this section shall not affect the present incumbent of that
office, except so far as relates to his giving bond and security, and
holding his office for three years from the date of his appointment;
and the said commissioner of the general land office shall receive
a salary of three thousand dollars per annum, payable quarterly.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That the commissioner of the
general land office be, and he is hereby authorized to appoint a
chief clerk, which said clerk shall receive a salary of sixteen hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
dollars per annum, and two assistant clerks, who shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived,
as a salary, twelve hundred dollars each per annum, paya<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble
quarterly.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the said chief clerk
shall enter into bond with three or more - securities, to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved
by the commissioner of the general land office, in the
sum of twenty thousand dollars, payable to the president or his
successors in office, conditioned for the faithful performance of
the duties of his office, (which bond shall be deposited in the
office of the secretary of state,) who, in case of the absence of the
commissioner of the general land office, or his inability to at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1404)
</p><pb n="1405" xml:id="P1405" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1413/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
63
tend to the duties thereof, shall perform all the duties appertaining
to said office.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That all officers appointed, or to
be appointed, under the provisions of this act, shall, before entering
on the duties of their office, take and subscribe the following oath,
to wit: “I, A B, do solemnly swear, that I will faithfully discharge
the duties of my office, without favor or partiality, so help me God,”
which said oath shall be transmitted to, and filed in the office of the
secretary of state.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the commissioner of the
general land office shall cause to be provided a seal of office, which
seal shall not be changed except by law: and certified copies of any
records, books, or papers, belonging to said office, under the signa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture
of the said commissioner, or chief clerk with the seal of office
thereunto attached, shall be competent evidence in all cases where
the originals could be evidence.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the commissioner of the
general land office be entitled to, and shall keep charge of the seal;
and also that he be, and is hereby entitled to and shall have custody
and control of all books, records, papers, and original documents,
appertaining to the titles of lands, heretofore and by the provisions
of the law denominated archives; and that the said books, records,
papers, and original documents shall become and be deemed the
books and papers of said office.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That all patents issuing from the
land office, shall be in the name of the republic of Texas, and under
the seal of said office; shall be signed by the president of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public,
and countersigned by the commissioner of the general land
office, or by the chief clerk thereof.
Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That no person appointed to an
office instituted by this act, or employed in any such office, shall
directly or indirectly be concerned in the purchase of any right,
title, or interest in any public land, either in his own name, right
or interest for any other person, or in the name or right of any
other person, in trust for himself; nor shall take or receive any fee
or emolument for negotiating or transacting the business of said
office, other than those fees allowed by law. Any person offend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing

shall
in the premises
against the prohibition of this act,
on conviction thereof before the
district court, be
removed from office, and fined in any sum not less then five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
dollars, and shall forfeit all the land he owns in the repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1405
)</p><pb n="1406" xml:id="P1406" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1414/" /><p>64
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
lic, and never after be allowed to hold any office of trust or profit
in this republic.
Sec. 9. Be it further enacted. That there shall be elected by
joint vote of both houses of congress, for each county, a county
surveyor, who shall reside at the county seat, and whose duty it
shall be to receive and examine all field notes of surveys, which
have been or may hereafter be made in said county and upon which
patents are to be obtained, and shall certify the same under his
hand to the commissioner of the general land "office, after having
recorded the same in a book to be kept by him for that purpose;
and shall immediately return the same to the president of the
board of land commissioners of said county. He shall before en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tering
upon the duties of his office, enter into bond with three or
more securities, to be approved by the board of land commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers
of the county, in the sum of ten thousand dollars, payable to
the president or his successors in office, conditioned for the faith<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful
performance of his duties; which said bond shall be recorded in
the clerk’s office of said county, and the original transmitted to
the office of secretary of state; and the said surveyor shall hold his
office for three years, and be re-eligible. He shall be entitled to
charge on all field notes and plats presented to him for inspection,
for every set of field notes and plat of a league and labor of land,
five dollars; for one-third of a league, four dollars; and for every
less quantity, three dollars. His books shall be open at all times
for inspection, and he shall be allowed thirty-seven and a half cents
for every search. He shall appoint as many deputy surveyors
as he may deem necessary for the county; and shall administer to
them the oath of office, and take the bond hereinafter prescribed,
and shall furnish them such instructions as may be furnished to
him from time to time by the commissioner of the general land
office; and such deputy susveyor, before he enters upon the duties
of his office, shall enter into bond, with two or more securities, to
be approved by the county surveyor, in the sum of five thousand
dollars, payable to the president or his successors in office, condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned
for the faithful performance of the duties of his office; and
for such appointment of a deputy surveyor, the county surveyor
shall be allowed to charge and receive from the person so appointed,
the sum of five dollars.
Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of
each deputy surveyor, to administer an oath to each individual
employed by him as chain carrier or marker, for the faithful
performance of his duties as such, in accordance with the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1406.)
</p><pb n="1407" xml:id="P1407" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1415/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
65
structions given him: and no African, or Indian, or descendant of
either, or any person under the age of sixteen years, shall be em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployed
in either of the above capacities: and further, it shall be the
duty of said surveyors to subscribe the name of each of the chain
carriers to his field notes, previous to his returning the same to the
county surveyor. He shall also state, to the best of his knowledge
or belief, the number of labors of irrigable lands, the number of
labors of temporal or arable lands, and the number of labors of pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture
lands, in each survey, for that class of claimants who are enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tied
to land under the constitution and colonization laws, which
shall be plainly written out in the field notes, and also inserted in
each patent; and for all such surveys he shall charge and receive
three dollars for each English lineal mile actually run.
Seo. 11. . Be it further enacted, That there shall be elected by
joint vote of both houses of congress, a commissioner, who shall be
president of the board, and two associate commissioners, for each
and every county, who shall compose and constitute a board of
commissioners for their respective counties, to be styled a “Board
of Land Commissioners,” whose duty it shall be to investigate all
claims on this government for head rights to lands; and they are
hereby authorized and required to grant to any person or persons, a
certificate of their claim or claims, upon such proof being made to
them, by the party or parties claiming, as is herein required, setting
forth in said certificate the amount of land the claimant is entitled
to, upon what conditions, and the time when he, she, or they, emi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grated
to this country. The presidents of the boards of land com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners
shall be receivers of public monies, for their respective
counties, and shall enter into bond with good and sufficient secu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rity,
to be approved by the county court, or if there be no county
court, the board of land commissioners, in the sum twenty thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sans
dollars, payable to the president of the republic of Texas, or his
successors in office, and conditioned for the payment of all sums
which may be received by him, on account of the public lands, to
the secretary of the treasury for the use of the republic, which bond
shall be recorded by the clerk of the county court, and the original
transmitted to the- office of the secretary of state, and for all public
monies which he may receive and pay over, he shall be allowed to
charge and receive two per cent.
Seo. 12. Be it further enacted, That every person who
shall claim a title to land in this government by virtue of the
( 1407 )</p><pb n="1408" xml:id="P1408" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1416/" /><p>66
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
colonization laws, or by residence in the country at the declaration
of independence, shall be required to take and subscribe the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing
oath: “I do solemnly swear, that I was a resident citizen of
Texas at the date of the declaration of independence, that I did not
leave the country during the campaign of the spring of 1836, to.
avoid a participation in the struggle, that I did not refuse to par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticipate
in the war, and that I did not aid or assist the enemy, that
I have not previously received a title to. my quantum of land, and
that I conceive myself justly entitled, under the constitution and
laws, to the quantity of land for which I now apply.” They shall
also be required to prove, by two or more good and creditable wit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nesses,
as the commissioners may require, that they were actually
citizens of Texas at the date of the declaration of independence,
and have continued so to the present time; and they shall also be
required to prove, in like manner, whether they were married or
single at the time of the declaration of independence, and what
amount of land they were entitled to under the law. Provided,
widows and orphans shall not be required. to take the oath, herein
prescribed; and all persons claiming a grant to land of this govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
by inheritance or by purchase, shall prove, in the same man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner
as above stated in this act, widows, orphans, or their legal rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives
not excepted, that the person whose estate they claim
is entitled to a grant to land of this government, by the laws of
the country, or that the person of whom they purchased is actually
entitled to said grant to lands of this government; and no pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser
of a head right shall be entitled to receive a grant either as
assignee, or in the name of the original claimant, unless proof
be also made that the person represented as entitled to the grant,
is actually a resident of the republic at the time the application
for the grant is made; and all orders of surveys of head rights pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cured
under the colonization laws previous to the declaration of
independence, shall be submitted to the examination of the land
commissioners and the holders of the same, whether they be origi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nal
claimants, their heirs, or assignees, shall be subjected to the
same formalities and requisitions in procuring said head rights as
pointed out for other individuals in this law.
Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That any person claiming
the benefits of any particular colonization law of Coahuila and
Texas, during their existence, fixing the prices to be paid for
lands by the colonists, shall prove by at least two respectable
witnesses, that he, or she, was actually residents of Texas during
(1408 )</p><pb n="1409" xml:id="P1409" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1417/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
67
the time said law was in force, which proof so made before said
board of land commissioners, shall entitle the claimant to have his
or her land at the price fixed upon by said colonization law which
was in force at the date of said claimant’s emigration to this coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />try.

Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That there shall also be elected
for the several counties, a clerk, by joint vote of both houses of
congress, who shall keep, in a well bound book to be kept by him
for that purpose, a correct account of all the transactions of the
board of land commissioners, the name of every person to whom
a certificate shall be given, the amount of land granted to each
person, the time of their emigration to the country, and the name
or names of the witness or witnesses, by whom the claimants sever<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ally
proved their claims; and the said clerk shall, at the end of every
month, forward to the commissioner of the general land office, a
correct list of the names to whom certificates have been given, the
amount of land granted to each individual, and the date of the
claimant’s emigration to the country; and-the said commissioner
of the general land office shall keep a record of all such returns
which may be made to his office; and the said clerk shall, before
entering upon the duties of his office, give a bond with good se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curity,
to be approved of by the board of land commissioners, for
the sum of five thousand dollars, payable to the president or his
successors in office, conditioned for the faithful performance of
the duties of his office as clerk and register, and the safe keeping
of the records thereof.
Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That every certificate which may
be issued by the authority of this act, shall be signed by the board
of land commissioners, and attested by the clerk, and for every such
certificate so issued, the party claimants shall pay the sum of five
dollars, one half of which shall go to the clerk, and the other be
equally divided between the quorum of the board actually presid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing.
And it is hereby made the duty of said board, and they are
required to meet at the court houses of their respective counties on
every other Thursday, then and there to transact the duties required
of them by this act, and shall remain in session so long as may be
necessary for the transaction of the business before the board, for
which services they shall be entitled to demand and receive the fees
herein allowed, and no more. Provided, that after the land offices
shall have been open three months, the said board shall not be
required to meet only on the first Thursday of each month.
89—vol. i.
(1409 )</p><pb n="1410" xml:id="P1410" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1418/" /><p>68
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
and if that day should fall on a regular court week, so as to inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fere
with it, then they shall meet on the next Thursday thereafter.
And further provided, that a majority of said board shall form a
quorum to transact the duties herein required of them.
Sec. 16. Be it further enacted, That the decision of a majority
of said board of commissioners shall be necessary to entitle any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son
to a certificate of their claims, but if a majority of said board
should decide that any claimant who presents himself, or herself,
before them for a certificate of claims, is not entitled to the amount
of land which they claim, said claimant may take an appeal from
their decision to the next district court for the county in which
said claimant may live, citing the board' of commissioners to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pear
as defendants, where it shall be tried; and in all such cases
the district attorney shall represent the interest of the republic,
for which services he shall be allowed a tax fee of ten dollars on
every such case, to be paid by the appellant, together with all other
costs of suit, in case he or she fails to obtain a verdict in his or
her favor. But if the appellant should obtain a verdict for the
amount of land which he or she claims, the costs of suit shall be
paid by the republic, when the commissioners shall issue a certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate
in accordance with such decision.
Sec. 17. Be it further enacted, That any certificate of claim to
land, which has been or may be obtained in the manner and form
herein prescribed, shall be sufficient evidence to authorize any
lawful surveyor to survey for any person holding such certificates,
any lands which he may point out, agreeably to all the laws
which do now, or may hereafter exist on that subject. Provided,
also, that where more than one application is made for the
same tract of land to be surveyed, the settler or occupant shall
have the preference if their claims be otherwise equal.
Provided, that no location or improvement made since
the declaration of independence by persons who have since
that time arrived in the country, shall be regarded when they
come in conflict with the claims of those who were here at the
declaration of independence. But those individuals entitled to
the six months preference, shall have the right of locating their
lands upon any vacant lands of the republic, without regard to
any improvements made by individuals who have arrived in Texas
since the declaration of independence. In all other cases, or in
case there be more occupants than one, the conflicting claims
shall be summarily tried by the nearest justice of the peace and
(1410)</p><pb n="1411" xml:id="P1411" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1419/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
69
six disinterested jurors summoned for that purpose, and upon their
decision the surveyor shall grant to the successful party the field
notes of the tract of land, given in all cases the preference to the
oldest occupant and settler. Provided, in all cases, that the claim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ant
shall apply for such certificate in the county in which he, or
she may reside at the date of the passage of this act; and provided
that persons claiming land by inheritance or assignment shall apply
for such certificate in the county where the testator died, or where
the assignor lived at the time of making such transfer.
Sec. 18. Be it. further enacted, That when two or more per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons
cannot agree to a division line of any land, which has never
been surveyed agreeably to law, it shall be lawful for either party
to apply to any justice of the county or territory in which the land
lies, or if their be no justice of the peace in the county or territory,
then to the nearest justice in any county or territory, and make
oath that he has tried and has not been able to settle the dispute
between himself and one or more other persons, (naming them,)
concerning a division line, and the said justice shall issue a war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant
to any lawful officer to summons the party or parties defend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ant,
together with six disinterested jurors, to meet upon the prem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ises
in dispute, together with such witnesses as either party may
choose to have summoned, to give evidence on a certain day, nam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
at what time and place. The justice shall also meet the par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties,
examine all the testimony before the jury, who shall on oath,
hear and determine to case in dispute, and shall also determine who
shall pay the cost of suit.—Each juror in such case shall be allowed
two dollars per day for such services; the other officers, such fees
as have been already established by law for other similar services.
Provided, that if the land in dispute shall be on a county line, it
shall be lawful for a justice of either county in which part of the
land may be, to act in such case, and in case either party be dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />satisfied
with the decision, they shall have the right to appeal to
the district court within ten days, upon giving bond security for
the costs.
Sec. 19. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of
the surveyor in all cases, before he runs a division line between
two settlers claiming lands, to notify the party or parties inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ested,
before running the same, in writing. And any survey
which may be made contrary to the true intent and meaning of
this section of this act, shall not be a lawful one, and the
field notes of every survey which shall be returned to any land
(1411 )</p><pb n="1412" xml:id="P1412" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1420/" /><p>70
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
office hereafter for the purpose of getting a title for the same,
shall be under oath of the surveyor, who shall swear it was exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cuted
according to law, and shall also swear the same was made
prior to the closing of the land office by the consultation, or sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sequent
to the opening of the same by this act, and if made prior
to the closing of the land office by the consultation, the same shall
also be proven by at least two respectable witnesses.
Sec. 20. Be it further enacted, That the commissioner of the
general land office is hereby authorized to grant, to all persons
holding an order of survey legally obtained previous to the closing
of the land offices in one thousand eight hundred and thirty-five,
and having a survey which was made agreeably to said order, and
in conformity to law in all respects, a patent for the same, upon the
• holder presenting the certificate of some board of land commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners,
that he is entitled to the quantity of land surveyed, and
making such proof to them as is required by law, and upon his
paying the several fees as the laws require.
Sec. 21. Be it further enacted, That all lands surveyed for in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dividuals
lying on navigable water courses, shall front one half
of the square on the water course, and the line running at right
angles with the general course of the stream, if circumstances of
lines previously surveyed under the laws will permit, and all others
not on navigable water courses shall be square if previous lines will
permit; and under no circumstances shall any one grant be located
in more than two surveys.
Sec. 22. Be it further enacted, That each and every individual
under the age of seventeen, who have volunteered in the service
of their country, and who have received honorable discharges, shall
be entitled to the same quantity of land as a head right, that they
would be though they were twenty- one years of age, and upon the
same conditions.
Sec. 23. Be it further enacted, That all single men who were
in the republic at the date of the declaration of Independence, and
entitled under the constitution to one-third of a league of land,
and who have since married, or may marry within the next twelve
months, shall be entitled to the additional quantity of two-thirds
of a league and a labor of land. Provided, that the benefits of this
section shall only extend to those who have contributed to the sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port
and defence of their country: and provided, this additional
quantity shall not be allowed to any whose wife has received a
league of land of this government.
(1412)</p><pb n="1413" xml:id="P1413" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1421/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
71
Sec. 24. Be it further enacted, That whereas many persons
have received titles under the colonization laws as'colonists from
the different commissioners of the county, and whereas many con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditions
were by the law attached to said titles, that all such con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditions
be, and are hereby cancelled, and the titles to all such lands
are hereby ratified and confirmed. Provided, that such persons
shall pay, or cause to be paid, to the president of the board of land
commissioners of the county where such land may be situated,
within six months after the opening of the land office, all money
which may be due or owing on the same: provided, that the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dition
of remaining in the country, and the provision prohibiting
the sale to aliens, shall not be repealed by this law. And further
provided, that no title by this act shall be confirmed, which was
illegal or invalid ab initio. And further provided, that this act
shall not extend to any grantee or individual for a greater amount
of land than one league and one labor.
Sec. 25. Be it further enacted, That no person shall, by virtue
of an improvement, have a right to claim more than one league
and one labor of land, and that improvement shall consist in the
, clearing and fencing in a farm like manner, at least four acres;
and this privilege shall not extend to any person or persons who
have previously received a title to the quantum of land to which
they were entitled, nor to any person or persons entitled to a grant
of land by purchase.
Sec. 26. Be it further enacted, That it is hereby declared, that
all empresarios’ contracts having ceased on the day of the declara<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of Independence, all the vacant lands of Texas are the prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty
of this republic, and subject alone to the disposition of the
government of the same.
Sec. 27. Be it further enacted, That in order to settle the
claims of empresarios, each and every one of the same are hereby
authorized to institute a suit against the president of the repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic
of Texas, which suit or suits shall be tried in the county in
which is situated the seat of government, and shall be tried as
all other land suits are required to be tried. And should any empre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sario
who should thus sue, fail to establish the claim for which he
sues, he shall pay all the costs of said suit. Provided, that neither
aliens nor the assignees of aliens shall be entitled to the benefits
of this act.
Sec. 28. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty
of the attorney general to attend to all such suits, in behalf of
the republic of Texas, and the president is hereby authorized to
(1413)</p><pb n="1414" xml:id="P1414" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1422/" /><p>72
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
employ such additional counsel as in his opinion he may deem
proper; the expenses of which shall not exceed one thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars
in each case.
Sec. 29. Be it further enacted. That every volunteer who ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rived
in this republic after the 2nd day of March, 1836, and before
the 1st of August, 1836, and has received or may hereafter receive
an honorable discharge and has taken the oath prescribed by the
constitution, or who may have died, shall receive the quantity of
land by this act secured to original colonists.—Provided, that the
priority of location mentioned in the thirty-eighth section of this
act shall be adhered to; and further provided, that none but the
person who served, or his heirs, shall be entitled to the benefit of
this provision, and all augmentation shall accrue to the original
claimants, and not to the person to whom it may have been trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred;
provided, no person who is entitled to the benefit of the first
part of this section of this act, shall be entitled to the benefits of
the latter part of the same; every person who has arrived in this
republic since the declaration of Independence, and previous to
the 1st of October, 1837, who is a free white person and the head
of a family, and who actually resides within the government with
his family, shall be entitled to a conditioned grant of twelve hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
and eighty acres of land, by paying the fees of office and sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veying.
The conditions of said grant shall be that both grantee
and his or her family shall remain and reside within this republic,
and do and perform all the duties required of otherlike citizens,
for the term of three years; after which time, he or she shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive
an unconditional deed for said land; and in no case whatever
shall a grant of that description be made unless it be satisfactorily
proven that all the conditions and provisions of the law have been
complied with. And all single free white men who have emigrated
to this republic since the declaration of Independence, and pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vious
to the 1st of October, 1837, shall be entitled to six hundred
and forty acres of land, and if they married before the 1st day of
October, 1837, they shall be entitled to an additional quantity of
six hundred and forty acres of land upon the same conditions as
above named, and all laws contrary to the meaning and provisions
of this section are hereby repealed.
Sec. 30. Be it further enacted, That all officers and soldiers
who engaged in the services of Texas previous to the 1st
of March, 1837, whose families are now here or may arrive
within twelve months from the date of their discharges, shall be
entitled to the same quantity of land as they would have been
(1414 )</p><pb n="1415" xml:id="P1415" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1423/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
73
entitled to, if their families had emigrated with them to the
country.
Sec. 31. Be it further enacted, That the board of land commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners
are hereby authorized to grant to persons claiming lands
of this government under the 29th section of this act, a certificate
of their claims, upon the same proof being made to them as is
required of other claimants, stating in said certificate, the amount
of land to which the claimant is by lave entitled; at what time he
or she arrived in this republic.
Sec. 32. Be it further enacted, That the commissioner of the
general land office, shall when required by the president of the
republic or either house of congress make a plat of any land sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyed
under the authority of the government, and give such in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formation
respecting the public lands and concerning the business
of his office, as shall be legally required.
Sec. 33. Be it further enacted, That the commissioner of the
general land office shall be, and he is hereby authorized to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point
a translator, who shall undergo an examination as to his
qualifications, and shall understand the Castillian and English
languages, and shall before he enters upon the duties of his office,
take and subscribe the oath of office herein prescribed, shall give
bond with two or more good and sufficient securities in the sum of
ten thousand dollars, to be approved of by the secretary of state,
and shall be payable to the president or his successors in office,
conditioned for the faithful performance of his duties, and said
translator shall hold his office for the term of three years and shall
be allowed a salary of two thousand dollars per annum payable
quarterly.
Sec. 34. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of
said translator, to translate into the English language, and record
in a book to be kept by him for that purpose, all the laws and pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic
contracts relative to the titles of land which are written in the
Castillian language, and also to translate and record in like man- .
ner, all original titles which are written in the Castillian language,
which may be on file in the office of the commissioner- of the gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral
land office.
Sec. 35. Be it further enacted, That should a vacancy
occur during the recess of congress, by death, resignation or
otherwise, of any member of either of the boards of land com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />misioners,
or of the clerk of either of the boards, or of
any county surveyor, it shall be the duty of the board of land
commissioners, to notify such vacancy to the commissioner of the
general land office, forthwith, and to recommend some person
(1415)</p><pb n="1416" xml:id="P1416" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1424/" /><p>74
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
suitably qualified to fill such vacancy, whereupon it shall be the
duty of the commissioner of the general land office to fill said
vacancy by an appointment, and report the same to the congress
immediately on its next session, which officer shall continue to per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form
the duties of the office, to which he is appointed, agreeably
to the provisions of this act, until his successor is duly qualified.
Sec. 36. Be it further enacted, That so soon as the certified
copy of the field notes and plot of any survey shall be made and
transmitted to the president of the board of land commissioners
for the county where the land or a part of it lies, and the amount
of money which is fixed by law as the price of such land, be paid,
the president of the board of land commissioners shall endorse a
receipt for such payment on the back of said field notes for which
he shall give duplicate receipts and transmit the field notes to the
commissioner of the general land office, who shall forthwith make
out in due form a patent for said land, and record the same in a
book to be kept for that purpose, and transmit the original to the
president of the board of land commissioners, for the county where
the land lies, who shall enter a minute of -the said patent on his
books and deliver the same to the party who is entitled to it, or
some one authorized by him to receive the same, taking a receipt
therefor; and the said patentees in all cases shall pay as government
fees the prices fixed by the colonization laws of Coahuila and Texas
in force at the time they emigrated' to this country. And if they
emigrated subsequently to the 2nd day of May, 1835, and previous
to the declaration of Independence, they shall be required to pay
the amount fixed by a law passed by the congress, of the state of
Coahuila and Texas on the above date.
Sec. 37. Be it further enacted, That the president of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
be, and he is hereby authorized to contract for the survey<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing,
and cause to be surveyed, at the , expense of this government
a sufficient quantity of land to satisfy the holders of all land scrip
that may have been issued and sold by this government, agreeably
to the law in all respects. And the secretary of the treasury is
hereby authorized to pay out of any money in the treasury not
otherwise appropriated, the expenses which may accrue in com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleting
such surveys: provided, it shall not exceed three dollars for
each English lineal mile actually run.
Sec. 38. Be it further enacted, That where two or more
locations have heretofore been made on, and titles granted for
(1416)</p><pb n="1417" xml:id="P1417" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1425/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
75
the same piece of land, or where the boundaries of different titled
surveys conflict with each other, the party who has his title or
order of survey of subsequent date, may on proper showing of all
the facts, and the certificate of a legal surveyor to the board of
land commissioners of the county in which the land lies, have his
former title cancelled by said board and a new order issued for his
quantum of land or so much thereof as shall be affected by the
conflicting lines or boundaries mentioned in this section.
Sec. 39. Be it further enacted, That the several land offices
contemplated and established by this act, shall commence and go
into operation on the first Thursday in February next.—Provided,
however, that the operations of the land office in the county of
Red River, shall not extend to any portion of the territory near
the supposed boundary line between this and the United States
government of the north, and provided, also, that should any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son
obtain a certificate for land from said board of land commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners
for the county of Red River, who at the date of the ’passage
of this act shall reside east of the boundary line hereafter to be run
between Texas and the United States, said certificate shall be void,
and their operations shall be confined to the granting and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleting
of land titles to all those who by the existing and previous
laws have acquired a preference in the first location. Of this class
are all citizens who were residing in Texas on the day of the decla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration
of Independence, and those volunteer soldiers who served
a tour of duty in the army of Texas previous to that time. For
this class of claimants the land office shall be opened and remain
six months in operation, granting and completing titles alone to
that class of claimants. After which other legal claimants shall be
entitled to have their land titles completed as herein provided and
directed. And the several boards of land commissioners shall be
permitted and allowed to commence receiving applications for
lands, and hearing testimony on the first Thursday of January
next, and in case the country shall be invaded to an extent inducing
the president to call out at least one-third of the militia for its de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fence,
the commissioner of the general land office shall have power
to close the land offices by proclamation, until such invasion has
terminated, and all laws heretofore enacted on the subject of pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic
lands shall be, and they are hereby repealed.
Sec. 40. Be it further enacted, That each county in the
republic shall be considered and constitute a section, and that
each county surveyor be required, as soon as practicable, to
(1417 )</p><pb n="1418" xml:id="P1418" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1426/" /><p>76
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
make out or procure a map of each county, on which plats of all
the deeded lands in the said county shall be made, so as to make
a fair showing of the same, for which he shall receive compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
by special appropriation hereafter to be made for that pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose.

Sec. 41. Be it further enacted, That audited claims against
the republic of Texas, shall be receivable in payment of public
dues on lands: provided, the benefits of this section shall not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tend
to any one individual for a larger quantity of land than two
leagues and two labors; and any one offering to pay for lands in au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dited
paper on the government, shall swear that he has not paid for
as much as two leagues and two labors in such paper before, either
by himself or his agent, which affidavit shall be filed with the chair<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man
of the board of land commissioners.
Sec. 42. Be it further enacted, That all streams of the average
width of thirty feet shall be considered navigable streams within
the meaning of this act, so far up as they retain that average width,
and that they shall not be crossed by the lines of a survey.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Vetoed by the president, and passed the house of representatives,
by a constitutional majoritv. Dec. 14, 1837..
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
Vetoed by the president, and passed the senate by a unanimous
vote. Dec. 14, 1837.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
AN ACT
To incorporate the Texas Steam Mill Company.
Sec. 1. . Be it enacted, by the senate and house of represen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
E. H. Burritt, Jabez Cornwall, Ezekiel Andrews jr., H. H.
Douglass, Nathaniel H. Andrews, Samuel M. Hart, Nelson Hart,
(1418 )</p><pb n="1419" xml:id="P1419" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1427/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
77
and Edwin Belden, together with their successors and assigns, he
and are hereby constituted a body politic and corporate under the
name and style of “The Texas Steam Mill Company,” with power
to sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded, answered and be an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />swered
unto, appear and prosecute to final judgment in any court
or elsewhere, to have a common seal, and the .same to alter at
pleasure, to elect in such manner as they shall determine, all neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary
officers and to fix their compensations, and define their duties,
to ordain and establish bye-laws for the government and regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of their affairs, and the same to alter and repeal: and to em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ploy
all such agents, mechanics and other laborers as they shall
think proper.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the object of the said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany
shall be to operate by steam power or otherwise in Texas
a saw mill, a grist mill, a planeing mill, a lathe and shingle mill,
and any machinery necessary in carrying on such other manufac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turing
or mechanical business as they shall determine to prosecute:
also to prepare materials and erect public and private buildings,
stores and offices upon contract.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the capital stock of said
company shall be thirty thousand dollars, actually paid in with the
privilege of increasing the same to fifty thousand dollars: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided,
however, that no additional stock shall be created during the
first year of the company’s operations.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That said company under their
corporate name shall have power to purchase, take, hold, occupy
and enjoy to them and their successors, all such lands, tenements
and hereditaments, and all such goods, chattels, and effects of every
kind as shall be necessary for the purposes of said company.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the stock, property, affairs
and business of this company, shall be under the care of, and shall
be managed by not less than three directors, who shall be chosen
annually by the stockholders, at such times and place as shall be
provided by the bye-laws of said company, and who shall be stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders,
and shall hold their offices for one year, and until others
shall be chosen in their stead.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the directors of this
company shall choose one of their numbers to, be president,
they shall also choose a secretary and treasurer of said company,
and such other officers as the bye-laws of the company shall pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe.
They may call in future subscriptions to the capital
stock of said company by instalments, in such proportions and
(1419 )</p><pb n="1420" xml:id="P1420" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1428/" /><p>78
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
at such times and places as they may think proper, by giving such
notice thereof as the bye-laws of said company shall prescribe,
and in case any stockholder shall neglect or refuse payment of any
such instalments for the space of sixty days after the same shall
become due and payable, and after he, she or they shall have been
notified thereof, the stock of such negligent stock holder, shall by
the directors be sold at public auction, giving at least thirty days
notice, thereof in some newspaper, and the proceeds of such sale
shall be first applied, in payment of the instalment called for, and
the expenses attending it, and the balance shall be refunded to
the owner thereof, and such sale shall in all respects entitle the
purchaser to all the rights of a stockholder to the extent of the ,
shares so bought.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That a majority of the directors
of this company, convened according to their bye-laws shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute
a quorum for the transaction of business, and a majority of
' the stockholders present at any legal meeting, and at all meetings
of such stockholders, each share shall entitle the holder thereof
to one vote.
■ Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the directors of the said
company shall have power to fill any vacancy which may happen in
their board, by death, resignation or otherwise for the then cur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rent
year.
Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That the books containing the
accounts of said company shall at all reasonable times be open for
the inspection of any of the stockholders, and as often as once
in each year a statement of the accounts of said company shall be
made by order of the directors.
Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That the stock of this company
shall be deemed and considered personal property, and be trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred
only on the books of said company, in such form as the
. directors of said company shall prescribe, and said company shall
at all times have a lien upon all the stock or property of the mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers
of said company invested therein, for all debts due from them
to said company.
Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That this act of incorporation
shall be, and continue in force for the term of ten years from and
after its passage.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 16, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1420 )</p><pb n="1421" xml:id="P1421" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1429/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
79
AN ACT
Supplementary to an act to appoint a Board of Medical Censors.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled. That no person shall be
eligible to election as medical censor, unless he be a regular gradu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate
of medicine and surgery, and have a diploma from some.college
or university duly authorized to grant the same: and should any
person be elected contrary to the intent and meaning of .this act,
such election shall be considered null and void.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 16, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To Incorporate the town of Mina.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of of
the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the citizens of
the town of Mina be, and they are hereby incorporated and formed
into a body politic and corporate, under the name and style of
the corporation of the town of Mina, and shall have the same
privileges, and be subject to the same regulations and restrictions
as are conferred and imposed upon the citizens of San Antonio,
by an act passed the present session of congress, entitled an act to
incorporate the city of San Antonio.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1421)</p><pb n="1422" xml:id="P1422" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1430/" /><p>80
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
To amend the act, entitled an act to raise a Revenue by impost
duties.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That from and
after the passage of this act, the following articles may be imported
into this republic free of duty, to wit: Sugar, Coffee, Tea, Salt,
Flour and all kinds of bread stuffs, pickled Pork, Bacon Iron and
steel, household furniture, cotton bagging, bale rope, books and
stationery, machinery of all kinds, wagons, carts and harness, with
necessary farming utensils, and lime and lumber, and implements
brought in by emigrants for their own use.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That from and after the passage
of this act all dry goods manufactured of cotton, or of which cotton
forms a component part, a duty of ten per cent, ad valorem shall
be levied and collected: all other goods shall be subject to, and pay
the duties laid down in the law passed 12th June. A. D., 1837.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To incorporate the Brazoria Insurance Company.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of' the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
the citizens Robert Mills, Edmund Andrews, David Mills, Jas.
E. Perry, Henry Austin, Charles D. Sayre, Samuel Puller, J.
G. McNiel, Samuel B. Brigham, and their present and future
associates, successors and assigns, be, and they are hereby incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porated
and created a body politic and corporate, by the name
and style of “The Brazoria Insurance Company,” and by the
( 1422 )</p><pb n="1423" xml:id="P1423" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1431/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
81
same name and style, they and their successors shall he capable of
suing and being sued, and maintaining any action to final judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
and execution,- and shall be in law capable of purchasing,
holding, improving and conveying any estate, real personal or
mixed for the use of said corporation, and the said corporation shall
have power to ordain, establish and put in execution such bye-laws,
ordinances and regulations as shall be necessary for the government
thereof, and it shall be lawful for said corporation after the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />piration
of the charter thereof, to use the corporate name, style
and capacity for the purpose of suits, for the final settlement and
liquidation of the affairs and accounts of the corporation, and for
the sale and disposition of their estate real, personal or mixed, but
not for any other purpose, or in any other manner whatsoever, nor
for a period exceeding three years after the expiration of the said
term of incorporation, provided nevertheless that the foregoing
section shall not be construed to authorize the said corporation
to purchase or hold any real estate that may not be requisite and
necessary to the conducting the legitimate business of an insurance
company.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the capital stock of said
corporation shall be two hundred thousand dollars, divided into
two thousand shares of one hundred dollars each, and the same
shall be created and paid in such manner and at such times as the
president and directors of said corporation shall require, of which
requisitions the president and directors shall give at least one
months notice in the Telegraph or other public newspaper, if
any there be in Texas, and cause the same to be notified to the
stockholders, and if any stockholder shall after due notice, neglect
or refuse to pay any instalment so required to be paid, he or she
shall cease to' be a member of said corporation, and the share or
shares so forfeited, may be sold by the corporation in- such manner
as they may think proper.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That for the well ordering
of the affairs, of the said corporation there. shall be nine direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors,
who shall be stockholders of the corporation; they shall be
elected by the stockholders at their annual meeting to be held
on the first Monday of January of each year for that purpose,
and the directors at their first meeting shall choose one of their
own number as president; provided, nevertheless, that until the
first annual election the persons named in the first section of
this act, shall have and may exercise all the powers given to the
president and directors by this act, and in all elections for direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors
the vote shall be by ballot, and each stockholder shall have
( 1423 )</p><pb n="1424" xml:id="P1424" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1432/" /><p>82
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
one vote, for each share he may hold, but no stockholder shall
vote at any election unless the share or shares upon which he may
claim to vote shall have been standing in his or her name on the
books of the said corporation for at least three months previous
to such election. In case of absence from any general meeting,
any stockholder may be entitled to vote by proxy.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the directors of said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration
for the time being, three of whom shall form a quorum,
shall have power to appoint such officers, clerks, agents and other
persons as shall be necessary for the conducting and executing the
business of the said corporation, and to allow said persons so ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed
such compensation for their services respectively as they
shall deem reasonable, and generally to exercise, all other author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity
and powers for the well ordering and governing the affairs and
funds of the said corporation.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That it shall be lawful for the
said corporation to employ the funds thereof in establishing and
sustaining the business of marine and fire insurance, to insure
against loss or damages by sea, fire, enemies, and all other risks of
loss or damage to which vessels and merchandize, are liable, ves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sels,
merchandize, treasure and freight; insure vessels in port, build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings,
merchandize and all other perishable property on land,
against loss or damage by fire, and to charge, collect and receive for
the same such premiums of insurance as the president and direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors
of said corporation may deem just, reasonable and commensu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate
with the risk. It shall be lawful for said corporation to lend
at a rate of interest not exceeding ten per centum per annum, any
surplus capital which they at any time possess, which may not be
required for the payment of losses ascertained to have occurred,
to purchase and sell bills of exchange, to lend money in bottomry
and respondentia security at marine interest, and to. do all those
things which an individual citizen may do in conformity with the
law. But it shall not be lawful for said corporation to issue and
put in circulation any promissory notes of the character of bank
bills, or to exercise banking privileges.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the shares of the said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration
shall be assignable and transferable according to such
rules and regulations as the president and directors thereof shall
for that purpose ordain and establish.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the president and di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors
of said corporation shall annually or semi-annually di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vide
to the stockholders thereof, so much of the profits of the
( 1424)</p><pb n="1425" xml:id="P1425" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1433/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
83
business of the said corporation as in their discretion they shall
deem safe and proper, and of the amounts so declared to be di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided
as the profits of the said corporation they shall reserve for
the use of the county of Brazoria, to be applied to the improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
of the entrance of the mouth of the river Brazos, one per
centum thereon, which shall be paid over to the treasurer of the
county of Brazoria.
Seo. 8. Be it further enacted, That the office of the company
incorporated by this act, shall be located in the town of Brazoria,
and so soon as the president and directors thereof shall establish
by evidence to the satisfaction of the justices of the county court
for the county of Brazoria, that ten per centum. of the capital of
said corporation has been paid by the stockholders to the actuary
or secretary thereof, and that the balance or residue of the capital
of two hundred thousand dollars has been secured to be paid when
called for in conformity with the provisions contained in section
second of this act, to the satisfaction of the president and directors...
thereof, and that the direction of said corporation has been organ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized
in conformity with the provisions of section third of this act,
the aforesaid justices shall give to them a certificate thereof, which
shall be their warrant to commence business operations under the
authority vested by this act.
Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That in case the increase of navi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation
and commerce to from, and of the river Brazos shall at any
time in opinion of the president and directors of the said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
require the employment of a greater capital than two hundred
thousand dollars, then and in that case, it shall be lawful for the
said president and directors, by and with the consent of a majority
of the stockholders of the said corporation to increase the capital
thereof, in such manner as they may deem expedient, to
such amount as they may deem requisite, not exceeding the
sum of five thousand dollars, on their paying into the treasury
of the county of Brazoria a bonus of five thousand dollars, which
bonus of five thousand dollars, shall together with all sums which
may accrue from the one percentum on the dividends of profits of
said company, appropriated by article seventh of this act, to that
object, be expended under the direction of a commissioner or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tractor,
to be appointed by the president and directors of said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration,
by and with the consent of the justices of the county
court for the county of Brazoria, in facilitating the entrance of the
mouth of the river Brazos by vessels, and in removing obstructions
therefrom.
90—vol. i.
( 1425)</p><pb n="1426" xml:id="P1426" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1434/" /><p>84
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That the charter granted by
this act shall continue in full force and effect for the full term
of thirty years, from and after the passage of this act, irrevocable,
but for account of misdemeanor, malfeasance or breach of law.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To define the boundaries of the county of Liberty.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the
territory included in the following limits shall constitute and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose
the county of Liberty: Beginning on the Gulf of Mexico at the
southwestern corner of the county of Jefferson, thence north along
the western boundary line of said county to the Big Sandy creek,
(thence down said creek with said county line, to its entrance into
the Neches river,) thence up said river to the southeastern corner
of the county of Houston, thence south of west along the southern
boundary line of said county to the Trinity river, thence across the
river in the same direction to a point nine miles distant, thence in
a direct line to the head of Cedar Bayou, thence down said Bayou
to its entrance into the Gulf of Mexico, thence along said Gulf with
all its meanderings, including the Trinity Bay to the place of be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ginning.

JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1426 )</p><pb n="1427" xml:id="P1427" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1435/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
85
AN ACT
Supplementary to an act entitled an act to organize the Militia of
this Republic.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That the mil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tia
of this republic constitute one division, to be commanded by a
major general, elected by joint vote of both houses of congress.
He shall in time of peace have three aids-de-camp, with the
rank of major of cavalry, either of whom when on duty shall have
the emoluments of the correspanding rank in the regular army.
Seg. 2. Be it further enacted, That the militia of Texas shall
be divided into four brigades, each to be commanded by a brigadier
general, to be elected in the same manner as the major general;
and when a vacancy shall hereafter occur, he shall be elected by
the officers of his brigade. All that portion of the country west
of the Brazos river shall constitute one brigade; all between the
Brazos and Trinity rivers shall constitute one brigade: all between
Trinity and Sabine rivers shall constitute one brigade; and all
north of, the Sabine and of Red river one brigade.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That each brigadier general shall
be entitled to one aid-de-camp with the rank of captain of cavalry,
whose pay and emoluments shall be that of corresponding rank
in the regular army, when he is in actual service.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That all adjutants created under
this law, shall have the same pay and emoluments, when in actual
service, as officers of corresponding rank in the regular army of
the republic, and shall be liable to like penalties of misdemeanors
or unofficerlike conduct.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the adjutant general shall
be elected by joint vote of both houses of congress, shall have the
rank and pay of colonel of cavalry, shall keep his office at the seat
of government, shall hold his office for two years, and be re-eligible,
by appointment of major general, subject to confirmation by con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress.

Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That so soon as the militia shall
have been organized in the respective regiments, it shall be the
duty of the colonel thereof, by his adjutant, to visit the respec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive
company beats, and cause, by lots, the privates of said beats
(1427 )</p><pb n="1428" xml:id="P1428" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1436/" /><p>86
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
to be enrolled in class number one, two and three, which classes
shall be liable, in the order in which they stand, to be called into
actual service by the president, to serve for any period of time not
less than three months, nor longer than six; each class when called
into actual service to be commanded respectively by the captain
and first and second lieutenants; and no class shall serve twice
until all the others shall have been called out.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the
captain and his officers, at each county muster, and in the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence
of his company, to cause the names of the newly enrolled
members thereof to be drawn, by lot, into the respective classes;
which drawing and public registering shall be as binding as if done
by the adjutant under the provisions of the sixth section of this
act.
Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That all laws or parts of laws,
conflicting with the provisions of this supplement, and now in
force, are hereby repealed.
Vetoed by the president, and passed the house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives,
by a constitutional majority. Dec. 18, 1837.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
Vetoed by the president, and passed the senate, by a unanimous
vote. Dec. 14, 1837.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
AN ACT
To encourage Steam Navigation.
Whereas, it is conceived that the best interests of the country
may be advanced by the encouragement of the navigation of the
Gulf of Mexico by steam packets, and as the tonage duties which
are now established by law, are calculated to impede the advance<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
of this desirable object, inasmuch as the emigrant is com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pelled
to pay a very high price for passage, thereby preventing
many from visiting the country who would otherwise feel inclined
to do so, therefore,
(1428)</p><pb n="1429" xml:id="P1429" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1437/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
87
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic, of Texas, in congress assembled, That each
and every steam packet which may arrive from any foreign port
at any port in Texas, be and they are hereby exempted from the
payment of any tonage duties; Provided, such packet shall be
bound at each trip to transport when required government stores
or other public property free of any charge therefor, and provided
further, that at no one trip shall they be required to transport more
than two hundred barrels in bulk, and provided that the benefits
of this act shall extend to no steam packet or vessel which shall
not be entered upon her first trip to this country as a regular packet
between the ports of Texas and some foreign port or ports.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That this act shall continue in
force until repealed.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To amend the several laws regulating the Post Office Department.
See. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That section
the ninth, of an act “creating a General Post Office, &amp;e.,” passed
December the twentieth, eighteen hundred and thirty-six, be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealed
from and after the passage of this act.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, by the authority aforesaid, That
the following rates of postage shall be charged on all letters and
packets, except such as are herein exempted, conveyed by the
mails and posts of Texas, namely: For every letter composing
a single sheet of paper, and conveyed any distance not exceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
forty miles, twelve and a half cents; over forty and not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding
one hundred miles, twenty-five cents; over one hundred
miles and not exceeding one hundred and fifty miles, thirty-sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />en
and a half cents; over one hundred and fifty miles, fifty
(1429 )</p><pb n="1430" xml:id="P1430" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1438/" /><p>88
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
cents: upon all ship letters, six and a quarter cents shall be charged
in addition to the above rates; and for every package composed of
four or more pieces of paper or thing, and weighing one ounce,
quadruple those rates, and in that proportion for all greater
weights: newspapers, carried not over one hundred miles, one cent
each; over one hundred miles, two cents: pamphlets, carried not
over one hundred miles, per sheet one and a half cents; over one
hundred miles, two and a half cents. All letters, newspapers, and
pamphlets, going out of Texas, it shall be the duty of the post
master to require the postage in advance.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That it shall be lawful for the
post master general to impose such fines and forfeitures upon the
mail contractors for all failures they make in not regularly and
faithfully complying with the terms of their contract, as in his
opinion may be just and proper. Provided, that no fine for a fail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ure
in delivering any mail shall exceed the pay of one trip.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of every
ferryman, or keeper of a ferry on any water course, to pass over
free of charge the driver or carrier of the mail and any horse or
carriage carrying the same.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the sum of twenty thousand
dollars is hereby appropriated for the purpose of facilitating the
transportation of the mails, to be paid out of any money not other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise
appropriated. ■
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Relating to the pay and allowances of the officers and soldiers of
the Army.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
from and after the passage of this act, no officer attached to the
army shall be entitled to pay or allowance who is not in actual
(1430 )</p><pb n="1431" xml:id="P1431" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1439/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
89
command, in camp or garrison, under the orders of the secretary of
war.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That from and after the passage
of this act, no non-commissioned officer or private shall be entitled
to any pay or allowance, unless in actual service in camp or garri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son.
'
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION,
Requiring the Auditor to settle with Mr. Thomas Brennan.
Resolved by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas in congress assembled, That the auditor be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired
to audit and settle with Mr. Thomas Brennan, purser of the
schooner Independence, the claims of the officers and crew of that
vessel.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To define the boundaries of the county of Red River.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That
after the passage of this act Red River county shall be bounded
as follows, viz: Beginning at the mouth of the Bois d’Arc, run<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ning
up that stream to Carter Cliffs, crossing thence south to a
(1431)</p><pb n="1432" xml:id="P1432" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1440/" /><p>90
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
point west of the head of Bid Cypress, east to its head, and down
that to Sodo Lake, thence east to the line of the United States,
with that line to Bed Eiver, up that to the beginning.
Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That the first courts of said
county shall be held at La Grange on the second Monday in Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary,
one thousand eight hundred and thirty-eight, at which time
and place the chief justices of said county, shall appoint two com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners
from the upper end, two commissioners from the lower
end, and one commissioner from the centre of said county, whose
duty it shall be after being duly sworn, to locate the temporary
seat of justice for said county, and make report thereof to said
chief justice within fifteen days after they shall have been so ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed,
and it shall be the duty of said chief justice to hold an
election for all the officers of said county in conformity with the
laws in such cases made and provided.
. JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVEEITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Altering the name of the county and town of Mina.
Eesolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas in congress assembled, That the name of the county
and town of Mina be changed and altered to that of Bastrop, and
shall be after the passage of this resolution known and called the
county of Bastrop, and town of Bastrop.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVEEITT,
President pro tern, of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1432 )</p><pb n="1433" xml:id="P1433" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1441/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
91
JOINT RESOLUTION
Relative to Consulates.
Be it resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the consular sys<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tem
of the United States of America, be, and is hereby adopted for
the government of the consular agents of this republic, so far as
its provisions may be suitable to the condition of Texas.
Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That it shall be the duty of the
secretary of state from time to time to furnish said consuls with
such instruction as may become necessary, for the proper regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of the commercial intercourse between this and foreign coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tries.

Sec. 3. Be it further resolved, That no consul of this republic
shall be allowed to charge any fees- for passports or certificates of
characters or intentions.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To define the boundaries of the county of Mina.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of
the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That all the
territory included in the following boundary shall com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose
the county of Mina, to wit: Beginning at the north east
corner of the proposed new county of Fayette, thence west
with said county line, passing its north west corner to Austin’s
colony line, thence with the same to the corner of Milam’s Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ony,
thence north to its north west corner, thence east to the
Colorado, crossing the same and running the same direction, to
the dividing ridge between the Brazos and Colorado- rivers, to
(1433 )</p><pb n="1434" xml:id="P1434" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1442/" /><p>92
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
the line between Austin’s little colony, and Robertson’s colony,
thence south with said line to the place of beginning: the same
shall be, and is hereby declared the boundaries of said county.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of M. A. Beremendi.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas in congress assembled, That Marcus A. Bere<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mendi,
a native of Texas, a minor, of about twenty years of age,
be, and he is hereby authorized and empowered with the consent
of his guardian to take possession of his patrimonial estate, and
his acts in all respects shall be as legal and valid as though he were
of lawful age; Provided, that the passage of this resolution shall not
operate to make or cause a confirmation of his titles.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro- tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To provide for the publication of the Laws and Journals of the
republic of Texas.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
there be and is hereby appropriated the sum of six thousand
(1434 )</p><pb n="1435" xml:id="P1435" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1443/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
93
dollars of the promissory notes of this government to be expended
in procuring the publication of the laws and congressional jour<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nals
of the republic of Texas.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the secretary of state be and
he is hereby required to contract immediately for the printing in
pamphlet form two thousand'copies of the acts and five hundred
copies of the journals of the first and second congress that have
not yet been printed and published for public distribution; and it
shall be his duty so soon as the said laws and journals shall be
printed to transmit by mail a copy of said laws and journals to each
of the chief justices, members of congress, magistrates, clerks, sher<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iffs,
coroners and constables of the several counties of this republic.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the secretary of state shall
require the contractors to give security for the faithful perform<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance
of their contracts and that the second auditor, be, and he is
hereby required to audit any drafts of the secretary of state for
the purposes contemplated by this act; Provided, the whole amount
shall not exceed six thousand dollars.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That all other laws authorizing
the printing of the acts and journals of congress, be, and the same
is hereby repealed.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dee. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Making provisions for persons who have been permanently disabled
in the service of Texas.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
Thomas William Ward, James C. Neill, James Belden, John
Thoms, Washington Somers, and all others who have been per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manently
disabled by loss of eye, arm or limb, or such other bod<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ily
injury as by certificate of the board of land commissioners,
( 1435 )</p><pb n="1436" xml:id="P1436" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1444/" /><p>94
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
shews his incapacity for bodily labor, by wounds received in the
service of Texas, be, and they are hereby declared to be entitled to
one league of land each, as a testimony of the gratitude of this
republic.
Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That the lands hereby granted
shall be included within that class of claimants to whom six months
preference has been given.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Tor the relief of Dugald Brown.
Resolved by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the auditor be, and
he is hereby directed to audit the claims of Dugald Brown, for the
sum of seven hundred and seventy dollars.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Amending the Judiciary Laws of the Republic.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That
in all cases of appeal to the supreme court the trial shall be, on
the facts as agreed in or certified by the judge of the court be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />low,
and if the facts should not be stated in a manner sufficient<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(
1436 )</p><pb n="1437" xml:id="P1437" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1445/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
95
ly full and clear to enable the supreme court to give its judgment,
then and in that case the said court shall remand the said cause
to the proper court in order that the facts may be fully and clear<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly
established and set forth, and in all cases of appeal, either from
the county court to the district courts, or from the district courts
to the supreme court, the party appealing shall have the right to
file the bonds required with the clerk of the court, to be approved
by said clerk at any time within six days after the close of the
terms. Provided, notice of the appeal be filed in court during the
continuance of the terms.—See sec. 9, sup. ct. act., and sec. 15
dis. ct. act.)
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That in addition to the powers
given to the district courts by the act establishing the powers and
jurisdiction thereof, approved December twenty-second, one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand
eight hundred and thirty-six, the said district courts shall
have power to hear and determine all suits or actions arising be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween
husband and wife for divorce or for a separate maintenance,
and may decree divorces as well from the bonds of matrimony as
from bed and board, or for a separate maintenance.—See 4th dist.
ct.)
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That a new trial shall be granted
in any case known to the laws of this republic for good cause shown;
but no more than one new trial shall be granted to either party in
the same cause.—(See sec. 19, diet. ct. act.)
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That no amendment shall be per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted
in any pleading or other proceedings in any cause after issue
joined, except upon such conditions as the court shall in its dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cretion
determine.—(See sec. 20, dis. ct. act.)
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That at the first session of any dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict
court, and ever afterwards the grand and petit jurors shall be
drawn in open court.—(See sec. 31, dist. ct. act.)
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the forty-sixth section of the
act establishing the powers and jurisdiction of the district courts
be, and the same is hereby repealed.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That nothing contained in the
several acts establishing courts of justice, shall be so construed as
to take away the right of either party, to an action to propose in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terrogations,
to his adversary, to be answered on oath according
to the laws heretofore existing.—(See sec. 41, act established 9th
July last.)
Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the proviso in the twen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty-second
section of the act punishing crimes and misdemean<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1437)
</p><pb n="1438" xml:id="P1438" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1446/" /><p>96
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
ors, approved December 21st, 1836, be, and the same is hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealed.

Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That in all criminal trials where
the party accused shall not be convicted, or being convicted, shall
not be able to pay the costs of prosecution the said costs shall be
paid by the republic, and the certificates of the judges to a bill of
such costs, shall be a sufficient voucher for the auditor to audit and
allow the same; the provisions of this section, shall extend to all
such cases as have heretofore occurred.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro- tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To provide for taking Testimony by Interrogatories.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives
of. the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That in all cases
either in the district or county courts where a witness resides with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out
the county where such suit may. be pending, it shall and may be
lawful for either party to file his or her interrogatories for such wit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness
in the clerk’s office where the suit may be pending, and serve
the opposite, or his or her counsel of record with a true copy of
such interrogatories, together with a notice, that application will be
made to the clerk of said court for a commission to examine such
witness, and it shall and may be lawful for the opposite party, or
his or her attorney to file cross interrogatories to such witness.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That at the expiration of
five days from the service of such notice, with a copy of said in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terrogatories
it shall be the duty of the clerk to issue a commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion
directed to two or more persons, directing them to cause
the witness to come before them, and the answers to said inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rogatories
and cross interrogatories shall be plainly and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinctly
written, sworn to and subscribed by the witness and also
subscribed by the commissioners, who shall envelope the same,
( 1438 )</p><pb n="1439" xml:id="P1439" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1447/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
97
directed to the clerk of the court from whence they issued, and
the said commissioners shall seal the said packet and write their
names as commissioners across the seals, which said packet may be
sent by mail or by private hand; if sent by mail the postmaster
shall endorse on the back thereof: Received from A. B., one of the
commissioners, and if sent by ’hand the party delivering them into
court, or to the clerk in vacation, shall make affidavit that he re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived
the said packet from one of the commissioners, that the same
has been in his possession ever since and has underwent no altera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
which package shall not be opened unless by leave of the
court.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That interrogatories thus taken
and returned to the court, shall be read in evidence in all civil
cases, and shall be as legal as if the witness was personally present
and examined in open court, any law to the contrary notwithstand<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing.

Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the provisions of this act
shall extend to justices courts, and all other tribunals established
by law.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That in all cases it shall be lawful
to take the testimony of females in civil cases, in the same manner
as herein prescribed, whether they be residents in the county or
not.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To authorize the Post Master General to establish a Post Route.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas in congress assembled, That the post master gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral
of this republic, be and he is hereby authorized and required,
as soon as practicable to establish, a mail route from Nacog<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />doches,
by way the of Epperson’s Perry, on the Sulphur fork,
to the seat of justice in Red River county, Jonesborough,
( 1439 )</p><pb n="1440" xml:id="P1440" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1448/" /><p>98
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
to the seat of justice in Fannin county, and that the mail carriers
along said route be required to perform one trip in two weeks, and
that the post master be authorized to establish such post offices on
said route, as he may deem necessary and proper.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION,
For the relief of Maria Antonio de La Garza.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the first auditor is
hereby authorized to audit the claim of Maria Antonio de La Garza,
for cattle, as per certificates of Sylvanus Hatch, John J. Linn, and
general T. J. Rusk, for sixty head of cattle,'at ten dollars per head,
six hundred dollars in military scrip.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of James Collinsworth.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in Congress assembled, That the treasurer
be, and is hereby authorized to pay to James Collinsworth three
thousand dollars, or so much as may remain due him, of that
(1440 )</p><pb n="1441" xml:id="P1441" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1449/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
99
amount, being for his services as commissioner to the United States,
that being the salary established by a law of the consultation passed
at San Felipe on the 8th Dec. A. D. 1835.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
President pro tem. of the senate.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of C. C. Dewitt.
Be it resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the auditor is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by
authorized to audit the claims of Christopher C. Dewitt, for ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices
rendered by him in the fall campaign, as per documents re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred
to the committee on claims and accounts, being for eighty
seven dollars.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President'of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
To translate the laws of the republic into the Castilian Language.
Be it resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That in justice to that
numerous portion of our fellow citizens who understand only the
Spanish language, and who are consequently wholly ignorant of
the most important laws to which their obedience is required,
91—VOL. 1.
(1441 )</p><pb n="1442" xml:id="P1442" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1450/" /><p>100
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
the secretary of state shall be authorized to contract with some per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son
properly qualified for the translation and compilation of such
general and penal enactments as have been made by the former
and present congress, that a sufficient number of copies of the same
shall be printed and distributed in those counties where the popu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lation
alluded to may reside, and that in future all general enact<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments
shall as soon as practicable be translated into Castilian, and
transmitted to the chief justices and justices of the peace of said
caunties, who shall give all due publicity to said laws; provided, the
expense shall not exceed three hundred dollars annually.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of Widow Kitty McCoy.
Be it resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled. That the first auditor
is authorized to audit the claim of widow Kitty McCoy as per vouch<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers
of Byrd Lockhart and colonel William H. Patterson for beef
and corn, valued at three hundred and seventy-eight dollars in
military scrip.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
. S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1442 )</p><pb n="1443" xml:id="P1443" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1451/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
101
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of colonel John Forbes.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas in congress assembled, That the first auditor is
hereby authorized to audit the claim of colonel John Forbes, as per
pay certificate of George W. Poe, paymaster, and approved by the
honorable secretary of war, for two thousand and sixty eight dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars
and fifty-two cents in military scrip.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Authorizing F. R. Lubbock to procure cisterns for the use of the
Capitol.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That F. R. Lubbock is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by
authorized to contract for and cause to be erected at the state
house in the town of Houston, a sufficient quantity of cisterns to
contain ten thousand gallons of water, and the secretary of the treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ury
is authorized to pay to said Lubbock in promissory notes of
the government an amount necessary for that purpose, provided
such amount shall not exceed five hundred dollars.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1443 )</p><pb n="1444" xml:id="P1444" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1452/" /><p>102
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
JOINT EESOLUTION
For the relief of Francis W. Thornton.
Be it resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas in congress assembled, That the first auditor be,
and he is hereby authorized and required to audit the claims of
Francis W. Thornton, to the amount of two hundred and three dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars,
and give him military scrip for the same.
JOSEPH EOWE, .
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAE,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To authorize attachments to be issued in certain cases therein
named.
Whereas many Mexicans residing upon our frontier stole and
drove off large herds of cattle, and took and carried off other prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty
belonging to citizens of this republic, and whereas those Mexi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cans
have abandoned the country, and removed beyond the Eio
Grande, so that persons from whom they have taken property are
wholly without remedy:
Sec. 1. Be it therefore enacted, by the senate and house of
representatives of the republic of Texas in congress assembled,
That in all cases it shall be lawful for any person, from whom prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty
was wrongfully taken, to sue out an attachment upon filing an
affidavit, stating to the best of his or her belief the value of such
property, and that to the best of his or .her belief the same was
taken by the person against whom such attachment is prayed, and
that the said party resides out of the jurisdiction of the court, so
that an action cannot be prosecuted against them; which said at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tachment
may be levied by the sheriff of the proper county, upon
the property, both real and personal of the defendant.
(1444 )</p><pb n="1445" xml:id="P1445" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1453/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
103
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That upon the return of such at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tachment,
the court shall proceed to the trial of such cause and
judgment and execution as in other cases provided for by law.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Declaring certain children Legitimate, therein named.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That Elijah
Sterling Black Robertson, son of Sterling C. Robertson and Fanny
King, and James Macklin Robertson, son of Sterling C. Robertson
and Rachael Smith, be, and are hereby declared legitimate chil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dren,
and capable in law of inheriting their parents’ property, in
the same manner as if they had been born in lawful wedlock.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For appointing two legal gentlemen to compile a Judicial Code of
Laws for the republic of Texas.
Be it resolved, by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That William
H. Jack and D. S. Kaufman, be, and they are hereby appoin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1445
)</p><pb n="1446" xml:id="P1446" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1454/" /><p>104
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
ted compilers of the laws of the republic, whose duty it shall be to
compile and report to congress at its next regular session a general
systematic code of laws, for the future regulation and administra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of justice in this republic, and that said compilers shall receive
as a compensation for said services such sum as congress shall here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after
determine and allow upon the completion of the work.
JOSEPH BOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To authorize the judges of the district courts to hold Special
Terms in certain cases therein named.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas in congress assembled, That upon application
made to any judge of the district courts, he shall be and he is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by
authorized to hold a special term of the district court for the
trial of any criminal, under the same rules and regulations as are
provided for by the judiciary laws.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That any district judge of the
republic be and he is hereby authorized and required to preside at
such trial, upon information being given: provided, that this law
shall not extend to any county wherein there may be a jail built
by the county for the safe keeping of criminals.
JOSEPH BOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIBABEAU B. LAMAB,
■ President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1446 )</p><pb n="1447" xml:id="P1447" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1455/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
105
JOINT RESOLUTION
Directing the auditor to respect the acts of G. W. Poe.
Sec. 1. Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of
the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That the auditor be
and is hereby' instructed to acknowledge all the official acts of
G. W. Poe, while acting in capacity of paymaster general of the
army, as well as of all other properly and legally appointed officers
of this republic, except the issuing of land warrants.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT EESOLUTION
For the relief of D. F. Weymouth.
Eesolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the auditor of pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic
accounts, is hereby required to audit the claims of colonel D. F.
Weymouth, for three thousand eight hundred and. eighty-six
thirty-eight one hundredths dollars: provided, that the said Wey<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mouth
deposites in the office of the auditor a full statement of his
claim against the government, and that he give bond with such se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curity
as may be satisfactory to the auditor of public accounts, as
he the auditor may require, that the claims herein provided for in
this bill, shall not come against the government again.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1447 )</p><pb n="1448" xml:id="P1448" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1456/" /><p>106
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
Authorizing persons to dispose of property by Will.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That legiti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mate
descendants alone shall hereafter be considered forced heirs,
and all persons having no legitimate descendants, are hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized
to dispose by will or otherwise of their estate: any law
heretofore existing to the contrary notwithstanding.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That in case any husband or wife
shall die intestate, and leaving no heirs, the survivor shall be the
heir and shall inherit the estate of the deceased spouse..
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of the Family of Erastus Smith.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the sum of five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
dollars per annum, is hereby appropriated for the purpose of
being paid by the president, to the widow and family of Deaf
Smith, until the said widow marries, or the courts of the country
have confirmed their title to land and town lot heretofore granted
by congress to said Erastus Smith, and the president is hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized
to draw upon the treasury for the above appropriation.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker, of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1448 )</p><pb n="1449" xml:id="P1449" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1457/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
107
AN ACT
To create a Justice of the Peace, and Constable for Galveston
Island.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of"the
republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That there shall be one
justice of the peace and one constable elected for the Island of Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston,
whose duties shall be such as are prescribed by law for the
regulation of all such officers in such cases made and provided.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, &amp;c., That the chief justice for the
county of Harrisburg be required to proceed and cause an election
to be held immediately after the passage of this act, on the Island
of Galveston, to elect one justice of the peace and one constable.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of John J. Linn.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the second
auditor is hereby authorized to audit the claims of John J. Linn,
for fourteen hundred and sixty-six dollars and two cents, upon his
filing sufficient vouchers with the second auditor.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 18, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON..
(1449)</p><pb n="1450" xml:id="P1450" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1458/" /><p>108
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
Granting lands to those who were in the battle of San Jacinto
and other battles.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic 'of Texas, in congress assembled, That all persons
who were actually engaged in the battle of San Jacinto on the
twenty-first day of April, eighteen hundred and thirty-six, and all
persons who were wounded on the twentieth of the same month,
so as to prevent them from participating in the battle on the twen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty-first
day of April, eighteen hundred and thirty-six, and all per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons
who were detailed by special order of the commanding general
to guard the baggage at the camp near Harrisburg, be, and they
are hereby entitled to six hundred and forty acres of bounty land,
on the following conditions, to wit: That each soldier claiming
land under the provisions of this act, shall produce a certificate to
the secretary of war, signed by the commandant of the company to
which said soldier belonged, and countersigned by at least one field
officer, accompanied by an affidavit by the person claiming land
under the provisions of this act, that his claim is just, true and orig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inal,
and that he has never presented a claim of a like nature for
liquidation.
Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That the secretary of war be
authorized and required to issue a land warrant for six hundred and
forty acres of bounty land to all persons presenting a certificate
as is required in section first of this act.
Sec. 3. And be it further enacted, That the bounty warrants
and also the patents issued thereon shall state on the face thereof
for what said warrant or patent was granted.
Sec. 4. And be it further enacted, That the lands granted by
this act shall not be subject to sale or alienation, mortgage or execu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
during the lifetime of the person to whom such warrant or
patent shall be granted.
Sec. 5. And be it further enacted, That all commissioned offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers
coming under the provisions of this act, by producing a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate
signed by at least one superior officer, accompanied by an
affidavit as is required in the first section of this act, shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled
to the benefits of this law, on the same conditions as is re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired
in the fourth section of this act.
Sec. 6. And be it further enacted, That all persons who
(1450 )</p><pb n="1451" xml:id="P1451" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1459/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
109
entered Bexar from the morning of the fifth to the tenth of De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cember,
one thousand eight hundred and thirty-five, and who actu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ally
took part in the reduction of the same, also those who were in
the action of the nineteenth of March, one thousand eight hundred
and thirty six; under the commands of Colonels Fannin and Ward,
also all those who fell at the Alamo under the command of Bowie
and Travis, shall be entitled to the same quantum of land as speci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied
in this bill, given to those engaged in the battle of San Jacinto,
subject to the same rules, regulations and restrictions, and entitled
to all its benefits: Provided, always, that any person who may have
participated in both battles, shall only receive as a donation, one
tract or parcel of land of six hundred and forty acres and no more.
Sec. 7. And be’it further enacted, That the legal representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of those who fell in the storming of Bexar be entitled to select
and perfect titles for their benefit by themselves or agent, to six
hundred and forty acres.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, Dec. 21, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of John A. Wharton.
Be it resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the auditor be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structed
to pay to John A. Wharton, or his representatives five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
dollars, in the promissory notes of this government, for ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices
and expenses incurred by him in going to and from Mata<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moras.

JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 21, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1451 )</p><pb n="1452" xml:id="P1452" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1460/" /><p>110
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
To define the boundaries of the county of Jefferson.
Be it enacted, by the- senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That all that territory in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cluded
in the following limits shall constitute and compose the
county of Jefferson, to wit: Beginning on the Gulf of Mexico, from
which a line drawn due north, shall strike Wolf Point, thence north
to Big Sandy creek, thence down.said creek to its entrance into the
Neches river, thence due east to the Sabine river, thence down said
river to the Gulf of Mexico, thence west along the Gulf of Mexico
to the place of beginning.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 21, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of Samuel Williams.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas in congress assembled, That the auditor of pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic
accounts be, and is hereby directed to audit the accounts of Sam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uel
Williams to the amount of five thousand two hundred and forty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eight
dollars and twenty-eight cents, that being the amount o*f his
claims, (that the committee to whom was referred his accounts and
vouchers,) that it is considered to come under the class of accounts
that should now he paid.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 21, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1452 )</p><pb n="1453" xml:id="P1453" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1461/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
ill
AN ACT
To authorize the Clerks of the several courts to appoint deputies
and requiring them to keep their offices at the county seat.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives
of the.republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the clerks of
the several county and district courts of this republic be authorized
to appoint a deputy, to whom they shall administer an oath, faith<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fully
to discharge the duties of their office, and they shall in all
cases be responsible for the conduct of their deputies.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That hereafter the clerks of the
county and district courts of this republic, be, and they are hereby
compelled to keep all papers pertaining to their offices at the county
seats of each and every county, and be ready either by deputy or in
person to attend to the business of their office from ten o’clock
A. M. to four o’clock P. M.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That any clerk or clerks who shall
fail within thirty days hereafter to keep their office at the place in
the manner as specified in the foregoing section, shall forfeit and
pay to the republic twenty dollars for each day they shall so neglect
the provisions of said section, to be sued for and recovered before
' any justice of the peace of the proper county, at the instance of any
person interested.
S. H. EVERITT,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 21, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Supplementary to an act to incorparate the Colorado Navigation
Company.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the senate and house of repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That
when said chartered company have completed their work as
( 1453 )</p><pb n="1454" xml:id="P1454" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1462/" /><p>112
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
contemplated by their charter, shall before assessing or receiving
tolls, announce the completion of their work to congress and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress
shall then immediately proceed to appoint three commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers
to examine the work, and also proceed to ascertain the amount
of expense necessarily incurred, and said commissioners shall allew
of no account for expenditures unless the necessary vouchers are
produced.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That when the commissioners
have reported, congress shall determine whether or not it will pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase
or annul said charter in accordance with its provisions, by
paying the principal expended with ten per cent interest thereon;
Provided, said determination not to purchase, or annul on the part
of congress shall not preclude them from the right of purchasing
at any future time, but if congress shall not agree to purchase or
annul as above, then said commissioners shall in conjunction with
three of the board of directors of said chartered company proceed
to assess the rate of tolls, which said assessment shall take place on
the first day of January in like manner as above.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, that if the said chartered com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany
shall complete their work during the recess of congress, shall
communicate the facts to the president, who shall appoint three
commissioners, whose duty it shall be with three directors to fix
the rate of tolls until the next session of congress, and if said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners
and directors cannot agree they shall choose an umpire, '
whose decision shall be binding.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 27, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Supplementary to an act to raise Public Revenue by direct
Taxation.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That
from and after the passage of this act, that the clerks of the sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1454
)</p><pb n="1455" xml:id="P1455" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1463/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
113
eral county courts, shall be, and are hereby authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired
to issue licenses to all retailers, pedlars, &amp;c., and receive the
duties of the government for the same, as is required by this act
in accordance with the above recited act.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, &amp;c. That the sheriffs of the sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral
counties of this republic, be, and are hereby authorized and
required immediately after the first of day of January next, and in
each succeeding year to proceed to collect the taxes, and dues to
the government, by advertising at the several precincts or places
for holding elections at least fifteen days, on which day the sherif
or a qualified deputy shall attend agreeably to this advertisement
for the purpose of collecting taxes to be raised by virtue of this'
act.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That on the failure of any person or
persons to attend and punctually pay the amount of taxes that may
be due the government, then and in that case, the sheriff shall
proceed and take an execution (to be issued by any justice of the
peace for said county,) against the goods and property of said'de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />linquent
or delinquents, and proceed to sell so much of the same
as will satify debts and costs.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the
several clerks and sheriffs of the several counties to report to the
secretary of the treasury on or before the first day of September
in each year, and pay over the amount of public monies that may
have come into their hands into the treasury of the republic.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted. That the several clerks and
sheriffs of the several counties shall be allowed five per cent, in all
monies that may be collected or received by them, and- that each
and every applicant for license for retailing &amp;c. shall pay to the
clerk as his fee the sum of one dollar.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 21, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1455 )</p><pb n="1456" xml:id="P1456" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1464/" /><p>114
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of F. W. Thornton.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the first auditor be,
and he is hereby authorized and required to pay to Francis W.
Thornton, in the promissory notes of this government, the amount
of a draft drawn in his favor for the purchase of provisions for the
army in 1836, for the sum of one thousand seven hundred and
twenty-two dollars and twenty-two cents, upon the said Thornton
presenting the aforesaid draft..
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 28, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION,
For the relief of H. C. Hudson.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That, the auditor be, and
he is hereby authorized to audit the claim of H. C. Hudson, for
three hundred dollars, for services to the government in arranging
the books, papers and acts of the consultation, council and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visional
government, in which he was occupied three months and
-------days.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 28, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1456 )</p><pb n="1457" xml:id="P1457" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1465/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
115
AN ACT
For the relief of Stilman S. Curtis.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the first auditor of
accounts, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to audit the
claims of Stilman S. Curtis, for horses and other property lost in
the service of Texas, in the winter and spring of 1836; provided the
whole amount shall not exceed three hundred and thirty-eight dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars.

JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 28, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON..
JOINT RESOLUTION
Providing for the purchase of Provisions and Munitions of War.
Be it resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That twenty-five thousand
dollars of the one hundred thousand dollars appropriated in an
act passed the ninth of June 1837, for the equipment and support
of a corps of rangers, is hereby- appropriated for the purpose of
purchasing provisions and munitions of war, and the secretary of'
war is hereby authorized to draw upon the treasury for that amount,,
for the above specified purpose: and he is hereby instructed to lose
no time in purchasing the requisite munitions and provisions.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 28, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
92 —VOL. 1.
(1457 )</p><pb n="1458" xml:id="P1458" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1466/" /><p>116
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
JOINT RESOLUTION,
Respecting county Surveyors.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That whenever it shall so
happen that the amount of surveying to be done (in any one county)
is not more than can be performed by one surveyor, which fact
shall be determined by the board of land commissioners, then and
in that case the county surveyor for said county, shall be allowed
to perform the duties of a practical surveyor, and perform all the
-duties as required of the deputy surveyors to be appointed under a
provision of an act to establish a general land office.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 29, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
.'Requiring the auditor to audit the claim of Thomas G. McGee.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />'public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the first auditor be,
and he is hereby required to audit the accounts of Thomas G. Mc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Gee,
for a stud horse, and allow him therefor such sum as he shall
show by the affidavit of two or more disinterested persons, the said
horse was worth at the time he was pressed into service; provided,
the amount does not exceed two hundred dollars.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 28, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1458)</p><pb n="1459" xml:id="P1459" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1467/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
117
JOINT EESOLUTION
For the relief of A. E. Bodman.
Eesolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the auditor be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired
to audit the account of A. E. Bodman for services rendered
as clerk to the executive and in the state department of the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
ad interim, allowing him such pay as is allowed to other
clerks for similar services.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVEEITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 28, 1837.
' SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To incorporate the City of Houston and other towns therein named.
Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives of the
republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That the citizens of the
City of Houston, and the towns of Washington, Crockett and Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fugio,
be incorporated under, and entitled to all the privileges and
benefits of the act granting a charter of incorporation to the town
of Brazoria, passed at the extra session of this congress.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIEABEAU B. LAMAE,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 39, 1837. .
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1459 )</p><pb n="1460" xml:id="P1460" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1468/" /><p>118
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
JOINT RESOLUTION,
Incorporating the town of Columbia.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas, in congress assembled, That the town of Colum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bia
is hereby incorporated with all the powers and privileges which
have been extended to Brazoria, in the act by which said town has
been incorporated, and that the limits of said town shall embrace
what was generally known as the town of Marion.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 29, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To create the county of Fort Bend.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That there
shall be laid off on the Brazos river, a new county to be called the
county of Fort Bend, which shall include all the territory within
the following limits viz: Beginning on the east side of
the Brazos river at the upper corner of a league of land granted
to Francis Biggam, on which said Biggam now lives;' thence
east with the north boundary of said league to- its north east cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner,
continuing on the Harrisburg and Brazoria county line;
three leagues from thence to the head of Bray’s Bayou,
where stands a low elm; thence running from the head of Bray’s
Bayou to a point on Buffalo bayou where the present county
line, running from Jesse H. Cartwright’s league, crosses the
bayou; thence northwardly to the southeast corner of Ful<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />shear’s
league of land on the Brazos river; thence west with the
south boundary of said league to said river; thence crossing said
( 1460)</p><pb n="1461" xml:id="P1461" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1469/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
119
river, and following its western bank to the mouth of sixteen mile
creek; thence up said creek to its source; thence in a southwardly
direction to the southeast corner of G. Coles land; thence westward<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly
with said Coles lower line, to the San Bernard; thence down said
stream to the southwest corner of league No. 8; thence with the
lower line of said league to the southeast corner; thence in a direct
line to the south prong- of Cow bayou; thence down said bayou to
its mouth; thence crossing the Brazos, and up said river to the
place of beginning.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said county shall be or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganized
in conformity with an “act organizing the inferior courts,
and defining the jurisdiction of the same,” and the county courts of
said county shall be held on the second Monday in January, April,
July and October, in each year.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the said county shall be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cluded
in, and shall form a part of the third judicial district, and
the district court of said county shall be holden on the last Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days.
in February and August of each year.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the
chief justice so soon as he shall receive a notice of his appointment,
to proceed to give notice, and, hold an election in the town of Rich<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mond,
for the permanent location of the seat of justice of said
county, and he shall make a return of the result of said election to
the secretary of state.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That said county shall be entitled
to one representative in congress, and the county of Fort Bend and
Austin shall form one senatorial district, and be entitled to one
senator.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That all suits which are now ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />isting
by or against any of the citizens of the county of Fort Bend,
shall be continued and concluded in the county in which they orig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inated,
in the same manner as if no division of the counties had
been made.
JOSEPH BOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 29, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1461)</p><pb n="1462" xml:id="P1462" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1470/" /><p>120
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
To regulate the proceedings of the several Courts in certain cases.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representatives
of the republic of Texas, in congress assembled, That where judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments
have been heretofore obtained before any alcalde or primary
judge, and returned as required by law to any of the courts of this
republic, it shall be the duty of said court on the application of the
plaintiff to issue a scieri facias or other notice, summoning the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fendant
to appear and show cause why execution should not be is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sued,
but no evecution shall be issued upon any such judgment,
until a scieri facias or other notice shall have been issued and served
in the usual way, upon the defendant or defendants.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That all suits brought in any of
the district or county courts of this republic, either by original pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess
or otherwise, shall be tried at the first term, unless good causes
be shown for continuance.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 29, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION,
Supplementary to a resolution for the relief of Samuel Williams.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
Texas, in congress assembled, That the amount author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized
by a joint resolution, to be paid to Samuel Williams, be paid
in the promissory notes; of this government, as intended, though
not clearlv expressed in the resolution alluded to.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 29, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1462 )</p><pb n="1463" xml:id="P1463" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1471/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
121
AN ACT
Defining the boundaries of the county of Jackson.
Seo. 1. Be it enacted, by the senate and house of representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the republic of Texas in congress assembled, That from
and immediately after the passage of this act, the following shall
be the lines of the county of Jackson, to wit: Commencing on
the Bay, at a place called the divide between the Trespalaccios and
Carrancahua creeks, running thence north twenty-nine degrees to
a corner, thence north twelve degrees east to the line of Colorado,
county; thence south eighty-two degrees west, to the mouth of
Smither’s creek, on the Lavacca, thence down the Lavacca, (to
the lower corner of Kent’s league of land; thence six miles with the
line of Gonzales county, from thence a direct line to the Bay at
the mouth of the
) thence with the middle of the Bay to a
point opposite the beginning.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the territory included within
the aforesaid lines shall be, and the same is hereby declared to be
the. county of Jackson.
■ Sec. 3. And be it further enacted, That there shall be an elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
held at the houses of John McHenry and Philip Demit’s on the
first Monday of January next, to be presided by such persons as the
voters may appoint at which election, the question shall be upon the
annexation of a part of Victoria county to the county of Jackson,
and the votes shall be confined to that portion of the county six
miles west of the Lavacca river, and should a majority of the voters
be in favor of being attached to Jackson county, it shall be so done,
if a majority be in favor of remaining in Victoria, the line shall
remain as it now is.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 29, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1463 )</p><pb n="1464" xml:id="P1464" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1472/" /><p>122
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
JOINT RESOLUTION
To incorporate certain towns therein named.
Resolved, by the senate and house of representatives of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public
of Texas in congress assembled, That the citizens of the
towns of Clarksville in the county of Red River, and the citizens of
the town of Lexington in the county of Fannin, and the towns of
Milam, Houston, Goliad, San Patricio and Jonesborough, be, and
they are hereby incorporated, and shall respectively have and enjoy
all the privileges which have been granted to the town of Brazoria.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the house of representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the senate.
Approved, Dec. 29, 1837.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1464 )</p><pb n="1465" xml:id="P1465" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1473/" /><p>INDEX.
Joint resolution, to suspend the operatians of the Land office
until the further action of congress.........................
Joint resolution making an appropriation to pay the public
printers.....................................................
Joint resolution making, appropriation of moneys for the use
of the Hospital..............................................
Joint resolution locating permanently the seat of govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
.......................................................
Joint resolution authorizing Wm. G. Cooke to sign the name
of the President to the promissory notes of the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
........................................................
Joint resolution for the relief W. S. Hendrick.
An act regulating elections.................................
Joint resolution requiring the chief justice of the county of
Brazoria to issue writs of election..........................
An act authorizing an appropriation for the Post Office.....
Joint resolution to authorize the secretary of war to grant Dis-,
charges.....................................................
J oint resolution granting letters of Marque and Reprisal...
An act to incorporate the town of Shelbyville, and granting
further powers to the corporations of San Augustine and
Nacogdoches ................................................
An act for augmenting the Navy, and making an appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
therefor...............................................
An act regulating the proceedings before justices of the peace.
Joint resolution requiring the secretary of war to execute cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain
duties.................................................
An act to provide for auditing contingent expenses of both
houses of congress, and making appropriation therefor. . . .
Page
3
3
4
4
5
6
6
10
10
11
11
12
13
14
15
15
(1465)</p><pb n="1466" xml:id="P1466" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1474/" /><p>ii
index.
Joint resolution for the relief of Hollond Coffee &amp; Co......
An act to provide for the appointment of notaries public....
Joint resolution to appoint a committee on printing.........
An act to incorporate the town of Brazoria..................
Joint resolution requiring the auditor to audit the accounts of
Nelson Jones...............................................
An act appropriating money for the purchase of a house for
the use of the president...................................
An act to incorporate the city of Richmond, and the towns of
San Felipe de Austin and Lagrange......
Joint resolution for the relief of Ellen ............
An act Fixing the salary of Indian commissioners. ...
Joint resolution for the relief of Manuel .........
An act amendatory to the several acts and ordinances granting
bounty lands..............................
Joint resolution allowing the secretary of war an additional
clerk ................................................. ....
Joint resolution for the relief of John ...........
Joint resolution for the relief of John M. Clifton......
An act for the relief of Edmund P. Crosby..........
Joint resolution making appropriations for the general land
office, and to defray the contingent expenses of both houses
of congress............................................
Joint resolution for the relief of John Woodruff...........
An act to incorporate the Colorado Navigation Company......
An act creating the county of Montgomery...................
Page
16
16
17
17
20
21
21
24
24
25
25
26
27
2%
28
An act regulating the time of holding district courts of Bra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zoria,
Matagorda and Jackson counties.......................
Joint resolution for the relief of S. Hatch.................
An act to establish the county of Payette...................
An act incorporating the city of San Antonio and other towns
therein named.......................•.......................
An act to create a hoard of Medical Censors for the republic of
Texas ......................................................
Joint resolution to compensate the commissioners appointed to
select a site for the seat of government....................
An act to define the boundaries of the county of Gonzales...
, An act to provide for the punishment of crimes and misda<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />meanors
committed by slaves and free persons of color....
Joint resolution concerning the public archives..........
Joint resolution authorizing the treasurer of the republic to
issue change notes..........................................
An act to clear out the rivers Attoyac, Angelina and Neches..
An act to prevent the issuing of individual printed or litho<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />graphed
notes...............................................
An act to define the boundaries of the county of Shelby.....
An act to define the boundaries of the county of Washington. .
( 1466 )
28
29
29
33
34
35
35
37
39
41
42
43
44
45
46
47
48
49</p><pb n="1467" xml:id="P1467" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1475/" /><p>Index.
iii
Page
50
50
51
An act to incorporate the town of Matagorda.................
Joint resolution for the purchase of the steamer Pulaski....
An act to pay the officers and soldiers of the army and navy..
An act supplementary to “an act to pay the officers, soldiers
and sailors of the army and navy”...........................
An act to define the boundaries of the counties of San Augus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tine
and Sabine ............................................
An act creating the county of Fannin..............................
Joint resolution locating permanently the seat of justice for
the county of Brazoria .....................................
An act to define the boundaries of Jasper county....
An act creating the county of Robertson...........................
Joint resolution requiring the auditor to audit the accounts of
Geo. W. Bonnel...............................................
An act to sustain the currency of the country..............
An act to prohibit the further sale of land scrip...........
An act to require the district judges to reside permanently in
their proper districts, and for other purposes .............
Joint resolution for the relief of Anson Jones...............
Joint resolution for the relief of Charles Durocha...........
Joint resolution to select a committee of five &amp;c. to locate the
seat of government ...........................................
An act precluding aliens from being appointed to office...........
An act entitled “an act to reduce into one act, and to amend
the several acts relating to the establishment of a General
Land Office.” ..............................................
An act to incorporate the Texas Steam Mill Company..........
An act supplementary to an act to appoint a Board of Medical
Censors.......................................................
An act to incorporate the town of Mina..................  .
An act to amend the act, entitled an act to raise a revenue by
impost duties...............................................
An act to incorporate the Brazoria Insurance Company..............
An act to define the boundaries of the county of Liberty ....
An act supplementary to an act entitled an act to organize the
Militia of this republic......................'.............
An act to encourage steam navigation....................  .
An act to amend the several laws regulating the Post Office
Department .................................................
An act regulating the pay and allowances of the officers and
soldiers of the army .......................................
Joint resolution requiring the auditor to settle with Mr. Thom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />as
Brennan .................................................
An act to define the boundaries of the county of Red River. . .
Joint resolution altering the name of the county and town of
Mina..............................................................
Joint resolution relative to Consulates ..........................
(1467 )
52
52
53
54
55
56
57
57
58
58
59
60
60
61
62
76
79
79
80
80
84
85
86
87
88
89
89
90
91</p><pb n="1468" xml:id="P1468" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1476/" /><p>iv
Index.
An act to define the boundaries of the county of Mina..........
Joint resolution for the relief of M. A. Beremendi.............
An act to provide for the publication of the laws and journals
of the republic of Texas.......................................
An act Making provisions for persons who have been perma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nently
disabled in the service of Texas .......................
Page
91
92
92
Joint resolution for the relief of Dougald Brown..............
An act amending the judiciary laws of the republic............
An act to provide for taking testimony bv interrogatories. . . .
An act to authorize the post master general to establish a post
route ........................................................
Joint resolution for the relief of Maria Antonio de La Garza..
Joint resolution for the relief of James Collinsworth.........
Joint resolution for the relief of C. C. Dewitt...............
Joint resolution to translate the laws of the republic into the
93
94
94
96
97
98
98
99
Castilian language............................................
Joint resolution for the relief of widow Kitty McCoy......
Joint resolution for the relief of colonel John Forbes....
Joint resolution authorizing F. E. Lubbock to procure cisterns
for the use of the capitol.................................
Joint resolution for the relief of Francis W. Thornton........
An act to authorize attachments to be issued in certain cases
therein named.................................................
99
100
101
101
102
102
An act declaring certain children legitimate therein named. . 103
Joint resolution for appointing two legal gentlemen to com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pile
a judicial code of laws for the republic of Texas........... 103
An act to authorize the judges of the district courts to hold
special terms in certain cases therein named...................
Joint resolution directing the auditor to respect the acts of
George W. Poe...................................................
Joint resolution for the relief of D. F. Weymouth..............
104
105
105
An act authorizing persons to dispose of property by Will. . . . 106
Joint resolution for the relief of the family of Erastus Smith. . 106
An act to create a justice of the peace and constable for Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston
Island.................................................
Joint resolution for the relief of John J. Linn ..............
An act granting lands to those who were in the battle of San
Jacinto and other battles ....................................
Joint resolution for the relief of John A. Wharton............
107
107
108
109
An act to define the boundaries of the county of Jefferson. . . . 110
Joint resolution for the relief of Samuel Williams.......	110
An act to authorize the clerks of the several courts to appoint
deputies and requiring them to keep their offices at the
county seat .............................................. Ill
An act supplementary to an act to incorporate the Colorado
Navigation company........................................ Ill
( 1468 )</p><pb n="1469" xml:id="P1469" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1477/" /><p>Index.
V
An act supplementary to an act to raise
direct Taxation......................
Page
a public revenue by
Joint resolution for the relief of F. W. Thornton...........
Joint resolution for the relief of H. C. Hudson.............
An act for the relief of Stilman S. Curtis..................
Joint resolution providing for the purchase of provisions and
munitions of War............................................
Joint resolution respecting county surveyors................
Joint resolution requiring the auditor to audit the claim of
Thomas G. McGee..............................................
J oint resolution for the relief of A. R. Bodman............
An act to incorporate the city of Houston and other towns
therein named...............................................
Joint resolution incorporating the town of Columbia.........
An act to create the county of Fort Bend....................
An act to regulate proceedings of the several courts in certain
cases...................... .2..............................
Joint resolution supplementary to a resolution for the relief of
Samuel Williams .............................................
An act defining the boundaries of the county of Jackson.....
112
114
114
115
115
116
116 .
117
117
118
118
120
120
121
Joint resolution to incorporate certain towns therein named.. 122
( 1469 )</p><pb n="1470" xml:id="P1470" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1478/" /><p /></div></body></text>
