<text><front /><body><div type="document"><pb n="1471" xml:id="P1471" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1479/" /><p>LAWS
OF THE
REPUBLIC OF TEXAS
VOLUME THIRD.
By Order of the Secretary of State.
HOUSTON.
1838</p><pb n="1472" xml:id="P1472" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1480/" /><p /><pb n="1473" xml:id="P1473" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1481/" /><p>L AW S
OF THE
REPUBLIC OF TEXAS
AN ACT
Securing the right of Appeal.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That in
the suits authorized to be commenced by Empresarios, under
the 27th section of the Land Law, against the President of the
Republic, the defendant shall have the right to appeal without
giving the bond and security required of appellants.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That in all cases where the
Republic is concerned as a party, either in her own name, or
the name of her officers, an appeal may be taken in her behalf
without bond or security.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
Approved, May 3, 1838.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To repeal a part of an Act incorporating the town of Gonzales.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled,'—
That so much of an act incorporating the city of San An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tonio
and other towns therein named, passed at the last
session of Congress, as relates to the town of Gonzales,
which requires the clerk to possess a competent know<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />93—vol.
i.
( 1473 )</p><pb n="1474" xml:id="P1474" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1482/" /><p>4
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
ledge of the Castilian Language, and requiring the members to
consist of eight Aldermen is hereby repealed;—and the members
of the Corporation of Gonzales shall consist of four Aidermen
in lieu of eight.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the Chief Justice of the
county of Gonzales, immediately after the passage of the act,
shall be authorised and required to issue writs of an election to
fill the offices of the above recited act for the fraction of the
present year.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B; LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 3, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Supplementary to an Act creating the County of Fayette.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That from and
after the passage of this Act, the south western boundary of the
county of Fayette shall be, and is hereby established as follows,
viz: beginning at the north east corner of a league of land
granted to J. Morris on the head of the La Bacca river; thence,
northwestwardly to the north east corner of a quarter of a league
■of land granted to Stiffler: provided, that nothing herein con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained
shall affect any rights of location made in conformity to
■the acts defining the boundaries of Gonzales and Fayette.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 3, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Providing for the removal of County Seats of Justice.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That a
( 1474 )</p><pb n="1475" xml:id="P1475" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1483/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
5
majority of two-thirds of the votes of the qualified voters of a
county 'shall be required to remove the seat of justice in any of
the counties of this Republic that now are or hereafter may be
established; provided, however, that if in any county the seat
of justice should be established at a greater distance than five
miles from the centre of said county; a majority of all the votes
shall be sufficient for its removal, provided such removal shall
be within the limits of five miles from the centre of said county.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That when, in the opinion of
the chief Justice of any county, the necessary number of inhabi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tants
apply by petition or otherwise for a removal of the seat of
justice, it shall be the duty of said chief justice to order an elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
for that purpose giving due notice thereof, which election
shall be held at the same places, and conducted in the same man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner
as elections for members of Congress, and the result of said
election shall establish the seat of justice, in accordance with
the provisions of the first section of this act.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 9, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
A BILL
To repeal a certain Act therein named.
(An Act to prohobit the bonding of duties.)
Whereas, the fifth section of an act, entitled an act to raise a
public Revenue by Impost Duties, authorizes the importer, fac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tor
or consignee, to give bond for the payment of the duties on
their importations, in instalments according to the amount of
duties; which act was approved on the twelfth day of June, 1837.
Sec. 1. Be it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of
Representatives of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled,
That from and after the first day of June next, so much of the
aforesaid act as relates to the bonding of duties as aforesaid,
shall be, and the same is hereby repealed.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty
of the Collectors of the different Ports in this Republic,
( 1475 )</p><pb n="1476" xml:id="P1476" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1484/" /><p>6
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
where any articles subject to duty may be imported, to hold the
same in his custody until the duties are paid, according to the
true intent and meaning of this act.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the Secretary of the
Treasury be, and he is hereby required to give publicity to this
act as soon as practicable, and that the different Collectors of
this Republic be informed through the proper channel, of the
existence of this law as soon as practicable; and in case of neglect
to pay the duties by the importer, within ten days, the Collector
shall proceed to sell the goods at auction, or a sufficient amount
thereof to pay the duties, after giving ten days’ notice of such
sale, and shall sell accordingly, unless payment be made.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That it shall not be lawful for
any Collector of the Customs to receive, either directly or in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />directly,
in payment of duties, any monies except the Promissory
Notes of the Government, or gold and silver; and any person
offending against the provisions of this act shall be dismissed
from office, and upon conviction fined in a sum not less than
one thousand nor more than five thousand dollars for each of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fence.

JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, Maj- 9, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION,
Authorising the President and Commissioner of the General
Land Office to issue titles to purchasers of Lots on Galveston
Island.
Be it resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That
the President of the Republic and the Commissioner of
the General Land Office are hereby authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired
to issue titles to purchasers of lots on Galveston
Island; provided that the said purchasers shall deliver to
the Commissioner a certificate of purchase, with a receipt
(1476)</p><pb n="1477" xml:id="P1477" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1485/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
I
for the payment of the purchase money in full, from the Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary
of the Treasury.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the House of Eepresentatives.
MIEABEAU B. LAMAE,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 9, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
।
JOINT EESOLUTION
For the relief of John F.. Kemper.
Eesolved by the Senate and House of Eepresentatives of the
Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the Auditor of
Public Accounts be authorized and required to audit the account
of John F. Kemper, as armourer for the term of eight months
and twenty-four days, agreeably to law in such cases made and
provided.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the House of Eepresentatives.
MIEABEAU B. LAMAE,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 10, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
A BILL
To create and define the Senatorial District of Austin, Colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rado
and Fort Bend.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Eepresenta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the
counties of Austin, Colorado and Fort Bend shall be, and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute
a senatorial district.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the Chief Justice of the
county of Austin shall be the returning officer of said senatorial
district.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That all laws or parts of laws
conflicting with this act be, and the same are hereby repealed.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the House of Eepresentatives.
MIEABEAU B. LAMAE,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 10, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1477 )</p><pb n="1478" xml:id="P1478" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1486/" /><p>8
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
Repealing the 37th section of an act organizing Inferior Courts.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That so much of
the thirty-seventh section of an act entitled an act organizing the
Inferior courts, and defining the powers and jurisdiction of the
same, as requires recording before the first of April, eighteen
hundred and thirty-eight, approved twentieth December, eight<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />een
hundred and thirty-six, be, and the same is hereby repealed.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 10, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To incorporate the Caney Navigation Company.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled,—That
there shall be established a company under the name and style of
the “Caney Navigation Company,” with a capital stock of fifty
thousand dollars, to be divided into shares of one hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars
each, for the purpose of clearing out a channel and making
navigable for steamboats, or other craft, the creek or river Caney,
and for connecting the said creek or river by canals or other
means of intercommunication with the head of Matagorda Bay,
Cedar Lake, and with the Colorado river, and for deepening the
channel at the mouth of said creek or river.
Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That books shall be opened
on the first Monday of July next to receive subscriptions to the
capital stock of said company at the following places, to wit: at
the towns of Matagorda and Manhattan, and at the house of R.
H. Williams, on Caney, under the superintendence of three com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners
at each place, viz: at the town of Matagorda, Silas
Dinsmore, John Duncan, and S. Mussina; at the town
of . Manhattan, J. E. Fields, E. R. Weightman, and
( 1478 )</p><pb n="1479" xml:id="P1479" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1487/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
9
Thomas Cayce; and at the house of E. H. Williams, T. Jamison,
E. H. Williams, and Wm. H. Jack.
Sec. 3. And be it further enacted, That the subscribers to
said company, their successors and assigns, shall be, and are
hereby created a corporation under the name and style of the
“Caney Navigation Company,” with similar- powers and priv- .
ileges, and subject to similar rules and regulations as are given
and, prescribed to the Colorado Navigation Company, by an act
entitled “an act to incorporate the Colorado Navigation Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany,”
approved December fourteenth, eighteen hundred and
thirty-seven: provided, that the town of Manhattan, at the
mouth of Caney shall be substituted in this act for the town of
Matagorda in the act above referred to, in all instances where it
occurs in said act, except in the one referred to in the second
section of this act.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIEABEAU B. LAMAE,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 11, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
EESOLUTION,
For repairing the President’s House, and purchasing Furniture.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the sum of
three thousand dollars of the Promissory Notes of this Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment
be, and the same is hereby appropriated to complete
and repairs and purchase furniture for the President’s House;
and that the said sum be expended under the direction of his Ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cellency.

JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIEABEAU B. LAMAE,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 11, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT EESOLUTION
Supplementary to a joint resolution, for the relief of John J.
Linn, approved December 18th, 1837.
Eesolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the
( 1479 ;</p><pb n="1480" xml:id="P1480" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1488/" /><p>10
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the amount au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized
to be paid to John J. Linn, by a joint resolution, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved
December the eighteenth eighteen hundred and thirty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />seven,
be paid to him in Promissory Notes of this Government.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, May 15, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Authorizing the President to appoint Notaries Public.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That there shall
be appointed for the county where the Seat of Government is
or shall be located two Notaries Public in addition to the Chief
Justice of said county; and also, one additional Notary in each
county of the Republic; which appointments shall be made by
the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 15, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To authorise the President to raise a Corps of Cavalry.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled,—That the
President be, and he is hereby authorized and required to raise
a Corps of Regular Cavalry, not exceeding two hundred and
eighty, rank and file, to be enlisted for a term of not less than
one, nor more than three years, as he may deem suitable, for the
purpose of protecting the Southwestern Frontier.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted. That said Corps shall, at no
time, be quartered within fifteen miles of any town.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That for the purpose of
(1480)</p><pb n="1481" xml:id="P1481" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1489/" /><p>Laws of the Republie of Texas.
11
enabling the President to carry this act into effect, the sum of
fifty thousand dollars of the promissory Notes of the Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
be, and the same is hereby appropriated, to be paid out of
the first monies that may be paid into the Treasury.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, May 15, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To provide for the foreclosing of Mortgages on Real and Per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal
Estates.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled. That from
and after the passage of this act, the method of foreclosing
mortgages on land shall be as follows: any person entitled to
foreclose a mortgage on land, or his or their attorney shall peti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
the district court of the county where such land or a part
thereof is situated, stating the case, and the amount of his or
her demand, describing the property mortgaged, and the court
shall grant a rule, that the principal, interest and costs, shall be
paid into the court on or before the first day of the next suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding
term of such court, which rule shall be served upon the
defendant at least ninety days before the time of payment, if
the party defendant be a resident of the Republic; if not, it shall
be published at least one month in some public Gazette, unless
the principal, interests, and costs be paid, the court shall pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed
to give judgment for the amount which may be due on such
mortgage, and order the property mortgaged to be sold to the
highest and best bidder, after the same shall have been adver<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tised
thirty days in some public Gazette, and the money paid over
to the mortgagee or his attorney; but when there shall be any
surplus, the same shall be paid over to the mortgager or his
agent, and in case of any dispute as to the amount due on any
mortgage, if the mortgager shall appear at any time within the
time prescribed in this act, before judgment shall be given, and
(1481 )</p><pb n="1482" xml:id="P1482" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1490/" /><p>12
Latos of the Republic of Texas.
make affidavit of such facts, the court shall order a trial of the
facts before a jury as in other cases.
Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That all mortgages on
negroes and other personal property shall be foreclosed in the
following manner: Any person or persons holding a mortgage
on personal property, and wishing to foreclose the same, shall
make application to the chief justice of the county, and make
affidavit before him of the amount of principal and interest due
thereon, which affidavit shall be annexed to such mortgage, and
thereupon, the clerk of the county court shall issue execution as
in cases of judgment, which execution being delivered to the
sheriff shall be levied upon the mortgaged property, and after
being advertised for at least sixty days in some public Gazette,
shall be set up and sold to. the highest bidder; provided always,
that if any disputes’ should arise as to the amount due on such
mortgage, the chief justice of the county court shall order the
sale to be postponed upon the defendant’s entering into bond
and security in double the amount of the mortgage, for the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />livery
to the sheriff of the property so levied upon; and the same
shall be returned to, and triable at the next term of the court,
as in other cases.
Sec. 3. And be it further enacted, That all mortgages upon
real estate shall, upon the usual proof, be recorded in the county
where the land is situated, within ninety days from the passage
of this act, or from the date of the execution of such mortgage;
and upon personal property in the county ■where the mortgager
lives. No mortgage shall take lien upon property mortgaged
unless so recorded.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, May 15, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AX ACT
Establishing the county of Galveston.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled,
That a new county to be called the county of Galveston
be, and the same is hereby established within the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(
1482 )</p><pb n="1483" xml:id="P1483" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1491/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
13
lowing limits, viz: Embracing the entire Island.of Galveston,
and the waters and Islands of the Bay adjacent thereto, includ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
Deer Islands and that of San Luis, together with parts of
the main land of Brazoria and Liberty Counties nearest the
Bay aforesaid; beginning at the mouth of Highland Bayou, and
running up the same to its source; thence due north to the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent
line between the counties of Harrisburg and Brazoria;
thence east with said line to the mouth of Clear Creek; thence
with the Bay of Galveston to Davis’s Point, (or Red Fish Bar);
thence with Red Fish Bar across the bay to Potter’s Point;
thence along the margin of East Bay, including the same to the
western boundary of Zavala’s Colony; thence due south to the
Gulf of Mexico; thence with the coast of the Gulf to the be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ginning.

Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the seat of justice for the
said county of Galveston shall be fixed at the city of Galveston
until otherwise directed according to law.
Seo. 3. Be it further enacted, That the chief justice for said
county shall at some early day, order an election to be held at
the city of Galveston for choosing the several officers required
in organizing a new county.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the said county of Galveston
shall be attached to and form part of the senatorial district of
Harrisburg and Liberty, and to the second judicial district. The
District Courts for said county shall be held on the last Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days
in April and October of each year, and the County Courts
of said county shall be held on the third Mondays in January,
April, July and October of each year.
JOSEPH ROWE,'
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 15, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Authorizing the payment of the Interest of the Funded Debt.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled,
( 1483 )</p><pb n="1484" xml:id="P1484" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1492/" /><p>14
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
That the Secretary of the Treasury be, and he is hereby required
to pay the interest accruing on the Funded Debt, at the time
it is made payable by law, and a sufficient amount of the Promis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sory
Notes of the Government to meet the object, is hereby ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated
for that special purpose.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the Secretary of the
Treasury be, and he is hereby required to pay the interest on all
other debts against the Government, which by law bear interest;
and that the same be paid semi-annually in the promissory notes
of the Government, a sufficient amount of which is hereby spe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cially
appropriated for that purpose.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 16, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To authorize the President to negotiate a loan on the bonds
of the Government, not exceeding five millions of dollars.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the
President of the Republic, for the purpose of effecting a loan, be,
and he is hereby authorized to issue bonds in the name of the
Republic for such sums as may suit the purchasers thereof, to
an amount not exceeding in the whole, five millions of dollars;
which bonds the President may authorize the commissioners of
the loan hereafter' to be created, to sign and deliver, in any
language required, after being duly countersigned by the min<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ister
or other diplomatic agent of Texas, resident at Wash<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ington,
London or Paris, the same to be made payable
to bearer, bearing an interest on the face thereof at a
rate not exceeding ten per cent, per annum, and to be
paid' to the holders thereof, at such time and place, and in
such currency as may be agreed on, and stipulated there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in,
to be made redeemable in thirty years from the day
( 1484 )</p><pb n="1485" xml:id="P1485" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1493/" /><p>Laivs of the Republic of Texas.
15
of date, unless the commissioners shall think it proper and
necessary; and for that object they shall have the power to nego<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tiate
two millions of the said amount of five'millions, redeemable
in a less time than thirty years, but not for a shorter period
than five years. And the said commissioners shall have power to
agree and stipulate in said bonds that the holder or holders
thereof may, at any time they may choose, surrender the same,
and in lieu of principal and interest due thereon, receive any of
the public lands at the minimum prices fixed by the Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
at the time for the sale of their vacant lands; or if said
lands are sold at auction, any of the said holders shall be al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowed
to bid and pay the amount of their bids, with any of said
bonds in like manner as they are permitted to do at the fixed
prices as above mentioned.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said commissioners
shall have power to negotiate and sell such bonds for the notes
of any bank or banks whose paper shall be at par with the best
bank paper in the city of New York or Philadelphia; and the
said commissioners shall have power to stipulate that the notes
of any such bank or banks purchasing such bonds to the amount
of one hundred thousand dollars or more, shall be received in
payment of all public dues, so long as said bank or banks shall,
in the judgment of the Government of Texas, be of good char<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />acter
and worthy of confidence.
Seo. 3. Be it further enacted, That the President shall, by
and with the advice and consent of the Senate, appoint two
commissioners, who shall have power either within the United
States or Europe to carry out the purposes and fulfil the objects
of this act in the manner specified therein, and shall be subject
from time to time to such instructions as the President may
communicate to them through the Secretary of the Treasury.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That in case of the death or
resignation of either or both of said commissioners during the
recess of Congress, the President is hereby fully authorized to
fill such vacancy or vacancies, until the meeting of the next
Congress.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty
of said commissioners to contract’ with the Bank of the
(1485)</p><pb n="1486" xml:id="P1486" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1494/" /><p>16
Laws of the B.epublic of Texas.
United States of Pennsylvania (if practicable,) if not, with the
Manhattan Bank of New York, or the Union Bank of Louis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iana,
to act for the Government of this Republic as fiscal agents
in the United States in all matters relative to the loan authorized
by this act, for all operations within the state in which such
bank may be located, and by its agents in other states of the
United States of America—also in Europe; and when the said
commissioners shall contract any loan or sale of any bonds au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized
by this act, it shall be their duty to deposite in the said
bank, or with its agency, nearest the place with the knowledge
and approbation of said bank by its President and Directory, the
amount of bonds corresponding with the amount of loan con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tracted
for, or bonds sold, which bonds shall be issued by such
bank or its agencies to the contractors or purchasers on the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
into the bank or its. agencies, to the credit of this Republic,
the amount of money contracted to be loaned, or paid therefor,
on which payment to the credit of this republic, the bank, or its
cashier, or the agency thereof, shall issue to the interested party
or parties the bonds or scrip for instalments thereon to the
amount so paid in conformity with the contract and not other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise;
and all such money shall be held by such bank subject to
the draft of the President of this Republic, countersigned by the
Secretary of the Treasury; and the said bank or its agencies
shall notify the Secretary forthwith of all deposites made to the
credit of this Government, and the said commissioners shall cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />respond
with the Secretary of the Treasury, and inform him of
all transactions done by authority of this act.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the
Secretary of the Treasury to lay before each and every congress,
early in every session, a full statement of all the sales of bonds
that may have been effected, showing the terms and conditions
of the same, the expenses accruing thereon, and what disposi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions
have been made of the proceeds of the same.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That for the punctual payment
of the interest, and final redemption of said bonds, the public
faith is hereby solemnly pledged.
Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That all acts and parts of
( 1486 )</p><pb n="1487" xml:id="P1487" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1495/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
17
acts coming within the purview of this act shall be, and the
same are hereby repealed.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, May 16, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Appropriating Five Hundred Dollars for purchasing a set of
Astronomical Instruments.
Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the
Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the sum of five
hundred dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated out of
the Promissory Notes of the Government of Texas, to be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended
under the direction of the Secretary of State, for the
purpose of purchasing a set of Astronomical Instruments for the
use of the Republic.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 17, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Relative to the Claims of Officers and Soldiers of the Army.
Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the
Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the Auditor be,
and he is hereby authorized and required to audit the claims of
officers and soldiers, according to the rates heretofore, allowed
by him.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 18, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1487)</p><pb n="1488" xml:id="P1488" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1496/" /><p>18
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
Providing for the location of Land Scrip issued by an Act of
Congress, dated the.6th day of December, 1836, and for re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />deeming
the same.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Eepresenta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled,—That
from and after the first Thursday of August next, all deputy
surveyors be, and they are hereby authorized and directed, upon
the application of any holder or holders of Land Scrip under the
before recited act, to survey at the expense of this Government,
a sufficient quantity of the vacant land of the public domain
within their respective sections, when said vacant lands shall be
pointed out to them, to satisfy such legal claims of all holders of
Land Scrip sold by this Government agreeably to law in all re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spects.

Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of
such deputy surveyors to make returns of all such surveys to
the county surveyor of his respective county.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the Secretary of the
Treasury be, and he is hereby authorized and required to pay,
after the same shall be audited, the drafts of the respective
county surveyors for such work of his deputies, at the rate of
three dollars per lineal English mile actually run, as well as
three dollars for examination and returning said surveys by the
county surveyor.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That hereafter it shall and may
be lawful for the bona fide holder of any land scrip, to present
the same to the Commissioner for funding the public debt,
which said Commissioner shall fund the same at the rate of
fifty cents per acre and grant certificates of stock therefor.
Sec. 5. And be it further enacted, That the thirty-seventh
section of the present Land Law be, and the same is hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealed.

JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the House of Eepresentatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the. Senate.
Approved. May 18, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1488 )</p><pb n="1489" xml:id="P1489" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1497/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
19
AN ACT
For the relief of persons therein named.
Sec. 1. Be if enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled. That the
First Auditor be, and he is hereby authorized and required to
audit the accounts of John H. Miller, for eighty dollars;—of
Daniel Tyler for sixty-three dollars;—of O. B. Hardeman for two
hundred dollars;—of Wm. Laney for thirty dollars per month
for the time he served as cook to the hospital, according to the
vouchers.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the Auditor be, and he
is hereby authorized and required to audit the claim of George
C. Childress for the sum of one thousand dollars, with interest
from the twenieth of March, eighteen hundred and thirty-six,
at eight per cent, per annum.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the said Auditor be, and
he is hereby authorized and required to audit the claim of one
hundred and fifty dollars in favor of M. A. Bingham, a draft
drawn in favor of Isom Parmer, on the sixth of March, eighteen
hundred and thirty-six; also, of S. Booker, for two hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars,
for a gray mare, valued at that price, lost in the service.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 18, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To provide for settlement of deceased soldiers’ estates.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled,—
That all persons who have, or may hereafter administer upon
the estate of deceased soldiers or officers shall, before the auditor
is allowed to audit the claims, or the Secretary of War, or board
of Land Commissioners, of any county, be authorized to grant
bounty warrants, or land certificates, enter into bond with ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved
security as the court may direct, for the faithful perform<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance
of the duties of such administration; a copy of which bond
94 —VOL. 1.
(1489 )</p><pb n="1490" xml:id="P1490" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1498/" /><p>20
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
and all the proceedings in such cause duly certified under the
hand and seal of the chief justice of such county, shall be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turned
to the Secretary of War.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That hereafter no letters of
administration shall be granted, nor any further action be had
under those that have already been granted, until publication
of such application for letters, or the existence of such letters
of administration shall have been made at least sixty days in ■
one of the public Gazettes, published at the Seat of Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment.

Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That no sale of any of the
effects of any deceased soldier or officer shall be made, unless
by order of the court granting letters of administration, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved
by the Secretary of War, and published in some news<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />.
paper sixty days, and all sales made contrary to the provisions
of this section, (unless by heirs of full age) shall be entirely null
and void.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of
all administrators on the estate of deceased soldiers, to return
to the court granting letters, within ninety days, an inventory of
all the effects of such deceased soldier, and annually at the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bate
court in January in each year, to make return of all his pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceedings,
unless by special leave of the Court, longer time be
granted; a copy of which said inventory and returns shall be
immediately transmitted to the Secretary of War.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of
the Secretary of War once in every three months, to publish in
some public Gazette, the names of all administrators, (and on
whose estate) that may be returned to him.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 18, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Supplementary to “an Act to raise a Public Revenue by Im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />post
Duties.”
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled,
(1490 )</p><pb n="1491" xml:id="P1491" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1499/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
21
That the powers and duties of the Collectors of the revenue
by impost duties, and other officers concerned in the collection
of the same, and the liabilities of the masters and owners of
vessels with their cargoes, and the shippers or consignees thereof,
are hereby declared to be the same as established by law in the
United States of America, and practised in the collection of their
impost duties on the 12th day of June, A. D. 1837.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the same penalties, dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />abilities
and forfeitures, and the like remedies for infractions of
the revenue laws of this Republic shall obtain and be issued,
as were established and in use in the said United States on the
twelfth day of June, A. D. 1837.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, May 18, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
RESOLUTION
For the benefit of Sidney Sherman.
Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the
Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That Sidney Sherman
be, and he is hereby allowed the sum of three thousand nine
hundred and seventy-three dollars and seventeen cents, for ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vices
rendered the government, and money expended for the
same; the amount to be paid in the Promissory Notes of the
government, and that the Auditor be, and he is hereby required
to audit his accounts to that amount.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Vetoed by the President and passed by a constitutional ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority
of the House of Representatives, May 17, A. D. 1838.
Joseph rowe,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
(1491)</p><pb n="1492" xml:id="P1492" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1500/" /><p>22
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
Vetoed by the President, reconsidered, and passed by a unani<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mous
vote of the Senate, May 19, 1838.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
AN ACT
To authorise the President to re-issue the Promissory Notes of
the Government as they return into the Treasury, and making
special appropriations.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled,—That the
President be, and he is hereby authorized and required to have
re-issued, and continue to have re-issued the Promissory Notes
of the Government as they return into the Treasury, until the
appropriations hereafter specified in this .act shall be met and
discharged; as also all other special appropriations which have
been, or may be made by this congress.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the amount of one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
and fifty thousand dollars of the Promissory Notes of the
Government be, and the same is hereby especially appropriated
for the payment of the. civil list claims against the Government.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the amount of two hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
thousand dollars ef the Promissory Notes of the Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
be, and the same is hereby especially appropriated for the
payment of military claims against the Government, for per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal
services rendered: Provided, the claims are in the hands
of the original holders, or their heirs.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the amount of one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
thousand dollars of the Promissory Notes of the Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
be, and the same is hereby especially appropriated for the
payment of the naval claims against the Government, for per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal
services: Provided, the claims are in the hands of the orig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inal
holders, or their heirs.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the holder or hold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers
of any claims contemplated in the third and fourth
sections of this act shall, before the payment thereof, be
required to take the oath specified in the act entitled “an
( 1492 )</p><pb n="1493" xml:id="P1493" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1501/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
23
act to pay the officers and soldiers of the Army and Navy,” ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved
December 14, 1837, which oath may be taken before any
person duly authorized to administer an oath.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That if, in the opinion of the
President, the situation of the Republic shall be such as to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire
a greater issue of the Promissory Notes of this Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
than has already been issued, he is hereby authorized to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />crease
the amount of issues to an amount not exceeding one mil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lion
of dollars.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of
the Treasurer to publish monthly extracts from his books, show<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
the amounts received and the amounts paid out, stating
specially to whom paid, and on what claims.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 18, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
RESOLUTION
For the benefit of Captains Boss and Lynch’s Companies.
Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the
Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the Auditor be,
and he is hereby required to audit the discharges of Captains
Ross and Lynch’s Companies for the time they were actually in
service.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
AN ACT
For the relief of Robert Hodge.
Whereas, it appears that a mistake has occurred in the
Land Office, whereby it appears that the following de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed
tract of land, lying back of leagues number one,
two, and three, east of San Bernards, was by mistake
granted to John Hodge on the fourteenth day of June,
( 1493 )</p><pb n="1494" xml:id="P1494" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1502/" /><p>24
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
eighteen hundred and thirty-one, which was intended for and
should have been Robert Hodge, therefore, Be it enacted by the
Senate and House of Representatives of the Republic of Texas
in Congress assembled, That the Commissioner of the General
Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rect
the aforesaid mistake in the records of his office, by chang<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
the name of John Hodge to that of Robert Hodge; both on
the original grant and the copy of the same now in the posses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion
of the aforesaid Robert Hodge.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 19, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of J. W. Fanning.
Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the
Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the Auditor be,
and he is hereby required, to audit the accounts of J. W. Fannin,
as approved by the Secretary of War, for eight hundred and
twenty-six dollars and fifty cents.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 20, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
For the relief of F. Neblin.
Whereas, F. Neblin acted as assistant commissary-general for
the army during the spring and summer of eighteen hundred
and thirty-six; and whereas, at that time, the commissary De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partment
was in a state of disorganization, for the want of
proper enactments; and whereas, the said Neblin, as appears
from receipts of various officers has discharged his duty faith<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fully:
Therefore,
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the
quarter master-general under the inspection of the Secretary
(1494 )</p><pb n="1495" xml:id="P1495" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1503/" /><p>Laios of the Republic of Texas.
25
of War be authorized to settle with F. Neblin, Assistant Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missary
General upon such terms as he may consider just and
equitable.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 21, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Granting a pension to Mary Millsaps and Family.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That from
and after the passage of this act, a pension of two hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars
per annum for ten years shall be, and the same is hereby
allowed and granted to Mary Millsaps and her children.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the
Secretary of the Treasury to pay the said pension semi-annually
in advance, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated.

Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That an amount of money
sufficient to meet the demand as aforesaid, is hereby especially
appropriated.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 21, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
In favor of the Officers and crews of the Schooners of War
Invincible and Brutus.
Be it resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the Sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retary
of the Treasury be, and he is hereby authorized to
pay out of any money in the treasury not otherwise ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated,
to the officers and crews of the Schooners of
War Invincible and Brutus, or their legal representatives,
one half of the avails of the prizes made by said vessels
on their last cruize, which have been legally condemned;
(1495)</p><pb n="1496" xml:id="P1496" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1504/" /><p>26
Laivs of the Republic of Texas.
according to their respective shares as established by law.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 23, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of Aaron Colvil.
Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the
Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the Auditor of
Public accounts be, and he is hereby authorized and required to
audit the claim of Aaron Colvil for the sum of seventy-five dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars.

JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 23, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Appointing Pilots.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
.of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That from
and after the passage of this act, it shall be lawful for the several
collectors of the ports throughout this republic to appoint and
control pilots of their respective ports, inspect the boats, &amp;c., ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pertaining
and belonging to the said pilots, and used by them in
the discharge of their duties as pilots, and be, in every way, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sponsible
to this Government, for the good conduct and man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />agement
of the aforesaid Pilots.
Sec 2. Be it further enacted, That all pilots who have been
appointed by law previous to the passage of this act, their ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointments
shall be submitted to the different Collectors as
above, for their ratification.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That any person who
shall be appointed as a pilot, shall enter into bonds with
(1496)</p><pb n="1497" xml:id="P1497" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1505/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
27
two or more securities, payable in the sum of five thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars,
to the collector of the port for which he obtains license as
pilot, for the faithful performance of his duties and his good
conduct, and also binding him to keep always good and sufficient
boats for his use.
' JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, May 23, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Establishing a Mail Route from Galveston to- Matagorda and
Texana.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the acting
Post Master General of this Republic be and he is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized
and required, to establish a mail route from the City of Gai<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston
to the towns of Matagorda and Texana, by the way of
Velasco- and Quintana, and contract immediately for the trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />portation
of the mail over said route once in every two weeks.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
S. H. EVERITT,
President pro tem. of the Senate.
Approved, May 23, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Providing for the punishment of offences in the depopulated
Counties.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled. That in
case of offences committed, in either of the counties of San Pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricio,
Victoria, Goliad and Refugio, it shall be the duty of the
sheriff of the -County in which such offence shall have been com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted,
upon the order of the Chief Justice of said county, to
transport the offender or offenders to the nearest County where
• the district courts are regularly organized and held for trial.
( 1497)</p><pb n="1498" xml:id="P1498" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1506/" /><p>28
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That all formalities and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceedings
on the said trial shall be conducted in the same manner,
as if the offence had been committed in the County where the
trial is held.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That when one or more persons
are thus transported to any County for trial, a special Court may
be called in the same manner, as if the offence had been there
committed.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That all judgments rendered in
the cases above referred to, shall be executed in the county where
the trial is held.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That this act shall cease its op<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erations
in each of the above named Counties, whenever a Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict
Court shall be regularly organized and held in the same
respectively.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the House of Eepresentatives.
MIEABEAU B. LAMAE,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 23, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Providing for the payment of the First Loan to Texas.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Eepresentatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That to fulfil and
carry into effect the contract of compromise made on the first
day of April, 1836, between the Government ad interim of Texas,
and the stockholders in the first loan negotiated by the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners
of Texas in New Orleans on the 11th day of January,
1836, the President of the Republic be and he is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized
to issue to the said stockholders the Land Scrip as stipu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lated
in said contract of compromise: Provided the said scrip
shall not be located until after the first Thursday in August
next, and further provided, that no interest shall be allowed on
said loan, but that the land hereby authorized to be given shall
be in full payment and liquidation of said loan.
JOSEPH EOWE,
Speaker of the House of Eepresentatives
MIEABEAU B. LAMAE,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1498 )</p><pb n="1499" xml:id="P1499" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1507/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
29
AN ACT
To amend an Act incorporating the City of San Antonio and
other Towns.
Sec. 1.' Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled. That the
third section of an “act incorporating the city of San Antonio,
and other towns therein named,” shall be amended by inserting
after the word “council” in the ninth line, the words, “and who
with the Treasurer and Collector.”
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the eighth section be
amended by striking out from the first and second lines, the
words “in conjunction with the Justices of the County Courts:”
provided, that this section shall not apply to Gonzales.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the ninth section of said
act be amended by striking out all after the enacting clause, and
inserting the following: “that the mayor be authorized and em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />powered
to act in all cases as guardian and custodier of the peace
and quiet of the city; and he is hereby vested with all the powers
necessary therefor.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That so far as relates to the
town of Victoria, no person shall be allowed to vote for, or be
eligible to fill any office in said council, who shall not be at the
time of the election, the owner of real estate, or actually paying
rent within the incorporated limits of said town, and who shall
not have resided therein, six months previous to the election:
provided, that the Mayor and a majority of the Aidermen, shall
be bona fide owners of real estate within said limits.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That all elections heretofore
held for members of the Council of said town, and which were
not held on the day specified in the fourth section of the above
recited act, are hereby declared null and void; and the Chief
Justice of the county of Victoria shall immediately, upon the
promulgation of this act, order an election for Mayor and Ai<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dermen
for the aforesaid town, for the balance of the year one
thousand eight hundred and thirty-eight.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That so much of an act
entitled “an act to incorporate the town of Brazoria, and
other towns therein named,” as relates to San Patricio, is
hereby repealed; and the town of San Patricio shall be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1499)
</p><pb n="1500" xml:id="P1500" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1508/" /><p>30
Laivs of the Republic of Texas.
corporated under the provisions of this act, and shall be entitled
to the same privileges and subject to the same restrictions as the
town of Victoria.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That so much of “an act, passed
the fourteenth day of December one thousand eight hundred and
thirty-seven, incorporating the city of San Antonio, and other
towns, as conflicts with this act, is hereby repealed: that the town
of Franklin in Robertson County, and the town of Refugio be
incorporated under the same regulations as prescribed in this
act, incorporating the town of Victoria. That so much of an
act, approved December the twenty-ninth, one thousand eight
hundred and thirty-seven, entitled “an act to incorporate the
city of Houston and other towns therein named,” that refers to
the town of Refugio, be, and the same is hereby repealed.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To amend an Act entitled an Act establishing the District
Courts.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That there
shall be a new judicial district established, to be called the Fifth
Judicial District.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the District Courts shall
be holden in the county of San Augustine) on the first Mondays
in March and September, and may continue three weeks. In the
county of Sabine on the fourth Mondays in March and Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber,
and may continue six days. -In the county of Jasper, on the
first Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember,
and may continue two weeks. In the county
of Jefferson on the third Mondays after the fourth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days
in March and September, and may continue one
week. In the county of Liberty on the fourth Mondays
after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and
(1500 )</p><pb n="1501" xml:id="P1501" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1509/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
31
may continue two weeks. In the county of Galveston on the
sixth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber,
and may continue until the business is disposed of.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the second judicial dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict
shall be composed of the counties of Brazoria, Fort Bend,
Harrisburgh, Austin, Colorado and Matagorda. The District
Courts shall be holden in the county of Brazoria at the town of
Brazoria on the first Mondays in March and October,' and may
continue three weeks; In the county of Matagorda on the fourth
Mondays in March and October and may continue two weeks.
In the county of Colorado on the second Mondays after the
fourth Mondays in March and October, and may continue one
week. In the county of Austin, on the third Mondays after the
fourth Mondays in March and October, and may continue one
week. In the county of Fort Bend, on the Fourth Mondays after
the fourth Mondays in March and October, and many continue
one week. In the county of Harrisburgh on the fifth Mondays
after the fourth Mondays in March and October, and may con- ■
tinue until the business shall be disposed of.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the third judicial district
shall be composed of the counties of Washington, Montgomery,
Robertson, Milam, Bastrop and Fayette.—The Courts shall be
holden in the county of Washington on the second Mondays in
March and September, and may continue two weeks; In the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty
of Montgomery on the fourth Mondays in March and Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber,
and may continue six days; in the county of Robertson on
the first Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember,
and may continue six days; In the county of Milam on
the second Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and
September, and may continue six days; In the county of Fayette
on the fourth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and
September, and may continue six days; In the county of Bastrop
on the fifth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and
September, and may continue two weeks.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That the fourth judicial
district shall be composed of the counties of Gonzales,
Jackson, Victoria, Goliad, Refugio-, San Patricio and
(1501 )</p><pb n="1502" xml:id="P1502" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1510/" /><p>32
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
Bexar.. The Courts shall he holden in the county of Gonzales,
on the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue
six days; in the county of Jackson on the second Mondays
in March and September, and may continue six days; In the
county of Victoria on the third Mondays in March and Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber,
and may continue six days; in the county of Goliad on the
fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue six
days; In the county of Refugio on the first Mondays after the
fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue six
days; In the county of San Patricio on the second Mondays after
the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue
six days; In the county of Bexar on the third Mondays after the
Fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />til
all the business is finished.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the fifth judicial district
shall be composed of the counties of Houston, Nacogdoches,
Shelby, Red River and Tannin: The courts shall be holden in
the county of Houston, on the first Mondays in April and Oc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tober,
and may continue six days; In the county of Nacogdoches
on the second Mondays in April and October, and may continue
three weeks; In the county of Shelby on the first Mondays after
the fourth Mondays in April and October, and may continue two
weeks; In the county of Red River, on the third Mondays after
the fourth Mondays in April and October, and may continue two
weeks; In the county of Tannin on the fifth Mondays after the
fourth Mondays in April and October, and may continue two
weeks.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That the Supreme Court shall
be holden at the Seat of Government on the second Monday in
January of each year, and may continue in session until all the
business before it is finished.
Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That the alternation of
the district judges, as now provided for, shall, from and
after the passage of this act, be, and the same is hereby
repealed; and the judges shall only be required to alter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nate
in case of the interest of either of the Judges in any
suit in his circuit, when such alternation shall be had by
( 1502 )</p><pb n="1503" xml:id="P1503" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1511/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
33
them in such manner as to suit the wishes and convenience of the
judges.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
For the benefit of John R. Foster.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the first
Auditor of Public Accounts be, and he is hereby required to
audit and allow the claim of John R. Foster, for personal services
in the army of Texas, from the eighth of October eighteen hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
and thirty-five, to the fourteenth of February, eighteen hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred
and thirty-six, and the Secretary of War is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized
to issue to said Foster a certificate to bounty land corre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sponding
with said term of service.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
For the relief of A. C. Horton.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the Secretary
of the Navy be, and he is hereby authorized and directed to allow
A. C. Horton at the rate of three hundred and fifty dollars per
month for his services as Navy Agent from the twenty-third day
of December, eighteen hundred and thirty-seven, to the time of
his return; and that the same shall be deducted out of the claims
now held by the Government against said Horton.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1503 )</p><pb n="1504" xml:id="P1504" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1512/" /><p>34
Laws of tire Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
For the relief of the heirs of certain persons therein named.
Whereas, a bill providing for the settlement of deceased sol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diers’
estates, makes it obligatory on those administering upon
their estates, to publish the act of administration three months
before they shall be permitted to act upon the duties of that of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice;
and whereas, the advantages of priority of location guaran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teed
to those who were here before the declaration of Independ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence
will be lost, because the time to which that priority is lim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ited,
will have transpired, and consequent injury result to their
heirs. Therefore,
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That J. C.
Duval and Wm. P. Brashear, upon the evidence of two or more
respectable witnesses testifying from personal knowledge that
they are the brothers, and consequently the lawful heirs of B. H.
Duval and R. C. Brashear, (who were of the number of the un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fortunate
companions of Fannin,) be permitted to receive their
pay, bounty land and head rights, in the same manner as if they
had complied with the law requiring them to administer and to
publish the act of administration, and forbidding them to act
upon the duties of their office until the expiration of three
months.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the Auditor be authorized
and directed to audit the accounts of B. H. Duval and R. C.
Brashear, and the Secretary of War, and Board of Land Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners
be directed upon the evidence of two or more respectable
witnesses, to issue the certificates for their bounty land and head
rights.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
' For the benefit of P. S. Wyatt.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in congress assembled, That the sum
of twelve hundred ■ dollars be, and the same is hereby
allowed to P. S. Wyatt to be paid out of the Promisso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1504
)</p><pb n="1505" xml:id="P1505" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1513/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
35
ry notes of this Government for fifty, stand of arms, and monies
expended by him in bringing a company of volunteers to Texas,
in the year eighteen hundred and thirty-five; provided that six
hundred dollars of the above appropriation shall be reserved by
the treasurer of this republic, until a similar demand shall be
made by the Government of the State of Alabama, on P. S. Wy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />att;
this provisor being made at the request of P. S. Wyatt.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
For the. relief of M. B. Menard.
Be it resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the Auditor
be, and he is hereby directed to audit the accounts of M. B.
Menard for the sum of twenty-one hundred dollars for his serv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ices
as commissioner of the republic of Texas to the United
States of America.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24,1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the benefit of William Kuykendall.
Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the
Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the Auditor of
Public Accounts is hereby required to audit and allow the claim’,
of William Kuykendall for two hundred and five dollars for a
horse and corn furnished the armv of Texas.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
95—vol. i.
(1505 )</p><pb n="1506" xml:id="P1506" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1514/" /><p>36
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
A JOINT RESOLUTION
Fixing the dividing line between the counties of Bexar and San
Patricio.
Be it resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That a direct line
running from the junction of the Cibolo or San Bartola creek,
to the Rio Frio, at a point thirty miles above its junction with
the Nueces; thence in a direct line to the town of Loredo, shall
be considered the dividing line between the counties of San
Patricio and Bexar, and shall be respected as such by the sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />.
veyors of the respective counties, provided that this act shall not
. .affect rights previously acquired by surveys legally made by the
surveyors of the county of San Patricio, below the old road from
San Antonio to the presidio of Rio Grande.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Establishing certain mail routes therein named.
Sec. 1. Be it resolved by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That there
shall be a mail route established by this act from the town of
Bastrop to the residence of Reuben Homsleys, on the Colorado
liver.
Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That there shall be established
a mail route from the town of Anahuac in the county of Liberty,
to the house of Thomas Stubblefield, on Trinity river, in said
county; also a route from the town of Shelbyville, in Shelby
county, to the town. of Milam, in Sabine county, by the way of
Hamilton on the Sabine river.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the benefit of Hiram Wood.
Be it resolved by the S'enate and House of Representatives of
(1506 )</p><pb n="1507" xml:id="P1507" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1515/" /><p>LojWS of the Republic of Texas.
37
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer
of the Republic be, and he is hereby authorized to’ pay out
of the promissory notes of the Government, the amount of a
draft in favor Hiram Wood for three thousand three hundred
and twenty-two dollars, for Naval supplies, out of any money in
the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, if, on examination of
the vouchers of the claim, they be found in conformity with
law and equity.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR.
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 26, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Supplementary to an Act providing for the Location of Land
Scrip, issued under the Act of Congress dated 6th Decem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber,
1836, and for redeeming the same.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That
the provisions of the above recited act do, and they are hereby
declared to extend to all Land Scrip issued and sold by the au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority
of the Government of Texas, in accordance with law in
all respects.
JOSEPH ROWE,
•Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR.
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
CHARTER
Of Galveston and Brazos Rail-road.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That
a company be incorporated under the name and style of
Brazos and Galveston Rail-road Company, under the
rules and regulations hereinafter mentioned: and under
this title may transfer their rights by succession or as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(
1507 )</p><pb n="1508" xml:id="P1508" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1516/" /><p>38
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
signment, and shall be persons in law capable of suing and being
sued, pleading and being impleaded, answering and being an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />swered
unto, defending and being defended, in all courts and
places whatsoever; and that they and their successors may have
a common seal, and may change and alter the same at pleasure;
and also, that they and their successors by the same name and
style, shall be, in law, capable of holding, purchasing, and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veying
any estate, real, personal, or mixed, for the use of’said
corporation, and doing and performing all things which are
necessary and common for companies of a similar nature to do,
not contrary to the provisions of this charter, as hereinafter en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />acted,
or to the Constitution of this Republic.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the said company shall
have the right to make turnpikes and rail-roads, from the main
channel of Galveston Bay to the Brazos river.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That the capital stock of said
company shall be five hundred thousand dollars,_and be divided
into five thousand shares of one hundred dollars each.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That the management of the
affairs of said company, shall be conducted by a board of five
directors, each of whom shall own at least fifty- shares of the
capital stock of the said company, and three of said directors
shall form a quorum to do and perform all the business necessary
to the successful operation of said improvements; that a ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority
of said directors shall appoint a President from one of
their number, and fill such vacancies as may from time to time
take place, from death, resignation, or otherwise; that after the
election mentioned in section eighth in this act, all ensuing
elections for directors shall be held annually at the village of
Austinia, on the first Monday of June of each year, and in case
of failure to elect, on the day fixed by this act, the corporation
shall not be dissolved for that cause, but the President and Di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors
for the time being, shall continue in office until there
shall be an election, and that the stockholders shall have one
vote for each share that they own, and may vote by attorney.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That on application for
(1508)</p><pb n="1509" xml:id="P1509" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1517/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
39
shares the sum of twenty dollars for each share applied for shall
he deposited with the commissioners, and the balance shall be
paid at such times, and upon such terms, as the President and
Directors may designate; provided, that no more than ten dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars
on each share shall be called for at a time; and also pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided,
that public notice in a Newspaper published at the seat
of government, be given for sixty days, and in case that any
of the stockholders neglect to pay any of the instalments after
being thus advised, at the expiration of said term, the shares,
as also the first or subsequent instalments which may have been
paid, shall be forfeited for the benefit of the company, and a
new subscription may be opened to cover any deficit occasioned
by said shares.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That the President and Direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors
of the said company shall prescribe the form of certificates
of shares of stock, and the manner of transferring such certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficates,
but the transfer shall be made in a book to be kept for
the purpose by said company at their place of doing business,
which transfer shall be made in the presence of, and attested by,
either the president or secretary of said company, and a trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fer
may be made by such shareholders in person, or by his, her,
or their agent: The power of attorney to such agent to be duly
proved and certified, and lodged with the president or secretary
of said company; provided, that no transfer shall be allowed to
be made on the transfer book, except it be done at least fifteen
days previous, or five days after the day of election, for Direct<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ors
as appointed in section fourth of this act.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That books for the subscrip<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of the capital stock of said company shall be opened as
follows, viz: At the city of Houston, for two thousand shares
of said stock, under the superintendence of W. G. Cooke and
Asa Brigham; at the village of Austinia, for fifteen hundred
shares, under the superintendence of James F. Perry and George
L. Hammeken; at the town of Brazoria, for fifteen hundred
shares, under the superintendence of Edmund Andrews and
Frederick A. Sawyer, and' shall remain open until at least one
thousand shares are subscribed for, at which time due returns
of all the subscriptions shall be made to the commissioners of
Austinia,
( 1509 )</p><pb n="1510" xml:id="P1510" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1518/" /><p>40
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
Sec. 8. Be it further enacted. That whenever one thousand
shares of said stock shall have been taken, the commissioners
shall give thirty days notice, in one or more Newspapers pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished
at the seat of government of this republic, that the num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber
of shares required by the act of incorporation to organize
the company, have been subscribed, and that an election will be
held at Austinia, or at such place as the commissioners may de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />termine,
to choose by a majority of the votes of the subscribers,
by ballot, to be delivered in person, or by proxy, duly authorized,
five directors, a treasurer, and such other officers as they may
think necessary to conduct the business of said company for one
year, or until other such officers shall be elected.
Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That when the company shall
be duly organized in conformity with sections four and eight of
this act, the President and Directors shall have full power to
borrow money upon the faith of this charter, to accomplish the
object of the present act: and may hypothecate the stock or other
property, real or personal, and issue certificates for the payment
of the same, and also to do and perform as directors of said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany,
everything necessary and proper to carry it into complete
operation.
Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That the President and Direc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors,
with such surveyors, engineers, artists, and chain-carriers,
as they may think necessary, are hereby authorized to enter in
and upon the land and enclosures, and public roads and high<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ways
in, through, and over which, the said intended turnpikes
or rail-roads may be thought proper to pass; and to examine and
survey the ground most proper for the purpose; and also that
the said President and Directors, shall have the right to sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vey,
lay out, and make their roads, through any improved or un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />improved
lands, on the most eligible route; and should the said
company or their agents not be able to make arrangements
with the owner or owners of the said land through which it may
be necessary to run said improvements, or should said owner or
owners, not be capable of contracting, or be absent or unknown,
the company may petition the judge of the county in which
said land is situated, giving a description of the lands which
they deem necessary and indispensable for their opera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions,
with the names of the proprietors, if they can be as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(151b)
</p><pb n="1511" xml:id="P1511" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1519/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
41
certained; and the said judge shall then summon a jury of six
freeholders, not interested in the company, who shall make a
report of the value of the land so required, and upon the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
thereof by the company, either to the owner, or to the
treasurer of the county, a good and bona fide title shall be
granted by the judge, a copy of which shall be recorded in the
Recorder’s office of the county where the land is situated; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided,
that the lands so required shall not exceed fifty yards
in width.
Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That should said company
wish to occupy any portion of the public lands by their im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provements
they shall have a right to take possession of, and
pay to the government, .the minimum price of such lands; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided,
that the land so required shall not exceed fifty yards
in width.
Sec. 12. Be it further enacted, That if any person or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons
whatsoever, shall wilfully, by any means whatever, injure,
molest, or destroy any part of the turnpikes or rail-roads, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structed
by said company under this act, or any of their works,
buildings, fixtures, or machines, or other property, such person
or persons, so offending, shall each of them be liable for all dam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ages
occasioned thereby, and at any time within twelve months
after such offence shall have been committed, and upon convic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
be punished by a fine not exceeding ten thousand dollars;
or imprisonment, not exceeding twelve months, or both, at the
discretion of the court.
Sec. 13. Be it further enacted, That, the said company may
establish on their different routes, and make use of, all kinds of
boats, vehicles, wagons, or carriages of any nature whatsoever,
for the purpose of transportation; that so soon as the work is
completed, the managers, or directors thereof, shall report to
Congress, who shall have the sole power of regulating the rates
of tolls for passing said railway; and all Government stores,
arms, ammunition and men, that the Government may find it
necessary to pass over said road, shall be transported free of toll
or other charge.
Sec. 14. Be it further enacted, That the said company
may construct -bridges, and make such improvements in
the different bays, rivers, bayous, creeks, &amp;c. as may
be deemed expedient by them or their agents, provided,
(1511)</p><pb n="1512" xml:id="P1512" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1520/" /><p>42
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
that said bridges do not in any way obstruct the navigation of
the aforesaid rivers.
Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That in the event that ten
miles of the aforesaid turnpikes or rail-roads, shall not be com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleted
within four years from and after the passage of this act,
the land Specified in sections ten and eleven, shall revert to the
original proprietors, the money paid by the company shall be
retained by the said proprietors, as an indemnification for the
occupancy of the same, and the said charter shall be forfeited,
.and forever thereafter be null and void.
Sec. 16. Be it further enacted, That this act shall not be so
construed, as to permit of banking privileges in any form what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever.

JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR.
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
To Amend the Direct Tax Law.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That.
it shall be the duty of the assessors, so soon as they may be noti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied
of their appointment, to advertise in at least three of the
most public places within each captain’s beat, giving at least
twenty days notice to all persons living within the bounds of
the same, that he will attend at the mustering grounds for said
beats on a particular day or days, for the purpose of receiving
a list of taxable property, at which time and place he shall at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tend,
and remain a sufficient length of time to enable all persons
who may attend to give in their several lists.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That each and every
person giving a list of their taxable property, shall take
the following oath, to be administered by the assessor, or
some other person duly authorized to administer an oath:
"I, A. B., do solemnly swear (or affirm as the case may
be) that this list contains a true and perfect account of
(1512)</p><pb n="1513" xml:id="P1513" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1521/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
43
all and every species of taxable property belonging to me, or in
my possession on the first day of January last, within the bounds
of this republic, and what I consider to be a fair valuation of the
same, and that no change or removal of property hath been made,
or entered into in order to evade the payment of tax, so help me
God.”—If the assessor, however, shall think the valuation to be
unfair, he may appoint two disinterested persons, who shall upon
oath affix the valuation thereof, which shall be final.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That if any person shall fail
or refuse to give a list of his taxable property before the expira<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion
of the time allowed the assessor to make his assessments,
he shall be subject to pay a double tax, and the sheriff is hereby
required to collect the same, and to make due returns in like
manner with other taxes, giving a correct account thereof, and
the sheriff in making his returns of monies, or other taxes by
him collected, shall swear and subscribe to the following oath,
to be administered by some person duly qualified to administer
the same: "I, A. B., do solemnly swear that the list of taxes
accompanying this affidavit contains a just and true account of
all the taxes by me collected up to this time; excepting such as
I have previously made due returns of.”
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of the
several clerks of the county courts to make out within one
month after he receives the returns from the assessor a copy in
alphabetical order, of the names of every person, who has given
in a list of their taxable property, together with a list of the
property so given in by them, and valuation, and post the same
up in the court-house where it shall remain subject to the
inspection of the public, and any person who shall be guilty
of mutilating, destroying or removing the same, shall be deemed
guilty of a high misdemeanor, and upon convicition, shall
be fined, not less than one thousand dollars, and imprisoned
not less than thirty days; and it shall also be the
duty of said clerks to make and furnish to the sheriff a
similar copy of such list of taxable property, on or before
the first Monday in April succeeding each term; for all
of which services the county court shall adjudge and al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1513
)</p><pb n="1514" xml:id="P1514" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1522/" /><p>44
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
low said clerks a reasonable compensation, to be paid out of the
county treasury, upon their order.
Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty of
the sheriffs to collect, as the law directs, all the taxes which
may be due from persons of their respective counties, and in
case any person should prove insolvent for their taxes, the sheriff
shall make a due return of all such to the clerk of the county
court, who shall make a list of the same and put it up in the
court house.
Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That all persons owning tax<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able
property situated within the bounds of the county in which
they reside, in giving a list of their property, shall describe the
same particularly, stating the quality, species, quantity, valua<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion,
and in what county it is situated, and a separate list for
property situated in different counties, lists of which taxable
property shall be transmitted to the clerk of each county where
such property may be situated, upon which list it shall be law<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful
for the county court to levy a tax for county purposes, which
tax shall be levied and collected as other county taxes are in
such county.
Sec. 7. Be it further enacted, That it shall not be lawful
for any county court, or any corporation, to levy and collect a
currency differing in character from that which is levied by the
republic.
Sec. 8. Be it further enacted, That hereafter a direct tax shall
be levied and collected alone upon lands, and slaves, horses, over
two: mules, over two; neat cattle over twenty-five in number;
clocks, watches, pleasure carriages, and town and city lots; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided,
that nothing in this act shall be so construed, as to repeal
so much of an act enforcing taxes on taverns, grog-shops, bil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liard-tables,
merchants, nine-pin alleys, and poll tax.
Sec. 9. Be it further enacted, That in all counties where
taxes have not been given in and paid according to the laws,
it shall be the duty of the assessor to assess, and the sheriff to
collect, the taxes for the preceding year or years, at the same
time the taxes are assessed and collected for the current year,
according to the rates established heretofore by law.
Sec. 10. Be it further enacted, That it shall be the duty
of the clerks of the county courts, in the new counties
(1514)</p><pb n="1515" xml:id="P1515" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1523/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
45
which have been created during the years 1837 and 1838, to ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain
from the clerks of the counties out of which such new coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties
have been created, a certified copy of the assessments or list
of taxes due upon property within the new county, which were
due before the division was made, which assessment or tax list
shall be delivered to the sheriff of the new county, and by him
collected agreeably to law.
Sec. 11. Be it further enacted, That in all cases where there
is no personal property to be found whereon to distrain for taxes
on lands and lots, the sheriff shall report all such lands and
lots to the county court, whose duty it shall be to enter up judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
against the same, and the owners thereof, for the amount
of taxes, costs and charges thereon, and an order of sale shall
issue to the sheriff, requiring him to sell the same, and the re-,
turn of the sheriff on such order shall be good in law as all
other sales made on a fieri facias; all lands and lots so sold may
be redeemed by the original owner, within twelve months from
the day of sale by paying fifty per cent on the amount.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR.
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
RESOLUTION
Declaring John Vince the Legitimate Son of Allen Vince and
Matilda Welbourne.
Be it resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That John
Vince, son of Allen Vince and Matilda Welbourne, be, and he
is hereby declared legitimate, and capable in law of inheriting
his parents’ property in the same manner as if he had been born
in lawful wedlock.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR.
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1515)</p><pb n="1516" xml:id="P1516" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1524/" /><p>46
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
Respecting the Abatement of Suits, &amp;c.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That
when any party may die pending any suit in any of the courts
of this republic, the suit shall not thereby abate, but upon the
death being suggested upon the docket, it shall and may be
lawful to issue a scire facias, returnable to the next term of the
court, which being served upon the executor, administrator,
guardian, curator, or heirs, they shall be made parties to said
suit.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That when any person hath or
may hereafter die intestate, and no person will administer on
said estate, it shall and may be lawful for any person who hath
commenced any suit against such intestate in his life time, and
may wish to recover the same, to issue a scire facias against the
heirs of such intestate, and in case the heirs or minors are ab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent
from the republic, it shall be the duty of the court to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point
a guardian for such heirs as are minors, for the purpose of
defending said suit, and on a return of the scire facias having
been served upon the guardian or heirs, as the case may be,
the said plaintiff may prosecute his said suit to judgment and
execution as in other cases.
Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That no suit now pending or
which may be hereafter brought in any of the courts by a feme
sole, shall abate by her marriage, and it shall be lawful for the
husband, at the next succeeding term after his marriage, to
make himself party to any such suit, and to prosecute the same
as if he and his wife had been original plaintiffs to such suit.
Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That no suits in any of the
courts which are now pending or which may be hereafter
brought against a feme sole shall abate by her intermarriage,
but their husbands respectively may be made defendants to such
suits, by scire facias, and judgment may be rendered therein,
and execution issue as though such suit had been instituted
against such husband and wife jointly; provided that nothing
herein contained shall be so construed as to make the husband
liable for any debts contracted by said feme sole before mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />riage.

Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That when any suit
(1516)</p><pb n="1517" xml:id="P1517" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1525/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
47
shall have been or may hereafter be commenced in the name of
one person for the use of another, and the person whose name
may be used, shall depart this life during the pending of such
suit, it shall not be necessary to revive said suit in the name of
the representative of the deceased, but said suit may be prose<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cuted
in the same manner as though said death had not hap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pened,
the same having been suggested on the record.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Supplementary to an Act Granting Lands to those who were
in the Battle of San Jacinto and other Battles.
Seg. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That
the conditions contained in the first section of the act to which
this is a supplement, so far as relates to the individuals who
were in the action of the 19th March, 1836, under the commands
of Colonels Eannin and Ward, and also those who fell at the
Alamo under the commands of Bowie and Travis, are hereby
cancelled.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the Secretary of War is
hereby authorized and required to issue land warrants agreeably
to all the provisions of the aforesaid act, which is not repealed
by this act, to the legal representatives, in the name of the heirs
of all persons embraced in the first section of this act, upon the
production of satisfactory testimony that the persons whom they
represent were among those who fell in either of the two actions
above named.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1517)</p><pb n="1518" xml:id="P1518" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1526/" /><p>48
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
AN ACT
To Define the boundary Line of the County of Montgomery.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the
boundaries of the county of Montgomery shall be as hereinafter
expressed, to wit: Beginning at a point on the east side of the
Navasoto river, where the San Antonio road crosses the same;
thence eastwardly with said road to the Trinity river; thence
down said river to the boundary line of the county of Liberty;
thence west and south with the boundary line of said county
till it strikes the northern boundary line of the county of Harris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />burg;
thence west with the boundary line of said county to the
county of Austin; thence with said county line to the Brazos
river; thence up said river to the mouth of the Navasoto; thence
up the Navasoto to the place of beginning.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That all acts and parts of acts
coming within the purview and meaning of this act be, and the
same are hereby repealed.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Supplementary to an Act entitled an Act to Authorize the Clerks
of the several Courts to appoint Deputies, approved Dec. 21st,
1837.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the clerk
of the Supreme Court be and he is herebv authorized to appoint
a deputy upon the terms and conditions prescribed to clerks of
the District and County Courts in the act entitled “an act to au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorize
the clerks of the several courts to appoint deputies, &amp;c.,"
approved December 21st, 1837.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
(1518)</p><pb n="1519" xml:id="P1519" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1527/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
49
AN ACT
Defining the Boundaries of the Counties of Bastrop and Gon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zales.

Be it enacted by the. Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That from and
after the passage of this act the following shall be the line be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween
the counties of Bastrop and Gonzales: beginning at the
northeast corner of a tract of land granted one Stifflin, thence to
its north-west corner, thence to the north-west corner of a league
granted to S, Hall, thence north-west with a line run and marked
by Bartlett Simes for the line between Dewit’s Colony and S. F.
Austin to the San Antonio road, thence westwardly with the
same to the Guadaloupe, up the same to the north-west of Mi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lam’s
Colony, thence north seventeen degrees east to the dividing<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ridge
between Colorado and Brazos, thence down the same clos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing
on Fayette.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Better to -Define the Duties of Sheriffs.
Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That if
any sheriff shall fail to return an execution within the time pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed
by law, or shall neglect to pay money recovered upon an
execution, to the counsel of record for the plaintiff in execution,
there shall be rendered against such sheriff, a judgment for the
account due upon the execution, with ten per cent, damages, and
also ten per cent, interest per month until the whole amount
shall be paid; provided, that the party moving for such judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment
shall have given to the sheriff at least three days notice,
before the motion made, which judgment may be rendered be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore
any court of record in the county where such execution was
issued.
Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That in any case where
the sheriff is a party to the suit, all processes shall be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />(1519)
</p><pb n="1520" xml:id="P1520" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1528/" /><p>50
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
ecuted by the constable of the township where the court is held
in cases where there is no coroner in the county, or if he be ab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent
from the seat of justice of the county, at the time the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess
is obtained, and in such case the constable shall have juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction
co-extensive with the county.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
Providing for Issuing Certificates of Head Rights to the Heirs
of those who fell with or under Fannin, Travis, Grant and
Johnson.
Be it resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That a certificate
from the Secretary of War shall be a sufficient evidence to any
of the boards of land commissioners to grant certificates of head
rights to the heirs, or legal representatives of those who fell
while under the command of, or with Fannin, Travis, Grant and
Johnson, in the Spring of eighteen hundred and thirty-six.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Defining the Boundaries of Austin County.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That all that
territory comprehended within the following limits shall
compose the territory belonging to the county of Austin,
to wit: beginning on the San Bernard at the lower line
of Cole’s League of Land, thence in an eastwardly di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rection
.with the upper line of Fort Bend County to the
north-east corner of said line on Buffalo Bayou; thence'
in a northwardly direction with the county line between
( 1520 )</p><pb n="1521" xml:id="P1521" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1529/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
51
Harrisburg and Austin to the head of Spring creek, thence in
a direct line to the head of Pond creek, thence to the mouth of
Beason’s creek, thence crossing the Brazos river to the mouth of
Caney creek, and up said creek with the line of Washington
county to its source; thence with said line to a league of land
granted to Harmon Hansley, thence to a league of land granted
to David Shelby, thence in a direct line to a league of land grant<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed
to Samuel O. Pettis, including said land, thence in a direct
line to the head of San Bernard, and down the same to the place
of beginning.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the relief of D. B. Friar.
Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the
Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the first Auditor
be and he is hereby directed, to audit and pay the claims of
D. B. Friar on this Government, in conformity with equity and
justice, and according to law.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
Relative to the Duties of the Collector of the Port of Velasco.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the
Collector of the Port of Velasco, be required to despatch
all vessels which may arrive at said Port destined to
Brazoria or Columbia, forthwith to their place of desti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation,
and to place an officer on board of said vessels to
96—vol. i.
(1521 )</p><pb n="1522" xml:id="P1522" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1530/" /><p>52
Laws of the Bepublic of Texas.
deliver the cargoes and secure or receive the duties thereon,
agreeably to law, and former practice.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1833.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the Benefit of John Talbott.
Sec. 1. Be it resolved by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled,—That
the Secretary of War be and he is hereby authorized and required
to issue to John Talbott a land warrant for twelve' hundred and
eighty acres of bounty land for his services as armorer at Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston
Island; provided always that twelve hundred and eighty
acres, is to be the full amount of bounty land the said Talbott
shall receive for past services.
Sec. 2. Be it further resolved, That the auditor is hereby
directed to audit the said Talbott’s claims on the Government
for pay, to the amount of fifty dollars per month for such time
as he acted as master armorer, deducting the amount he may
have received.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
AN ACT
For the Belief of George Sutherland.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of
the Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the auditor
be authorized and required to audit the claim of George Suther<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />land
for fourteen hundred dollars, it being for corn, cattle and
hogs furnished the army.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 24, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1522)</p><pb n="1523" xml:id="P1523" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1531/" /><p>Laws of the Republic of Texas.
53
AN ACT
Appointing Commissioners to view and mark out a road from
Bastrop to Red River.
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives
of the Republic of Texas in Congres assembled, That
R. B. Craft, William Barton, and Captain Lynch, be,
and they are hereby appointed Commissioners to view and
mark out a road from Bastrop on the Colorado river, to
the Trinity river, at or near the uper Three Forks, and
that Baily English, Robert Sloan, and Levi M. Rice be, and
they are hereby appointed Commissioners to view and mark our
a road from the point on Trinity, at or near the upper Three
Forks thereof, so as to intersect with the road marked out from
that point to Bastrop on the Colorado river, to some point on
Red river not below the Spanish Bluffs, nor above the Cross
Timbers, and it shall be the duty of the said two appointments
of Commissioners to confer with each other and fix on. the time
at which they will meet, at or near the Three Forks of Trinity,
so as to depart from the same point (or agree on the point) at
which said road shall cross Trinity river, and it shall be the duty
of said Commissioners to report to Congress at the next session,
and shall be entitled to three dollars per day for said services,
out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated;
Provided/however, that they shall not be paid for more than
twenty days.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 26, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
JOINT RESOLUTION
For the Relief of John Murray.
Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the
Republic of Texas in Congress assembled, That the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer
of this republic be, and he is hereby authorized and
required to pay Capt. John Murray, with the promissory
notes of the Government, the sum of two thousand one
(1523)</p><pb n="1524" xml:id="P1524" facs="https://texashistory.unt.edu/ark:/67531/metapth5872/m1/1532/" /><p>54
Laws of the Republic of Texas.
hundred and one dollars and thirty-five cents, being the bal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance
due on his draft audited 16th July, 1836, at Velasco,
which audited draft shall be the voucher for the Treasurer.
JOSEPH ROWE,
Speaker of the House of Representatives.
MIRABEAU B. LAMAR,
President of the Senate.
Approved, May 26, 1838.
SAM. HOUSTON.
( 1524 )</p></div></body></text>
